<movie id="464" title="Robin Hood Prince of Thieves">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says you stole his bread.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lowlife jabbers some more. The Interrogator debates.</context>
      <utterance>It is a lie. I caught him stealing ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut off the infidel's hand. The jailers haul Peter to the chopping block.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!... I took the bread.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not true.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Interrogator stares into Robin's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>They're not interested in truth. You are too weak, Peter. You would not live through it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He indicates an Arab prisoner, who is dragged forward. His struggling hand is laid on the executioner's block.</context>
      <utterance>Sacrifice for the weaker? How noble... As you wish... Cut off this one's hand as well!... But first...</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prisoner's face braces for the pain. A red-hot scimitar flashes down. The hand flips into a basket. Twitching. Robin is next. His composure fails. He flops to his knees, crying. The Interrogator laughs. The jailers unlash the thongs on Robin's hand. They stretch it out, forcing it down. Robin goes limp, sobbing. Peter catches his eye... Robin winks. The scimitar. Drawn from the coals. Spitting flame. Arcs down. Robin is suddenly galvanized.</context>
      <utterance>Show them the courage of Allah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurls his holders aside. Swings upward, driving his fast into the executioner's throat. Grabs the sword. Slash. His thongs melt like butter. A jailer leaps at him. Steaming, the scimitar slices into the man's chest. Despite his bindings, Peter wrestles the Interrogator. Knife pressed to his throat, Peter is forced against the furnace. At the last second, he flips the man into the fire. Screaming.</context>
      <utterance>And this is English courage.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's for five years of hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Warned, Robin ducks away. Slams the jailer's head into the wall. Peter frees himself, but they are still outnumbered. While fighting, Robin acknowledges the man who shouted the warning. An imposing, shaven-headed SARACEN. Heavily-muscled arms and chest, covered in tattoos. Even his bald head is ornamented.</context>
      <utterance>Behind you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You speak English?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The king's own. Set me free.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Robin.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin sidesteps, propelling a guard into a pit.</context>
      <utterance>For pity's sake. Mine is a sentence of death.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two more guards attack, yelling fury. Robin eyes the curved scimitar.</context>
      <utterance>Don't trust him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A guard swings at him with a giant axe. Robin slashes... shears the axe handle in two.</context>
      <utterance>What I would give for an English sword. This is a pruning hook.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs the man through. Peter loses his sword. His opponent moves in for the kill... Peter grabs tongs from the fire and smolders his opponent with a backhand. Commotion outside. RAISED VOICES and RUNNING FEET.</context>
      <utterance>Hmm! Not bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Free me and I will show you a way out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should we trust you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't, you are dead men.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door bursts open. More guards rush in.</context>
      <utterance>He makes a point.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slashes the man free.</context>
      <utterance>A good point.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robin!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever blood is in his veins, he does not deserve to die here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He beckons them to the back. A hidden door leads into a tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>This way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are fast, my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guards drop down from above, carrying torches. Blocking the way.</context>
      <utterance>Five years I've waited for the smell of free air. That makes a man fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A narrow opening to their left... they splash through. Half running, half crawling in the dank water. Fire arrows land around them. The orange smoke is choking.</context>
      <utterance>You will need to be yet faster.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flames illuminate the walls, alive with a loathsome mass of crawling slime. Peter falls. A pursuer descends on him, thrusting a blazing torch at his face. The Saracen intercepts the blow. Grabs the man's neck, SNAPPING it with one mighty twist.</context>
      <utterance>Poison air. Hold your breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. I misjudged you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gasping for air, they find the tunnel veers steeply down- ward. A slippery, granite tube. Losing purchase, they slide headlong. Sharp, rusted spikes jut out from the walls ahead. Robin grabs at the walls to break the fall. No use. They're picking up speed. He turns his sword crossways, bracing it against the sides of the tunnel, as a brake. Sparks fly. The sword cuts into Robin's chest... but it works.</context>
      <utterance>Save your breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allah be praised.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bloodcurdling scream. A pursuing guard tumbles down the sewer chute. The three men press themselves against the wall. The man hurtles by... is impaled on the spikes. A draft of fresh air from the roof of the tunnel. Using the spiked guard as a ladder, Robin climbs. Removes a grating.</context>
      <utterance>Amen, brother.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raising his sword, Peter faces the oncoming soldiers.</context>
      <utterance>Come, Peter. We must hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is mortal. Leave me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peter shakes him off.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on to my shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin looks despairingly to the Saracen.</context>
      <utterance>My mother... my little sister. Tell them I love them. Tell them I died a free Englishman.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin knows it's true. Peter pulls an insignia ring from a hidden pouch in his clothes. Thrusts it into Robin's hand.</context>
      <utterance>His wound is by the heart. We cannot save him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take this to my sister. Swear you will protect her for me... Swear it, Robin!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Summoning hidden resources of strength, Peter charges at the oncoming soldiers, brandishing his sword.</context>
      <utterance>I swear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fells the first Arab. The Saracen pulls Robin away.</context>
      <utterance>For England.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They vanish into the night. Fighting like a man pos- sessed, Peter is swallowed in a sea of enemy soldiers.</context>
      <utterance>Come now! Do not fail your friend. Make his sacrifice an act of honor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DESERTED ALLEY - LATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robin and the Saracen catch their breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Farewell, friend. God speed you on your way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins. This strange man has a sense of humor.</context>
      <utterance>Our way is together. With the speed of Allah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I go to England.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I go to England.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>England? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saved my life. I must stay with you until I save yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go your own way. I relieve you of your obligation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only Allah can do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I don't want you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins broadly. Offers his hand.</context>
      <utterance>You have no choice... unless you think you can kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARACEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Resigned, Robin takes the proferred hand.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Aslan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robin of Locksley. You know a short route to England, Aslan?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's bleeding from a face wound. Another man grabs him from behind. Locksley's craggy-faced retainer, DUNCAN. Older than his master, but still strong, he holds Kenneth back.</context>
      <utterance>My Lord! Help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must wait... I am sorry you were disturbed, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Lord, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The peasant falls to his knees.</context>
      <utterance>It is alright, Duncan.  You are Kenneth of Cowfall?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've taken my Gwen. My daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who has taken her?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Men on horses. In masks.  We tried to stop them. My son is dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cannot go alone, Master. Let me ride for help.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kicks his horse into motion.</context>
      <utterance>That may be too late. Kenneth, lead the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Master, stay! There is an evil moon tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Duncan looks up. Crosses himself. Dark clouds race across the moon.</context>
      <utterance>Good will overcome, Duncan. Trust in that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They came this way, my Lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Onward then. What is this place?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Locksley reacts -- a hint of fear. They move on... Ahead, the hillside glows, rimmed in eerie light. Strange primitive CHANTS, wafted on the wind. Locksley ties his nervous horse to a tree. Parting undergrowth, Kenneth creeps forward. Cries out. He's face to face with the maggot-eaten skull of a goat. Beyond it, a gruesome host of half-skinned human skulls, all arranged on stakes. Some male, others with rotting female tresses, staring eyelessly into the night. Kenneth turns to run... A hand grabs him.</context>
      <utterance>Nearby the Gregor Caves.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the crest of the rise, they peer down into the craggy valley. A cave opening, ablaze with flames leers at them like the mouth of hell. Before the cave, a circle of stones. A miniature Stonehenge. A medieval orgy. Men and women in masks and loose robes. Dancing. Drinking. Reveling. Pure carnality. Lord Locksley and Kenneth watch in horror. Faces ashen.</context>
      <utterance>Steady, man. They are to dissuade the faint of heart. Think of Gwen.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Druids.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An unearthly SCREECH. A creature leaps into the circle of stones. Grotesque gargoyle head, horns, fur-covered arms and legs. A living Hieronymous Bosch DEMON. Its clawed hands slash across a reveler's back, drawing blood in vicious streaks. The creature tastes the blood. The reveler is ecstatic.</context>
      <utterance>I trusted we were rid of such evil a century ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it the devil?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws his sword. A crucifix sculpted into the hilt. A girl is dragged from the cave. Kenneth buries his head.</context>
      <utterance>If it is, I have some Christian steel that will test his hide.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Demon shrieks, dervishing around GWEN, who is carried onto the central plinth stone. A pagan altar, the shape of an elephant's head with its trunk raised. A masked figure stands at the head of the altar. The high priest of the dark rite. The girl's body shudders as blood-red liquid is forced down her throat. The Demon's voice is husky and hideous.</context>
      <utterance>Gwen? Kenneth nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hypnotized by the creature's voice and snake-like move- ments, Gwen stretches herself out. A single beam of sunlight slices through the mist, like a laser. The first light of the rising sun, it strikes directly on the altar, tracking down towards the girl's heart. The Demon's raised talons close in on the white flesh of her neck. Gwen's eyes are open wide, in a trance. The crowd of revelers encircle the plinth. Awed anticipation... A warrior's yell! Sword raised, Locksley THUNDERS in on his CHARGER. The terrified crowd parts. The Demon screams like a banshee.</context>
      <utterance>Come, my virgin flower.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The followers throw themselves at Locksley. He beats them off. The high priest issues orders to armed guards, who run to intercept. One aims a spear. Locksley hacks the shaft in half. Cuts men down left and right. Reaches the altar stone.</context>
      <utterance>Kill him! Kill him!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gwen shakes off her trance. The Demon launches itself at Locksley. Talons rip flesh from his face. With all his strength, Locksley hurls the creature down.</context>
      <utterance>Gwen! Up, girl, up!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His broadsword swings in a mighty arc. Slices across the gargoyle's skull. Clean through half the face... Impossibly, the demon rolls back to its feet.</context>
      <utterance>In the name of God!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SHERIFF OF NOTTINGHAM. Powerful build, black beard, cruel intensity in every feature.</context>
      <utterance>Nottingham!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are an unwelcome surprise, Locksley.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The King shall hear of this, Nottingham.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Locksley is surrounded. One by one the men reveal their faces. Locksley backs up in shock, recognizing them.</context>
      <utterance>I think not.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSELY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God help us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One day all England will worship with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crone spits venom in his face.</context>
      <utterance>Never.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Locksley's agonized cry fills the valley. On the hill- side, Kenneth averts his eyes. Turns to run. Five masked figures block his way.</context>
      <utterance>I am Mortianna. You will die with my name on your lips.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan steps from the boat, sniffing the air. The French sailors keep their distance from him. Robin takes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Home. Thank you, Lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My friend, you have escorted me home. I beg you to free yourself of your vow. Return with the boat. I know how heavy your heart must be, this far from your family and native land...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode>SARACEN</mode>
      <context>A sailor creeps up behind Aslan, club in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Because I love them so dearly, I cannot dishonor them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods to the sailor, who swings the club down. The Saracen sidesteps, grabs the man's arm and flips him into the surf. He turns a cold stare on Robin.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you'd say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin laughs. The Saracen remains intense.</context>
      <utterance>No man controls my destiny. Especially not one who attacks downwind and stinks of garlic.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles broadly. Robin claps him on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>If our positions were reversed, I would have done the same. Only I would have succeeded.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come, Aslan. By nightfall we will celebrate your honor when we dine with my father.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You owe the sheriff three bushels of flax.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You starve us. First the drought, now you take what food we have left.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For starving people, you look fat enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not here, sir. None but the woman and children.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is your mate? The man they call Little.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He died last winter.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers join in his laughter. Incensed, Fanny pounds her fist on his legs. Gisborne kicks her down.</context>
      <utterance>Is that so? We hear he is very much alive. Hiding out in the forest. He probably ran away to escape your scolding tongue.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BOY of 12 springs from nowhere, thrusting a hay fork at Gisborne's throat.</context>
      <utterance>Norman swine!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wulf backs off. Nostrils flaring with repressed hate.</context>
      <utterance>No, Wulf! Don't! 'Twill only make it worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While two soldiers grab the Boy, others examine his hiding place. A secret thatched door, built into the side of a haystack... a bow and quiver... and a deer carcass. Gisborne dismounts.</context>
      <utterance>Seize him!</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Lord Nottingham's deer. Is this how you repay the Sheriff for his protection?</utterance>
   <speaker>WULF</speaker>
      <mode>BOY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a wolf protects sheep.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I killed it. We needed the meat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poachers hang. Either he dies or you die.</utterance>
   <speaker>WULF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother lies to protect me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gisborne drags the boy to the carcass.</context>
      <utterance>No, Wulf!</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cups his hand in the deer's blood. Smears it on Wulf's face.</context>
      <utterance>You have deprived us of a hunt, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses his bloody glove to the dogs. They tear at each other in their effort to rip at the glove.</context>
      <utterance>The hounds know the scent well.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run, boy. Like a deer. Give us some pleasure before you die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why must you walk in back of me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In your land am I not the infidel? The unbeliever, the instrument of evil?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our races have fought for a hundred years to prove that point.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I trust it is safer to appear as your slave than as your equal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For an 'infidel' you have uncommon clarity of thinking. Yet you refuse to tell me about your home and family.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are my burdens.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Saracen maintains a moody silence.</context>
      <utterance>You speak my language. You have the diplomacy and honor code of a nobleman. I ask again, why were you to be executed?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... A woman?</context>
      <utterance>So, I must continue with my guesswork. You are highborn? Probably... You fell from favor... Clearly... Why? You broke the law? You were a rival for power?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan is silent, but Robin knows he's right.</context>
      <utterance>By the Lord, that's it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ignoring him, the Saracen stops. Examines the darkening sky.</context>
      <utterance>They say there are Arab women of such beauty that they can possess a man's mind, that he would be willing to die for them. Is that not so?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is close to sunset.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No reply. Aslan unfolds a prayer rug.</context>
      <utterance>Your people must marry women chosen for them by others, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is she? The Mullah's daughter? ... Another man's wife?... That's it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Endless clouds. Is there no sun in your cursed country?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What is her name?</context>
      <utterance>You dog! You painted old dog!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way is East?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her name?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>East?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her name?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin folds his arms. A standoff.</context>
      <utterance>East?!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn you!... Jasmina.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, Jasmina! Is she beautiful?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way is East?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan throws his rug on the ground. Kneels.</context>
      <utterance>That way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would know blindfolded. I'm five miles from home... Was she worth it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin stands smiling over him as Aslan begins his prayers... BAYING of HUNTING DOGS... In the distance, the boy Wulf runs toward them, ducks behind a tree and clubs the leading dog with a branch. The other hounds close in... panting with exhaustion, Wulf swings into the branches. A hound savages his leg. The soldiers surround the tree. The boy clambers precariously onto the highest branch... Robin surrep- titiously steals a crossbow from one of the soldiers' horses.</context>
      <utterance>Worth dying for.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers hack at the trunk. The tree quivers.</context>
      <utterance>You're not playing by the rules, boy. Deer don't climb trees... Perhaps he thinks he's a game bird. Shall we teach him to fly? Cut it down!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shrouded in his pilgrim's hooded cloak, he approaches them.</context>
      <utterance>Hold!... I am curious as to what manner of creature is so fearsome that it takes six men to attack it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stand back, stranger. This is no affair of yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A truly dangerous animal.</context>
      <utterance>Have we treed the devil himself? Let me see... Ah ha! A small boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is the Sheriff's land.</context>
      <utterance>I advise you to move on, pilgrim.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong. This is my land, and my tree. Therefore, whatever is in it also belongs to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I grow dangerously tired of your wit... Chop it down!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances nervously at Aslan, who's still at his prayers. The men stop in mid-swing. More surprised than scared. Gisborne gestures to the largest of them.</context>
      <utterance>The man who strikes that tree dies.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chop down the hooded fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aslan! It's time to redeem that vow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Set the dogs on him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Saracen remains head down. Or did we see him steal a glance? Gisborne signals his men to attack. A wave of flashing steel.</context>
      <utterance>Aslan, get off your damn knees! I have four of them cornered.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Backed up to a tree, he grabs a branch and kicks out. Two men fly back. He lunges at a third. His sword strikes flesh. Robin sidesteps and hurls the fourth onto a sharp tree stump. Gisborne thrusts. Robin reacts too slowly. Blood flows from his arm. His sword falls.</context>
      <utterance>I hope there's enough of me to satisfy you all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gisborne is on him, sword pressed to his back. Robin freezes.</context>
      <utterance>Aslan!!</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment of silence... Like lightning, Robin spins, kicks out Gisborne's legs. Slams one foot on the man's sword arm, the other on his throat. Throws back his pilgrim's hood.</context>
      <utterance>Well, hooded stranger, allow me to know your name before I run you through.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robin of Locksley!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He obeys. Robin raises his sword.</context>
      <utterance>On your knees, Gisborne. Pray.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin drives the point into Gisborne's rear. The man leaps.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Locksley! No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gisborne takes off, colliding with Aslan as he folds his rug. Reacts in shock at the sight of the strange Arab. Keeps running.</context>
      <utterance>Now get off my land. And tell your cousin the Sheriff what happens to his scum when they pick on my people.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You worthless savage! You travel ten thousand miles to save my life, then leave me to be butchered.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will fulfill my vow when I choose.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which does not include prayer times, meal times, or any time I'm outnumbered six to one!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You whine like a mule. You are still alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan examines Robin's wound. Dismissive.</context>
      <utterance>Barely.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A flesh wound. Why did you let their leader go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wulf climbs cautiously from the tree.</context>
      <utterance>After six years of the stench of death, I have no stomach for needless blood on my hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy nervously eyes Robin and the Saracen, fingering a crucifix around his neck. Runs off into the woods.</context>
      <utterance>Have no fear, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The conquering hero returns.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan's humor is infectious. Robin's anger relents.</context>
      <utterance>Ha! It was you he was scared of.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warm hearths, hot food, real beds.</context>
      <utterance>Come, my strange friend. Beyond that hill lies the prettiest little castle in all Christendom.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With feather pillows?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With feather pillows. Warm and soft like Jasmina's embrace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His VOICE ECHOES around the fallen battlements. Aslan places a hand on his shoulder and points... Suspended high on a tower wall is a decaying human corpse.</context>
      <utterance>Father! Hello!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - MEDALLION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>round the corpse's neck. The Locksley crest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A paroxysm of rage and grief. He smashes furniture. Slams his fists relentlessly into the wall. Pained, Aslan looks on.</context>
      <utterance>Noooooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spent, he leans against the wall. In the silence, they hear an eerie TAPPING. Robin draws his sword... A hunched, old man emerges, walking with the aid of a staff ... Duncan.</context>
      <utterance>I should have been here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn you, Duncan. Why didn't you cut him down?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Master Robin, is it you? A miracle. I thought God had abandoned us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You left my father to hang like a common thief, carrion for the crows.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Duncan steps into the moonlight. His face crudely- scarred.</context>
      <utterance>Easy... Look at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What has happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say they captured him worshipping with the Druids. He signed a confession before the Bishop of Hereford.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they have witnesses?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just one. Kenneth of Cowfall. The Bishop decreed all the Locksley lands forfeit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you believe the charges?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not even when they took my eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did this to you, Duncan?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin holds the old retainer to his chest. Stares into the night in silent rage.</context>
      <utterance>Guy of Gisborne. With the sheriff looking on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir Guy. His Lordship is not to be disturbed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves the Sentry aside.</context>
      <utterance>Away, fool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smashes his fist into his chair. She timidly uncovers.</context>
      <utterance>Who bade you cover up?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His attention is riveted on a dark niche in the corner of the courtyard. UNEARTHLY SOUNDS emanate from the black- ness.</context>
      <utterance>Cousin, I trust you justify your intrusion with news of profound value.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I met a hooded man today. He bade me warn you not to harm his people.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name?</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robin of Locksley.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha! The prodigal son returns. He is a whelp. This girl could best him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This whelp bested five of my men in the blink of an eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heavy scorn. The sheriff pats Gisborne's hand like a child's. The voice from the darkness becomes a loud CHANT. A wrinkled, monkey-like figure dances INTO VIEW, wearing a necklace of human fingers. You might think she was a hundred years old, if not for her incredible agility. MORTIANNA.</context>
      <utterance>Your men were probably drunk. Yet you survived, cousin?</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You brought her here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crone's fingers dart into a bag. Emerge with a writhing, SQUEALING mass... a PIGLET. A knife flashes. Blood spurts into an ornate, sacred platter. The girl flinches in horror. Mortianna shakes the con- tents of a pouch across the bloody dish. Carved bone dice -- Runes. She rattles the platter. The rune symbols dance in trails of blood. Eyes vacant, mouth frothing, she hisses out her incoherent visions. Nottingham follows her every move. A connoisseur.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Change the seat of power.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>London?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Change it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Excellent. How?</context>
      <utterance>Move the capitol to Nottingham?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ally with royal blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put someone on the throne and rule through him? Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The idea takes shape in Nottingham's mind. Mounting intensity.</context>
      <utterance>That is not revealed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ally with royal blood. What else do you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Armies.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yours. Men and weaponry in great numgers.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And victory?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Much blood will be spilled.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one. I have seen no one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lie! A man... A painted man.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whimpers. Spins, as if fearing invisible intruders.</context>
      <utterance>I have seen my death.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The painted man. He haunts my dreams.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mortianna trembles like an epileptic. Eyes wide with terror.</context>
      <utterance>Locksley has a companion. A dark- skinned foreigner. He had the marked skin of Islam.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws herself at Nottingham for protection. He caresses her. Gisborne is thunderstruck.</context>
      <utterance>Kill them! Kill them!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cousin. Prove to Locksley that your survival was his last mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the painted man! Kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He continues to stroke her. Her trembling subsides.</context>
      <utterance>Kill them both.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mortianna reaches out bloodied fingers towards the young girl, who shrinks away. Nottingham gently takes the girl's hand.</context>
      <utterance>You have done well, Mortianna. Exceedingly well. No one shall harm you, I swear it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mortianna grabs the terrified girl's wrist. Drags her away.</context>
      <utterance>Now, my child, Mortianna's kisses will seem soft, like an angel's.  Take her. You have earned her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is madness bringing the hag here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fear not for my sanity, Guy. For in madness, there is great power.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our last words in this world were spoken in anger. He called the Crusades a foolish quest, said it was vanity to force other men to our religion. He was right.  Please forgive me, Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He loved you till the end, young master. He never gave up hope of your return.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I failed him. I should have been here at his side.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must leave, head north to safety. Gisborne will surely seek revenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what you're thinking. But one man can achieve nothing against so many. You would need an army.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads the old man away.</context>
      <utterance>Come, friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He still stands vigil?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Duncan offers half the bread to the Saracen.</context>
      <utterance>Like a rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A curse on the Saracens! Were it not for their ungodly ways, he would never have left. This would never have happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It surprises me that one who curses others so readily has lived so long.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not recognize the style of your voice, friend. Are you Irish? A Cornishman?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Er... no.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What manner of name is Aslan then?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fine Saracen name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He chokes in shock. Spitting bread.</context>
      <utterance>Lord, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin raises his dagger over his wrist. Aslan runs to him.</context>
      <utterance>Lord, yes. But eat in peace. I take no offense.  By the prophet! What is the man doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Too late. Robin slashes the dagger across his palm. Rain and blood mingle. Streaming onto the grave.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear by my own blood. I will not rest until I have restored my father's name.  ... Or until I am dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We make a fine army, do we not, Duncan? A blind man, an Arab, and a fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fine, wet army. I have never witnessed a storm of such duration. When does summer come to this land?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then Allah truly is great.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, pray?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They approach a stone wall, surrounding a thatched mansion.</context>
      <utterance>No food, no shelter, and weather that would curse the end of the earth. We will all quickly be dead, and I shall be rid of my vow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You despair too soon, Aslan. We shall find food and shelter here among friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter's home. It is nearly seven years since we left here together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hatch slams shut. Robin pounds again.</context>
      <utterance>No beggars!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. The hatch slides back.</context>
      <utterance>Open up!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell the mistress of the house that Robin of Locksley is at her door.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slams the hatch again. Robin jams in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Her ladyship is not at home.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shouts through the hatch, over his bruised fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Aagh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is the child Marian at home?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin refuses. She waits imperiously behind the locked door. Robin reluctantly withdraws his hand. Instantly the hatch slams.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe she is. Maybe she isn't. Remove that hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They wait, shivering... The door opens a crack.</context>
      <utterance>The hospitality here is as warm as the weather.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three start forward. Her bony finger points at Robin.</context>
      <utterance>Leave your weapons.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waits. CREAKING FOOTSTEPS on the balcony.</context>
      <utterance>Wait here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dim lighting. Robin cannot make out who it is.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Robin of Locksley.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lie. Robin is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I may meet my maker soon from lack of sustenance. But for now I am real enough.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Step into the light. Turn around.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Who are you?</context>
      <utterance>By heaven, am I to dance next?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the maid Marian.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then show yourself, child. For we knew each other well.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the king away, these are lawless times. There are outlaws villainous enough to kidnap and ransom a relative of his.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I am not one of them. Besides, I am sworn to protect you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Protect me? Robin of Locksley was nothing but a spoiled bully.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves into the light... Fat. Rotten teeth. Ugly as sin.</context>
      <utterance>Allow that years of war and prison may change a man. Step forward, Marian, so I may see how you have changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Er... the years have been kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A figure steps behind Robin. Sticks a sword in his back.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Now remove yourself from this household.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you can see, we are already well protected.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, Marian! ...ouch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INSIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chunks of horn fly. Robin parries and thrusts. The horns get shorter. Robin retreats. Left with just the nubs, Robin hurls the deer head at the mask. Gaining advantage, he charges. Grabs the dagger hand, smashes it into the wall. The knife drops. Robin wrenches off the mask. Long hair tumbles down... a beautiful YOUNG WOMAN. The front door CAVES IN. Aslan stumbles through... just in time to see the woman's knee fly up into Robin's crotch. Robin folds. The battle is over. The young woman stands over Robin.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin croaks through clenched teeth.</context>
      <utterance>As she was saying, we have no need of your protection.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marian.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would he wish me to be protected by the boy who burned my hair when I was a child?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were together five terrible years in a Saracen prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I know you didn't abandon him there to save your own skin. Robin hands her Peter's ring. She is shocked.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marian, I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns her back. He searches for a way to reach her.</context>
      <utterance>I will forward your condolences to my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On my return, I found my father dead. The Sheriff denounced him as a Druid and took our lands.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The people fear the Druids so much they'd believe anything. Nottingham would have me burned at the stake as a witch if he thought he could possess my property.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you not join your mother in London? You would be safer there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will not retreat. Besides, I have no interest in life at court. Gossip-mongering and currying favor. Here I am my own person.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The you must allow me to be your guardian.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to face him. Streaming tears.</context>
      <utterance>I do not need a guardian.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin grabs and holds her.</context>
      <utterance>My brother is dead. You cannot take his place.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marian, I don't want to replace him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes meet... a sudden intimacy between them. Robin moves closer. Marian begins to respond, then pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs back to the house. Robin stares after her. Aslan appears in the doorway with Duncan.</context>
      <utterance>This is wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs to a bluff... a column of soldiers snakes up the hillside.</context>
      <utterance>Robin! The old man hears horses. Approaching fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty or more. In battle armor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soldiers coming here? Is this your protection?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I killed some of the Sheriff's men. I fear I have placed you in danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan runs into the stables.</context>
      <utterance>I can take care of myself. There are horses in the stable. Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marian ices him with a glare. Aslan reappears, with two bareback horses. Soldiers appear on the crest, led by Gisborne... With a mischievous grin, Marian runs to the soldiers.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop them! They're stealing my horses!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In answer, Aslan grins. Leaps onto a horse. With a single swift move he hoists Duncan up behind him and digs in his heels. The mare leaps forward, and over the estate wall.</context>
      <utterance>Damn the girl! Aslan, can you ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads his horse at the wall. It stumbles. Barely clears it. Stones fly. Robin struggles to hold on. Marian stands directly in Gisborne's path.</context>
      <utterance>He can ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have been sheltering outlaws, Lady Marian.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gisborne knows she is lying.</context>
      <utterance>They're thieves, you imbecile. Bring back my horses, or the Sheriff will know of your cowardice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads the pursuit. A SOLDIER hangs back. Grabs Marian's hair.</context>
      <utterance>You're lucky he didn't steal your virtue too.  A crown to the man who brings me Locksley's head.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A kiss for me, Saxon bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She unsheathes the dagger from under her skirt. Jabs the blade into his wrist.</context>
      <utterance>Kiss this!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shocked and pained, the man gallops away. Marian looks down at her dagger hand. It shakes violently.</context>
      <utterance>Try me again, if you want to leave a hand behind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan shouts from the far bank.</context>
      <utterance>Damn you, animal!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin continues to hit his horse and hurl abuse. Closing in, the soldiers unfurl their crossbows. A flight of BOLTS WHISTLES ominously close to Robin. He must jump or die.</context>
      <utterance>Treat it like a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gently, man. Soothe it!</context>
      <utterance>Have you never had a woman?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pats the horse soothingly. The animal edges forward.</context>
      <utterance>Of course I've had a woman! Come on, pretty one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Softly. With your knees.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers reload. Robin urges the horse at the steep drop.</context>
      <utterance>I know! I know!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another wave of crossbow bolts. Robin launches the frightened animal into space. Hooves flail... touch down. Scramble up the other bank. Robin enthusiastically pats the horse's neck.</context>
      <utterance>Easy, easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The first two pursuers misjudge their leaps. Their mounts land sprawling in the riverbed.</context>
      <utterance>I love you!</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robin of the Hood! Son of the devil worshipper.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your pleasure, Gisborne?</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was I who strung your father's corpse to the castle gate. My pleasure will be in doing the same to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You survived one meeting. Our next will be your last.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father died a coward, cursing your name and squealing like a stuck pig.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin puts the device to his eye...</context>
      <utterance>Here they come. Look.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOPE POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The soldiers are close!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this Arab magic?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He replaces the tube in his pouch.</context>
      <utterance>No. Arab science.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did your uneducated kind ever take Jerusalem?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan laughs. Robin points towards an endless expanse of trees.</context>
      <utterance>God knows!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can lose them in the forest.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sherwood is haunted, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He remounts. They race into the trees. Gisborne's men thunder up,... slowing as they enter the forest. Peering around them in trepidation, they slowly rein in. Robin looks back.</context>
      <utterance>Either we take our chances with the ghosts, or become ghosts ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gisborne curses his men, urging them on.</context>
      <utterance>They're not following.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, damn you! There are only three of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eerie HOWLING and RATTLING of bones. Aslan draws his sword.</context>
      <utterance>It's not the men we fear, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wraps his scarf over his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Banshees. They say they fly in your mouth and suck you dry of blood before you can scream.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIND GUSTS the trees in angry waves. Emits deathly SHRIEKS. The HORSES WHINNEY. Unnerved, Aslan smites around him with his scimitar. Wheels at the sounds, striking only air.</context>
      <utterance>Be quiet! Listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Duncan clings to his back. Robin points.</context>
      <utterance>Allah protect us from the evil spirits.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan slashes out, futilely.</context>
      <utterance>Behind you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan flails. Robin cracks up.</context>
      <utterance>No, there! And there!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin reaches into the branches. Pulls out a string of hollowed wooden tubes -- WINDCHIMES. Dozens of such strings on all the trees. He blows over the hollow end. A low chilling MOAN.</context>
      <utterance>Cease your mad laughing. I can feel them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His laughter is broken by a piercing YELL. A red- jacketed figure swings down out of a tree on a rope. Catapults him to the ground. The bushes are instantly alive. Shaggy, wild-eyed men, armed with cudgels, scythes and hayforks. Twelfth- century Hell's Angels. The red-jacketed young turk, WILL SCARLET, leaps around Robin.</context>
      <utterance>Here are your ghosts, Duncan. A child's toy put to good use. You scare easily, my painted Saladin.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ring around the rosie!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan makes no move to intervene.</context>
      <utterance>Aslan!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Atishoo, Atishoo. We all fall down. Beg for mercy, rich man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg of no man. Which of you scum has guts enough to face me man to man?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Robin looks up... I mean up! A towering figure. Seven feet of grinning, muscled brute. The giant extends a vice that passes for a hand. Hauls Robin to his feet. His eyes twinkle with merriment. His whole body shakes when he laughs, which is often.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, bollocks, mate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are ya, m'old cock?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses, checking the faces of the angry peasants.</context>
      <utterance>Er... Robin...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Hood. Robin Hood. Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John Little. Bestman o' the woods.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bestman? You lead this rabble?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We waste time. Tax him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tax? For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For passage through Sherwood.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will pay no tax. Besides, I have nothing but my cloak and my sword.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grabbing Robin, Little shakes him like a doll. Something CLINKS. Robin's father's medallion. Laughing heartily, Little rips it from Robin's neck and tosses it to Scarlet.</context>
      <utterance>A man who travels with two servants and claims he's without money, is either a fool or a liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men cheer. John snatches the medallion back from Will.</context>
      <utterance>And this one is a liar.  Ahah! Gold!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is sacred to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin draws his sword.</context>
      <utterance>Sacred to us too, mush. This here'll feed us for a bloomin' month.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will have to fight me for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins hugely. A boy pushes his way through the throng.</context>
      <utterance>I'd love to, mate.</utterance>
   <speaker>WULF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, father! I know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for the medallion. John pulls it away.</context>
      <utterance>This man is your father? Tell him how I saved your hide from the Sheriff's soldiers. That deserves some gratitude, I believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw ya don't, laddie.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be Robin of Locksley. The blackguard who abandoned us to Nottingham's plundering.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WULF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful, Father. He fights like a demon. He walloped six o' Sheriff's men?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another grin. Licking his lips in anticipation, he lunges for Robin's wrist. Wrenches the sword free. Bends it into a pretzel.</context>
      <utterance>Is that so?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan shrugs. Robin swings a fist into the giant's gut. John doesn't flinch. Hoists Robin off the ground with one arm. Cannonballs the other fist into Robin's stomach. Robin folds.</context>
      <utterance>Aslan!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh dear! The little rich boy is lost for words. Thanks for the taxes, Locksley.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woodsmen find this hysterical. They disappear into the tree. Will administers one final kick before leaving. Robin staggers to his feet. Glares furiously at Aslan.</context>
      <utterance>And for the laughs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son of an Arab whore! Once again your assistance was invaluable.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seemed more in danger of losing your pride than your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Many were from your father's farms.</context>
      <utterance>I recognized some of the voices.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your avenging army, my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That rabble?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All they need is a leader.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They have a leader. A very large one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Defeat him and they will follow you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allah has taken your brains.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear the voice of a spoiled child, Master Robin. I suggest you cease your brave talk of revenge and flee to the north.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, too? You expect me to fight that behemoth?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father would expect you to act like a man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my bridge. No one crosses without paying tax.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just bugger off, mate, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you wish to cross, it will cost you a gold medallion.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't I hurt you a bloody nuff for one day?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he's in a hurry to end his mortal misery, help him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John grabs a hefty, gnarled staff. Strides to the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have the courage to face me again, John Little? Or should I call you 'Little John'?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His confidence melting, Robin glances back at Duncan and Aslan, who grins like a fan at a boxing match. John storms at Robin. Staffs thrash. Driven back, Robin connects a blow on John's foot. The giant is off-balance. Robin follows up. Lands a couple to the ribs. John responds with heavy swings, which Robin blocks deftly. Back and forth, blow for blow, all blocked. John chuckles with every swing. Enjoying the time of his life. Their staffs lock. It's strength against strength. Robin is no match. With one mighty thrust, John hurtles him into the stream. The woodsmen cheer loudly. Aslan watches impassively. Robin scrambles back onto the bridge. John waits, grinning.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, m'old cock. You wanna nuther good wallopin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lil' wet behind the ears, mate?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John charges. Robin fends him off, gets in some shots of his own. John swings in a giant arc. Robin ducks. John loses balance and falls to his knees. Robin allows him time to right himself. John comes at him again, pummeling. Wood splinters from the impact. Brute force versus agility. Agility is beginning to prevail, when Robin's staff splits in two.</context>
      <utterance>Don't fool with him. Get him!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The coup de grace. Lands heavily. Robin teeters. Falls. Disappears under the foaming water... does not re-emerge. John waits. The spectators rush to the bank. No sign.</context>
      <utterance>Swimmin' time again, ol' chum.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Robin arcs up out of the water. His hands clamp onto John's ankles. Robin heaves with all his might. John topples headfirst into the water. Surfaces in panic.</context>
      <utterance>Bloomin' shame. 'E were a brave 'un.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He submerges again. Robin pulls his head above water.</context>
      <utterance>Help! Cain't bloody swim.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The terrified giant sputters. Goes under again, flailing with arms and legs. Robin holds his head just above the surface.</context>
      <utterance>Do you yield?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you yield?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John struggles, then his feet hit bottom... The water only reaches his chest.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Now put your feet down.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be buggered.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tense pause while all wait for Little's reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Pay me the tax.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN LITTLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Robin back the medallion. Chuckling loudly, he swoops Robin up in his arms and carries him to the bank.</context>
      <utterance>Robin Hood, ya got balls o' solid rock.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spits black objects from his mouth. Dead bees. John grins.</context>
      <utterance>A fine brew, Little John.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the jug back. Sneezes royally, spewing all over the brew. Oblivious, he hands the contaminated jug to Aslan.</context>
      <utterance>Real honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With regrets, I decline.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An Englishman's mead not bleedin' good enough for ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the contrary. I thank you, but my faith prevents me from partaking in such enjoyments.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swigs. Passes the jug on to Duncan, who drinks heartily. Wulf cautiously approaches Robin.</context>
      <utterance>Your bloody loss, mate.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, boy? Speak up!</utterance>
   <speaker>WULF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I owes ya m'life.</context>
      <utterance>I wanna thankee, Lord Locksley.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You owe me nothing, Wulf. I am glad I chanced by in time to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wulf tries the brew. The impact is instant. He turns green and runs. His father cracks up.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, lad, drink! 'Twill put hair on your bloomin' chest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John points to a short fellow with the build of a tree trunk.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me about your men, John.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This stumpy one 'ere's David o' Doncaster. We calls 'im Bull.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you come by the name, Bull?</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cuz o' my size, Sire.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you are short?</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Proudly, he starts to pull down his pants.</context>
      <utterance>Nay. 'Cuz I be so long.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drunken laughter. Robin turns to the next man at the fireside.</context>
      <utterance>No, Bull. Save it for the ladies.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man's bald pate blushes scarlet as he tries to respond, but he stutters too badly to get out a comprehensible word.</context>
      <utterance>Your name, friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others make hiccup and belching sounds, and crack up at Hal's embarrassment. Hal strikes out angrily at his tormentors.</context>
      <utterance>That be Hal Brownwell, but the lads call i'm Hal Hiccup.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is murmuring around the group, but no one elects to try it.</context>
      <utterance>Hold! Hal, you have the face and hands of a farmer. I wager you are a strong and honest man, and I'd be glad to have you at my side in a fight. The next man who makes light of you will have to answer to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is it there are so many of you in hiding?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're outlaws. Got prices on our 'eads, every man jack. Blasted Sheriff says we owes 'im taxes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you fare?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We get by, I reckon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While the Sheriff steals your land and your families starve?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What in bloody blazes'd ya have us do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your ghosts will only keep his men at bay so long, my friend. Soon the Sheriff will hunt you down and hang you. You must fight back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We show as much as a toe outside the forest, they'll slaughter us like bleedin' sheep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must organize. Win by guile.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'We'? Ya lookin' to join us, matie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. To lead you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha! I would never be led by the son of a Druid.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murmurs of agreement from around the fire. Robin turns to Will.</context>
      <utterance>There are many here who knew my father to be a kind and generous man. I doubt that in their hearts they believe him capable of such a horror.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your name, friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Count me not a friend, Locksley.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will gets up. Angrily pushes his way out of the group.</context>
      <utterance>Stuff a flippin' cork in it, Will. The man's our guest.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That there's Will Scarlet. Pay 'im no 'eed. 'E's full o' piss and wind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is right to distrust me. I am a rich man's son. I have done no honest labor. But today I am as poor as any of you. Nottingham has stolen all that I own. And when I killed Gisborne's men, I, too, became an outlaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ya must be bloody jokin'.</context>
      <utterance>Ya're full o'bloody wind an' all, mate. This 'ere load o' rubbish agin the Sheriff's bloomin' army?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can win. And I believe we will.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughing loudly, he throws back his head for a long draught of mead.</context>
      <utterance>Ya're a daft bugger, Robin Hood, but ya're a brave 'un, I'll give ya that. Drink up, laddie, cuz tomorrow ya mayn't be so lucky! Tomorrow I shall best ya an' crack that blasted noble head in two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have led you wrong. This is no army. These men live like dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>English dogs. They can learn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sullenly stalks away. Robin shakes his head. Aslan is right. He rouses Duncan, who is asleep at his side. The old man groans awake, holding his head. Seriously hung-over.</context>
      <utterance>Learn what? To build kennels?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too much mead, old friend. What day is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sunday, I believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Do they still give alms to the poor at the mass?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They do. These days the need for mercy is greater than ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I must ask you a favor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin gazes into space, trying to look blind. The Guard sniffs his soiled hand.</context>
      <utterance>Do I know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, you stink!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon my blindness, sir. I'm always falling down.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He launches a kick in Robin's rear. Robin hobbles away, hiding a smile. The Guard tries to wipe off his hand on the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Yeech! Get away from me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nottingham and Gisborne sit piously among the congrega- tion of nobles and wealthy merchants.</context>
      <utterance>We beseech thy blessing, Lord, on all your people, but most especially on our noble Lord Nottingham. Grant him the wisdom to guide and protect our glorious city.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rear of the church. Standing crushed together, the poor and afflicted. Old and young. Starving children. Among them, Robin. The sermon ends. As the nobles file out, the poor are galvanized. Begging hands reach out.</context>
      <utterance>Grant him also the strength to bring to justice the lawless men who threaten its safety. Help him to stamp out the curse of the dread Druids who would seize from us our children, even as wolves steal the lambs from their mothers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>VARIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rich drop a few mites, sparking a mad scramble. Church officials roughly keep order. Marian passes some coins to the mother of a small child. A hand grabs her wrist.</context>
      <utterance>1. Alms! 2. Have mercy, milady. 3. Pity, fine sir. 4. For my baby. 5. Etc.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alms for a blind man. For one who cannot see your beauty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you care for my safety?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, for mine. I do not wish to be seen with an outlaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Under the Sheriff's law, that's a badge of pride.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's put a price on your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hundred gold pieces.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that all? I have not annoyed him enough. Soon he will offer ten thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For ten thousand I would turn you in myself.  Nottingham is mounting an army.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has rounded up every blacksmith in the county. He has them holed up in the castle making swords and armor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is he planning?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but there's no limit to the man's ambitions.  Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you need me, I will be with the woodsmen. Send for me as 'Robin Hood.'</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robin! Do something for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a bath.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a grin, he slips into the crowd as Nottingham arrives.</context>
      <utterance>Care to join me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises her hand, as he did the girl's in the castle. Kisses it.</context>
      <utterance>You shine like the sun, my lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have been meeting with young Robin of Locksley.  My cousin tells me the knave deprived you of some horses.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. A most disagreeable experience.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That gleam of insanity. Robin watches from a distance.</context>
      <utterance>I deeply regret it, and I promise you he will be brought to justice. For subjecting you to such treatment, I will hang him from the walls with his own entrails.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sheriff places his hand possessively on her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I would like to see that, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dear, a woman of your refinement is not safe living alone. If you would consent to bring your household within the city walls, I could give your needs my most personal attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thank you, Lord Nottingham, from the heart, but for now I prefer to stay in my family's ancestral home. My cousin, King Richard, will be deeply moved to hear of your concern for my welfare.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alas, the King has many enemies both abroad and at home. I fear for his safe return.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sheriff smiles sourly and takes his leave. Marian deflates with relief. The Sheriff walks alone towards a side door.</context>
      <utterance>Fear not, my dear Sheriff. He will return. When he does, he will wish to reward his faithful subjects.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEGGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nottingham makes to shove the man aside. With a swift move, the beggar grabs the Sheriff in a headlock. Slides Nottingham's own dagger to his throat and drags him out of sight.</context>
      <utterance>Alms, my lord.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nottingham starts to struggle. Robin draws blood.</context>
      <utterance>A hundred crowns, Sheriff? You insult me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember young Robin of Locksley, Sheriff? Meet Robin Hood. Your nemesis. Your avenging angel.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you kill me, you will hang.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I kill you, I will hang happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to give you a chance. A chance you do not deserve. A chance to right your wrongs.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From this day forward you will cease to tax my people. You will renounce the charges against my father, and you will return his lands to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because for every harm you do, I swear by God I shall visit on you threefold in return.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Empty words.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A YELL from across the church. Gisborne has spotted them. Robin digs the knife a little deeper.</context>
      <utterance>I am here with a blade at your throat. As long as I live, you will always know that I could be here again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your answer?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never, fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gisborne yells orders. Robin hurls Nottingham against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Then it will begin..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A personal loan from the Sheriff.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should not have left without me, Englishman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How so? You have not raised a finger to protect me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before I had a choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was my choice to do this alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A foolish risk. If you had been killed, I would be cursed for eternity for failing to fulfil my pledge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aslan, if I didn't know better, I would swear you were worried about me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starve them out. Slaughter their livestock. I want to see Locksley's own people fighting each other to bring him to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear he will not live to see the next full moon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go' bless ya, sir. Leave us the sow. She's with young 'uns. The next litter'll feed us through the winter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've heard of Robin Hood?</utterance>
   <speaker>FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Soldier brutally kicks the old man to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then pray he is brought to us before winter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You brought this misery on us, Locksley. We can barely feed ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheriff hasn't left us a bloody pot to piss in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This provokes a barrage of protests. The men are angry.</context>
      <utterance>Then we shall take from him and his rich friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Murmurs of general agreement.</context>
      <utterance>Brave talk, Locksley. I say we take the rich boy in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will, do you think the Sheriff will give everything back after I am gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He will give us the reward, and our pardons.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unarmed.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, Will. You can take me in on one condition. You must fight me. You may use the Sheriff's horse and arm yourself as you please. I will fight on foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unarmed?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you lose, you will accept me as your leader. If you win, you may take me in. Dead or alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead, Locksley.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This man has true purpose. He means to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you have given him the means.</utterance>
   <speaker>WULF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will is ruthless, Robin. Guard your back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will bends, as if checking the horse's legs. Secretly grabs a handful of sand. Swings into the saddle and digs in his heels. Closing in, Will flings the sand in Robin's eyes. Robin clutches his hands to his face, blinded. Will spins back to the attack. His sword slashes. Reacting to the sound, Robin rolls aside. The men cheer like a big fight crowd. Robin's POV is blurred. Ducking the blade, he grabs Will's arm. A blow glances off his shoulder. Robin falls to his knees, still blinded. Will rides right at him, to trample him. Robin scrambles away. Will wheels his horse. A flashing hoof grazes Robin's chest. Robin leaps to his feet and yells at the top of his lungs. Panicked, the HORSE rears, WHINNYING wildly. Will struggles to stay in the saddle. Loses his sword. Robin seizes the moment and runs to a water trough. Douses his face. Yells at Will.</context>
      <utterance>I am grateful for your concern, friends, but I have to prove to them it is possible to overcome unequal odds.  I am ready, Will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will grabs a spear from a bystander. Robin stands his ground. Will lunges, Robin sidesteps.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, you little piss pot. Do your worst!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the men laugh. Will is incensed. Robin ducks and weaves, easily evading Will's repeated charges. Robin ducks right under the horse's belly.</context>
      <utterance>The horse is smarter than you are, Will.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will stabs wildly, more and more frustrated. Laughter spreads, as Robin plays hide and seek around the horse's legs. Grabbing the end of the spear, he clowns a tug of war. Enraged, Will strains and tries to kick Robin away. Suddenly, Robin lets go. Unbalanced, Will flies back- wards off his mount. Robin snatches the spear and raises it over his fallen adversary. The crowd falls silent. Robin strikes. The point quivers in the ground below Will's crotch. Will wriggles in terror. Impaled, his pants rip open.</context>
      <utterance>Here, Will! You aim like a girl, Will!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd is convulsed with laughter. Robin catches his breath. Does not see Will, who grabs a heavy staff and runs at him. A strong hand grasps Will's arm as he is about to strike.</context>
      <utterance>Thank the Lord you are not endowed like Bull.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Overpowered, Will relents. With a defiant glance, he skulks away.</context>
      <utterance>Bollocks, Will. Jus' bugger off, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya got us by the short and curlies, Robin Hood. Now let's hear what ya got to bleedin' say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nottingham has taken from us everything we own. Now we are going to start taking from him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Ow in bloody blazes are we gonna do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are going to tax him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here they come.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two wagons. Twenty escort.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the telescope.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty? They usually have five.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOPE POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>barrels, and a tax wagon. The wagon is an armored box on wheels, with crossbow slits in the side. Guy of Gisborne commands the escort.</context>
      <utterance>A phalanx of mounted soldiers, a cart loaded with</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bull calls up from below, where a ragged group of woods- men lies nervously in ambush.</context>
      <utterance>This is no ordinary convoy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'ow many?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Er, about ten.  Why scare them? They can't count anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they call me the barbarian.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Together they run down the hill, keeping low. Gisborne eyes the forest. The beer cart is steered by a fat red-faced FRIAR, raucously singing hymns and quaffing from a jug, which he repeatedly dips into one of the barrels. ARROWS WHISTLE in. The Friar yells and drops his jug. A soldier is hit. At the forest edge, four woodsmen reload their longbows. Dressed in green, their faces camouflaged. The mounted soldiers charge them. The woodsmen run into the trees. As the horsemen close in, the runners leap into a trench. Lift up matted screens of brush and grass. It's as if they disappeared. The soldiers slash wildly at the thick screens. More arrows fly. More soldiers fall. The others spin in confusion, trying to discern the enemy. More woods- men break from cover. Run down a narrow path. Gisborne urges his men to pursue. They ride in single file, beating their way through the tangled branches. The runners dive into the trees, as other men haul on ropes, raising a giant screen in the soldiers' path. The horses swerve, on the edge of a twenty-foot drop to the river gorge. Momentum carries many of them over the cliff.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In answer, a swordblade jabs up through the roof, near his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Surrender your weapons. I give you my word you shall go free.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He signals to Aslan, who steers the tax wagon into the river. Water floods in through the slits. Inside, panic. Drowning rats. The bowmen scramble out. What they see stops them dead. Both banks are men in green, longbows aimed directly at them.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, I feared as much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be buggered.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns at the sound of a brawl from the Friar's cart. The Friar is at the bottom of a struggling heap of bodies.</context>
      <utterance>This treasure had a purpose. We must find out what.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin drags the men off. The Friar clambers to his feet. Around him are strewn battered and winded woodsmen.</context>
      <utterance>Get off him. He's a man of the cloth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He indicates his cargo of barrels.</context>
      <utterance>The Lord's blessing on you, kind sir. These sinners were attempting to steal these libations destined for the monks of St. Catherine's.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ignoring him, the Friar mounts the cart.</context>
      <utterance>It appears to me, Reverend Friar, that many of the libations have found their way into your own esteemed person.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A thousand pardons, sir, but duty beckons. I must hasten on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A moment, my reverend friend. You travel with poor company when you travel with Nottingham's soldiers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This sparks a chorus of comments.</context>
      <utterance>Aye, tax him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My men are thirsty and have much to celebrate.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord bless me, sir, are these your men? I had mistook them for common thieves. Kindly step aside.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Friar relents, loosening his grip on the reins.</context>
      <utterance>Surely the Lord has the charity to spare a few barrels to good Christian men.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Casually reaching under the seat, he pulls out a club. Smites Robin with it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, sir, if you wish them to share in the good Lord's brew...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin staggers. The Friar whips up the horse. Dazed, Robin grabs for the fat man's leg. Gets a holy sandal full in the face.</context>
      <utterance>... you must best me for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Friar's horse, as obese as his driver, slowly raises his head from the grass and ambles forward. Robin runs after them and dives at the Friar, toppling him from the cart.</context>
      <utterance>Giddyup, nag!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scrambling to his feet, the Friar glances skyward.</context>
      <utterance>You leave when I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sweeps his foot, knocking Robin's legs out from under him. Hurls his full body weight on top of him. Whooomf!</context>
      <utterance>Protect me, Lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bounces on Robin's stomach. Robin can barely breathe. The woodsmen are enjoying the spectacle.</context>
      <utterance>Yield!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Confess that Friar Tuck is a better, holier, and braver man than thou art, knave.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never! Whoomf!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desperate, Robin bites the Friar's leg. Tuck howls. Robin extricates himself, grabs for a weapon. Smashes the Friar's head with his drinking jug.</context>
      <utterance>Yield, I say! Yield to Friar Tuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dives onto the Friar and hammers his head into the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Yield yourself!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tuck holds up a hand in surrender. Robin eases off.</context>
      <utterance>Yield to Robin Hood.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Lord, for teaching me humility.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Friar struggles to his feet. He reviews the motley faces of his potential flock. His eyes light on the grinning Saracen.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Friar Tuck. We have need of an honest man of God, to minister to these men and their families. What do you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He punches Robin in the gut.</context>
      <utterance>I'd rather roast in hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flicks the reins, steering the cart into camp. Women and children rush to greet their men. Jeer the roped soldier-prisoners. The Friar checks out his flock. A woman curtsies, another crosses herself, children touch his robe in wonder.</context>
      <utterance>Giddyup, Friar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tuck surveys the hopeful, hungry faces. The little hamlet of half-built huts. He folds his hands in a moment of prayer.</context>
      <utterance>What do you say now, Tuck? Here are the meek of the earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Lord moves in mysterious ways. I accept.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will not regret it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye, but you may.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buy yourself a new son, Stephen.</utterance>
   <speaker>FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Little John and Bull approach. John indicates the two prisoners roped to a nearby tree.</context>
      <utterance>Thankee, Robin.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cain't get a bleedin' squeak outa 'em, Rob.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'd be spittin' it out good if they'd knowed anythin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reckon the Cap'n knows summat, Rob, but stubborn ol' cocker 'e is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps it is time for some heathen persuasion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN OF SOLDIERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>stares up at Robin defiantly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spare your breath. I know nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe you. But this Arab here, he's got it into his barbarian brain that you know a whole lot more than nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hasn't eaten in weeks.</context>
      <utterance>I strongly advise you to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does he want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For Godsakes, get him off me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Robin, no! They be God-fearin' men.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cannot stop him, John. Besides, if they will not tell what they know, then they must pay the price.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blood-curdling SCREAMS from behind the wagon where Aslan has dragged his victim. The Captain's face pales. Then silence.</context>
      <utterance>Kill 'em aye, but not like this. 'Tain't Christian.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, roughly, he says that he doesn't care for the way your friend tastes, and he wants you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, God, no! I'll talk. Just keep him away. Keep him away!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure changed the color of 'is britches, didn't 'e?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan repeats his wildman act, munching on a chunk of venison.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks to our cannibal friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gonna laugh my bloody balls off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd the Sheriff be sendin' gold north o' the border?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To hire mercenaries. The Celts are savage tribesmen, trained to kill from birth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye, the Romans built a bleedin' great wall to keep 'em out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does 'e want wi 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since he also has every Smith in the country working in his castle, we can assume he is planning a little war.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agin' who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>England.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nottingham tests the sword against an anvil.</context>
      <utterance>We were ambushed. In Sherwood Forest.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Any losses?</context>
      <utterance>Spanish steel, cousin. So much stronger than our native blades.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the men are gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the gold?</context>
      <utterance>Yet again you are the sole survivor, cousin? Interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it er... disappeared.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robin Hood?</utterance>
   <speaker>GISBORNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were woodsmen, dressed in green.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He places a hand reassuringly on his cousin's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Robin Hood.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without warning, he drives the blade into Gisborne's belly.</context>
      <utterance>Cousin, we must be strong. We cannot allow this outlaw to make fools of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I cannot allow a lieutenant to fail me.  It is indeed fine steel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God bless you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>VILLAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An' Go' bless Robin 'Ood, friar. They says as 'ow none o' the Sheriff's cronies dare go within miles o' Sherwood for fear o' havin' their pockets pinched.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, the good Lord giveth and the good Lord taketh away.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless Robin Hood takes it first!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How dare you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In response, she starts pelting him with stones.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Lady Marian.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You send men to drag me from my home in the middle of the night, like some slave girl? Is this the way the famous Robin Hood treats a lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah well... er, let me finish this bath you wished me to take. Then I'll explain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I demand an explanation right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you will be patient, I could spare your propriety by...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will decide when my propriety is compromised.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you wish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slugs him. Robin stumbles backwards into the water. Bull grins, gesturing to Sarah and pointing to his own black eye.</context>
      <utterance>How dare you expose yourself to me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The big 'un did the same to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right m'lad. Let's see how close you can git to that bugger. Wulf takes aim. His arrow slices clear through his father's arrow, splitting it in two. Little John slaps Wulf on the back and beckons everyone over.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin leads Marian through the camp... the beginnings of a village -- women doing laundry, kids playing, men prac- ticing archery and swordplay, others working on defenses, camouflaging a giant pit. Marian is impressed, but not about to admit it.</context>
      <utterance>Take a gander at this 'un, mates. Never seen nuthin' like it in my bloomin' life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin leads her into a hut. Inside is a trove of cap- tured loot -- purses, jewelry, weaponry, fancy coats and... the treasure chest. At Robin's nod, Bull throws back the lid. Marian is speechless.</context>
      <utterance>This better be damned important.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nottingham robs the poor. We rob Nottingham and give back to the poor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think he's going to let you get away with all this? The man is without mercy. He will annihilate you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody has to take a stand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. She checks the faces. Her eyes meet Robin's. Is there a hint of concern for him also?</context>
      <utterance>You're taking a stand with the lives of these people. These young ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want from me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nottingham was sending this gold to buy reinforcements from the Celtic tribesmen. We need to warn King Richard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nottingham would not dare challenge the King.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The King is not in England to be challenged, is he? While he is away, he may lose his country.  You are Richard's cousin. You can get word to him. He would believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little girl approaches, holding a bouquet of wild flowers. Touched, Marian kneels to accept the offering.</context>
      <utterance>Now you want me to participate in your folly?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sending Duncan with you. Give him some warm food and a real bed. I grow tired of his bellyaching.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin laughs and speaks to Marian in a stage whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Hah! I have endured more hardship in my lifetime than any man here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell him I told you, but he may be useful to you. There is no one to whom I would rather entrust your safety.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking the lead rein from Duncan's horse, she rides away.</context>
      <utterance>Duncan, you are most welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you send word to the King?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll think about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is a personal matter, my Lord, but one of vital importance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the letter to a solemn courier.</context>
      <utterance>I understand, my dear lady. This is my most trusted emissary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The courier bows in acknowledgement. Marian indicates Sarah.</context>
      <utterance>You will travel to France immediately. You must give this directly into the hands of the King, and him alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My lady-in-waiting will accompany you. Surprised, the courier glances at the Bishop.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dear, I could not vouch for her safety. The journey is fraught with danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate your concern, my Lord, but Sarah is an accomplished rider. I must insist that she goes along.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you wish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wulf runs up to Little John in panic.</context>
      <utterance>We have to be ready to move camp at any time. The only way we can be attacked is from the Nottingham Road. We hide lookouts in the trees, here and here. If they see soldiers, they shoot warning arrows. Whistles by day, fire by night.</utterance>
   <speaker>WULF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father! Come quick. Mother's dying.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fanny screams. John kneels beside her, taking her head.</context>
      <utterance>The child comes early.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hush, m'lass. Ya'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'S not like t'others, John. Oh God, it pains me so.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya're sittin' thar like a fat sow. Help her, man, help her!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan appears in the doorway, with Robin. Whips back the blanket. Fanny's chest is covered with black squirming creatures.</context>
      <utterance>I am doing all I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to pull the parasites off. Tuck jumps at him.</context>
      <utterance>By Allah, leeches!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan pushes him away, continuing his work.</context>
      <utterance>Get away from her!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John is paralyzed with confusion. Tuck appeals to Robin.</context>
      <utterance>Blood is like air. If she loses blood, she and the child will die.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He lies. He is the devil's seed, sent to lead us astray.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tuck raises an arm to strike Aslan. Robin blocks the blow. Aslan gently touches the mother's stomach.</context>
      <utterance>Fool, both the Bible and the Koran instruct us to preserve life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your baby has not turned. It cannot be born without help.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know, you damned savage?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you will allow me, I can help her. It will not be without danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do not listen to him! He will kill her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fanny cries out. John looks to Robin, pleading for advice.</context>
      <utterance>If you do not listen to me, she will certainly die. And the child, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John's eyes meet his wife's. She nods.</context>
      <utterance>The good Friar has done all he can. I suggest you let the Arab try.  If I am wrong, and they die, then you may take my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So be it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He storms out. All business, Aslan speaks to Wulf.</context>
      <utterance>Then it will be on your head. I have warned you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wulf runs to obey. John looks horrified. Robin eases him outside, then returns to Aslan's side. They whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Bring me a needle, thread, water, a skinning knife, and burning ashes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The child must be taken out by the knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The knife?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have seen it many times with horses.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Horses? By the Lord, what are her chances?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>not good.</context>
      <utterance>After wasting so much blood...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wulf runs back in. Aslan holds up a piece of wood.</context>
      <utterance>Now you tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts the red-hot knife from the ashes.</context>
      <utterance>Are you ready?... Bite down on this... Robin, hold her steady.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John moves to the hut. Wulf restrains him.</context>
      <utterance>I tell you, the barbarian is killing her.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The mother heaves, then drops.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she gone?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan holds up a bloody struggling infant.</context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mother revives. Aslan places the child on her breast.</context>
      <utterance>It is a boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up the needle and thread. Robin's eyes turn to the woman's abdomen... He faints.</context>
      <utterance>Your son, my lady... Robin, hold her skin together while I sew her up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Aslan the knife and extends his bloodied wrist.</context>
      <utterance>This day God has taught me a fine lesson.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan slices his own wrist. The two wrists clasp together in the universal sign of brotherhood. Everyone cheers.</context>
      <utterance>I would be honored.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are a good man, my barbarian friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alas, I am not permitted...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you dare to insult his works?</context>
      <utterance>Our God made this brew, brother. I merely combined the ingredients.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>COURIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah leans down to look and the courier cudgels her across the neck. She falls from the saddle, unconscious.</context>
      <utterance>My horse seems to be favoring a foreleg.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reveals a large scar on his wrist -- removes his mask -- the man who attacked her earlier. He prods her with his sword.</context>
      <utterance>We meet again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drop your blade.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drops the sword. He hurls her against the table. Lays his blade against her chest.</context>
      <utterance>You are still overmatched, soldier.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Resignedly, she raises a hand to loosen the string on her dress. With the other hand she reaches behind her, grabs a pepper bowl. Flips the contents into his face. Screaming, he grabs his face. She reaches for her dagger. He slashes with his sword. She backs to the fireplace, grabs a spit of roasted chickens... drives the point clean through his chest. He stares in shock at his own blood pouring from the cooked fowls pinned to his breast... FOOTSTEPS... masked soldiers converge from both sides of the house, dragging the servants. Duncan is shoved through the door.</context>
      <utterance>You owe me favors, wench. Bare your breasts... or I will do it for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sorry, my lady. There were too many. She stares at the invaders with studied calm.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there something you need, gentlemen? I remember no masked ball on my calendar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>REDHEAD BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget about Locksley. He is no threat.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can we control all England if we cannot control our own county? The people are turning him into a hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREYBEARD BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is impossible to attack him in the forest. We have tried everything. He is cunning.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sounds of COMMOTION outside. The door swings open. Framed in the doorway is a colossus in black armor. His helmet is the head of a dragon. He slowly raises the visor. Deep tribal scars on his cheeks. Implacable ferocity in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Then we will be more cunning. I must be rid of him. We may not be able to intercept his next warning to the King.</utterance>
   <speaker>CELTIC CHIEFTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want the heads of the men who stole my gold.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome, sir. We were discussing how to rid ourselves of those very men. The outlaws who band with Robin Hood.</utterance>
   <speaker>REDHEAD BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Lord Nottingham, I must protest. It is a mistake to ally ourselves with foreigners.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREYBEARD BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can these Celts do that we cannot?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come, you son of Saladin. A toast to all of Jehovah's children. The saved and the damned.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He downs the entire jug in one long draught. Refills it.</context>
      <utterance>This must be a truly evil potion, to make the soul feel this good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tuck laughs and drinks. Aslan sways and topples at the Friar's feet. Heaves up all over the holy sandals. Tuck looks at Robin.</context>
      <utterance>Come, holy man. A toast to all of Allah's children. The true believers and the fat infidels.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The dancing demon! Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ARROW WHISTLES into a tree. Robin reacts.</context>
      <utterance>If it was Jehovah who created this brew, he is truly wise. He built the punishment into the crime.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They need help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bloke wearin' a mask o' the Druids rode by. Tossed 'im down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure it was a Druid mask?  Damn them to hell! They must have Marian. Do you know where they meet?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Gregor Caves, I 'eard tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will go there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! You stay here, dammit! I will go alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You forget yourself. I am not your servant.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then be my friend. There are women and children here in greater need of your courage.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Robin his telescope.</context>
      <utterance>Take my eyes, then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A figure in a flowing white robe. Angelic. Floating towards him... Marian. He tries to speak her name. Reaches out his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Robin!... Robin!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her LAUGH ECHOES around the cave, as if hundreds of lost souls are laughing with her. Robin crawls away, cover- ing his ears. Marian lifts his face to hers.</context>
      <utterance>Death is not to be feared, Robin. Embrace it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weakly, Robin tries to push away the cup. Her hand grips his chin, forcing his mouth open.</context>
      <utterance>Drink this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The liquid trickles over his lips. He tries to focus. Her features are BLURRED, her voice hypnotic.</context>
      <utterance>Drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her face is inches from his. He tries to pull away, his subconscious sounding alarms.</context>
      <utterance>Look at me. Listen to me. You belong to me. Your soul is mine. You will obey my every word. Do you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, Marian?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you love me. Say it. You love me.  Say it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives himself to her. Their lips meet... something changes in his vision. Her eyes glow red. Her face starts to shrivel -- He is kissing the wrinkled lips of Mortianna. He pulls away... strong arms grab him. He shakes his head, trying to make sense. Through his BLURRED vision, we see he is surrounded by masked men.</context>
      <utterance>Kiss me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is Marian?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A guard forces Robin's hand across the page... then cries out, clutching his back... An arrow lodged be- tween his shoulders. In the cave mouth are Wulf, bow in hand, Bull kneeling beside Sarah's corpse, and Aslan.</context>
      <utterance>She is with friends.  Your resistence is strong, but useless. Sign this.  You are a Druid like your father. You consort with the devil. Your confession will be witnessed by the Bishop of Hereford.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan's war CRY RICHOCHETS off the cave walls. A curved scimitar in one hand, a straight English sword in the other, his arms are lethal windmills. The masked guards are cut down left and right. Mortianna retreats, scurry- ing into the depths of the cave.</context>
      <utterance>The painted man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Too late. A sword is driven through Bull's gut. Aslan grabs the attacker by the neck and pile-drives him into the cave wall. The man's SKULL CRACKS against the rocks. Aslan runs to Robin's side, as Wulf hurries to Bull's. Robin is slumped against a rock.</context>
      <utterance>Behind you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan runs to the back of the cave, searching. Wulf is crouched beside Bull, who murmurs his dying words.</context>
      <utterance>Marian?</utterance>
   <speaker>BULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya be sure Sarah gits a Christian burial. Promise me, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WULF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan stumbles at the edge of a deep crevasse. Far be- low he sees Mortianna, clambering down the steep rock. For a second their eyes meet. She hisses -- venom, hatred, fear -- then is gone.</context>
      <utterance>I promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have fulfilled your vow. Now you can leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your gratitude warms my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ignored my request.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is fortunate that I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because of you, another good man is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He urged me to bring him. He was a brave man and I grieve for him. Praise be to Allah that I do not grieve for you also. Or for my broken vow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To hell with your damn vow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ahead of them, Wulf shouts and reins in. He points into the distance. A huge cloud of smoke is darkening the sky.</context>
      <utterance>I am glad you are feeling better.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The forest! Ride!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scared and injured woodsmen careen out of the trees. Full retreat.</context>
      <utterance>Ya'll be jus' fine. Lil' smoke ain't gonna kill ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Most of them keep on running.</context>
      <utterance>'Ere, lads... Over 'ere! We must make a stand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn y'all! Ya're no more use than a load o' wet farts.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's that damn Locksley? I'll swear he betrayed us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hal runs to join them, stuttering.</context>
      <utterance>Bollocks, Will. Quit yer bloody bellyachin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C... cccc...</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C... ccc? What the bloody hell ya sayin'? Cows?... Cowards?...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cccc... elts!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Celts? Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gggg... God help us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chieftain does not turn his head.</context>
      <utterance>I want prisoners.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEFTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We came to fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With only a short flick of his head, the Chieftain spits. Nottingham waves his arm, signalling his own foot sol- diers to advance. The Chieftain raises his sword. Instantly a tumultuous chilling roar from his warriors. They charge forward.</context>
      <utterance>Nevertheless, I need prisoners.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Half-hearted support from about a dozen men, including Tack.</context>
      <utterance>Stop 'ere and flippin' well fight 'em, that's what. Whadya say, lads?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nay, reveren'. Ya best be goin' wi' the wenches.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snatches a quarterstaff. John slaps him on the back. The men are encouraged.</context>
      <utterance>This holy man believes in doing God's work with his hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's give 'em a bloody good wallopin' an' all, lads.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He climbs onto Wulf's horse, steers it right at the heart of the enemy... Aslan blocks his way, grabbing his reins.</context>
      <utterance>Wulf, stay here. I need your horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? Out of my way!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saved your life. I will not let you give it away for no purpose.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of my way, damn you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does the witch still have possession of your senses? If we meet up with the survivors we may yet give them some help. And do some damage to the enemy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man swings, Tuck sidesteps.</context>
      <utterance>Surely you would not harm a man of the cloth?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pummels the man to the ground with his staff. The woodsmen are broken into two groups. One group, including Will, is surrounded and surrenders. The others fight on. Bleeding from several wounds, Little John is surrounded by four Celts. He spins, challenging them, spitting out expletives. Defiant to the last... suddenly his attackers are hurled aside. Robin rides right through them, slashing with his sword.</context>
      <utterance>You would? Then to hellfire with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tuck is driven to the ground... his assailant is deliver- ing the lethal blow, when Aslan cuts him down. Tuck glances heavenwards.</context>
      <utterance>'Bout bleedin' time, mush.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Lord.  And thank you, Allah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Distracted, he doesn't see a Celt swing at his back... but Wulf's arrow pierces the man's adam's apple. He freezes in mid-air, before toppling at John's feet. When John turns back, Wulf is being dragged away by three of the Sherrif's men. He attempts to pursue, but is intercepted by two more Celts... and struck down. Aslan charges between the two Celts. Slashes down with both swords. Both men topple to the ground simultaneously. Suddenly all is quiet. The smoking clearing is a mass of fallen bodies. Only four men seem to be alive. Robin, Aslan, Tuck, who is slouched against a tree gasping for breath, and Hal, who kneels clutching his wounded shoulder. Robin dismounts and runs to Little John. Overwhelmed and exhausted, he slumps over the giant's unmoving form.</context>
      <utterance>Git the bleedin' 'ell outa there, ya li'l bugger.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin manages a relieved smile. Aslan strides over. All around them lie slain Celts and woodsmen.</context>
      <utterance>Don't 'ee start bleedin' blubberin', or ya'll make me bloody vomit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a fiendish mind that planned this campaign.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were an honor to your countrymen today, Aslan. You fought better than twenty English knights.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This war is the God of Abraham against the forces of evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares across the desolate clearing.</context>
      <utterance>Well, the war is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is too much blood on my hands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you prefer pain or death?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST WOODSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dignity masking his terror. Nottingham appears to consider.</context>
      <utterance>Death.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man is dragged away by guards. The next PRISONER --</context>
      <utterance>Torture him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you? Pain or death?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND WOODSMAN</speaker>
      <mode>PRISONER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Er... pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Torture him... you see, it makes no difference.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will kill him for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WULF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nottingham strides up to Will, drawing his sword.</context>
      <utterance>Will, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would I need you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nottingham places his sword point against Will's throat.</context>
      <utterance>All your attempts to kill him have failed. Your army failed. Your Celtic mercenaries failed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you can succeed?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am one of his men. He would never suspect me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WULF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knows you always hated him, traitor.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nottingham slides his blade between Will's teeth.</context>
      <utterance>He is a trusting fool. He will believe me. If he doesn't, he will kill me and you have lost nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He withdraws the blade. Will tries to smile.</context>
      <utterance>If you fail, I will personally cut out your lying tongue.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I succeed?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to Will. A smile of mock apology.</context>
      <utterance>His friends will..  ... torture him!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will look better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My pride brought us to this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, friend. It was you who gave these men pride.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gave them nothing but false hope. Tomorrow we will disperse. These people can move south and start over. You must go home and win your Jasmina.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am no longer your responsibility.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is for me to decide.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn you, Arab. I want you out of my life. Can't you understand that? Go home. Go back to your own kind. Aslan stares at him, then turns away. Not the time for argument. Robin fingers his father's medallion... rips it from his neck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The noose tightens on her neck. As she dies, her face shrivels into the cackling features of Mortianna. Next, Robin's father. He stares accusingly right AT us.</context>
      <utterance>Kiss me, Robin.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOCKSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he pulls the rope, the executioner peels back his hood... It is Robin. Gloating, he hauls on the rope. His laughter blends with that of Mortianna in a hideous cacophony.</context>
      <utterance>Why have you betrayed me? Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will! I thought you were taken.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you escape?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promised to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Will can answer, Little John runs up. Grabs Will's throat.</context>
      <utterance>And will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quickly, others arrive. Aslan, Tuck, Hal, Fanny, with kids clinging to her skirts.</context>
      <utterance>I'll wring yer scrawny neck, Will Scarlet. I'd be doin' yer a bloody favor an' all.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will is choking, unable to speak. John loosens his hold just enough for Will to splutter out...</context>
      <utterance>Afore ya kill 'im, John, ask 'im if Wulf be still alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y... e...</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Git us a rope, Hal, and we'll put the bleedin' weasel outa 'is misery.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, wait. Let us hear what he has to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No bugger 'scapes the Sheriff, 'nless 'e's linin' 'is bloomin' pockets.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A traitor sneaks in and out under cover of darkness. Will walked in and announced himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye. 'E always did 'ave balls o' brass.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's sss... string 'im up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John reluctantly moves his hold from Will's neck to his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Let him speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will eyes the accusing faces. Hal searches, lifts Will's shirt. His whole skin is lacerated with deep gashes and fresh burns.</context>
      <utterance>Search 'im, Hal. 'E'll 'ave a bloody blade on 'im somewheres.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps back. Ready to listen.</context>
      <utterance>Bugger me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bring a message from Nottingham. Our men are to be hung in the square on Saturday. At high noon.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about my boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fanny drops her head on John's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>The boy, too. Ten men in all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their deaths are a warning. Anyone who associates with the outlaw Hood is to suffer the same fate. Man, woman, or child. Even anyone who so much as utters his name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robin Hood! Robin Hood! Robin Hood!  May as well be hung for a sheep as a lamb.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hangings are to be part of the celebration for the Sheriff's marriage.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will turns his gaze directly on Robin.</context>
      <utterance>Marriage, eh? What lucky wench gits to play with the Sheriff's codpiece?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lady Marian.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He takes a bride of royal blood?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone reacts with shock. Only Robin appears unsur- prised.</context>
      <utterance>Aye, and then with King Richard gone, he takes the bloody throne.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right, Will?</context>
      <utterance>You were to use this news to get close to me, and then kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not straightway, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your intention, Will?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That depends on you, Locksley.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How so?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never trusted you, that's no secret. What I wanna know is, are you gonna finish what you started?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will ya stay and keep us fightin' till every man jack of us is dead? Or will you run like the spoiled little rich boy I always took you for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You present quite a choice. What would you have me do, Will?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you run, I will kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin checks the other faces.</context>
      <utterance>And if I stay, will you all stay with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the end, friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If my heathen brother stays, I stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't get it out. Little John covers Hal's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmm... meee... tttt...</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daft buggers.</context>
      <utterance>'E's in. We're all bloody in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's your answer, Will. We finish it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan is crushing charcoal into a mixture of yellow powder, which is turning black. Tuck approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Lord, grant us the courage to endure, and if you're as smart as I believe you are, grant us victory... and the victuals to celebrate it with.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you pray with me, son of Allah?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tuck takes a bowl of the powder close to the fire to examine it. Aslan snatches it back... Before Tuck can react, Robin walks up.</context>
      <utterance>I have prayed for you, often, my brother. But, let us put prayer aside and help our gods in a more practical manner. I must reveal to you the mysteries of the black powder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan throws a handful of powder into the firel A fire- ball rips ten feet in the air... Tuck falls on his ass in terror.</context>
      <utterance>Will it work?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are truly a wizard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin reaches out and shakes Aslan's hand. A moment of bonding. He moves on to the others, clasping each man's hand as he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>There is no such thing. But if there was...  ... I would surely be one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment of tension before Will takes the proferred hand.</context>
      <utterance>We have no armored knights, no glorious banners. But I am honored to be going to battle in this company. Today we fight not just for the lives of our friends, but to save all England.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We may be only six men, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She strides towards them from the trees.</context>
      <utterance>Seven!</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where's the little 'uns?</context>
      <utterance>What in blazes ya doin', woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Them's safe, wi' my mother.  Robin, I been to town an' seen the scaffold and the guard towers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya gone bleedin' cracked, girl?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go an' birth eight babies and then you can come an' tell me 'bout hurtin', ya big ox. I ain't gonna sit aroun' an' let one o' 'em die, neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin starts to draw a diagram on the ground with a stick.</context>
      <utterance>Ya should be bloody well mindin' the other seven. Tell 'er, Rob.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Little John double-takes.</context>
      <utterance>Fanny, show me the exact location of the scaffold.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marian smiles as he leans toward her... and spits in his face.</context>
      <utterance>How is my bride?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slowly wipes off the spittle... and slaps her hard.</context>
      <utterance>Ah... You are overwhelmed with happiness.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mortianna emerges from a dark corner, bearing the goblet she used at the Druid ceremony.</context>
      <utterance>I will never marry you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marian struggles against her bonds.</context>
      <utterance>Hold her!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guards viciously restrain her, forcing her mouth open. Mortianna pours the blood-red liquid down her throat. Marian fights, gagging and choking... until the drug takes its effect. She slumps forward. Nottingham watches with amusement.</context>
      <utterance>Get away from me, you disgusting hag. I will not... augh!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clasps the dice-like runes.</context>
      <utterance>When we are married, thirty of the northern barons will pledge me their support as king. As you predicted. Mortianna squats on the floor besides a platter of blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mortianna rocks on her heels, clutching her taloned hands to her sides. She chants, fingering the bloody stones.</context>
      <utterance>What do you see in the portents?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at Nottingham, her red eyes demented.</context>
      <utterance>The union. The blood of the lion and the house of Nottingham. New faith. New power. New souls.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ours!</context>
      <utterance>If there is no union, there will be darkness, despair, death.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How can we be in danger?</context>
      <utterance>Di not give me riddles, woman. We are to be married within hours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The blood does not lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me how it will result.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have told you what I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mortianna runs at him. Points her bony finger at his heart.</context>
      <utterance>Confound you, crone. Without my protection, the people would hunt you down, rip out your black heart and burn it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Without me, you are nothing. You are straw, a fleabite, a speck.  Laugh, fool. I birthed you from this body. I stole a babe in this very castle, and killed it so that you might rise in its place. You are my son.  Together we are strong. Now is not the time to doubt. Now is the time to believe, to be bold. The bold will prevail.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you got there, Father?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It has a mighty kick.</context>
      <utterance>The Lord's finest brew for the good Nottingham's fighting men.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nottingham shouts to one of his mounted guards, who rides over, grabs Will by the collar, and drags him to his side.</context>
      <utterance>Sheriff! My Lord Sheriff! I have word for you! Of Robin Hood!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, the turncoat. Did you succeed?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sheriff strikes down with his armored hand. Will crumples.</context>
      <utterance>I found his lair, but alas he still lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hands yank Will to his feet. Dazed, he tries to speak. Disinterested, Nottingham turns away, until he catches...</context>
      <utterance>Stretch his neck with the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...He... He... is here!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will struggles to get free of his holders.</context>
      <utterance>Locksley, here? Where ?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call off your dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Release him!... Now, where is he?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want your word, in front of these witnesses. If I tell you, I will go free.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nottingham's jaw tightens. Eyes the prisoners, the scaffold.</context>
      <utterance>He is concealed. He is going to free the prisoners and stop the wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put Hood in my hands, you go free.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the reward. Ten thousand crowns.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn your worthless hide! Just tell me where he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The parade of prisoners reaches them. Seeing Will, Wulf charges at him, screaming in blind rage. Soldiers grab Wulf. Throw him down, kicking and beating. Voices in the crowd plead to let him be. Someone tries to intervene, gets hurled down.</context>
      <utterance>The reward!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll get your reward. Where is he?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Step down, friar.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you wish, sire. Is there something amiss?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tuck glares at Will with unconcealed hatred.</context>
      <utterance>This man claims you have outlaws concealed in these barrels. Among them the cursed Robin Hood.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This man will rot in hell as a knave and a liar. These are libations for the celebration of your lordship's nuptials.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Break one open!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cask is shattered... wine torrents out.</context>
      <utterance>Why waste fine vintage, my lord?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A drum roll. The Sheriff's attention turns to the scaffold, where the first victim is escorted up the steps -- Wulf. Tense, Tuck pulls a tinder box from his robes, strikes a flame.</context>
      <utterance>Try another. There are many barrels, only a few outlaws.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your business, woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gestures below. The Sentry looks, then turns back to her... notices the rope. With all her might, Fanny rams his head into the stone battlement. Twice. Three times. He slumps unconscious.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't doin' no 'arm, m'dear. Likes a good 'angin', I do. Luvly view up 'ere, ain't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wrenches the longbow from his back, fumbles for an arrow.</context>
      <utterance>'Bout time, ya gurt lug.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We be too late.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here... By God... Let's fight 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hal! What happened to your stutter?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A guard attacks, Hal fells him.</context>
      <utterance>It's gg... ggg... g..oh crap!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No stutter this time! The woodsmen join battle with the guards. The Chieftain cudgels his Celt attacker across the head. The boar's head helmet tumbles... revealing Aslan.</context>
      <utterance>Take that, ya mug.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEFTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan retreats, fending off the Chieftain's shattering blows.</context>
      <utterance>Impostor! You dishonor the clan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sheriff's men drag Will off before he can choke him. Raging, Nottingham climbs to his feet. Will is held by four men.</context>
      <utterance>Pain or death, you butcher?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drives his sword repeatedly, insanely, into Will's belly.</context>
      <utterance>Here's another message to Robin Hood, written in your blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL SCARLET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finally drops... Nottingham heads for the castle. Robin attempts to follow. He swings from the noose, using the rope to vault over the surrounding soldiers. As he lands, he is waylaid by one of the barons and his men.</context>
      <utterance>It's over, fool. You can kill my body, but you cannot kill our spirit.</utterance>
   <speaker>REDHEAD BARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chieftain knocks Aslan down. Aslan loses his sword.</context>
      <utterance>It's Hood! Get him!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEFTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan spots one of John's arrows protruding from a dead Celt's back. Scrambles over and tears it out.</context>
      <utterance>I am iron. I am rock. I am your death.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaps... rams the arrow through the Chieftain's mouthpiece... out the back of his neck. The Chieftain grabs his helmet, trying to rip it off. He topples, his life's blood gushing from both sides of his neck. Aslan plants a foot on the slain warrior.</context>
      <utterance>You talk too much!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The onlookers are inspired. Grabbing weapons from fallen soldiers, many join the fray.</context>
      <utterance>Englishmen! I am not one of you, yet I fight for you. Against a tyrant. Join me now. Join Robin Hood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A guard winds down the giant gate. Nottingham hurls him aside.</context>
      <utterance>Lower the portcullis! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hacks at the ropes. The gate slices down like a guillotine, pinning soldiers and peasants alike. Fighting his way towards the gate, Robin sees with dismay that the portcullis is closed. Weakening, he staves off the redhead baron's vicious assault. Suddenly peasants are swarming over his attacker. The baron is dragged off and trampled down.</context>
      <utterance>Too slow, fool!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friends! We must raise the gate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't shoot fast enough. As they descend on him, he leaps from the battlements onto a soldier's back. Grabs his sword.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, ya ckicken-'earted buggers. Ya milksops, ya bleedin' pansies.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's backed up against a battlement, outnumbered five to one.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, m 'old cock. Ya mind if I borrow this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are rebelling. We must escape.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marry us. When I am declared king, that rabble will not dare go against us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mortianna screams and slashes her talons across the Bishop's outstretched hands. Blood flows.</context>
      <utterance>Is is madness to delay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORTIANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Face them, or face me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Light all the barrels, Tuck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son, there is a holy war being waged outside. Release all these wretches and God shall surely find you a place in heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAILER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHAM! Tuck takes the lethal cudgel full in the chest. Flies back.</context>
      <utterance>I'd rather go to hell!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin backs in, bloodied, fencing with four remaining soldiers. He smashes one by swinging the heavy door into him, hurtles a pew at another. He springs off another pew, taking down a third.</context>
      <utterance>...your bodies to be bound in immortal wedlock. Do you, Marian Dubois, take... The chapel DOORS SHATTER inward.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marian remains immobile. Mortianna moves to her side. Robin is struck in the thigh. Like a vulture, the Sheriff waits. Tiring, blood pouring from his leg, Robin prepares to fight him.</context>
      <utterance>Marian, run! It's me, Robin. Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I warned you, I would find you no matter what.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his sword to reveal its handle. A crucifix sculpted into the hilt... Robin's father's sword.</context>
      <utterance>No companions? No army? You rush to your death for the sake of a woman. Lust has turned you into a fool... Recognize this, Locksley?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lunges. A savage, accomplished swordsman, with fire in his eyes. Exhausted, Robin is driven back, parrying desperately.</context>
      <utterance>Appropriate I should use it to kill you with, don't you think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grinning, he pulls open his robes, revealing chest armor ... and a miniature powder keg. He holds it to his flaming torch and tosses it to the jailer... Stupified, the man catches the smoking bomb.</context>
      <utterance>The Lord helps those who help themselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KEG ERUPTS, blowing the jailer through a wall.</context>
      <utterance>Give my regards to the devil.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone attacks his assailants from the rear. The tide turns.</context>
      <utterance>Ya gutless bloody sissies.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wulf! I told ya to keep outa the fightin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WULF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Father. Couldn't help myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wulf sends an attacker plummeting off the parapet.</context>
      <utterance>Well, ya'll get a bloody good wallopin' if we get 'ome... For now, let's see how well I taught ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="166" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees a familiar pair of holy sandals marching towards him. Tuck leading a barefoot army. Dozens of ragged prisoners, armed with chains and torture implements.</context>
      <utterance>No! Fight on. Fight!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dying, Hal manages a weak smile.</context>
      <utterance>Sinners, beware! God's avengers are at hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tuck flails a chain at a Celt.</context>
      <utterance>Go' bless ya, Tuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man spins to strike back... freezes... grinning... Aslan!</context>
      <utterance>Repent, heathen!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="167" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A blow slices Robin's arm. His sword flies from his grasp. Nottingham gloats. Two of his men scramble back to their feet. Robin is beat... a war cry! Aslan, followed by Tuck.</context>
      <utterance>You should have stayed away, Locksley. Fools like you never learn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ali akbar!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amen!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="168" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So! You sold your soul to the devil?</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I swear it, in God's name.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bishop surreptitiously draws a dagger from his robes. A taloned hand grips a spear... Mortianna creeps up on Aslan.</context>
      <utterance>Blasphemer! You accuse innocent men of Druid worship while you practice the black arts yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aslan spins... too late. Screeching, Mortianna drives the spear into Aslan's side. He cries out and slides to the floor. Nottingham uses Robin's distraction to regain his sword. Back on the defensive, Robin tries to evade the blows. Mortianna drags Marian out onto a balcony. Robin cannot pursue. In acute pain, Aslan struggles to his feet. Grasping the spear where it enters his side, he pulls with all his strength. The Bishop, concealed dagger in hand, approaches Tuck.</context>
      <utterance>Watch out!</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sure you would not strike a man of the cloth.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without an eyeblink's pause, Tuck punches the Bishop so hard, he flies back THROUGH a stained-glass WINDOW.</context>
      <utterance>Think again!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="169" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NOTTINGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blade comes whirring down... clang! It's blocked. Robin has the altar's crucifix in his hand. He swings it again, slamming Nottingham across the temple. The Sheriff hits the floor. Robin grabs his father's sword. Raises it two-fisted. Nottingham tries to squirm away.</context>
      <utterance>What can your puny God do for you now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drives the sword down, like a stake, right through Nottingham's heart. The man shudders, and is still. Robin stands over him. Drained. Tuck rushes outside. Kneels at Aslan's side. Robin spots Marian swaying on the edge of the steep parapet.</context>
      <utterance>This is for my father.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="170" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stumbles out of the fountain... and storms at him, pounding her fists on his chest.</context>
      <utterance>Robin? Oh God, is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin grins at the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>How dare you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marian looks about her... the chaotic aftermath of battle. Reality gradually sinks in. She folds against Robin's chest. Little John arrives, his huge arms enfolding Wulf and Fanny.</context>
      <utterance>I think she's feeling better.</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We done it, mate. We clobbered the buggers.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you 'urt?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spots a group kneeling beside the fallen body of Aslan. His smile fades. He runs over. Cradles Aslan's head.</context>
      <utterance>It will mend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aslan, my friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="171" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going home the easy way, Robin.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You die on me, you son of satan, and I swear I'll bury you as a Christian in St. Catherine's Cathedral with a thousand monks chanting prayers for your miserable soul. You hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no strength, Brother Tuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fine friend you are! By the grace of Allah and Jehovah we have won the day, and you want to give up the ghost. I'll pickle your remains in mead, lay you in your grave with a pig for a companion, and mark it with a cross as big as this castle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please! It hurts when I laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See. There's life in the heathen dog yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, Tuck. Look after him. You deserve each other. Robin stands, Marian joins him. Around them cheering grows, till the whole crowd is in unison.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robin Hood! Robin Hood!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="172" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FRIAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The husband draws back the bride's veil. Robin and Marian. They kiss... long.</context>
      <utterance>You may kiss the bride.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING RICHARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I kiss the bride?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who would dare refuse his king's request?</utterance>
   <speaker>KING RICHARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look radiant, cousin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are deeply honored by Your Majesty's presence.</utterance>
   <speaker>KING RICHARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue down the aisle, past the smiling congre- gation. Waiting by the door is Aslan. He and Robin embrace.</context>
      <utterance>It is I who am honored, Lord Locksley. Thanks to you I still have a throne.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robin laughs.</context>
      <utterance>My friend, a word of advice... Ride her better than your horse.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
