<movie id="467" title="Ronin">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE BODY suddenly twitches -- this guy is not quite dead. The Killer raises his silenced pistol.</context>
      <utterance>God loves me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't think he's too fond of you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>UGLY AMERICAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>And now we're PULLING BACK DOWN THE LENGTH OF THE BAR. We see THREE MEN sitting seperately at the bar, paying no attention to each other. One of these men watches the game with real interest. The Ugly American talks on from off screen.</context>
      <utterance>This is not football...</utterance>
   <speaker>UGLY AMERICAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Football is three hundred pound guys, they run way too fucking fast, they got helmets made of kevlar they use to spear the quarterback into the next life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>A WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - And we see a woman named DEIRDRE on the phone: striking, dark-haired, Irish. She carries herself with the same professional edge as the men inside the bar. Deirdre listens for a moment to the voice on the other end, and before she speaks she sense something - A SILHOUETTE stands in the shadows of the bar, watching Deirdre. She gives this silhouette a measure glance before speaking, her hand creeping ever so slightly towards her coat.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The silhouette steps into a POOL OF LIGHT. This is SAM. Tough, lean, enigmatic. Somebody you might trust, but whom you'd never cross. Sam returns her look before he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam moves towards the bar, and Deirdre returns to her phone conversation.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here...  No, it was nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I'm late...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think we're here to meet you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent turns towards the others, including them in an expansive gesture.</context>
      <utterance>Who else would you be?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps the police?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent smiles at Sam's answer, satisfied, and makes room for Sam to join them. Vincent takes a pack of cigarettes, shakes them so that one sticks out, and offers it to Sam.</context>
      <utterance>I know cops -- and you're no cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent looks a little disappointed at this as we go -</context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He trusts you to lock up?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent takes out his pack of cigarettes and offer them around the table -- again, nobody takes on. Vincent seems really disappointed by this.</context>
      <utterance>Let's just say he knows who I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody wanna tell me what we're waiting for?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The question isn't what we're waiting for... it's who.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who the fuck is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever hired us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a kind of general look around the table -- a nod or grunt of acknowledgement, indicating that all of these men were hired the same way.</context>
      <utterance>I got this gig through a contractor. And he most definitely didn't know who was doing the hiring, only that they were paying a lot of money...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So none of us knows who's paying the freight, this is just some anonymous job. For all we know, we're working for different people.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that is an interesting proposition.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How so?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because if there's more than one party involved, if we really are working for different people, then perhaps some of us are on different sides.  Your orders might be different from mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you talking about, man? I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a surprise...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a surprise for you, blondie...</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't both of you shut up?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY &amp; SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a BEAT. Gregor, Swede and Larry look at Sam, who glares them all down. Lastly, Sam turns and looks at Vincent. The two men nod at one another, acknowledging a kind of mutual respect.</context>
      <utterance>Knock it off!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The point remains: we could be working for different people. There's a chance for one of us...  Maybe more than one of us -- has been paid to cross the others. I don't know about you guys, but I like to know who I'm working for. It can help prevent a great deal of...  ...unpleasantness.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From OFF SCREEN we hear a new sound: LAUGHTER. ANOTHER ANGLE - Deirdre has entered the bar, and she's amused by this last exchange.</context>
      <utterance>Anybody tries to unpleasant me I'll put two between his eyes -- one to do the job and the other to make sure it takes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good to see you've all got such faith in our little undertaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name is Deirdre, and I'm running this show.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you? IRA?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From here on in you want something you pay cash for it: no credit cards, no bank accounts are in place: ten percent up front, the rest when the job is done.  You. What do you do and what should we call you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These days they they call me Gregor -- and I'm a tech. I do electronic work, surveillance, computer runs. Deirdre turns to Sam.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam. I'm a weapons guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were a soldier, were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deirdre gives Sam a look -- and he returns it. Finally, Deirdre turns to Larry.</context>
      <utterance>Once.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I drive -- and my name is Larry. Larry from the States.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Vincent. And I coordinate.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coordinate what?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men exchange another look. A pecking order is developing among the group: Vincent and Sam are both natural leaders, and now they're feeling one another out.</context>
      <utterance>Things. This is my country, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coordinate all you want, but make sure whatever you do gets cleared through me.  Are we in sync on this, Vincent?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deirdre waits a BEAT, letting Vincent know what she isn't any more intimidated by him than he is by her. Finally, she turns to Swede.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They call me Swede.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's they?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what is it you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?  I kill.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shoot alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gets the job done.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All in the stomach, though. Your man might live.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for long.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long enough to shoot back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been known to happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well... My way works too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My way is better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - Deirdre sits nearby, looking at the cell phone.</context>
      <utterance>Is it alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's quite satifactory.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, because it cost enough. There's cheaper phones by far than that one, man: you better fucking use it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I intend to. This phone is wired like no other: it's got an encryption chip and instant sat-a-link recognition, it can talk to any computer in any language and make it understand. With my custom hardware and this phone I can trace the target's cell phone signature and follow him anywhere he goes...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd stake my reputation.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But would you stake your life, that's the question...</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From off screen we hear MUNCHING. It's - Larry inhaling a sandwich. A malicious look comes over Swede's face, who's cleaning a pistol and sitting near Larry.</context>
      <utterance>In this business, your life and your reputation are more often than not one and the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should watch what you eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck died and appointed you food czar?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just worried about your health, Larry. You could stand to shed a few pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you could stand to get a little smarter, ain't that right you dumb blonde fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both men eyeball one another, and then suddenly Larry reaches for his piece, and as soon as he does this Swede does the same thing, but before they can do anything - DEIRDRE'S GUN swings INTO FRAME, smashing Swede in the face and dropping him to the floor. Larry's mouth drops open in surprise, but it's too late: Deirdre kicks him in the stomach and then rabbit punches him in the back of the neck, driving him to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Who you calling dumb, dickless?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent and Sam start off, moving towards the door, while Swede and larry slowly pick themselves up off the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go for a ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where to?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To see a man about a thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can do that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who gave you permission to park here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty much what you'd expect.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says this is their block.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As in, they own it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I suppose he's saying that we oughta give them something for using it, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know that you spoke French.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON THE LEADER - Who's smirking at Vincent and Sam. Sam's words make a great deal of sense: the Leader is speaking the universal language of "give me some money or I'll kick your ass."</context>
      <utterance>I don't. But the language he's speaking is universal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess we oughta give them something... CUT BACK TO: Vincent and Sam.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent backfists the Leader in the nose -- hitting him so hard that the Leader skitters back on unsteady feet and then sits down on his ass. This blow hurt, but the real damage is to the Leader's pride. Now - One of the Toughs rushes at Sam, only to have Sam perform what looks like a jujitsu throw which savagely jerks the Tough off his feet and flattens him.</context>
      <utterance>If you think we should.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam reaches down as if to help the Tough, who ignores the hand and totters to his feet. As soon as he's up he turns and runs away, followed by the other Toughs. Now only the leader is left behind. He looks for a second at Vincent and Sam, and then turns and runs after his friends. Vincent calls after him in French, but whatever he says isn't translated. Vincent turns to unlock the car.</context>
      <utterance>Oh man, I am sorry about that...  Let me give you a hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you say to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now the two men are in the car, which starts up and drives off, as it does we -</context>
      <utterance>I asked if we could give him anything else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a nice move you did on our young friend. Judo?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jujitsu.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same thing, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. Similar, but not the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the difference?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent laughs, and Sam looks out the window at the city of Paris as we MOVE THROUGH to the outside world of -</context>
      <utterance>One's a lot more painful than the other.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help yourself.  Since when do you smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have, I don't know, maybe a cigarette a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A cigarette? As in one?  One cigarette a week, who smokes like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, I smoke a pack-and-a-half a day, and I tell myself I could be worse.  It's just so damned pleasurable.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has it's moments.  Course, you get cancer and die, that's the down side.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent stamps his cigarette out, looking vaguely unhappy that Sam has spoiled his smoke.</context>
      <utterance>There is that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Vincent: why bring me along for the ride? Job like this calls for a warm body, somebody who can stand around and look threatening. A tough guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like Larry or Swede.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. Why not bring them?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just say I thought the conversational possibilities were limited. Of course, I might have brought Gregor, but he didn't seem like the right candidate -- for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch that one, he's an ex-spook for sure, maybe Stasi, maybe KGB. He's smart, Gregor is.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So is the woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deirdre? Smart, yeah, and seriously goddamned dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder if she truly left the IRA.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've wondered that myself. None of this answers my question, though...  Why bring me?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to see who you were.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent, driving all the while, gives Sam a sideways glance before speaking.</context>
      <utterance>Who am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were once some kind of special forces. Airborne Ranger, maybe a Navy SEAL. After that you rode shotgun for the CIA in some place like El Salvador or Afghanistan, a real mercenary.  Only now -- now you're like the rest of us, it's a very competitive market since the end of the cold war. There's a lot of hired guns out here, and not nearly enough work to go around.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right: there's not hardly enough work these days, nothing that pays the big money, anyhow. Then along comes this job, paying so much goddamned money I couldn't afford not to take it. Somebody's paying through the nose for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They certainly are. Whatever it is we're going to steal, it must be quite something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And on that thought we -</context>
      <utterance>Whatever it is it must be goddamned priceless.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lovely, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men enter the park, which is, indeed, open to the public. Inside, sitting on a bench in the back, almost invisible from the street, we see - FRANCOIS, a stubble-faced tough with a stained shirt and bad teeth. Vincent and Sam draw near. This next conversation between Francois and Vincent is in FRENCH WITH ENGLISH SUBTITLES.</context>
      <utterance>They'd have to keep something like this under lock and key in New York, and it would still get fucked up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent signals for Sam to stop. Both Vincent and Sam are still several feet away from Francois.</context>
      <utterance>That's good right where you are, Vincent.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so fast.  Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's company.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad company...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam hasn't said a word -- he doesn't seem to understand what's been said, but he has noted the urgency with which Francois spoke. Now - We HOLD FOR A BEAT. Neither Vincent nor Francois pulls out a piece to shoot Sam. Instead they wait to see if Sam will respond in any way to what Francois said. The conversation now switches to ENGLISH, which (it turns out) Francois speaks fairly well.</context>
      <utterance>He's a cop, Vincent, he's French and he's a cop and you better shoot him in the fucking head right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to see something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent isn't going to answer, but the overbearing Francois chimes in.</context>
      <utterance>See what?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wanted to see how you reacted when I said that you were a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told him I was a cop?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He asked me to say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He asked you to?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I needed to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need to know a lot of shit, Vincent.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francois's French words give Sam pause -- he's wondering what's being said, as - Vincent moves towards Francois, leaving Sam several steps away. The conversation is again in</context>
      <utterance>Are you ready?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's been a slight problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francois gives the slightest of nods, indicating that Vincent should look towards a place perhaps thirty yards away - A COPSE OF TREES, where we see a SNIPER pointed a telescopic rifle at Vincent.</context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you say a word in English, Vincent, my friend with the high powered sporting rifle will shoot you in the throat. Sorry to screw you over like this, but the information you want might get me killed if I give it to you, and that's a price I'm not willing to pay.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I take it you still want the money...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SAM'S POV: Looking at Vincent and Francois. The men are talking, and from here we can't really hear them speak. All Sam can see is an earnest Vincent listening to Francois talk, almost as if Francois is giving Vincent instructions. Now - Vincent reaches into his pocket, reaching for the envelope of cash he's carrying. As he hands the money to Francois, Vincent uses his free hand to pull out his gun while - Sam already has his gun out -- somehow he figured out what was going on -- and now Francois looks on in stunned disbelief as - Sam fires a single shot, hitting Francois in the shoulder, driving him away from - Vincent, who now squeezes off several rapid fire shots at the sniper, while - Francois, bleeding but still very much alive, now has his piece free just as - The Sniper, his gun firing wildly into the air, falls to the ground, shot dead by Vincent, and now - Francois is drawing a bead on Vincent when - Sam hits Francois with a fusillade of bullets in the chest and now - A SINGLE SPENT BULLED CASING flies through the air in SLOW MOTION and lands on the ground, spinning around until it comes to a halt and - A HEAVY SILENCE FALLS, as the last echo of the last gunshot finally dies. Vincent and Sam look at one another, see that they're still alive, and then look back at - The two men they've shot. Francois isn't quite dead. Blood bubbles from his lips as Vincent leans over him. Again, they speak in</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's my information?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCOIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In here...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A LONG ANGLE - Vincent whispers in Francois's ear, whose grin blanches as he realizes Vincent means to hurt him. Francois whispers something back and then - BANG. Vincent shoots Francois in the head, killing him instantly. Then Vincent bends down and retrieves the envelope of money which Francois had tucked inside his shirt. As Vincent does this, Sam comes up from behind.</context>
      <utterance>Then you better find it in your heart to tell me, Francois, because while your death is inevitable, it still isn't decided how painful it's going to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now would be a good time to get the fuck out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, what you pulled back there, that was bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I needed to see if you were a cop.  I'm a popular man with the police, Sam, and whenever they try to catch me they always do it with an inside guy -- some man on some job who seems more trustworthy than all the others put together. And that's the guy you have to watch out for.  I hate cops...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BEAT, the two men driving in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Well I ain't a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That there was a gun pointed at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw you look off when Francois nodded his head. I figured he wasn't pointing out a particularly rare shrub, and the rest was easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how did you know I would have the presence of mind to pull my weapon when I did?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because that's what I would have done...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent's voice trails off -- he doesn't know what to say. Sam takes the money out of the envelope -- half he keeps for himself, the other he gives to Vincent.</context>
      <utterance>You saved my life back there in the park. I know this doesn't begin to make it right between us...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam opens the door to the house, but Vincent has one last thing to say to him.</context>
      <utterance>What I did back in the park I did because we're working together -- we're on the same team.  This is business -- this is work. We did it together, we share the spoils, even split.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam almost smiles cynically at this: debts of honor don't seem to be something he believes in.</context>
      <utterance>I owe you a heavy debt.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They enter the house and the door closes behind them. A second later we hear -</context>
      <utterance>Whatever you say.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you do with the money?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We kept it...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hazard pay...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The two of you were supposed to go to a simple meet and come back with a simple piece of information, and instead you went to fucking war...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deirdre shakes her head in disgust and rises. We FOLLOW HER</context>
      <utterance>We weren't real thrilled about it either...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's the deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you guys do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel as if I've wandered onto the set of Enter The Dragon. Could you teach me to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't think to see you again tonight. You were pretty pissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still am.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deirdre spings at Sam, throwing martial arts combinations at him: punch followed by kick, elbow strike followed by palm thrust. Sam parries her blows as she drives him across the floor until he's got his back to the wall. Their movements are controlled, but powerful, and there's something almost flirtatious about the whole thing. Now - Deirdre throws one last punch which Sam ducks. He slips behind her and suddenly they square off in earnest. The previous martial arts stuff was a kind of choreographed exercise, but now - They spar for real -- they never hit one another, but they come awfully close, hands and feet whizzing through the air, throwing rapid-fire combinations and techniques. They're not angry, but they're not kidding, either. Finally - Deirdre feints a punch that distracts Sam's attention from - The KICK she throws right behind her punch, and she smiles as - WHUMP! Sam wasn't distracted at all -- he drops to the ground beneath her kick and catches her standing leg with a sweep which takes her to the ground and now - She's trapped beneath him. The two of them are breathing hard from the exertion, their faces close to one another, shining with sweat and excitement and - We've gone from flirting to an almost primal seduction, and with their faces only inches apart Deirdre leans in to kiss Sam, and he's about to meet her half way when he pulls back.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Part of me says I should just look at this as a perk. You know, a bonus. But then I remember you're you -- Deirdre who used to belong to the IRA -- and it occurs to me that deceit and subterfuge come very naturally to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's saying they don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when I consider that, I have to wonder if you don't have some ulterior motive for being here, with me, right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But for the time being, I'm willing to forget about it... They finally kiss, slowly and then building in intensity, and as they start to make love the CAMERA MOVES UP - THROUGH THE BUILDING, floor by floor, until we've reached -</context>
      <utterance>I probably do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would imagine that the great satisfaction in all of this will be killing the American.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hadn't thought about it. Understand me, Gregor -- I take no pleasure in killing. It doesn't bother me one bit, but I don't get off on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A means to an end, is that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I guess we're set.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is one other thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Swede pulls Gregor down to the rooftop with a harsh THUD. Within seconds he has his gun pressed to Gregor's head.</context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't cross me...</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's going to do that!</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you, Swede, I can't do this without you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to make sure you knew who you were dealing with.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swede is now on his feet, walking away, back into the apartment house.</context>
      <utterance>I do, I do...</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he's gone. And as soon as he is, we notice something strange about Gregor: he's not the least bit scared -- he laughs a little low laugh as we -</context>
      <utterance>Just remember it, then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - Sam is somehow sitting up, wide awake -- looking at Deirdre with a penetrating glance.</context>
      <utterance>No goodbye?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Sam, don't take it the wrong way when I tell you we won't be doing this again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to explain yourself to me, Deirdre.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I don't have to, Sam, it's just that, for once, I want to. when I was a -  Patriot, it was a given I'd sleep with any man it was deemed necessary for me to sleep with. You know: any man who needed setting up. Sometimes so we might blackmail him, sometimes so he could be killed.  Sometimes so I could kill him myself. IRA isn't exactly an enlightened feminist organization, Sam. To most of the men I with I was always the girl. "Send the girl to do it." "Tell The girl to take care of it." "Have the girl fuck him."  But I look at you and I get this feeling you take me for what I am: no more, no less.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a hired gun, Deirdre -- just like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somewhere in all of this Deirdre has sat back down on the bed, and somehow now she's only inches away from Sam. They're lips brush and - A MUTED PHONE RINGS in a nearby room, breaking the moment. A QUICK BEAT, then -</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. And last night I wanted to be with someone who was just like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I better be getting that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duty calls?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deirdre gives Sam a light kiss on the lips and then she opens his door. The muted phone is a little louder now. Deirdre closes Sam's door as she exits, but - Sam reaches out a hand and catches the door right before it snaps shut. He watches THROUGH THE DOOR CRACK as - Deirdre cross the hall and opens the door to her room, and now the phone rings loudly until the door shuts, muting the sound once again, shutting Sam out. The phone stops ringing as Deirdre answers and as this happens Sam shuts his door and as the door closes we go to - BLACK. Just for a second. And then - BLINDING SUN hits us in the eyes as we find ourselves above -</context>
      <utterance>Just business.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now then, let's run through it one more time, shall we?  What's your job?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I use my cell phone to get computer access to the telecommunications satellite used by our target. I trace his cell phone signature and use it to pin point his location as he moves through Nice, relaying that information to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call me with the target's route, I follow along until we've reached the attack point and then I run his squag ass off the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which leads us to...</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ride with fat-boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eat shit and die slowly...</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After we stop the target car I get out and use the heavy artillery to kill the driver and his bodyguard.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I blast the lead car into oblivion...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While Sam and I take out the back two cars...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leaving...</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Leaving me to step in, drop the target in the back seat, and get the package...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While...</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's taking me anywhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then Swede and I split with the package and meet you back at the rendezvous.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then Sam, you and I clean up whatever's left to be cleaned.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good. Now all we have to do is live long enough to get paid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is this broad?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should learn a little patience.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's consider a virtue in some corners of the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE CAR PHONE rings, and Swede pushes a button. Deirdre's Voice is heard on the speaker phone.</context>
      <utterance>Not in mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello gentlemen, are we ready?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE TARGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BANG. Swede puts one shot between the Target's eyes, ending his life. Now - Swede takes out a DAI-SHO, the smaller of the two traditional Japanese Samurai swords. With one slashing blow he hacks off the Target's HAND AT THE WRIST and grabs the briefcase. The SEVERED HAND is still caught in the handcuffs, so that it is carried along for the ride. Now - DISTANT SIRENS sound from OFF SCREEN as Swede moves back towards Larry and the Volvo, and as he goes he raises the briefcase (with its severed hand) in a kind of mock salute to Sam, who starts to move back towards Deirdre and Vincent, who have taken care of the remaining Bodyguards, and now the SIRENS are growing closer as we - START TO MOVE IN SLOW MOTION as Swede approaches the Volvo and - Deirdre and Vincent are already at Vincent's Fiat, waiting for Sam, and so they don't notice that - A VAN has been parked nearby this entire time, and now the van's side door slides open, and unseen by any of the others - Gregor steps out of the Van, a gun at his side, and a predatory look on his face as - Swede reaches Larry and the Volvo just as - Sam has reaches the Fiat, and now he looks back and sees - Gregor, crossing the street, and now - Sam screams a warning to Larry, but it's way too late because - Swede shoots Larry in the neck, hitting him above the protective covering of his bullet proof vest. Now we're MOVING IN REAL TIME as - Larry manages to get his backup piece drawn, a snub-nosed .38, and he fires all six shots into - Swede, hitting him in the stomach -- it's the same way Larry shot the target in the warehouse. Swede is sent flying backwards, where he crashes to the pavement. For a second we think he's dead, but then he gets up, in pain but alive, just as Sam predicted. Swede claws at his shirt to reveal that he too wears a bullet proof vest. By now - Larry has rolled out of the Volvo, crawling away but too weak to go far, and now - Swede has Larry in his sights, he's going to kill him.</context>
      <utterance>Not today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't particularly like killing, tubby, but I want you to know that this one I'm going to enjoy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swede turns to follow Larry's gaze, and as he does - Gregor walks INTO FRAME and puts his gun right beneath Swede's chin. Before Swede can even compute this, Gregor pulls the trigger, firing straight up into Swede's brain. Then, without even looking at Larry, who is lying helpless on the ground - Gregor takes the briefcase and gets into the Volvo, driving off just as - Sam arrives, kneeling down by Larry. The SIRENS get louder.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SIRENS reach a crescendo as a group of GENDARMES arrive, charging with automatic weapons drawn. Between the French cops and our heroes lies the shot up wreck of the Target Car, and now - Sam takes out a GRENADE, pulls the pin, and rolls it across the ground, beneath the Mercedes, which the cops have just reached. Seconds later - The Car EXPLODES, cutting off the cops, and as this happens, Vincents puts the pedal to the floor and gets the fuck out of Dodge. We start to SLOWLY PULL BACK on the remains of this battle: the dead bodies, the shot up cars, the broken glass, and that flaming, smoking hulk of a Mercedes in the middle of the street.</context>
      <utterance>We've been crossed...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a cocktail. Mostly demerol, cut with a little crank because we might need you awake in the real near future.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine with fucking me, we got work to do. I don't care what it takes, we are getting our property back and putting it into the hands of the people who are gonna pay us a great deal of money when we do. I don't know about the rest of you guys, but I'm not the kind of guy to just sit back and take it in the ass.  I don't mean that in, like, a literal way...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finding this package is a thing easier said than done. We don't even know what it is.  What did we steal?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When this whole thing started you made it clear: you're running the show. And I don't believe you'd be running this show if you didn't know what was going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I don't!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent's gun is out in the blink of an eye, at Deirdre's head, but she's as fast as he is and her gun is drawn as well, jammed into his stomach.</context>
      <utterance>And I don't believe you...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go shoot me if you want, Vincent, but you'll be dead before I hit the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you dead, woman, I want the the truth!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - Sam has the two of them covered with his gun - an interesting moment, because he can shoot either Deirdre or Vincent, but not both at the same time. The question is: whose side is he on?</context>
      <utterance>Both of you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BEAT. And then Vincent and Deirdre lower their weapons, followed by Sam.</context>
      <utterance>...put your guns down and chill out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam's look isn't romantic, but it implies a level of trust based upon their physical intimacy.</context>
      <utterance>Like it or now, we're on the same side: we're here and the package isn't.  You're not the boss any more, you're our partner. So tell us what you know, so we can figure a way out of this mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, what did we steal?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...  Well I don't! It's a goddamned mystery to me just like it is to you.  But I do know who we're working for. My people, and the Russian mob.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your people? Who the fuck is your people?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you think, Larry? The IRA.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you believed me?  But it wasn't my people who did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because if they had she'd be gone along with the package, instead of sitting here with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. Gregor, he was the Russian's man. It was my people came up with the idea for this run, but the Russians who had the capital to finance it. Gregor, he was their insurance, and I was ours. Everybody else was supposed to be neutral. Gregor must've got to Swede...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never did trust that blonde fuck...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why you were riding with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The question still remains: what do we do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gregor's cell phone...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna do, call him up and ask him to give us back our shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he bring that with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bought it for him -- all the stuff he was using, it was in his contract. Cost a nice penny, too, especially that goddamned phone: Gregor had expensive tastes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check this out.  Gregor's a spook, or he was one until recently. When he was a spy he lived the life -- you know, a prince in some Eastern Bloc country where nobody had shit and Gregor had everything. Then the wall goes down. No more Cold War. And Gregor is out of a job. No apartment, no special stores with Western food and video tapes. I would bet dollars against shit that Gregor liked that phone and he doesn't want to give it up. And I wouldn't be surprised if he's arrogant enough to think...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dapper Gent also has an accent, a much thicker one than Gregor's; it's an accent that places the Gent as a resident of what used to be called the Soviet Union.</context>
      <utterance>It's a beautiful street, no?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAPPER GENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always in a rush, you are. All these years I've known you, you could never wait for anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAPPER GENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is important.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you really think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAPPER GENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gregor, still driving, takes out a SILENCED PISTOL, and the Dapper Gent reaches for his own piece.</context>
      <utterance>You know it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dapper Gent loweres his hand, leaving his gun in his coat. Gregor pulls the van to a curb.</context>
      <utterance>Relax!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We find one particular LITTLE GIRL, around eight, holding the end of a jump rope, wearing a light blue dress. She's breathtakingly beautiful, and now - Gregor raises his silenced pistol, as if to shoot her.</context>
      <utterance>Do you see that one? The girl in the light blue dress?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAPPER GENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gregor pulls the trigger, as he does so the Dapper Gent jogs his arm, and we hear the soft thwpfft of the silenced shot just as the shot goes off - Missing its mark, harmlessly shooting into a tree, causing a SINGLE LEAF to float to the ground behind the playing children. Nobody notices a thing. BEAT. The Dapper Gent is visibly shaken, because there is no doubt that Gregor would have killed the Girl if the Gent hadn't ruined his aim.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing, have you lost your mind?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAPPER GENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gregor leaves his gun dangling in the air a moment longer than necessary and then starts the jeep as we -</context>
      <utterance>To make a point. I don't know her, and I was ready to splatter her brains all over the sidewalk.  I don't particularly like you, so imagine what I'll do if you try anything...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's under your seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAPPER GENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dapper Gent looks down, and sure enough, the edge of the Briefcase sticks out beneath the seat.</context>
      <utterance>As my American friend Larry would say: are you fucking deaf? It's under your seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAPPER GENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a laugh the Dapper Gent hands his satchel to Gregor, whose eyes literally dance with the prospect of his reward. He can't help himself, he opens the satchel and there it is - COLD HARD CASH in large bills, enough for Gregor to live like a prince for quite some time. Gregor sucks in an involuntary breath and then looks back up to see - The Dapper Gent hasn't reached for the Briefcase. Instead he's taken out his gun, and it's only inches from Gregor's head.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you'd do that, Gregor. I thought I trained you better than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAPPER GENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dapper Gent yanks out the Briefcase, and as he does - THE SEVERED HAND comes whipping out along with it, still attached by the handcuff chain. The Hand flies up in the Dapper Gent's face, and we notice that the Hand is starting to rot -- it's bloated and swelling and horrific and it scares the shit out of the Dapper Gent, who drops his gun and fumbles with the Briefcase as - THWPFFT...we hear the sound of another silenced shot as we -</context>
      <utterance>I've never particularly liked you either, Gregor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it done?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEAT. The Phone Voice doesn't respond for a moment -- whoever this is they didn't expect to hear from Gregor. The Voice switches to English.</context>
      <utterance>It's done.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gregor, is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Much to your disappointment, no doubt.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a mistake, it shouldn't have happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in the middle of saving you people a great deal of money -- the least you could do is have the decency to pay me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Phone Voice says something unintelligible in Russian, cut off by Gregor as he angrily snaps off his cell phone and we -</context>
      <utterance>What I do is none of your concern. What you should do is wait for my next phone call. I'm going to find a place where I can tilt the field in my favor. When I'm ready, I'll call you and tell you what I want you to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In answer Sam takes out Vincent's pack of cigarettes and tosses them back to him. Vincent looks almost delighted at this.</context>
      <utterance>You weren't around when I woke up, I thought maybe something had happened.  This has been one very fucked up job, Sam, and I'm not taking any more chances on anybody...  Including you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came up here to sneak a smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were smoking?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It was on the table.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you don't mind I took your pack.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam considers for a minute, and then takes one. Vincent does so as well, and he searches for his lighter, which he can't seem to find, because - Sam has it, and he lights their cigarettes, and then hands the lighter back to Vincent.</context>
      <utterance>Please, help yourself. Smoke as many you'd like.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I borrowed that, too...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course...whenever you feel like it just help yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEAT. The two men smoke in silence, looking out at -</context>
      <utterance>I have a feeling I'm about to start buying my own.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>BACK ON Sam and Vincent.</context>
      <utterance>That was a bad bit of business, today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot of people died.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen a lot of people die before.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't. Not like that. How do you get used to it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't. You just learn to live with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't lie -- there have been times when I had to do it, times when the only way to get out alive was to see that the other man didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We live in a singular world, my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never really thought I was part of the world you move in, Sam, to tell you the truth.  I'm a hood, a thief. Big time in a small time king of way. To the local police I'm a prize, to the local hoods I'm a legend. But to a guy like you I'm just another two bit hired gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This conversation might have gone further, but it is interrupted when Deirdre pokes her head up onto the roof.</context>
      <utterance>You might be a hired gun, Vincent, but I got a feeling you cost more than two bits.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, I was starting to think that the two of you had thrown it in and walked away.  There's someone on the phone downstairs asking for you, and my somewhat limited French leads me to believe that he might have something to tell us about Gregor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(circles something on map) That's Aix en Provence, where he used the phone. Sam runs his finger along the length of the highway on the map. Destination: Paris.</context>
      <utterance>He's going north.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going back.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not necessarily. He could go off road at any number of places. He might not even be in the country anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Paris. The route's too indirect for anything else. A guy like Gregor, he doesn't waste time on this road unless he has to be on it in the first place. Otherwise, he'd be out of the country by now. He's going to Paris.  Now I just hope we can find him before he gets there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If somebody else doesn't find him first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Opera? This is an opera festival?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you that, Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mom and Dad continue their discussion, but we've left them behind, MOVING THROUGH the seats and cafes until we get to a cafe on the outskirts of the Town Square. Here, in the most removed table in the entire Square, we find Gregor sitting in the shadow of the trellis. Unless you're on top of him you can't see him, but he can see everything perfectly. His cell phone sits on the table in front of him -- he picks it up and starts to punch in a number.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you meant Phantom of the Opera. You know, Andrew Lloyd Weber, Cats, that kind of thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This...this is incredible. Is the rest of Europe like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some places, not all. Italy, for instance, they're serious about their food. But try bloody Britain, anywhere in the U.K., you don't get much fancier than a deep-fried bar egg. Food's not our thing, you see.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best beer in the world known to man or God.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best beer in the world? Budweiser for me, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Budweiser? You talk to me of beer and you've the unbridled gall to mention Budweiser in the same sentence? That's not beer! Christ, it's not even a poor excuse for rabbit piss.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? Whatta you drink, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I drink what every civilized man, woman and child in the world drinks: Guinness.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Who has finished his phone call and returned to join them.</context>
      <utterance>I hate to interrupt a conversation of such cultural depth... CUT AWAY TO REVEAL: Vincent -</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent raps lightly on the car window next to Sam's head -- Sam's eyes shoot open: a light sleeper. All eyes are on Vincent, who waits for a BEAT before he reveals his news.</context>
      <utterance>...but we've got to get back on the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm driving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>EDVARD, the more dangerous looking of the two Gunmen responds.</context>
      <utterance>Edvard, is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDVARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Gregor, they sent me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm touched, really, that they'd send someone of your caliber. It's nice to know that they didn't make the mistake of underestimating me twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDVARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a mistake, trying to kill you. Mikhi did it without consulting me, I'd have never allowed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure. But I'm sorry to say that it's too late for trust: we have a serious problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDVARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll double your price.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Do you have the money with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDVARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have the material?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You first, Edvard.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDVARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps we could both go at the same time...</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GUN COMES INTO FRAME, trigger cocked, the barrel placed to Gregor's temple.</context>
      <utterance>I think not.  After you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Gregor stiffens, as we PULL BACK ON Sam, who has snuck up on Gregor and gotten the drop on him.</context>
      <utterance>After you, asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT TO THE GUNMEN'S POV: Looking into the Tunnel - It's dark, they can't see a thing, but they've heard Sam's voice and they know something's wrong.</context>
      <utterance>You might have been one mean technical spook, Gregor, but you wouldn't have lasted a week in the field.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDVARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gregor, are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gregor's fine... CUT AWAY TO REVEAL: Deirdre - She's snuck up on the Gunmen, weapon drawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Gunmen reach for their pieces and as they do -</context>
      <utterance>...but I think you're in a bit of trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CUT AWAY TO REVEAL: Vincent - And his piece is also out -- the Gunmen are trapped, and they know it. Now we notice that - The Ancient Geezer and his Tour Group are coming towards us. Meanwhile, back in -</context>
      <utterance>Don't even think it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk to me unless you tell me what I want to hear, understand?!? You have no choice in this, don't think about winning, think about staying alive. I want the item, and if you don't give it to me, I'm gonna kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have it with me...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sent it to myself in Paris.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sent it where?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Gregor runs forward, towards the exit. Sam runs after him, tackling him just as they reach - THE OUTSIDE, where the two men roll into plain sight of - The Gunmen, who are still covered by Vincent and Deirdre. Now we notice - That the Ancient Geezer and his Tour Group are really close, no more than ten yards away, as - Sam has Gregor pinned face first on the ancient stone of the theater. He looks up at the others, and that's when it happens - Edvard looks at Sam and recognizes him.</context>
      <utterance>A post office box.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDVARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know who he is? He's with Interpol, the Internation Police. He's a cop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a cop...you're a fucking cop...I should kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now Sam runs into the tunnel, after the others, leaving Vincent for a fraction of a second to sigh, and then follow Sam into -</context>
      <utterance>But you can't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EDVARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do I know you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vienna.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDVARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edvard's finger tightens around the trigger, when -</context>
      <utterance>Of course...I remember. I quite liked you, I'm sorry to have to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Edvard is startled by the sound of Sam's voice. Even as he squeezes off the shot, Edvard turns to look at Sam, and as he does so, Vincent strikes out at the gun, sending the shot awry, causing it to - RICOCHET wildly, whining around the room, until it - Rips through Sam's side, a nasty wound but not fatal, as - Edvard tries to fire another shot but it's too late, because - Vincent fires a single shot to the head that kills Edvard.</context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That makes twice now you've saved my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't save your life back there. Risked it, maybe -- but I didn't save shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You need a doctor.</context>
      <utterance>You see it your way, I'll see it mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know one around here? Somebody you trust?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...I thought I'd take you to the hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No hospitals. I'll fix this myself if I have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fix it yourself?  Why are we even doing this? There's no need to run, Christ...  You're a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're with Interpol -- you're a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I was a cop, a real cop, I'd have busted you a long time ago. This isn't about you, it's about the job I have to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what job is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEAT. Sam takes out his own pack of cigarettes, offers one to Vincent and takes another for himself. They smoke for a second, before Vincent speaks.</context>
      <utterance>My job, Vincent, a job you don't need to know about. I can't go to the local cops -- they'd never be able to get close enough at this point. It's me or nobody, and I've been on this job too goddamned long not to finish.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks to me like we're all that's left of our group.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We? There is no we in my world now, Vincent, just me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This doesn't involve you, don't you understand? I can't even guarantee you any money out of all this.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't about money for me, not anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam gives Vincent a look and shakes his head in disbelief -- Vincent's loyalty and sense of honor is something he's never seen before, and Sam can only smoke in silence and consider this as we -</context>
      <utterance>Yes I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we're done with this, I want to do for that one myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now there's the Deirdre I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what's that supposed to mean, Seamus Reilly?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means I was worried that all the time you spent away from the fold might have affected you. You've been living the life of the hired gun -- the well paid hired gun, I might note. There's no glory to it, but there are those that like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you thought that maybe I'd grown too attached to this charade I've been playing, is that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been known to happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not to me, you know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seamus's taunt works: Deirdre whips out her gun and puts it to his head.</context>
      <utterance>I thought I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seamus glares at Deirdre for a moment, and she glares back at him until he starts to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I guess you don't know me, then, if you think I won't kill you for an insult like that!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deirdre glares a moment more and then puts away her gun.</context>
      <utterance>Just testing, lass. Forgive me, but I had to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deirdre gives Seamus a look to make sure this last point is clear and we -</context>
      <utterance>Remember what we agreed on, Seamus: when we get home, I don't play "the girl" again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Jean-Pierre.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, my friend.  He doesn't look French to me, Vincent.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>American.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Vincent's American friend, shall we see what we can do for you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you won't have a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent pours a healthy splash of rubbing alcohol onto the wound and - Sam grits his teeth as the pain explodes up his central nervous system.</context>
      <utterance>Douse the wound with alcohol.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent picks up the clamp.</context>
      <utterance>Take the clamp...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent attaches the clamp to Sam's wound. It takes perhaps fifteen seconds, and everyone of those seconds is agonizing for Sam. He sweats, he grits his teeth, he grunts the smallest of grunts. But he doesn't move. Finally Vincent is done.</context>
      <utterance>Peel back the skin and attach the clamp.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, it's done.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see the bullet?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clearly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>remember, Vincent, what we're doing here is routine. I've done stuff like this at least twenty times in the field. There are no vital organs where you're working, no major muscles or arteries -- you can't kill me. Just make sure you've got the bullet before you try to pull it out. Vincent probes the wound with the forceps. This takes probably thirty seconds, and it hurts even more then when the clamp was attached. Several times - Vincent seems to have the bullet in his grasp, but it slips, and each time it slips - Sam makes the smallest of noises, as if to indicate the level of the pain. Finally - The forceps firmly grasp the bullet, and with a single tug, Vincent extracts it.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Now take the forceps, and</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses the bullet through the air, and we FOLLOW IT IN SLOW MOTION as it lands in - A SAUCER, which sits on the kitchen counter. We're back in REAL TIME, as the bullet rolls around the plate for a second before coming to a halt. Now - Sam breathes the hugest of sighs, and his face relaxes. Instantly, Vincent puts a lighted cigarette in Sam's mouth, and he drags deeply on it.</context>
      <utterance>A souvenir...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you can stitch me up on you own?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, we'll take care of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's exactly what he does.</context>
      <utterance>Then if you don't mind...  I'm gonna pass out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's tough, your American friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Sam's tough alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you respect him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never seen a man who could have taken what he just went through.  He's a cop?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly? But close enough, eh?  So he saved your life, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both men stare back into the fireplace and we HOLD FOR A BEAT before we -</context>
      <utterance>If he hadn't you'd have put a bullet in his head a long time ago.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - Jean-Pierre stands in the open front door of the farmhouse, with a cup of coffee. Now, Jean-Pierre moves out to join Sam, sitting down on another chair opposite him.</context>
      <utterance>You're feeling better?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some, thanks. Enough to move on, for now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should really let a doctor look at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But first you have something to take care of?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something important? A thing that cannot wait?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It gets done now or not at all. Another couple of days and the parties concerned are gone where I can't get them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive my intrusion into your affairs, but I am the one who connected Vincent to this job, his agent, if you will. He is one of my oldest friends and I owe him a great debt, much like the debt I suspect he owes you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Vincent looks up when he hears his name and he moves towards the sound of the voices.</context>
      <utterance>Vincent doesn't owe me a thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sees this differently, as you well know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't expect that he would.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You suffered through an agonizing pain last night, pain you could have avoided by declaring yourself an agent of the law.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vincent told you that I'm a cop?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now Jean-Pierre produces a LONG BARRELED REVOLVER which he places loosely in his lap -- a gesture which seems to say, "you'd better explain things to my satifaction or we're gonna have a problem." Sam notices the weapon, but he doesn't react overtly.</context>
      <utterance>Not a word. But no ordinary criminal would have the extensive military and medical expertise you do. And so I place the pieces of the puzzle together in a way that makes sense to me. You work for some government agency and you carry a gun, and in my world, that makes you a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this is what, a test?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEAT. Sam looks at the Revolver again.</context>
      <utterance>Call it a reckoning of character.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I was healthy, I could take that away from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>QUICK CUT TO: Vincent - Who stands inside the house, out of sight, but not out of ear shot. He's listening to everything, and we notice that Vincent has taken out his own gun. BACK ON Jean-Pierre and Sam. By now Jean-Pierre has raised the pistol. He doesn't point it at Sam, but his finger cocks the hammer.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps. But you are not healthy, and if you try I'll kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what is it you want to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose I want to know how a man like you is created.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Created?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps forged is a better word. Like steel. Like a sword. You're a modern Samurai. I've spent my life around extraordinary men -- men like Vincent. But I've never seen anyone like you.  I'm afraid Vincent will die if he goes with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vincent's life is his own burden; he'll have to carry it for himself. And I'm not any kind of Samurai.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem one to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LONG BEAT. Something in Sam's speech touches Jean-Pierre. He relaxes his finger on the hammer.</context>
      <utterance>A Samurai has honor, a Samurai live by the code of Bushido, the way of the warrior. I'm just a killer for hire.  The world isn't about honor, anymore. It's about survival.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN-PIERRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BACK ON Vincent - Who relaxes his grip on his gun. BACK ON Sam and Jean-Pierre - And we're PULLING BACK, AWAY from the Farmhouse, which glows in the morning sun as we -</context>
      <utterance>Survival. I suppose that's as good a cause as any.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the case?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a problem...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Problem my ass! I think you're lying to me, and if you are you're a dead man!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would somebody tell me what fucking well happened in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're lying to me you poor excuse for a human being, I'm gonna blow your brains all over this car.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gregor is beyond speech -- he can only whimper.</context>
      <utterance>Ease up, man...I'm just checking to make sure you're on the level.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>sadistic. Neither Gregor nor Deirdre smiles in return as we -</context>
      <utterance>And it seems to me I saw a sign in there that says they got a late afternoon delivery. Why don't we come back later today and do this all over again, huh? Seamus smiles a smile that is more than a little bit</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony looks up and sees something that catches his attention.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, they're both great movies. One is more of a character study, the other is more of a straight action thing, but they're great movies, and he's an amazing fucking filmmaker.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent and Sam have entered the store. Sam's ability to be back on his feet in such a short time is amazing -- but we can see that he's not the same guy he was at the start of the film. what he does from here on in he does by sheer force of will. Now - Tony moves to join them, and the conversation immediately turns to English.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me...</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My man, how you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm alright. And you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doing well.  This is?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend. I was telling him about how you always have the latest tapes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony's office, it turns out, is the area behind the COUNTER. Tony raises a section of the counter that allows him to get to the other side, and then he closes it behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't we step into my office...</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent checks out the store before he starts speaking. The place is empty except for - The single Customer Tony was just talking to. The Customer is still considering the two films Tony was showing him.</context>
      <utterance>So what can I do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wondering if you had any movies that were particularly new.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Matter of face there's this flick I've been hearing about. I haven't seen it, but from what I hear it's pretty cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the story?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An unlikely group of partners.</context>
      <utterance>It's an international thing. Several different peoples involved, criminals from all over the world, experts brought together to do a job. But maybe the most interesting thing about it is that preeminent in the plot we find the Russian Mob and the IRA in bed together.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have the tape?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Customer approaches the counter. He has both tapes with him.</context>
      <utterance>I might know where you could get a copy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me do some business with my boy here, and I'll meet you across the street in five. I gotta make homes here feel like he's getting a good deal while I give him the pleasure of overpaying me for a couple of second generation pirates.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I've heard so far, it's all a lot of talk. I wasn't so sure what to make of it at first, cause, like I said, the Irish and the Russians are an unlikely mix.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you might know where we can get a copy of this tape?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All depends on whether you want the Russian or the Gaelic language version.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gaelic.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Russian would be easier.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause the Russian production company would be easier to find.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the Irish tape we want.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gonna be tough. Tony scribbles something on a piece of paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last I heard there was a film rep for the Irish players staying at this address, name of Seamus Reilly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seamus Reilly.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seamus Reilly, boy's a serious Irish Auteur -- a real firebrand. Thinks his more moderate filmmaking brethren have turned to making movies for peace-loving pussies, if you see what I'm saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam reaches for the piece of paper, but Vincent puts his hand on top of it.</context>
      <utterance>I get the picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tony and I have to talk some business, first.</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta try and overcharge him, he has to moan about the price, we settle somewhere in the middle.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why don't you wait outside, this won't take long. Sam smiles slightly and rises from the table, moving towards the exit. Behind him in rapid-fire French, Tony and Vincent are now discussing the price of the information. They are both loud and abusive, and obviously they're enjoying themselves immensely.</context>
      <utterance>It's a matter of respect.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Irish representative?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent gives Sam another piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The address of the Russian production company. Just in case we need to find them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent starts the car and we -</context>
      <utterance>Thorough man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure your friend got the right place?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEAT. Vincent wants to know something important.</context>
      <utterance>If Tony says this is it, then it's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, Sam: why do you do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Continue when it would be so much easier to give it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then quit.  You don't work for Interpol, Sam.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I do. You heard him, you heard the guy -- that's what he said, what Edvard said.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LONG BEAT. Sam considers what to say, and then decides he owes Vincent the truth.</context>
      <utterance>It's a cover, then. A cover within a cover, a feint within a feint.  You work for the CIA, it's the only possible answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a field agent -- last of an already extinct breed. I do dark ops.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dark ops?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Assassination.</context>
      <utterance>Dark operations. Wet work. Kidnaping.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very ugly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not very zen of you, huh? Not so much the modern Samurai after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never made that claim.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Jean-Pierre did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were behind the door?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was waiting to see what would happen. I didn't want to kill him if I didn't have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You would have done that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would have tried not to. But yes, if it would have kept him from shooting you, I would have.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could you have done that?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THEIR POV: Through the Windsheild - Deirdre exits the apartment building.</context>
      <utterance>Because I owe you.  Look at that...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Now Deirdre is followed by Seamus and Gregor.</context>
      <utterance>All things come to those who wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>BACK ON Sam and Vincent.</context>
      <utterance>He's not dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't have the package.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent and Sam exchange a look -- now they both figure it out.</context>
      <utterance>You said it yourself: Gregor's not dead. If they had the package, they'd have killed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT &amp; SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're going to get it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something in his voice conveys enough of a threat that she backs off. Now she and Sam exchange a long look.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do it...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if it isn't Mr. Interpol himself.  I can't believe I misjudged you like I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh please..you're on some sort of holy mission?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a patriate.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't even think that I'm buying that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you get off saying word one? All the time pretending to be one of us, it's the same thing we were doing, Seamus and myself. And here you are so high and mighty, like you're so different from the rest of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say I was.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CUT AWAY TO: Gregor and Seamus are leaving the post office. By now, Seamus has taken the package away from Gregor. Unseen by these two men - Vincent is approaching from the side, on an intercept course, his hand inside a bag which he carries with him. Now - Deirdre turns and shoots Sam a look. He's still watching her keenly, and we can see that she's aching to reach for her piece, but she can't because Sam is still on her like a hawk.</context>
      <utterance>Bloody fucking hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls back the folds of his suit jacket, revealing his gun, putting his hand comfortably on the pistol grip.</context>
      <utterance>Don't even think it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent is closing on Gregor and Seamus, another ten seconds and he'll have them. Now - Deirdre looks back at Sam, then back at the situation developing in front of her, and then suddenly - She slams the car into gear and drives off, tires squealing while - Sam pulls his piece, sighting down the barrel and - He can't do it, can't shoot Deirdre. Now - The sound of the car alerts Seamus, who turns in time to see - Vincent, who is raising the bag wrapped around his hand as - The car flies directly at - Vincent, who if forced to jump out of the way even as he pulls the trigger of the gun hidden within the bag. The end of the bag explodes in a burst of fire, but the shots are off the mark - Missing Seamus and Gregor as - Vincent rolls out of the way, just in time, while - Deirdre brakes the car to a screaming halt, as Seamus pushes Gregor in ahead of him and then gets in. Seconds later, the car pulls out, even as - Sam drives up in the Peugeot to Vincent, who picks himself up off the ground and leaps into the car. The last thing we hear is the sound of Sam's Voice as the Peugeot drives off.</context>
      <utterance>I'd kill you before you had it halfway out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put your seatbelt on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know? Bullshit, you had her, there was no way out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What in bloody hell is going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're part of the team. One of them's the guy I told you about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Interpol?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is it these fellahs managed to get the drop on us?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you: they're good...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This better be the real thing or you're a dead man!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is, I'm telling you it is!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZING-SHATTER! A BULLET blows a hole in their back windshield as - The Peugeot is catching up, and Vincent is leaning out of his window, firing away. Now - Seamus turns to Deirdre.</context>
      <utterance>You've told me a lot of things, boyo...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lose them!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deirdre swings the wheel wildly, and the Compact takes a screaming turn, followed by - The Peugeot, and now they're both speeding towards another junction, where several other roadways of the Periferique run together. Now we see that - Seamus is returning Vincent's fire, even as - The Junction approaches, and now - Seamus screams at Deirdre.</context>
      <utterance>You lose them!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deirdre swerves to the right only to discover that she's now on an - EXIT RAMP, going against heavy traffic. Now - Deirdre swerves her car around, side-swiping several cars, but avoiding a major crash while - The Peugeot follows along, and now - One of the cars that Deirdre side-swiped careens wildly down the ramp, crashing into - The Peugeot, which grinds to a halt as Vincent and Sam bounce forward in their seats, restrained by their seatbelts. The car has stalled, and Sam has to start her up again and slam it into gear before following after - The Compact, which now has a lead of perhaps fifty yards -- but at least it's possible for the Peugeot to follow after the Compact, because it's the only car on the highway ahead of them that's GOING THE WRONG WAY, and now we - PULL BACK, LOOKING DOWN FROM ABOVE, and the two cars are flying through the rush-hour traffic, going the wrong way, and now - The Peugeot is gaining ground as Sam turns to Vincent.</context>
      <utterance>To the right!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a cigarette.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme a goddamn cigarette!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're not French, you don't live here, you don't know these roads. Why are you driving? He puts the cigarette in Sam's mouth and as he does - The Peugeot weaves in and out of the traffic, gaining ground on the Compact, and now - SCREEEEECCHHH!!!! About fifteen cars pile up, crashing into one another, and yet somehow - The Compact Car emerges from the pile up unscathed, and Seamus breathes a hugh sigh of relief.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you driving?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About time!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Peugeot has also managed to avoid the pile-up, and it's back on their tail.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good Christ! Can't you lose these jokers?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now the Peugeot SLAMS into the side of the Compact Car, and as it does - Seamus opens fire with his gun, even as - Vincent unloads the better part of a clip as - Glass shatters in both cars, and now Deirdre looks up to see - A FORK IN THE ROAD, and the left side of the fork is closed off, blocked by - A SERIOUS CONCRETE BARRICADE, and the Compact Car is headed right for it, and now - Sam has the Peugeot pinned right to the side of the Compact Car, metal against metal, a scream of steel as the Barricade rushes straight at them and at the last second - Deirdre slams on the brakes as - Seamus fires one last shot that - blows out the window in front of Sam's eyes, causing Sam to - Jerk the wheel of the Peugeot wildly, spinning out of control onto the exit ramp as Gregor reaches over and unbuckles Seamus's seatbelt right as - The Compact Car slams into the Barricade and CRASHES, and we're in SLOW MOTION as - Deirdre is driven forward by the force of the impact, but there's a driver's side air bag, and it explodes, cushioning her, even as - Seamus is hurled form the car, crashing through the windshield and flying through the air as - The Compact Car flips over and over and over while - Gregor, who is wearing his seatbelt, hangs on for dear life to the Briefcase, which he grabbed back from Seamus before the crash, and now - Seamus hits the ground with a terrible thud, his face sliced to ribbons by the windshield, but somehow still alive as - Sam tries to control the Peugeot, which is in a spin on the exit ramp as - Gregor kicks open the back door and slides out of the Car, carrying the Briefcase with him, as - Deirdre struggles to free herself from the wreck, which is now - On fire, and now - Sam has managed to stop the Peugeot, but it's too late to go back, because - A VERITABLE FLEET OF COP CARS is now closing on the accident, and it's too late to turn around, and even as - Deirdre manages to pull herself out of the wreck, it - EXPLODES into a ball of fire, and the blast wave of fire - Hits Seamus, knocking him down, covering him for a second, even as - Deirdre hurls herself through the flames and comes out - Rolling away with Seamus, who is now not only cut to pieces, but his face is covered with some hideous burns. Now Deirdre pulls Seamus over the side of the embankment, right before the cops arrive, and the two of them roll/fall almost thirty down a steep incline, even as - Sam catches a quick glimpse of - Gregor, scurrying away from the highway, carrying the Briefcase, and now Sam has to gun his car and get gone, because the Cops have reached - The Wreck, which is quickly burning itself out, and as the Cops look into the debris they see that - THERE'S NOBODY LEFT. Everybody's gone.</context>
      <utterance>They're good!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - And we see the rest of the apartment: there's practically nothing here. A table with a couple of chairs, a fridge. An open door leads to a bedroom with a small, spare bed and a nightstand with a cheap lamp.</context>
      <utterance>Nice place.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not here very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Business keeps you on the road?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men crass the room towards - A METAL CABINET which is tucked into a nook in the wall - VINCENT'S HAND turns a heavy- duty COMBINATION LOCK and then: Click, the cabinet opens and we see -- WEAPONS. An endless cache of guns, knives, explosives, surveillance devices, gun scopes -- you name it, it's here. Now Vincent's Hands reach into the cabinet and start taking out weapons. We PULL BACK ON - Vincent, who gives the weapons to Sam. Sam checks to make sure the weapons are loaded and/or ready for use, and then piles them, one on top of the other.</context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I don't need to say this to you, but I need to say it to you.  This is my job, I have to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you don't, and you know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If our positions were reversed, would you leave me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEAT. Sam can't say anything, because he knows that what Vincent is saying is true.</context>
      <utterance>I think not.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we need anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent thinks about this for a seoncd -- and then burst out laughing as we -</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We need out fucking heads examined.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better be careful, Seamus, before something happens a plastic surgeon can't fix.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plastic fucking surgeon?  You think I'm going to fix this, Deirdre lass? It's the mark of the patriot, and I'll wear it like a badge. As for those who done it to me, I'll take my pound of flesh before this is all over.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're thinking with your gun, Seamus, and not your head...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEAT. Deirdre bristles at Seamus's words but says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!!!  Shut up and drive! I'm your superior officer and you will do as I goddamn well say, is that understood?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I need to repeat myself?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Seamus. I heard you the first time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not here. They might see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent offers one to Sam, who declines with a shake of his head.</context>
      <utterance>If I'm going to die for the CIA, I'm going to go out smoking.  Besides, there's half a forest between us and them, they can't see a goddamned thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time to quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not just like that... Just before I turn around and it's six months from now and the first thing I do when I wake up in the morning is light a cigarette.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What of it?  Samurai pain in the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you stop with that...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? You've got more force of will than anyone I've ever seen. You handle a gun like it's a part of you, you perform surgery on yourself without anesthesia...  And most amazing of all, you quit smoking, just like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The mark of a true Samurai.  What I do for the Company, Vincent, is no different than what you do. We're both hired guns, and this is a job -- like any other job.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why then, Sam, don't you act like this is a job like any other? Surely, if you are a hired gun, you realize that some times you just have to walk away without getting what you came for.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I don't walk away.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the one thing I've got left to hold onto.  Jean-Pierre is one of your closest friends, is he not?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Closest and oldest.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And yet you would have killed him to save my life.  You have a sense of honor, Vincent, that I can't even remember anymore. I don't know that I ever even had it to begin with. All I know to do, Vincent, is to finish my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when you finish? What then? This package, whatever it is, do you give it to the CIA? Do you really think they deserve it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a good question.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have a good answer?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MIKHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit, sit...  Would you like one?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Mikhi, I wouldn't.  Since I won't speak your language, and you can't speak mine, English will do nicely.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever you wish...  This has all been a terrible mistake, Gregor. I wanted to play straight with you, but Edvard insisted we try and kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Edvard said the same thing about you before he died.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm shocked, shocked to think that you'd believe him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gregor raises the Briefcase which is still attached to his wrist via the handcuff. Gregor rests the Briefcase on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Enough!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moment of truth. Before this scene can develop any further, a VOICE comes from Off Screen, and as the Voice speaks, Gregor blanches.</context>
      <utterance>Ahh...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - Deirdre and Seamus have entered the room. And we notice something unusual: nobody is alarmed (except for Gregor, that is). It's as if they were expected.</context>
      <utterance>The moment of truth, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Seamus speaks he walks through the room, examining the valuable china and crystal, all the while moving inexorably closer to Gregor. His face is, if anything, even more horrific than it was a short while ago, as his formerly fresh wounds have started to scab over.</context>
      <utterance>What is he doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I doing here? Why, I'm here to see my partners, Gregor, the boys in the Russian Mafia. See, your bosses had hoped to screw me by hiring you to pull your thieving double cross. But they only just found out that what's in the briefcase is completely useless without me. I can't fight them, and they can't kill me -- that means we're gonna have to do business together.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you hate each other!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a little hate between business partners?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you've got it all figured, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Figured enough to know there's an odd man out and I'm looking at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think not.  I have, of course, taken the precaution of wiring the briefcase to explode five seconds after it opens. Unless, of course, I deactivate it before it goes off.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That fucking figures...</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should any of you decide to rush me, I'll kill myself and whoever happens to be near me at the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And more importantly --</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEAT. Nobody moves. Nobody speaks. Until finally -</context>
      <utterance>I'll destroy whatever's in the case.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before this entirely too-weird scenario can play itself we go back to -</context>
      <utterance>It looks, Gentlemen, as if we're gonna have to sit down to table and work out an agreement.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent and Sam split up, moving into separate WINGS of the Chateau, and as they move off Sam speaks a word of warning.</context>
      <utterance>Let's work our way through the building. I'll take one wing, you take the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then they're gone, and we're with - Deirdre, who's running through the house, going from room to room, and we're with her for a minute, the JAPANESE DRUM starts to play again, and now it's joined by more and more drums, and they continue for the test of this sequence and suddenly - A HUGE BURST OF GUNFIRE is heard, dragging Deirdre's attention towards -</context>
      <utterance>Watch your back, Vincent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Deirdre can't do it. There's something between these two, and now - Sam looks around and sees Deirdre's other pistol lying on a broken chair, and now he - Kicks out with his foot and hits the chair leg, causing it to function as a lever, sending the gun - THROUGH THE AIR in a graceful SLOW-MO arc until it - THWACKS into Sam's Hand. Now he's armed and he looks back at - Deirdre. Her FINGER tightens on the trigger, she's almost ready to shoot -- if Sam raises his piece, he's a dead man.</context>
      <utterance>Go on, them...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In response Sam stares at Deirdre for a BEAT and then he smiles an enigmatic smile and - He steps sideways, into a nearby corridor, vanishing.</context>
      <utterance>Let it go, Sam, walk away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs after him but she's too late -- The corridor outside is empty. Now we're back in -</context>
      <utterance>God damn it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll die if we stay here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gregor sits back down, fairly close to Mikhi. Then, in a manner so deft that Mikhi never even notices, Gregor extracts a wickedly thin stiletto blade from the leather lining of the Briefcase. Before Mikhi can even react, Gregor stabs his arm forward in a savage arc - JAMMING THE BLADE into Mikhi's throat. Mikhi drops his gun and reaches for the blade, already gagging on the blood spray which shoots from the slashed artery. Within seconds - Mikhi falls to the ground, jerking viciously in his death throes as - Gregor picks up the pistol and runs to leave the room, and as he does we move to -</context>
      <utterance>You'll die if you leave here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to stop doing that!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men don't have time for any more words, they move from the Gallery and find themselves in -</context>
      <utterance>I'll work on it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - Seamus Reilly has come in behind them, and he's got his gun pointed straight at Sam's heart. If Seamus is enraged at discovering Gregor's absence, he's overjoyed to find Sam in his place.</context>
      <utterance>Turn around real slow, and try hard not to breathe when you do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's you...  You're the one did this to my face, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seamus pulls the trigger and his BULLET spins out towards Sam, ready to blow a hole through him except that - Vincent leaps forward and takes the bullet -- it rips into his side, a huge splash of red against his white shirt. He falls to the ground, horribly wounded, but he's given Sam enough time, and now - Sam and Seamus open fire on one another - BULLETS RIPPING into the table, chewing up the china and crystal, taking glass shattering bites out of the CHANDELIER above the table, turning the Dining Room from a primo Louis XIV showpiece into shit as the two men move about and then suddenly - They're face to face, each with a gun to the other - Mexican Standoff. Suddenly, from Off Screen -</context>
      <utterance>Have a nice afterlife.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - Deirdre has appeared, her gun leveled at the two men.</context>
      <utterance>Seamus!</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deirdre, do for him, woman, put a fucking bullet in his head! Deirdre hesitates, uncertain.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>These last words sink into Deirdre: she is a soldier. Her gun swivels towards Sam.</context>
      <utterance>Do it, for Christ's sake, do it so we can find that stinking Gregor, he's got the bloody package! For God's sake, you're a soldier...</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deirdre makes up her mind.</context>
      <utterance>You're one of us...You been born and bred with your own people, you can't go against your nature. C'mon, girl, I'm you're people.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She fires a shot - Blowing Seamus off his feet and through a huge PLATE GLASS WINDOW.</context>
      <utterance>I'm no girl, Seamus...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves with Sam to Vincent, who is seriously wounded -- perhaps life-threateningly so.</context>
      <utterance>And you ain't nobody's people.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get him out of here...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finish the job...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam considers, but before he can make up his mind, Deirdre sees something through the wreck of the Dining Room Window - OUT ON THE BACK LAWN - We've already seen that it's bordered on one side by the woods, for the first time we notice - A LAKE, which laps against a PRIVATE DOCK, where a row boat is tethered. Now - BENEATH A VERY FULL MOON, the stark figure of Gregor makes its way toward the Dock.</context>
      <utterance>Finish it!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam turns at the sound of her voice and sees Gregor making his escape. Sam looks back at Vincent, who is almost passed out from blood loss.</context>
      <utterance>Sam...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Same makes up his mind, and as Vincent passes out, Sam runs out after Deirdre and towards -</context>
      <utterance>I'm really sick of you saving my life. Go out and get the bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now they reach the Dock and they find - Nothing -- no Gregor. And the Boat is still there. Before Sam can restrain her - Deirdre stps out towards the Boat.</context>
      <utterance>He's got the briefcase rigged to explode five seconds after anybody other than himself tries to open it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But it's too late: Gregor steps out from behind - A BOATHOUSE, and before Deirdre can even figure out what happened, Gregor has her in an arm lock, a gun to her head. His free hand sticks out and we see the Briefcase, which is still handcuffed to his wrist.</context>
      <utterance>Deirdre, wait up --</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gregor and Deirdre are poised at the edge of the lake. This Private Dock is made completely of stone, and the drop to the water is nearly five feet. Sam has reached a position where there is no right answer. Still, he points his gun at Gregor, who in turn shields himself with Deirdre's body.</context>
      <utterance>You might have made a good field agent you arrogant American prick, but you're not smart enough to go up against me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Put down your weapon and walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, shoot... Shoot and kill the bitch, I don't care.  And yet you don't shoot. Interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do it, Sam!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREGOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll kill me anway, Sam, shoot though me and kill this fucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEAMUS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE - Seamus is somehow still barely alive -- he's not long for this world, but the will for revenge has driven him this far.</context>
      <utterance>If you don't, I will...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam pulls Deirdre out of the water and then the two of them immediately turn and move towards Vincent, and as they do we start to PULL BACK on them, and now the SOUNDS of SIRENS can be heard, one, then two more, and then a symphony of noise. And we're STILL PULLING BACK ON - THE CHATEAU - Or what's left of it, because it's started to burn, and quickly the flames start to rise into the night, like something out of medieval times as we -</context>
      <utterance>Alright? It's bloody fucking freezing in here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to speak with that man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam reaches into his coat, and for a moment everybody thinks he's going for his gun, but instead he comes out with - A PIECE OF PAPER. He hands it to the Detective.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I can't allow that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Detective eyeballs the number suspiciously.</context>
      <utterance>Call that number and ask them what you should do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can see your friend, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The field dressing you put on saved his life.  Where di you learn to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor isn't entirely satisfied with this answer, but it's the only one she's going to get, because Sam moves past into -</context>
      <utterance>Here and there, I guess.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You son-of-a-bitch...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You speak French.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lies back on his pillow, pissed and yet amused.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Your field dressing saved his life." That's three I owe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't owe me a goddamned thing, Vincent, and you know it. You stepped in front of a bullet for me.  I owe you a heavy debt.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better get some sleep, alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me something first.  The package: what was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Nobody knows, except a bunch of people who are too dead to tell us. There's probably a couple of guys back at the Company who know, but I don't think they plan to tell me anytime soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gone. Destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam turns for the door but Vincent has one last thing to say.</context>
      <utterance>I guess that's for the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Same has to think about this for a second, and his answer reveals just how full circle he's come.</context>
      <utterance>Sam, when Gregor had Deirdre by the lake, you could have killed the two of them with one shot. You could have had the package, finished the job. But you didn't, you sacrificed the job to save her life. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And on that note Sam exits the room, leaving a bemused Vincent behind.</context>
      <utterance>It's what you would have done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A RIVERSIDE CAFE - Where Sam, Vincent and Deirdre are having morning coffee. A mostly-healed Vincent is smoking a cigarette, trying to get Sam to light up.</context>
      <utterance>Would you just smoke already...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just to keep me company, Sam -- I hate smoking alone.  How about you? I thought all you IRA types smoked.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only the stupid ones. Cigarettes kill more patriots than bullets.  Besides, I'm not IRA no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where do you go from here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I was thinking...Maybe the three of us might partner up -- guns for hire, that sort of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two of them turn to Sam, but he shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>I'm up for that...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me. You work too often with the same people and you become friends -- clouds your judgement.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEIRDRE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come off it, Sam -- if we weren't friends already we wouldn't be here now, would we?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sam can't help it -- he's interested.</context>
      <utterance>She's got a point.  Besides, I know of a job that's available.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much does it pay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOOM! The Punk pulls the trigger, a blast of fire as - Sam's gun is already out, TWO QUICK SHOTS squeezed off and - The Punk is capped twice in the head, dead, sailing away on the Ferry which never stops as - THE CAFE goes wild, CUSTOMERS running, screaming, WAITERS dropping their trays. But - Sam doesn't run, and neither does Vincent. Sam stands, stunned by what he sees - Deirdre lies on the ground, hit full on in the chest: she's dead. A BEAT OF PURE SILENCE - Broken by SIRENS in the distance, but quickly growing closer. Now - Vincent looks at Deirdre's corpse, then at Sam, who is unable to move. For maybe the first time in his professional career, Sam is staggered by the loss of a life. Vincent gently takes Sam's arm.</context>
      <utterance>This is for Seamus!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vincent literally drags Sam away and now the SIRENS have arrived, followed quickly by - THE GENDARMES, who come running into the Cafe but - It's empty except for Deirdre's body. Now -</context>
      <utterance>Let's go!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Sam isn't there to take the cigarette -- Vincent looks around, trying to see what happened to his friend, but the fog has covered any sign of Sam. Vincent stands there, stunned, alone, the cigarettes in an outstretched hand that slowly falls back to Vincent's side as he realizes that Sam has left him on purpose. Then - Vincent lights both cigarettes at the saem time and throws one of them over the stone wall - THE GLOWING CIGARETTE arcs through the air until it lands in the river where it extinguishes with a hiss.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor's orders...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Sam...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
