<movie id="468" title="Runaway Bride">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ike walks out of his apartment building talking on cell phone. IKE (cont'd) What do you think? Good idea, right? Boring, down to death, pointless -- It sucks. Ike yells at a CONSTRUCTION WORKER. IKE (cont'd) If you guys are here any longer, they're gonna make you sign a lease.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Fisher, pick up. I have some column ideas I want to bounce off you. Not there? Okay. Listen I'm thinking of writing about those mind-numbing informercials that are always on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSTRUCTION WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike turns and walks down the street, talking into cell phone.</context>
      <utterance>Your column should be so funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spots a RICH LADY with tons of diamonds getting out of a Limousine, talking to a CHAUFFEUR. He goes up to her. IKE (cont'd) Excuse me. I was thinking of doing an article on limousines. What would you say to people who never had a chance to drive in a limo? They walk up to her DOORMAN.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I was also thinking I might write about...</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike walks off. They stare at him as he goes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I don't know any people like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>T-SHIRT VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ike, when are you going to put me in an article?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike enters the bar. The Woman drops the shirt she was holding and walks off with her children. The T-shirt Vendor goes back to selling his shirts.</context>
      <utterance>When your t-shirts stop shrinking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Man continues speaking as Ike and the woman continue their conversation.</context>
      <utterance>I see photos of a lot of dead writers on these walls. Got any living ones? I have a story to tell that could win one of them a Pulitzer.  Picture this, if you will. A small town in Maryland, a sleepy little village, within that a hardware store...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's in store for us in tomorrow's column?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Woman gets up and begins throwing darts.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know yet. I'm kind of a last- minute man. Ideas don't flow until an hour or two before deadline.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is very interesting. You get your ideas for your column from life. You start up a conversation with a woman in a bar, attack her choice of reading material, try and get a rise out of her while you contemplate whether or not she's worth hitting on.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts throwing darts.</context>
      <utterance>No, I can't hit on you until I get an idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's flattering.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Woman goes to her bar stool, gathering her bag and leaves a tip for the Bartender.</context>
      <utterance>No, you don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I do understand. So my not responding to your baiting me will inspire one of those potential bitter diatribes you love to write about women and all the things we do to drive men crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whacks him with a newspaper, then shakes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>I don't write bitter diatribes about women... very often.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Woman leaves the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Only when the ideas aren't flowing, huh? Well, it was very nice to meet you, one-minute man.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's last minute man.  And it's the quality that counts.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, for a good looking man, you strike out a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings. Te Bartender answers it as Ike sits back on his bar stool. Ike grabs the woman's magazine that she left on the bar and starts glancing at it. The Man at the bar has heard the whole thing. MAN (cont'd) I said, I've seen much worse. Ike looks at the Man with reservation. The Man is George Swilling.</context>
      <utterance>I've seen much worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike gets up and moves to the dart board. He removes the darts. MAN (cont'd) I've witnessed far more treacherous and nefarious exits than that. At least she castigated you in private.</context>
      <utterance>The brush-off.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not as private as I thought. Ike turns slightly, giving the man his back. IKE  Kevin, you've got some napkins?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Writing or wiping?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bartender gives him cocktail napkins and a pen. Ike starts making notes. Ike looks up from his writing. The Man gets up and starts throwing darts.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a pen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, come on. They deserve it. They love you, they hate you, they're hot, they're cold, they're high, they're low...</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... They're up, they're down. It's really fun making this list with you, but I've got a column to go write.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ike.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike moves to the Bartender and pays him.</context>
      <utterance>But you don't have a really superb idea! Well, there's a girl from my hometown you could write about.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, we don't need any new ideas.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both Ike and Bartender turn and stare.</context>
      <utterance>She likes to dump grooms right at the altar. They call her "The Runaway Bride".</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike turns and heads for the door. The Man calls after him, getting up from his stool without stopping his enthusiastic story. MAN (cont'd) Adios. Plows down the aisle, knocking old ladies out of her way like the running of the bulls at Pamplona. And guess what?</context>
      <utterance>She performed the travesty seven or eight times. Right at the altar she turns around and runs like hell. Bolts.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I give up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike stops in his tracks. He turns back around in spite of himself.</context>
      <utterance>She has the next victim all lined up. She's twirling another body on the spit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imagine if you will, a small town in Maryland...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"But how can one blame me when every time I step out my front door I meet fresh proof that the female archetypes are alive and well? Te mother, the virgin, the whore, the crone; they're elbowing you in the subway, stealing your cabs, and overwhelming you with perfume in elevators."</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"But perhaps, in fairness to the fairer sex, I do need to broaden my horizon and add some new goddesses to the pantheon: I would like to nominate for deity..." Fisher hands a file to Elaine.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"... The cheerleader, the coed, and the man-eater, the last of which concerns me most today." Fisher leaves and we hold a USA Today sign.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"To be fair, the man-eater isn't exactly new. In Ancient Greece, this fearsome female was known as Erinys, the devouring death goddess. In India, she is Kali, who likes to devour her boyfriend Shiva's entrails while her yoni devour his -- dot dot dot, never mind. In Indonesia, the bloody-jawed man-eater is called Ragma..." Te Man sits at the bar near to the Bartender.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is known as Miss Maggie Carpenter</context>
      <utterance>You noticed these are all countries without cable.  "... And in Hale, Maryland where she helps run the family hardware store.</utterance>
   <speaker>..."</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>".... AKA, the Runaway Bride."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The older one, Mrs. Pressman, listens with a pained expression as the younger one, Peggy, continues to read the column aloud. Neither one can believe what they're reading.</context>
      <utterance>Holy moly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"What is unusual about Miss Carpenter is that she likes to dress her men up as grooms before she devours them. She has already disemboweled six in a row by leaving them at the altar."... I can't ready anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy and Mrs. Pressman step into a hardware store.</context>
      <utterance>"And her ritual feast continues as she prepares to make a sacrifice out of the seventh fiance. So all bets are on and we hope that this boomerang bride isn't honeymooning with Las Vegas odds makers because many predict that this girl is out of there before the race... before the rice hits the ground"  Holy moly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell Maggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you tell her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. You're her best friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, it's just possible that she hasn't read this yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the counter, they see a copy of USA Today opened to the article about Maggie. MRS. PRESSMAN (cont'd) ... Or not! We follow MAGGIE down the back stairs inside The Hale Hardware Store, the prettiest, most welcoming shop of its kind anywhere in small town USA. Somehow the place ha taken on the spirit of the owner's daughter; both stop and shop-girl radiate brightness, charm, and possibility. Maggie comes down steps with a faucet handle and goes to an elderly customer, MR. PAXTON.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe she hasn't read the paper...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we go! One antique hot water handle with the "HOT" still on it, guaranteed to fit any American Standard cast iron tub with a four-inch center made between 1924 and 1938. In other words, I think you're out of the doghouse with Mrs. Paxton.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. PAXTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallelujah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie rounds the bend, another customer, EARL, stands by the paint machine.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, Mr. Paxton, I'll put it on your account.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So -- Mag -- you've seen this, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I've seen it. And I have to say it's the rudest and most offensive... joke anybody's ever played on me! To their amazement, Maggie starts smiling. MAGGIE  You guys! How long did this take you? Maggie stays amused. MAGGIE  Where'd you get this done?  You creeps! I should disinvite you! And why did you say seven times? This is four.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie looks at the stricken face of her friends.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, Maggie, you told us to bachelorette jokes, so we didn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy looks like she is going to cry with sympathy for Maggie. Maggie is starting to feel uncomfortable. She looks down, dubiously, at the paper.</context>
      <utterance>Holy moly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up the paper and brushes it against her apron, leaving an INK SMEAR!! She nearly kneels over. MAGGIE (cont'd) (sitting) Bag. Peggy and Mrs. Pressman immediately spring to her side. They give her a bag to breathe in.</context>
      <utterance>Um, you know, now would be a good moment to tell me this is fake.  It won't be funny if you drag it out. Okay?  Okay, well... I mean, I can find out... Real newspapers smear. Phoney papers don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bag.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll put in a good word for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, don't mention my name in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A buzz.</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike goes into Ellie's office. Elaine picks up her phone.</context>
      <utterance>You can go in now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Anyway, I'm just dropping you big city folk this little note to say that I have thought of a ritual sacrifice that would satisfy my current appetite: Ike Graham's column on a platter. Yours truly, Maggie Carpenter. P.S. -- I have inclosed a list of the gross factual misrepresentations in your article. There are fifteen." Ike sits as Ellie puts the letter down and takes off her glasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fully. I like her. She has wit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I left four messages. You don't return my calls.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fisher gets and places a photo of the cat on a bookshelf on his way to the other side of the room.</context>
      <utterance>So? I never returned your calls, even when we were married. And what's Fisher doing here anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ellie asked me to come down to offer moral support.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when does Ellie need moral supp--</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- It's for you, Ike.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellie pushes USA Today lawyer's letter across the desk for him to read. Ike picks it up and skims the letter. His face is as impassive as stone.</context>
      <utterance>Journalism lesson number one. If you fabricate your facts, you get fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lesson number two. Never work for your former spouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not nothing to do with it. You cooked this story up and you know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't cook up a story. I had a source.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone reliable, I'm sure. A booze- hound in a bar?</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In vino veritas.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike gets up and stands near Ellie, making his point. IKE (cont'd) Besides, I'm a columnist. This is what columnists are supposed to do. This is what you like. We push, we stretch, we go out on a limo. That's what makes me good!</context>
      <utterance>Don't knock drunk guys in bars. Drunk guys in bars are good. It means they're not driving.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's what makes you unemployed.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike puts down the letter and puts his glasses back into his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>I merely write the stuff. You're the one that serves it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellie hands Ike Maggie's list.</context>
      <utterance>Not anymore. I have to draw the line.  She sent us this list. Our lawyers say it's actionable.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lawyers.  I don't know, Ellie -- Firing me is going to be very tough on you. It's going to be hard to get over. There will be therapy bills for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already made an appointment for later today.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? You want custody of my job? ... Why not just consider my wrist slapped and call me when you feel I've served my time?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fisher winces and looks away. Ike and Ellie look at each other for a sober moment. ELLIE (V.O.; cont'd) If you go quietly, I'll get you severance pay. Ellie fidgets with her toy rake, then Ike heads for the door. He laughs a little at the painful truth of her words and walks out. Ellie collapses back in her chair. Fisher goes to her and rubs her shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Ike. This is permanent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob test the weight of the backpack adding dehydrate food.</context>
      <utterance>She canned him, she canned him...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie puts the paper on the kitchen counter and starts to read aloud, paying no mind to Bob, who is sticking her arms through the straps of the backpack.</context>
      <utterance>Come here, Mag, and try this on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob continues to hold up the weight of the backpack as he straps it onto Maggie's shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Listen: "Dear Ms. Carpenter, I apologize to you for this unfortunate matter. Ike Graham's column will no longer be appearing in this paper. Best of luck in you upcoming marriage!"</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is the weight of the pack you're going to have to carry in the Himalayas. Tell me if it's too heavy. Bob lets go and Maggie FALLS BACKWARD, disappearing behind the counter, and hitting the floor, with a THUD. Bob looks down at her. Maggie's voice rises from the floor behind the counter. MAGGIE (o.s.) It's a little... It's a little heavy... Help me, baby. Bob has no answer. He reaches a hand down. He yelps as Maggie pulls him down on top of her, out of frame. We HEAR them giggle and kiss.</context>
      <utterance>That-a-girl! You sacked him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ike, I really liked the Runaway Bride piece, and since I do freelance stuff for G.Q., I'm in a different position now...</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop walking.</context>
      <utterance>What are you trying to say to me, Fish?</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vindication. How would you like to get some? A chance to prove that, though your facts weren't entirely straight, your theory was correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The real story on Miss Carpenter.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start walking again.</context>
      <utterance>All the gory details.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The anatomy of the black widow spider of Maryland.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wouldn't be a bad way to get you back into writing feature pieces again.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop at the coffee table and grab something to eat.</context>
      <utterance>This is good. It is a good story, Fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All true. All accurate.</context>
      <utterance>If she runs, then it's a cover story.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, you were right. I hated my column, but I can do this assignment.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you've got it. If you leave tomorrow for the hinterlands, you'll have plenty of time before her next wedding trot.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Paid vindication" That's what I call justice.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Justice, yes. Paid, I don't know. They like the idea, but my hands are tied with budget restraints.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks away.</context>
      <utterance>But I'll get my normal fee, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He follows him.</context>
      <utterance>You want me to do it on spec?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say "spec" like it's a dirty word. Nobody ever paid Shakespeare to write a play! Plato never got a book advance...</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ike's car drives into Hale, passing a billboard reading, "Welcome to Hale."</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah! I happen to know from reliable sources that Nietzche got expenses and a rental car. We hear Fisher laugh. IKE  I'm going to make this work, Fish. I'm going to do it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy rolls over in her chair, picks up her dog and rolls back to her station.</context>
      <utterance>Cindy, you better 86 Sprout. He seems to be enjoying the petroleum distillates.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it. Back to obedience school.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy sits in the chair. Maggie spins her around and around.</context>
      <utterance>Okay -- have a seat... gently, carefully.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a goddess!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't even need to change this gasket, just put in a little hydraulic fluid.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUST THEN. Ike enters the salon, taking off his sunglasses. Peggy hops off the chair.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it. When you talk like that, I get turned on and it frightens me.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello. I'm looking for Maggie Carpenter. There was a sign at the hardware store across the street...</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a little early in the game for Ike to be thrown off guard.</context>
      <utterance>Are you a reporter?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been our experience that anyone with some sort of gewgaw on his loafers ends up being another big city reporter wanting to interview Maggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About her upcoming wedding and all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike smiles down at his loafers and shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>No, about her getting that asshole from New York fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am just such a reporter. And you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy steps aside. Ike moves toward Cindy and Mrs. Pressman.</context>
      <utterance>Peggy Phleming. Not the ice skater.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Te ladies shake his hand and introduce themselves.</context>
      <utterance>And who are these lovely ladies?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cindy. Maggie's unmarried cousin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Pressman. No relation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking for Maggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie looks over from her sitting position on the floor. She gives Ike the once-over, focusing on the shoes.</context>
      <utterance>Yep. Maggie -- Someone to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reporter?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike crouches to see Maggie on the floor just as she rises to her feet. Ike straightens up. For a moment, he is thrown by her beauty and intelligent eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Yup!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's pretty much all been covered.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you have a different angle.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Originality is my speciality.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on -- Nobody interviews Maggie in here unless they're getting haircut.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's the boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, no. I just got one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir. I have an actual fact for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mrs. Pressman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's her fourth time to the altar, you know. Not seven like they said.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During the Ike/Mrs. Pressman exchange, Maggie looks at Ike. There's something familiar about him. She looks over at Peggy and beckons her to a copy of Ike's column affixed to a mirror. A goatee and horns, have been scrawled on Ike's byline picture. He's been "devilized". Peggy coughs as she recognizes Ike in the newspaper clipping.</context>
      <utterance>I know. Tell me something. Do you think she's going to make it all the way this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Pressman continues her story to Ike.</context>
      <utterance>She swallowed her gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure. Mr. Schullian runs the newsstand, he's our local bookie, you know, he's giving eight to one odds she won't. He says she's so famous now, maybe Vegas will give odds on her. I'm going to wait to hear what the pros say.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good fact. Well, you let me know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, instead of a haircut, how about a wash? You know, get all that city grit out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll answer my questions? Maggie nods affirmatively. IKE   Fine. You wash, I'll ask the questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike hands Peggy his jacket. A mystified Peggy leads Ike to the sink. While she does this...</context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike sits in the chair near the sink. Maggie shakes out a smock and puts it around Ike. MAGGIE (cont'd) So, what do you want to know? Ike leans and rests his head on the sink. Peggy bends over him and wets his hair. She grabs various hair coloring products.</context>
      <utterance>Have a seat. Peggy, why don't you give him the special treatment that strengthens the follicles.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting nervous?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike pulls the cloth down from over his face.</context>
      <utterance>Nervous? Not at all! No. I've never been more certain in my life. Except -- I am having all kinds of weird dreams.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weird dreams? You're going to tell me about them?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETE, wearing a hat, comes in the front door of the salon.</context>
      <utterance>In another one...</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike peeks out from under his towel as Maggie continues.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Pete, I'll be right with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike listens intently and stares steadily into her eyes. Peggy removes the towel. His hair is divided into equal parts and dyed orange and red. MAGGIE (cont'd) So what do you think? Ike stares back at her, the tickle of suspicion creeping up his spine.</context>
      <utterance>I'm inside the church. Everyone I know is there, only they're not really them. They're like Frankenstein monsters, but without the bolts coming out of their necks. It's all very "Night of the Living Dead". And here's the creepiest part -- I look down at my dress and it's red. I mean, I have no idea what it means. Red's not my color!</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you'd look good in red.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie swivels his chair so that Ike faces the mirror. Ike looks at his brightly colored hair.</context>
      <utterance>No, she's talking about your hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike stares at his hair in total confusion. With icy calm, Ike rises from his chair and primps the end of his hair as if giving it the finishing touches. Then he sees his defaced newspaper clipping and all becomes clear. He picks up the article and shows it to everyone. Ike does a slow burn.</context>
      <utterance>You're all ready for football season, Mr. Graham.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike turns and puts the clipping up on the mirror. IKE (cont'd) (to Peggy) My jacket, please. Peggy hands him his jacket. IKE (cont'd) (sarcastically) Thank you. Ike moves toward the door. He spots Pete. IKE (cont'd) (putting on jacket; to Pete) Excuse me, Pete, do you know a place that sells shampoo... Strong shampoo?</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I think I nailed the personality profile of the women of Hale.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc's Pharmacy. Third and Elm. Tell him Pete sent you. Want my hat?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike smiles at Maggie and exits.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He seems crabby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts on her sunglasses.</context>
      <utterance>If you're looking for Elm Street, it's that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks the other way.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops walking and turns to Ike.</context>
      <utterance>If you came down here in the pursuit of happiness, you might as well go back. Because you can't make me feel bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not here to make you feel bad. I'm here for vindication. In my heart...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike walks back to Maggie.</context>
      <utterance>You have one?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PASSERSBY stare at Ike's hair and giggle.</context>
      <utterance>I feel I'm right about you. You got me fired, lady. You destroyed my reputation and you screwed up my hair. You chew men up, spit them out and loved it. And I'm down here to satisfy myself on that point.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did something happen to make you care about reality?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Conviction. Conviction that I'm onto the truth. You're going to do the same thing to "poor bastard number four" that you did to the last three. You're going to run again. And I'm not leaving until you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to be very disappointed.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her for a beat, stung by her words.</context>
      <utterance>I'd love to stay and chat, but I've got to get back to work. I still have my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie walks away. Ike walks a few steps and stops at a KID on a bike.</context>
      <utterance>I have nothing to hide, Mr. Graham. Talk to whoever you want. You might actually stumble upon a fact or two.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kid agrees. Ike puts the hat on and starts to cross the street. An OLD WOMAN walks by and hits him with a newspaper. Ike is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, kid, I'll give you ten bucks for your hat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Te family dog, Skipper, sits near a ceramic dog table. Maggie smiles as she walks in the front door and puts down her tool box and bag.</context>
      <utterance>You know, when I only see one dog, I know I've had too much to drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie enters the parlor to see Ike smiling evilly from his seat on the couch. IKE (cont'd) (innocently) Hello, Maggie. I just came by to apologize to your family. (looks to Walter) When I'm wrong, I'm wrong. I pushed a story. I made a mistake.</context>
      <utterance>You'll never guess who came crawling into town with his tail between his legs. IKE  Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raises the bottle to Maggie.</context>
      <utterance>In other words -- he's only human. An he brought us a bottle of wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They made me put my hat back on.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. Scared the hell out of Skipper.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie stares at them both.</context>
      <utterance>You've got to be kidding me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie gives him a look that says, "You are not absolved." She smiles stiffly, looking back at Ike. She then sits on the arm of Bob's chair and puts her arm on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, you should have seen Skipper.  It wasn't that funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie takes the wine bottle from the table next to Walter. She snaps a look to Bob, who follows her.</context>
      <utterance>So, the forces of good and evil have already met.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll help you take into the kitchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We overhear them murmuring in annoyed tones about the wedding plans as they exit... Walter puts down his drink.</context>
      <utterance>Check on the crabs, Bob.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, I hope they don't have a fight out there. You don't think they'll call it off...?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, wedding cake freezes. This we know.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike notices that he's been sewn to the veil.</context>
      <utterance>You know, your daughter seems...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grandma cuts the thread and separates the veil from Ike's sleeve. IKE (cont'd) (continuing his thought) ... Like such a lovely girl. Walter points to a portrait painting on the wall.</context>
      <utterance>That's okay, Grandma.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like her mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, beautiful.  I just can't see her leaving multiple grooms in the dust like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, you can. She's has 'em all on tape.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has a tape?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad's fishing trip, Grandma's knee operation, Grandma's birthday...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walter cracks up.</context>
      <utterance>Gotta tell you this about my daughter. My daughter makes real good time, even in a long dress and heels. Maggie may not be Hale's longest running joke, but she certainly is the fastest.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON: A tape. It reads: "Maggie I, II, III." Ike's interest is more than piqued. Ike picks it up. They get up and go to the dining room.</context>
      <utterance>Ha ha.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike's hammer flies out of his hand. He goes to pick it up.</context>
      <utterance>This is good, Dad, don't leave anything out.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I've come to see it as a bonus, really, that we've been able to plan, and pay for, so many weddings.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walter reacts.</context>
      <utterance>Not this one. This one's on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fair.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Despite what you think, I don't do it on purpose. And I have no intention of doing it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike raises his eyebrows in question. Bob explains. BOB (cont'd) Sports psychology. It was my major in college.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, Maggie. Just keep your eye on the ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the town's unofficial fitness trainer. Big advocate of the mind and body combining for success. You could say or you can quote me, I'm a glass half full king of guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everest. Is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twice...</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Without oxygen...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob and Maggie kiss Ike two little love-birds. BOB (cont'd) I'm taking her trekking on Annapurna on our honeymoon. Ike is highly amused.</context>
      <utterance>My girl likes to brag about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How romantic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walter cracks up, Maggie shoots Ike a look. He smiles back.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing like sharing your nuptial bed with two Sherpas and a yak.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This one's very popular, but oh, you've used this one before... Brian. But I like the white dinner jacket.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he's no good. Too blond.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll go with total traditional.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, Ike comes up behind her as she discards another groom.</context>
      <utterance>Too dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he's got the Bobster's eyes. Maggie cringes at the sound of Ike's voice. IKE  No -- the Bobster's eyes are closer set. She ignores him and continues her search. IKE   Could I have two coffees, please? And what is that wonderful smell?  I'll have two of those delicious looking cinnamon rolls.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Trout steps away to get his order. Ike moves to the other side of Maggie and picks up the bride and groom figure.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.  Here, Maggie. I think this makes the best you.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes the bride figure repeatedly knock the groom figure in the head and run away screaming. IKE (cont'd) Bam, bam, bam, bam, bam! Oh, help me! Help me! Yup! That's her all right. Mrs. Trout just about bursts a gut laughing. Maggie takes the bride from Ike coldly.</context>
      <utterance>Let's see... Excuse me, isn't that cute? Ahh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike turns and goes to her.</context>
      <utterance>You must be that Mr. Graham fellow.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am. And who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betty Trout. Five dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Betty. I take it you're going to be making the wedding cake and they say you're throwing --</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts picking lint off his sleeve and buttons his cuff.</context>
      <utterance>-- The luau for Maggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grandma made me the cutest outfit. I can't wait to show it to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pre-wedding luau?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Trout turns and grabs Ike's bag containing two coffees.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. My husband and I love luaus. It'll be fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Trout beams. Maggie understands his answer a little better. Mrs. Trout hands Ike his items and he pays.</context>
      <utterance>Fun? Fun isn't the word.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're still in town, you should stop by.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm sure he doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie steps over, carrying her bride and groom figure choices.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I would love to come.  Thank you. Thank you so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to leave with his bag. Mrs. Trout stops him.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your two cinnamon rolls.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Bye, Betty. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie hands Mrs. Trout her bride and broom figures. Maggie looks at Mrs. Trout, suddenly nervous. She dashes out. Mrs. Trout imitates Ike bamming the bride and groom, laughing.</context>
      <utterance>He's not a nice person.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I love you.</context>
      <utterance>Maggie, don't marry Coach! Marry me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dennis runs on as Maggie continues toward her goal: Bob and Ike, standing together on the other side of the field.</context>
      <utterance>You're jail bait, Dennis. Go away. Run your laps. Go. Go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike smiles broadly atop of the sled as he sees Maggie approaching, looking mighty peeved. He nudges Bob and points to Maggie. Bob lights up at the sight of her. BOB (cont'd) Good job, gentlemen... Special teams. The football players move away from the sled. Bob moves to Maggie, leaves Ike alone. BOB (cont'd) (to Maggie) Hey, honey! Bob kisses and embraces Maggie. She doesn't see Ike immediately, then:</context>
      <utterance>Drive! Drive! From your hips, get low, get low, get low. Next!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is he up to now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ike just came by to check out the team.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike grins and shows Maggie the notes in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>And talk about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob -- are you making friends with this man?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob grabs Maggie around the waist and smooches her adoringly. Maggie scowls at Ike. He nods, all charm.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just bragging about how great you are. I'm the luckiest man alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike leaves. Bob calls after him.</context>
      <utterance>Well -- I've got to get moving -- lot of work to do today! I'll see you two love-birds later.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you at the wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie is aghast. She stares at Bob. Ike joins in behind a line of peppy cheerleaders.</context>
      <utterance>You bet ya, Coach.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the wedding? You invite him? Bob, don't you realize he's writing another article about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I do. But the bet defense is a good offense, right? You're not going to let your opponent throw you off your game.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't understand this guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him come to the wedding. You're not running, right? Say it. "I'm not..."</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not running.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if you're not running and Ike Graham is there to see it, then any article he writes has got to have a happy ending, right? All we're doing is turning lemon into lemonade.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob gives Maggie a big hug.</context>
      <utterance>I've got news for you. No amount of sugar and water is going to turn like Graham into something you want to take on a picnic.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob blows his whistle, then puts Maggie on the football sled. BOB (cont'd) I want you boys to take my princess on the ride of her life... Honey, tell 'em where you parked your car. Maggie screams as the boys push her down the football field.</context>
      <utterance>Where's that homemade sunshine?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of an impure nature?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- like -- I'm having a problem with that whole turn-the-other-cheek concept. I want revenge. I want to destroy this guy's life, career, everything. On the sin scale, how big is that? I mean, can I "Hail Mary" my way out of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Child, any sin in one's heart is...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name's Maggie. It wasn't this side of ten years ago that you had your tongue down my throat. So don't call me "child", Brian. It annoys me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST/    BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian closes the confessional window and exits</context>
      <utterance>Now don't get upset.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian leans into her confessional. She steps out to join him.</context>
      <utterance>Brian, open up. Don't ignore me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's a nice looking and gentle man. They regard each other for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>You're not even Catholic, Maggie -- you really shouldn't come to confession.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian moves away. Maggie follows and sits in a nearby pew.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I'm just so stressed out about that slime-ball reporter being in town. I jus had to come warn you he might show up here and start asking you all kinds of ridiculous questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, he only asked me one ridiculous question. The rest weren't so bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You talked to him! Did you tell him we dated before you were a priest?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes, I'm sure I only did you good, Maggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A woman, MRS. MURPHY, rushes in.</context>
      <utterance>What did he ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, am I too late?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman goes into the confessional booth to wait.</context>
      <utterance>It won't take long. Jus two venials.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only respectful things. What did we have in common back then... What kind of music did you like... Did you ruin my life when you left me standing at the altar...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could I be angry at you when clearly what has happened to me is as God intended?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good one! Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian sits next to Maggie.</context>
      <utterance>It happens to be how I feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God... Of course. I'm sorry -- I mean, I'm...  Brian -- I've got to go. The man's a lunatic, but I know exactly where he's going next.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to rush out, then stops herself.</context>
      <utterance>God bless you, Maggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves to the confessional, knocks, then speaks to Mrs. Murphy. MAGGIE (cont'd) Excuse me, sorry, forgot my purse. Good luck. Maggie closes the booth curtain and turns to Brian. MAGGIE (cont'd) Wait -- what was the ridiculous question he asked? Brian smiles mischievously.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, wait, my purse.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wanted to know how you used to like your eggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to go, then stops in her tracks as she hears:</context>
      <utterance>Weird. Like after all those years you would remem--</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie looks at Brian. Suddenly, she remembers too.</context>
      <utterance>-- Scrambled, with salt, pepper and dill. Same as me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really sorry that I hurt you, Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm happy here, where I'm supposed to be. But if you ever become a Catholic, may I ask you a favor, Maggie?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could your confess to Father Patrick from now on?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she scampers out. Brian goes back into the confessional.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CRASH, coming from the nearby back room, we hear loud muttering in Spanish, then out stumbles GILL CHAVEZ, 34, wearing a grease- stained Grateful Dead tie-dyed T-shirt. He grins triumphantly, worshipfully cradling a CASSETTE TAPE in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Gill? Lydia? Gill?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie regards her former fiance with patient warmth.</context>
      <utterance>Hey -- I found it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gill looks up and gives Maggie a fond, hazy smile.</context>
      <utterance>Found what?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out the cassette from its case. It's broken. The tape is dangling from the cassette. GILL (cont'd) (disappointed) Oh, I'll play it for you. Gill picks up an electric GUITAR and starts to play.</context>
      <utterance>Mags! Hey, look -- The tape from the Radio City Music Hall concert -- Remember that night I as trying to get Jerry to let me sit in on "Ripple"?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the hydraulic lift slows, the car is lowered, revealing Ike sitting in the driver's seat. He has been enjoying the photograph he's holding.</context>
      <utterance>We went to San Francisco twice. Remember one time we had a flat tire... Which picture?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie swipes for the photo, but Ike is faster at pulling it away.</context>
      <utterance>Imagine! Maggie Carpenter topless in a public arena.  And I see there was a chill in the air.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me that!</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gill takes off his guitar and sets it down.</context>
      <utterance>But the most interesting thing here is that I don't see the rose tattoo that I've heard about on your back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ike bet me fifty bucks you don't still have it, Mags. I said "You're on, man! Maggie loved that thing!" And I could really use fifty bucks. Maggie is conspicuously silent. GILL   Mags?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie seethes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna show you guys anything. I am a soon-to-be-married woman. Now give me that photograph.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to grab the photo again. Ike pulls it away.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, I would love to give this to you. Just give us one quick gander at that rose, and, I'll gladly hand it over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie quickly turns around and pulls down the back of her shirt, revealing the top of her back and a pristine expanse of skin. No tattoo. MAGGIE (cont'd) (turning back around) Satisfied?</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gill is still trying to grasp the meaning of this.</context>
      <utterance>Completely.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maggie? You got it removed?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gill, I'll go ya double or nothing if was a stick-on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maggie?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There it is on Gill's chest: the rose tattoo. Maggie sighs, pained. Gill shows it to Ike. Ike looks at the tattoo. He shakes his head at Maggie.</context>
      <utterance>Look.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, look, man. I think the man is heartbroken.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie moves the lever on the wall again, sending Ike back up to the ceiling in the car. She grabs the photo from Ike and exits.</context>
      <utterance>He is not!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hydraulic lift stops moving. Ike leans out.</context>
      <utterance>I think I am. Gill grabs his guitar and sits. GILL  Hey, Ike, what would Jerry do?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike sings and taps along in tempo on the side of the car as Gill sings and plays "Ripple".</context>
      <utterance>Jerry. He'd play. He'd play... Jerry would play his heart out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, he's on base. Can we talk about my life now? -- Ike's going to turn that tattoo stuff into a big deal -- that I was never serious about Gill, blah blah. He's totally out to get me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what reason? Some personal satisfaction?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what he says, but if he thinks that I don't realize he's writing another article, then he's an idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's probably because you got him fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya think?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that he doesn't deserve to get fired... Look! Cory's going for second!... Sneaky!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There he is. Snoop Doggy-Dogg.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over there. Ten o'clock. He's talking to our little Dennis. Dennis will turn into one of those "sources say" things.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike finds Maggie in the crowd and leaves Dennis.</context>
      <utterance>He looks better with that stuff out of his hair. He's an attractive man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Peggy can protest, Maggie climbs down off the bleachers and goes and stands near the dugout near the rest of Cory's team.</context>
      <utterance>I'd say you've been in the sun too long. You handle him, okay? I could use five minutes off from that creep.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike comes up to Peggy.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, that's fine. I can do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Peggy Phleming, "not the ice-skater". Ike indicates the seat next to Peggy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike sits down comfortably.</context>
      <utterance>That's Maggie's seat...</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts drinking it. ON THE FIELD, Cory is getting ready to steal third. IKE (cont'd) That your husband out there? Cory Phleming, a local radio announcer.</context>
      <utterance>... And this is Maggie's beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you listened to his morning show, "Wake up with ballplayer"?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet. I had a phlemless morning. I hear he's a pretty good ballplayer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This game is pretty important to him. He made all-stars in high school, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy takes a small sip off her soda.</context>
      <utterance>That must have made you proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cory dives in for third and makes it. The crowd goes wild. Peggy yells and jumps in. PEGGY (cont'd) Good job, honey! But Maggie's whoop sails out above it all. Cory waves. But not at Peggy. He directs his delight at Maggie, who jumps up and down by the dugout. Ike looks between Cory, Maggie and finally, Peggy. Peggy jerks her waving hand back down to her side and sits down. Ike pretends not to have noticed. The two watch as Maggie and Cory smile at each other.</context>
      <utterance>He was going with Maggie back then.  He was never one of her... I mean, they were never going to get... They just dated for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nice that they're still friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What did you do to her?</context>
      <utterance>You've been here for three minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike does an on-the-button imitation of Maggie jumping excitedly at Cory. Now Maggie sees what he's getting at.</context>
      <utterance>You can turn that finger around.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You misinterpret everything. We've all been friends our whole lives. But that's the types of relationship you wouldn't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike walks away. Alone, Maggie tries to seem enthused.</context>
      <utterance>Obviously, I'm not the only one who doesn't understand it. The USS Maggie leaves quite a wake... Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I cheer good. What is he, a cheer critic?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee, hey, wake up. Give me the key to the reporter's room. I want to snoop around.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Second floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie moves up the stairs towards Ike's room.</context>
      <utterance>Don't take anything big.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We HEAR Ike slamming his body against the bathroom door. As Ike breaks in, he runs to the window and yells after her.</context>
      <utterance>I want to have a very serious discussion with you as to why you're such a pain in the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She disappears around the ledge of the building and runs off. Ike's neighbor, Harvey, sits reading near his window.</context>
      <utterance>You do that. And remind him he's bringing the wine to the luau. Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy stops in her track. Maggie is sitting curled up in a salon chair. She looks like she hasn't slept.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think I flirt with Cory?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning to you, too. You look good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Do you think I flirt with Cory?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie looks miserable.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy moves to the salon mirror near Maggie with her cup of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>I don't mean it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I think sometimes you just sort of spaz-out with random excess flirtation energy and it just lands on anything male that moves.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy pours her coffee out of its Styrofoam cup into a ceramic mug.</context>
      <utterance>On anything male that moves? As opposed to anything male that doesn't move?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like certain kinds of coral. Peggy sits in the salon chair next to Maggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to kill myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you think I'm all like... "Hey man, check me out".</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't think you're like, "I'm charming and mysterious in a way that even I don't understand and something about me is crying out for protection from a big man like you". Very hard to compete with. Especially to us married women who have lost our mystery.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're very mysterious!</context>
      <utterance>But you haven't lost your mystery!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm weird. Weird and mysterious are two different things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You're quirky. Quirky and weird are two different things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie looks ready to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Peggy, there's distinct possibility that I might be profoundly and irreversibly screwed up. Despite that, I love you and I can promise that I will no longer flirt with Cory, and I beg your forgiveness.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not worried about you and Cory or Cory and me or even that you're irreversibly screwed up. But, Maggie, you've been like this since we were kids. And I think now that you are aware of it and that it hurts people's feelings, maybe it's time to move on with your life and commit to someone of your own, like Bob, if he's the one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're right.  Is there anything I can do to make it up to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something that brings warmth to my heart.  Duckbill platypus.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie makes her funny face. Peggy doesn't laugh.</context>
      <utterance>It's only funny at Camp Birchwood at three in the morning at a tick hunt. It's not anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maybe we both grew up.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. It's not funny now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Will you fix my hair?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie smiles cheerfully at Ike from the foot of the bed. He narrows his eyes at her.</context>
      <utterance>Freeze. Hold on to those covers -- I didn't come here to see Ike Junior.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I take it the desk clerk is one of your many admirers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike notices Maggie is holding two coffees.</context>
      <utterance>How do I do it? I'm not that beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie hands it to him.</context>
      <utterance>Coffee. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You must be very proud.</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome. Your notes made interesting bedtime reading -- if you like trashy fiction. Your observations are distorted, ungrounded an incomplete.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike puts a shirt on as Maggie speaks.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not a boastful man. What's your point?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My point is that one again, you're getting it all wrong. That won't improve your reputation any, and it's not very flattering to me either. So, I'm going to give you a chance to write the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie turns away from him as he dresses.</context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike clears his throat as he stands putting his pants on. MAGGIE (cont'd) I want a big wedding and a killer dress and for a grand I will answer all your questions and let you follow me around. Ike takes his coffee with him as he picks up his glasses, puts them on and crosses to the window.</context>
      <utterance>I've decided to cooperate and let you interview me.  For a thousand bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My magazine doesn't pay because for stories. It's not what you call ethical.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No credit cards.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, but making up the facts as you go along is ethical? Actually, I meant you. You probably got severance or expenses or both. I'll take your check.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why should I pay you dollar one?</context>
      <utterance>You've seen the post-its. I've already got more juicy material than I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike knows she's right.</context>
      <utterance>Because I think you're writing on spec and with a first person interview, you might actually sell that thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven-fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six-fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scowling, he writes out the check and hands it to her. Maggie looks at it and smile sweetly.</context>
      <utterance>Done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Put your finger in.</context>
      <utterance>It's a birthday present for my cousin.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his finger in the wrong hole of the machine.</context>
      <utterance>Cindy the manicurist.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his finger in the correct hole. She turns it on. The brushes rotate.</context>
      <utterance>No, the other one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it. This whole thing is pretty incredible.  I think you could probably sell this lamp idea in New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe someday.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You afraid to try?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not afraid. Just... Maybe someday.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm impressed. Absolutely incredible.  I didn't expect pink and lacy, but this isn't exactly a woman's room.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What an incredible chauvinistic observation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie hands Ike another ring. This one is in the shape of a Grateful Dead rose. MAGGIE (cont'd) Gill. Of course. He proposed at the tie-dye t-shirt stand at a Dead concert. It was very sweet until he hallucinated that the drum set was a blood-sucking space alien.</context>
      <utterance>That's Brian's. He took me ut canoeing on the lake and gave me the ring in a velvet box. Ike snores. Maggie hits him. MAGGIE   It was classic.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always a mood killer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie hands Ike a third ring. It's in the shape of a butterfly and studded with multi-color gems. MAGGIE (cont'd) George. He proposed at a butterfly farm in St. Thomas. The ring was inside a cocoon.</context>
      <utterance>Still sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a little "Silence of the Lambs" for me. I can't believe you waited for the wedding to run.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Maggie shows Ike the ring on her hand. It's a gold " 1" with a diamond set into the number. MAGGIE (cont'd) And here we are at Bob. He proposed during the seventh inning stretch... Ike touches her hand to examine the ring more closely. Her surprise at his touch shows on her face as she finishes her sentence. MAGGIE (cont'd) ... At an Oriole's game. She takes her hand down. Ike steps away.</context>
      <utterance>He's an entomologist! I thought it was very unique.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike picks up his cup of cappuccino and moves behind the couch.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. Don't tell me. The scoreboard lit up with "Mary me, Maggie."</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was one of the most wonderful moments of my life. Cal Ripken even applauded.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Highly suspect.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? It was incredibly romantic!</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie stares at Ike for a beat. His words have taken a little bit of her breath away. She covers.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's just me, but -- if you got to dress it up, it doesn't ring true. Ike moves back to the couch. IKE  I think the most anybody can honestly say is, "Look..."  "I guarantee that we'll have tough times. I guarantee that at some point one or both of us will want to get out of this thing. But I also guarantee that if I don't ask you to be mine, I'll regret it for the rest of my life. Because I know in my heart -- you're the only one for me"</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves from the fireplace to a chair and sits. MAGGIE (cont'd) I'd like it better on a scoreboard. (lightly) Is that how you proposed when you asked your wife to marry you? Ike is taken aback. MAGGIE (cont'd) Don't look so surprised, you've got divorce written all over you.</context>
      <utterance>I like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a work in progress.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? Is that what you said to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I think I said something eloquent like, "So, uh -- maybe we should, ya know. What do you think?"</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike takes a swallow of cappuccino.</context>
      <utterance>Now that's romantic. A proposal like that and you didn't find eternal bliss? What went wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike is restless. He stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should ask her some time. Ever thought of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike puts down his cup of coffee, gets his tape recorder and sits close to Maggie.</context>
      <utterance>Call me crazy, but I believe that check I gave you entitles me to ask the questions for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie move to TV. She picks up Ike's stolen post-it notes and her wedding video on top of the TV, and goes to the front door. MAGGIE (cont'd) I'll just need one more day to make sure your check clears.</context>
      <utterance>Fair enough.  Actually...</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even with everything that's happened I've still never been married and I still deserve a beautiful dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie gives Ike a smile that lights up the sky. They go inside.</context>
      <utterance>Agreed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>POLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll be the prettiest little flower girl in your daughter's wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flower girl sees Maggie and runs and hides behind Polly.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Whittenmeyer. Hi, Polly!</utterance>
   <speaker>POLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Maggie. You'll have to excuse her, Maggie. Some of the children are afraid of you since you dragged that little boy up the aisle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Whittenmeyer comes forward to greet Maggie.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't drag.  He tripped on his shoelaces.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WHITTENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie leads her to the front window.</context>
      <utterance>You've come for your dress. Good! I'll get it from the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WHITTENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Polly, take Leslie into change.  But the one you have on hold is lovely.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. But I've changed my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WHITTENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie is keenly aware of Ike listening in.</context>
      <utterance>It's one thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have one thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this dress for sale?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WHITTENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike watches with regret as Maggie's child-like enthusiasm drains away, her happy mood crushed by the tactless assault of the shop owner. He's starting to see that it's no always easy being Maggie. There's a tremor in her voice.</context>
      <utterance>It just seems like an awful lot of money to spend on one of your dresses, Maggie... You only wear them for about ten minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike calls out to Mrs. Whittenmeyer.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's a good point.  The other dress is nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Whittenmeyer. May I talk to you for a second? She walks over to him. IKE  I don't know much about this kind of thing. I'm from out of town. You're a salesperson, right? You're here to sell wedding dresses.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WHITTENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I've been here for thirty years.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wants that one.</context>
      <utterance>Perfect. Because Miss Carpenter is here to buy one. But not just any one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WHITTENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike goes over and takes the mannequin out of the window. Mrs. Whittenmeyer catches the wig as he puts the mannequin under his arm. IKE (cont'd) Look, Aunt Bea, we're buying this beautiful dress and anything else she wants or I'm coming back here with a squirt gun filled with India ink. Mrs. Whittenmeyer wilts under Ike's fierce gaze. She turns to Maggie.</context>
      <utterance>It's a thousand dollars!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WHITTENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will he really do that? Maggie gives her a look. MR. WHITTENMEYER   Well, why don't you pick out some accessories while I get this ready, dear. Polly, will you come help me, please? Polly comes to help carry the mannequin away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>POLLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. WHITTENMEYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie looks gratefully at Ike.</context>
      <utterance>Shhhh! The man has ink!</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tough to spend money in this town.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look... uh... You look fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's better than fine.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. The newspaper's upside down.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glows. Then the moment between them is broken as she suddenly remembers something and grabs the veil off her head.</context>
      <utterance>Bob will be very happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob! I almost forgot! I have to meet Bob!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Pressman, I think we're ready to order.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're out the special because somebody...  ... didn't order enough sausage.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike looks at Maggie. He'd bet a thousand bucks on what she'd say next.</context>
      <utterance>Let me have the garden omelette. Egg whites only.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that? I can't order my eggs without sarcasm?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Bob has been talking, Ike has been watching Maggie's face. The joy seems to have drained out of her.</context>
      <utterance>Neutral corners you two. You're on the same team now. Any more fighting and it's fifteen minutes in the penalty box.  Maggie's the nicest person you'll ever meet. But she's always focusing out there. She's got to start focusing more in here.  That's why she's had some -- whatever you want to call it -- problems in the past.  That's what we're working on -- focus. Right, Maggie? Focus on Maggie. Focus on Bob.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lead Maggie through a visualization exercise. All the sports shrinks use this head stuff. Visualize the end zone, if you catch my drift. Bob takes out a notepad and hands it to Maggie. BOB  Here's today's mantra: "It's an open field to Big Bob."</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me. When you get to the altar, will you spike the bouquet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, there's no... Before Maggie can finish, Ike intercepts her.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm off. A reporter's work is never done.  Mrs. Pressman, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tootaloo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>GRANDMA JULIA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We hear Grandma as through the hotel doors, we see Maggie exit the diner. She gets a bag from inside the cab of her truck and comes inside the hotel where she finds Ike talking to Grandma, who is having tea with her friend, NETTA.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to explain about the weddings. There are reasons why they didn't come off. Three weddings, no "I do's". You can't believe how much cake we were left with. I should weigh three hundred pounds. I don't think her father minded spending so much money on booze that nobody drank.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ike... Hi, Grandma.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gram here was going to give me the skinny on why you run from marital bliss.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike winces.</context>
      <utterance>Right, cover your ears, Netta. It's not that she's afraid of the wedding, she's afraid of the wedding night. Innocent girls are terrified of "the one-eyed snake".  Why, when I was a virgin bride, I took a knitting needle with me into the bed...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, Grandma, I charmed the one- eyed snake awhile ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, I forgot. I'll tell you one thing, your grandpa didn't forget that wedding night.  You can take your hands off your ears, Netta. Your tea's getting cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie moves toward door.</context>
      <utterance>Can you excuse us a minute?  May I have a word with you, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps over to Maggie in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Bye, Netta... Bye, Grandam.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie hands Ike a 30-year-old LP: Miles Davis' "Kind of Blue."</context>
      <utterance>I found this and didn't know if it was something interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God -- It's Miles Davis. This is "King of Blue"! This is the original recording. Hard to find in good condition. Where did you find this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was in the attic. It was jus sitting there gathering dust.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's valuable. Hang onto it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps outside, leaving Ike with the record.</context>
      <utterance>No. You take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm... Figuring out what kind of music I like and then finding me a rare album. You're not trying to soften me up, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and walks back to the diner where Mrs. Pressman is outside watering plants. Ike looks after Maggie and then back down at the record in his hand. Somehow it makes him sad.</context>
      <utterance>No -- I'm cleaning an attic. I wouldn't attempt the impossible.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Maggie helps the man get up, we see that it's Walter, Maggie's father -- dead drunk.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stumble and lurch, exiting the bar toward Maggie's car.</context>
      <utterance>I haven't had any fun since you got your driver's license...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steady.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not exactly having fun, either...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good boy, Port Hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Skipper, Dad... Steady.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>See you later, Mr. Travis. (then to Maggie) That guy has a problem... Maggie, you can run everyone's life but your own. Maggie's having trouble keeping him steady as she opens the car door. Ike is there in a flash to help her pull Walter into the car. WALTER (cont'd) Good daughters let their fathers pass out. Walter passes out on the front seat.</context>
      <utterance>I changed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ike... Please don't write anything about this --</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie looks at him with real gratitude. She swings the car door shut.</context>
      <utterance>No. Forget about it. Don't even think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch your leg, Dad.  I'm so tired of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you let him sleep it off in the trunk. I'll take you for a ride. Then we'll come back for him.  Keep an eye on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm too loaded.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie thinks about this for a moment. She takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>I was talking to the dog.  All right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... I'll just grab my jacket.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your filter's clogged. This takes unleaded.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you fix it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First I have to find some tools. I need a half and a nine-six-tenth.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie slams the food closed.</context>
      <utterance>Wrenches. My dad's gonna love that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kind of isolated.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An uncomfortable silent pause. Ike breaks the moment.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's kind of nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike stares off down the road. Maggie indicates a building in the distance, then turns off the car lights.</context>
      <utterance>There's one thing we New Yorkers know how to do is hail a cab. If there's no cab, we walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie points diagonally across the field to where a gas station sign glows and the lights from the outer house twinkle. He smiles and follows her into the field. MAGGIE (cont'd) Be careful of snakes.</context>
      <utterance>I can get some tools over there.... and save the battery... There's one thing we country girls know how to do is cut across a field. It's quicker.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps carefully into the field, then hops gingerly toward Maggie.</context>
      <utterance>Snakes? Are you serious? I don't like snakes. I've never even seen a snake.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOMENTS LATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maggie leads Ike through a cornfield.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike chooses his words carefully.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think there's only one right person for everybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But I think attraction is too often mistaken for rightness. Attraction is very misleading. And if it's mutual, it's well, terribly distracting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike nods as they come to a wooden fence. She puts her hand on his shoulder. Ike puts his hands around her waits to give her a boost over the top. We see the flicker of misunderstanding cross Maggie's face at the initial contact. Neither of them moves -- forward or back, but the electricity is obvious. ANGLE ON: Ike. His conflicted feelings are apparent. With difficulty, Maggie straightens up and they both quickly remove their hands. MAGGIE (cont'd) (lightly) I suddenly forgot how to climb a fence. They look at each other for a moment, then:</context>
      <utterance>Yes it is. And it doesn't mean anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE AND IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She climbs over the fence on her own and Ike follows. They see an old guy, LIONEL, whittling on a porch. MAGGIE (cont'd) Lionel, can I borrow some tools?</context>
      <utterance>"Tools".</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we need a half and nine- sixteenths.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gonna bust out of another wedding?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure well known around here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, well, my theory was that she may be running because she gets attention... Negative attention is attention. Like when women whack you on the street because of your column, that's negative attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is about her negative attention, not mine. Did you get the reimbursement for the dress yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm paying for the dress. Do you think she's still gonna run?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ellie enters the kitchen, hears the question and shakes her head to herself. If only these boys would give it up.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll come by and tell you all about it.</context>
      <utterance>Look -- I'll be in there later today.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're coming here?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then come for dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, we'll order out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ike hangs up and watches more of the George Swilling wedding video.</context>
      <utterance>Order out like a Philistine, when you got the Galloping Gourmet here?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get this man a Kamikaze.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Splendid dissection of Maggie Carpenter, very professional job. Ike sits and leans over to George.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could have told me you were fiance number three.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And end up in the papers? I've been humiliated enough already to last a lifetime, thank you. I'm sorry she got you canned.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a cacophony of contradictions.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm writing another article on the cacophony.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like a moth to a flame.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, can't stay away from her, can you?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess you'd know about that. You're an entomologist, right? How's business?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad. I was traveling around studying the reproductive and migratory patterns of locusts when Maggie met me.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neuter a locust, feed the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike wipes the smirk off his face. Like Maggie's other men, this guy has a worthy accomplishment under his belt. GEORGE (cont'd) You know Maggie was the only girl I ever met who would hold my tarantula. On the first date. IKE (cont'd) So, tell me, George, why do you think she ran?</context>
      <utterance>Not the world. Just Africa and China.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same as you said. What did you call her? A "man-eater", "a devouring death goddess."</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think that's why she ran.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike sips his drink before answering.</context>
      <utterance>Why do YOU think she ran?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I'm working on it. I was on the wrong track.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you defending her?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I call it like I see it. I'm a journalist. I'm a truth teller.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unbelievable, she got to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>GORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George heads out.</context>
      <utterance>Join the club.  Here, you need this more than me.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As George pauses in the doorway, Ike holds up his tape recorder. IKE (cont'd) What kind of eggs did she like?</context>
      <utterance>I'm writing an article, I'm getting paid to do this, it's going to be a cover story, it's going to be published ... The facts will be read someday.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George exits.</context>
      <utterance>Poached, just like me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Overpriced nice apartment and Chinese takeout. That's New York living.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Just call me when you have it.  Ike, how is the story coming? Is she a man-eater?</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or a vegetarian?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nice guys, but he just out of prison.</context>
      <utterance>Or does she pick "NGB'S" -- "Nice Guys, But..." Nice guys, but I'm cheap. Nice guys, but he lives with his mom...</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... They're interesting guys. Each one of these guys has something going for him. I mean, one's been up Everest. Another's become a priest. One's a pretty good guitar player. And this guy today tried to end world hunger, if you can believe that...</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, Ike. Getting a complex, buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fisher, let him talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But one of those guys -- not one of them -- knew her at all. Each one was convinced that she was perfect for them, but they didn't see her. And she never showed up so they couldn't see her. It's a very symbolic thing happening. She becomes what she thinks they wanted to be. Fisher doesn't like the sound of this. He glances at Ellie, who is looking very interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She joins Ike at the piano. Ike gets serious.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... Oh, Jay... Okay... Bye.  Fisher, don't forget the fortune cookies.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what I did to you? Is that what happened? Did I just not see you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hugs her.</context>
      <utterance>No. No, you didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well -- I'm sorry, I'm really sorry, Ellie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellie blinks back sentimental tears.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, too.  Wow. That only took us between years to say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dennis poses with Maggie. Cory poses with Bob. Mrs. Trout runs out of film and goes to get more, leaving Peggy and Maggie alone. Peggy whispers to Maggie.</context>
      <utterance>Pictures of the King and Queen.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lighten up, wahine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lighten up, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This party is for you and Bob. Get your mind off the reporter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't seen him in twenty-four hours. It just gives me the creeps a little bit. I'd feel better if I knew where he was.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: Ike just entering the party. At least he tried. He's got a tropical sheet wrapped around his pants and shirt. He walks to the bar and is greeted warmly by Lee. Maggie gets very flustered. PEGGY (cont'd) What are you doing?</context>
      <utterance>Would it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie dances affectionately with Bob as Mr. Trout, tending bar, greets Ike.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to go dance with Bob. Because he's the man.  I like those grapes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What can I get you?</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Mr. Graham, welcome to our luau.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got something without a toy in it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike leans into Maggie, enjoying the smell of her hair. She notices, but acts casual.</context>
      <utterance>Aloha. That's a very fetching headdress you're wearing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you disappear to?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Missed me bad, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Attention. Listen to Walter. Listen close, he slurs.  Shut up, wahines!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lou Trout stands with his glass raised.</context>
      <utterance>In the tradition that has grown through the years, it is now Toast Time! First up, our host, "A Honey of a Beekeeper", Lou Trout..</utterance>
   <speaker>LOUT TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are shouts of "Hear hear!" Walter roars.</context>
      <utterance>May the groom's heart be filled with hopes and the bride's feet be filled with lead!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May the pitter-patter of little feet not be Maggie's.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May the gifts be returned!</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The laughter swells and swells, led by Walter.</context>
      <utterance>May the back of the dress be as pretty as the front!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie finishes the punchline along with his father.</context>
      <utterance>You know the old saying, "You're not losing a daughter..." Well, I'd like to! Walter gets a bit laugh. He goes again. WALTER  Maggie may not be Hale's longest running joke...</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, give me a minute.  Are you all right with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you all right with this? You think this is funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't and I don't think you should...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a joke. They're kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER AND CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on and give us a toast.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike watches their reaction. The silence is deafening. All the guests stare at Maggie. Mortified, she holds back tears.</context>
      <utterance>You want me to make a toast? Okay... I'll give you a toast. To Maggie's family and friends. May you find yourselves the bull's eye of an easy target. May you be publicly flogged for all of your bad choices and may your noses to rubbed in all of your mistakes...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But enough toasts, let's hula. Let's start the music up. She gets everyone up to hula. Band plays fast tune. Maggie walks through the CROWD down the steps and outside. Ike follows, but Peggy grabs a coat for her. Bob watches her go as Cory approaches.</context>
      <utterance>That was funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Bob. I got twenty dollars bet on--</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob rushes after Maggie.</context>
      <utterance>Not now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike exits. Then, Bob comes over.</context>
      <utterance>Maggie. Maggie.  Here. She may need this. It's not really Hawaii.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd Maggie go?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cory comes over with Dennis to Bob and Peggy. BOB/PEGGY/CORY/ DENNIS CHUFFA: About Bart Starr and football. (Which keeps Bob from going outside to follow Maggie). Bob thinks about it.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, she just went to get me something from the car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the only goddamn person in there pulling for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You humiliated me!</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Maggie, I defended you. Humiliating you is what everyone else is doing. It's the theme of this party.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had it under control. Now they feel sorry for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they should. Because they're about to watch you hang yourself again. Maggie has no response. IKE  -- Tell me something, do you really care about Mount Everest?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fun! It's high.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or the sexual habits of locusts?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was very interesting research George was doing!</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of Dead Head gets a temporary tattoo?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already explained about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where you ever really going to run the leper colony in Molokai?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian told you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or maybe you just wanted to wear the headdress.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every one of those times I was being supportive. Something you won't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Supportive? You weren't being supportive. You were being scared. Just like now. You are the most lost woman I have ever laid eyes on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lost!</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. You're so lost you don't even know how you like your eggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What!?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the priest, you liked them scrambled. With the Dead Head, fried. With the bug guy, poached. Now it's egg whites only, thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's called changing your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's called not having a mind of your own. What are you doing, Maggie? You really want to let that man drag you up Annapuma on your honeymoon? You don't want to climb Annapuma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I do!</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She fights back angry tears.</context>
      <utterance>No you don't. You want a man who will lead you down the beach with his head over your eyes just so you can discover the feel of the sand under your feet. You want a guy who will take you into a cave with a thousand candles just to read you a poem. You want a man to wake you up at dawn because he's burning to talk to you and he can't wait another minute to find out what you'll say. Am I right? He's laid her flat. Maggie can't speak. IKE  Am I right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: Bob comes outside.</context>
      <utterance>Stop. Stop it! I'm getting married on Sunday, and you're just trying to make me run! Why? Because you're a cynical, exploitative, mean-hearted creep who wouldn't know real love if it bit him in the armpit! And all you do is tear other people down and-and-and laugh at them, and criticize what they do, because you're too afraid to do anything yourself! I read your column. You never wrote one about you. I'm not the only one who's lost and you know it! Am I right? Well? Am I right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both Maggie and Ike are breathing hard. Bob comes up to Maggie and gives Ike a very hard look as he puts his arm around his fiancee. BOB (cont'd) You know... Blocked Bart Starr, crewcut ... Are you okay? Maggie adjusts her face as best she can.</context>
      <utterance>Mag. Help me out here. Green Bay. Right guard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lets him lead her away.</context>
      <utterance>Let me take you back inside, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike looks at her drooped shoulder and he shakes his head and walks to his car.</context>
      <utterance>Jerry Kramer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, why does Maggie need another wedding rehearsal and two days before the wedding? She's already done this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob is making her visualize the ceremony.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie turns on Ike with "cheerful" hostility.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, we're ready. Want me to have Ike leave now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No -- Actually, let's make Ike the pastor.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd rather not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Team effort, Pastor Ike... Cindy, ready?  Cindy, come on. Cindy leaves to join the girls in the foyer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going to be the pastor?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. I want him to be front and center and to watch everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened at the luau?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I don't even want to talk about the luau.  What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy joins them.</context>
      <utterance>It's for the bell.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bob's in a hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Be the ball."</context>
      <utterance>Don't be nervous, Maggie. Let us visualize. Remember what Bob said?</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Sink the putt."</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Make the shot."</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Nothing but net."</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Never say die." Maggie puts her hands up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy and Cindy exit. Maggie pulls the bell rope and sways back and forth as she rings the bell.</context>
      <utterance>Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie stops ringing the bell and pulls herself together. She walks into the aisle looking a little shaky. She takes a few tremulous steps slowly with her eyes closed, peeking occasionally with one eye.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At this pace, it could be an evening wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold it! Hold it! I think we're taking this too fast. He begins to pace. BOB  We need to limber you up a little. You're tensing.  You stand here and be me so she knows how far she'll have to go.  I'm going to walk with you. Bob goes to Maggie and walks behind her. BOB  Visualize! Visualize! It's game time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm spiraling through the air.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Bob. She kissed me back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I kissed him back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie looks at Ike, wondrous, confused.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I caught that. Want to tell me how long this has been going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About a minute...?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little longer for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you expect me to say to this?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob hauls back and punches Ike in the face. Ike drops.</context>
      <utterance>How about -- "I hope you'll be very happy together"?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob storms down the aisle and out of the church.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you'll be very happy together.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Take care of him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At least I backed out before the wedding. That's progress! He keeps marching. Now Peggy appears next to Maggie. Maggie calls again. MAGGIE (cont'd) Some woman is going to make you a lot happier than I ever could... The words are barely out of her mouth when Cindy comes out the door, racing after Bob at a full sprint. MAGGIE (cont'd) See?</context>
      <utterance>Bob, I'm sorry!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy goes to her car. Cindy joins her as Bob speeds off in his car. Now Ike takes Peggy's place next to Maggie. Maggie turns to face Ike. They are both beet red, stammering and unable to look at each other, trying to act normal.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Maggie -- in the words of Mrs. Pressman: "Holy moly". Call me later.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. So... what, uh... What just happened? Just now? Jus then? In there?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I, uh -- I frankly don't even want to talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike GRABS Maggie and BOOM -- they are all over each other, kissing frantically, tongues, hands, hair, elbow, you name it. Blathering fools.</context>
      <utterance>Me, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you. I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come up for air.</context>
      <utterance>I love you, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie sits on the railing, then Ike backs up and sits on the opposite railing. IKE (cont'd) You have to go down an aisle and say "I do". You have to get married.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. We have to talk. We have to do some talking now. Pull up a railing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To who? Are you asking me?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike backs up to opposite railing and sits facing Maggie.</context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you!</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you do have the dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the church.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the wedding date. There's the two of us.  So, you think... maybe... You have to go down the aisle with somebody you love and who love you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So am I.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both nod and sit there smiling, sort of. The organist, Ted, closes the church door.</context>
      <utterance>So, we'll...</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike pulls his tape recorder out of his pocket and quietly speaks into it.</context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting married.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love his eyes. I just believe they're listening to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His hair... any color.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I like his tight butt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grandma!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's really found it.</context>
      <utterance>See, this is a mature relationship.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DINA NAPOLI</speaker>
      <mode>OF WBAL</mode>
      <context>Meredith, the low-end public access TV reporter, films himself pointing a cheap video camera himself.</context>
      <utterance>Wedding bells are ringing for the fourth time today in Hale, Maryland. Maggie Carpenter, "Always a Bride -- Never a Bridesmaid", will be attempting to complete her fourth wedding ceremony. We'll come back on the air when the results are in. Back to you, Jessica.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEREDITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The NY T-shirt Vendor pitches his wares.</context>
      <utterance>The turnout for this morning's wedding is usually reserved for royalty or Hollywood stars, but Maggie Carpenter is Hale, Maryland's special star and the citizens of Hale are out in full force today.</utterance>
   <speaker>T-SHIRT VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reporter JULIE MURPHY stands near Grandma Julia and Mrs. Pressman. JULIE MURPHY (Channel 6) The bride's been here for almost an hour, but being around in the beginning was never her problem. We'll be here, showing you the full wedding ceremony, we hope. Reporter JACKI and TIFFANY stand at the edge of the CROWD reporting.</context>
      <utterance>I got "Bye-bye Birdie". "What part of 'I do' don't you understand?"... Get your "Runaway Bride" T-shirts here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKI/REPORTER #3</speaker>
      <mode>WBOC TV16</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will she or won't she? That is on the minds of these several hundreds folks, who are standing here this morning. Not to mention on the mind of Groom Number 4, ex-USA Today columnist, Ike Graham, who is missing in action.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not coming. Watch. He's not coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. I saw eight geese flying in a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and your lucky geese. You always see geese.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not eight...</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And in a "V".</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They ad lib various words starting with the letter "V". Maggie is nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Eight is good... "V" could be Victory.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rub your ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, rubbing your ears is very soothing. Cory does that to me when I hyperventilate. Maggie rubs her ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do it to our dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hurting.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After they rub Maggie's ears a bit:</context>
      <utterance>We'll rub.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all squeeze and peer out window. They scream in excitement. Cindy rushes to Maggie's wedding dress.</context>
      <utterance>He's here! He's here!</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get the dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's here!... He's here!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy moves to help Cindy with the dress. Maggie stands alone at the window a moment. She picks up a toy horse.</context>
      <utterance>Now's the time for calm... If you don't calm down, you won't get your dress on...  He's the one... He's the one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie goes over to Peggy and Cindy, and starts to get into her bridal gown. They continue to ad lib words standing with the letter "V".</context>
      <utterance>This is not a good sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to hurry. The Sunday School kids will be here soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIE MURPHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the groom just pulled up. There was talk of a "now show", but he is here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DINA NAPOLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ike Graham is here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Pressman stands, shooting Ike with her video camera. IKE (cont'd) (pleading) Mrs. Pressman, please.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot ours so she has one with an ending.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PRESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're no fun.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. There's no microphone.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike retreats into the church. Lee comes up to him again with his video camera: CHUFFA about Scorsese.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over Ellie's shoulder, Ike sees Fisher's grinning face. IKE (cont'd) We are friends, aren't we, Fisher?</context>
      <utterance>Friends. Thank you. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course we are. Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you'll be my best man.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm good, I don't know if I'm best.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go talk to the pastor and he'll tell you what to do. And someone will tell me what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You always looked great in that suit... And Ike?  I'm happy for you, honey. Ellie whispers in his ear. ELLIE  I'll have a car around the back to whisk you out of here if she runs. Ellie kisses him on the cheek and walks away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob hands the flower to Ike. Ike is shaking. Bob catches this and looks up to Ike. It is a moment of clean honesty between the men.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the boutonniere and puts it on Ike's lapel. BOB (cont'd) I'm glad it's you.</context>
      <utterance>Ike. Need help?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to find out I wasn't for her in the fourth quarter.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got any last minute advice?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bob turns and leaves, going down a side staircase.</context>
      <utterance>Maintain eye contact.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no idea what I'm doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your job is... the ring.  Do you have the ring?!</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike gives the ring to Fisher. The Pastor approaches Ike. Ike turns away and look out over the guests. IKE'SPOV: There are most of the TOWNSPEOPLE we've come to know, plus some NEW YORKERS for Ike, with little ponytails. Armani wire rims, Donna Karan bodysuits. There's a lot of smirking, checking out the hicks, forming their stories for cocktail hour. Elaine is in back all dressed in black, mourning Ike. Mrs. Trout approaches Ike.</context>
      <utterance>I just found out I'm best man! I'm lucky I have a suit... What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should thank Lou and I for the wedding car -- a '63 Buick.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Trout starts picking lint off Fisher's jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on. You're practically family.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello. I'm Fisher.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TROUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This doesn't want to come out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just pull a hair from my neck.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Trout, go back to your seat!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GRANDMA JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck, Maggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grandma leaves. Walter steps up.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Grandma.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really rooting for this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy turns off the fan. Cindy takes the bag from Maggie.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CINDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie spits her bubblegum into the bag. Peggy hands Maggie her bouquet.</context>
      <utterance>Spit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy and Peggy nod and leave. The door closes.</context>
      <utterance>No sauntering down the aisle. Just make time. Let's just get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Elaine from New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello. I'm Bob, Maggie's fourth attempt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay. There's a lid for every pot. Besides, I'm comfortable with Ike. I mean, Jack Dempsey lost his heavyweight title to a New Yorker.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The organ begins to play. The organist is Ted. Grandma, Walter, Mrs. Pressman and the Trouts watch. Mrs. Trout picks lint off of her husband's jacket.</context>
      <utterance>I know. Gene Tunney.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're ready, Maggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dennis closes the door behind him as he goes back into the chapel. Maggie has a moment alone. She looks at back door as possible escape route, then changes her mind. She signals the start of the wedding by knocking on the door.</context>
      <utterance>Just a second.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives her bouquet to a little GIRL as she goes by. Ike comes down stairs.</context>
      <utterance>There's a man coming down those steps with lots of candy in his pockets. If you tickle him, he'll give candy.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KIDS mob him, grabbing his pockets. Ike fights his way through KIDS.</context>
      <utterance>Maggie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie looks back once, tearful and regretful, and disappears inside the truck. The truck races off. The PHOTOGRAPHERS turn their cameras on Ike, en masse. He is enveloped by a barrage of bright lights. Ellie and Fisher, who have also stepped outside on chapel front steps, are looking around as Ike turns around the corner and past the church.</context>
      <utterance>Maggie!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, he's running after her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, he's in pretty good shape.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look after the FedEx truck and watch Ike chasing the truck down the road away from the church.</context>
      <utterance>Poor Ike.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maggie!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you think she's going?</utterance>
   <speaker>FISHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cindy, Cory, Peggy and Meredith also rush out of the church and comment on Maggie's runaway. Further down the road, Ike still chases the truck, yelling:</context>
      <utterance>Wherever it is, she'll be there by ten- thirty tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the truck rounds the bend in the road and disappears, Ike stops and stares alone after the disappearing truck. A swarm of REPORTERS catch up to him, flashing pictures and asking questions. Another camera flashes and we cut to:</context>
      <utterance>Maggie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay? I'm closing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just finishing up, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to go to Butch's for a drink or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm just going to head home.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy starts to go, then moves close to Maggie. PEGGY (cont'd) (stepping closer and making a "V" with her fingers) You know, I was just thinking about that geese thing. I think the "V" was half of a "W". A "W" for...</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wedding. Wedding.  You just have to get the rest of your ducks in a row.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. You still think that he was....</utterance>
   <speaker>PEGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peggy exits. Maggie stares, losing herself in thought. Then a VOICE startles her.</context>
      <utterance>Quick. Very quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie jumps and turns to see: DENNIS -- the kid from the high school football team, popping up from a low position near the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Marry me, Maggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Dennis.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am going to propose, you know. I mean, the right way. Soon as I turn eighteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dennis takes the candy and starts to go.</context>
      <utterance>You're sweet, Dennis. But you've got to go. I'm closing up. Here's a candy bar and one for your brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dennis exits. Maggie is alone. She turns out the lamp she designed, then on again. She turns off the other lamp on the counter and exits. We hold on Maggie's designed lamp.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not giving up. A person shouldn't give up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Maggie. Home for lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie walks in and kisses Grandma on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>She's been doing this since the last wedding. I don't think it's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Grandma, what's for lunch?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turkey and cheese.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walter laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, your grandmother and I were thinking about opening a wedding gift museum.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just stop it. Don't say another word like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maggie, it's just a joke...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A harmless joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie takes a plate and exits.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's humiliating and you've been doing it since I was a kid. I don't like it. Stop. You may not like having a daughter with problems. But guess what? I don't like having a father who's drunk all the time. I'll eat in my room.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMA JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walter reacts.</context>
      <utterance>That needed to be said. You know -- you're always making jokes about her, so they won't make jokes about your drinking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Ike. He closes the closet and crosses to his desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie smiles tenuously. She's more than a little terrified.</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me. My doorman is one of your many admires... I knew I should have given him a better Christmas gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been making friends with your cat.  Is it okay that I'm here?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have much choice in the matter now, do I? But I can't speak for Italics.  Traitor!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike looks at her. Apparently the word "mad" is an understatement. MAGGIE (cont'd) ... Or... furious. Ike looks at her again. MAGGIE (cont'd) ... Irate? Livid? How's that? He starts putting cat food in a bowl. The cat leaves Maggie's side and starts to east.</context>
      <utterance>I don't blame you for being mad...</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're terrific.</context>
      <utterance>Livid is good. So what is it, Maggie? You here on business? I saw your lamps.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike leaves the kitchen, turns on the balcony lights and re-enters the living room from the balcony.</context>
      <utterance>It's something I've always wanted to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You actually could make breaking and entering into a new career.  So, what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike moves away from her and sits on the steps near the balcony window, listening.</context>
      <utterance>I wanted to talk to you about why I run or ride away from things.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so... When I was walking down the aisle? I was walking toward somebody who didn't have any idea who I really was. And it was only half the other person's fault, because I had done everything to convince him that I was exactly what he wanted. So it was good that I didn't go through with it because it would have been a lie, but you -- you knew the real me.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike takes this in. She's reaching him -- but then the defenses go back up. He turns to her.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't. And you being the one at the end of the aisle didn't just fix that.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike moves out to the balcony. After a moment, Maggie follows him.</context>
      <utterance>No, I couldn't fix anything...  But I still ended up chasing a truck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand why you bring up the truck. Let me explain something. The fact is, you've seen me at my worst, most embarrassing, deviously plotting, potentially but not certifiably, psychotic state. And if you liked me then, I mean, now... I can't imagine...  Benedict. Ike has no response. MAGGIE  I love eggs Benedict. I hate all the other kinds. She hesitates. MAGGIE  ... I hate big weddings with everybody staring. I would like to get married on a weekday while everybody is at work. If I ride off into the sunset, I want my own horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She returns to the balcony and hands him the box. IKE (cont'd) What's this?</context>
      <utterance>Should I be writing this down?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens it. It's her running shoes.</context>
      <utterance>These are for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Used?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're mine. I'm turning in my running shoes to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she is glowing at him, shining with the full force of her.</context>
      <utterance>This is getting serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie glances around and spots a DECK CHAIR, which she turns so it is facing the city lights. Then she softly says: MAGGIE (cont'd) If you could have a seat, please. Ike sits. Maggie takes the box from him and puts it aide. And then she gets down on one knee.</context>
      <utterance>And one more thing. I know it's hard to believe there could be more. Um...</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie smiles up at him. Ike tips his head back and covers his eyes with his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike swallows, overwhelmed, overjoyed, and scared shitless.</context>
      <utterance>No, no -- don't hide your face, this only happens once in a lifetime. It's definitely a first to me, and you're not going to want to miss it. He smiles as he looks at Maggie. MAGGIE  I love you, Homer Eisenhower Graham. Will you marry me?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maggie hops cheerfully back to her feet.</context>
      <utterance>Maggie, I gotta think about this a little bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. She gets off her knees and stands. MAGGIE  I was hoping you'd say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was, because if you said "yes" right away, I wouldn't get to say this next part. And I've been practicing it.  Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike takes her hands affectionately.</context>
      <utterance>"I guarantee that we'll have tough times. I guarantee that at some point one or both oof us will want to get out. But I also guarantee that if I don't ask you to be mine, I'll regret it for the rest of my life. Because I know in my heart -- you're the only one for me".</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty good speech, Maggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ike looks into Maggie's shining face and pauses. He gets up and motions with his hand for her to stay seated. He goes inside and turns on some music. The cat is sitting by the radio. He returns to the balcony and takes Maggie's hand.</context>
      <utterance>I borrowed it from this guy I know. So?</utterance>
   <speaker>IKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start to dance a slow dance.</context>
      <utterance>Dance with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
