<movie id="470" title="Rush Hour">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, we see massive SECURITY PREPARATIONS all around the city.</context>
      <utterance>Eager to mend its tarnished image, Los Angeles has really put out the welcome mat for tomorrow's summit. The city promises quite a party as leaders from Japan, China, South Korea, Australia, the U.S. and others begin talks for the largest free-trade treaty in history. The SCENE changes to TAPE of DELEGATES from other countries arriving.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>The SCENE returns to LAX.</context>
      <utterance>The one sour note is North Korea, the only Pacific Rim country not participating. There are rumors of secret meetings with North Korean representatives, but U.S. officials insist the North must first hold democratic elections, and halt its nuclear weapons program -- as they claimed to have done back in 1995. We CUT TO a heated debate in the UN SECURITY COUNCIL. Then ARTILLERY FIRE over the Korean DMZ.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tensions remain high since last year's skirmishes between North Korea and the U.S. So any chance of the communist North joining the Pacific Partners seems highly unlikely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bolts out of bed, wearing nothing but a pair of striped bikini briefs. Miranda rolls over, sleepy, unconcerned...</context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pete... please... we have to be up early tomorrow. Call the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He races down the hall -- right past the house alarm keypad, its LCD reading "ARMED." He grabs an aluminum baseball bat from the umbrella stand. Forgetting to disarm the house alarm, he yanks the front door open. The house alarm begins SHRIEKING.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pulls the pillows over her head and sighs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not again...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WESTEC GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asshole 2 is still trying to gouge Carson with the screwdriver. Carson glares at the dopey Guards.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody... chill! Bikini boy! On the ground!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Asshole was trying to boost my car!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mike -- call 911!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guards seem to get it. Without warning, one takes out a TASER and ZAPS Asshole 2. Carson lets go just in time.</context>
      <utterance>Been trying...  It's busy.  He's the good guy, you schumcks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are six bathrooms in this house, Sam.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She quickly closes the door behind her. Sam laughs.</context>
      <utterance>But only one with a smoking section.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>[Go change.] Ambassador Han's X-ray stare turns to Joy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BUTLER appears with a phone. He WHISPERS to Mrs. Han.</context>
      <utterance>[You smell like a fireplace.]</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the Governess...  Hello, Hilda...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Good morning, Summit Day! It's gonna be the Super Bowl, the 4th of July, the Olympics and Woodstock all rolled into one! All over town there'll be parades, concerts, rallies, festivals... So get out there everyone, but plan your drive- time accordingly! This is Bobbi Marchfelder, your Eye in the Sky... We CUT TO the White House lawn, where the PRESIDENT is about to board a helicopter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORNING ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The President is on his way...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We CUT BACK to the studio and the MORNING ANCHOR.</context>
      <utterance>...It's an honor hosting my fellow leaders in Los Angeles, the capitol city of the Pacific Rim...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORNING ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll see the menu for Mayor Simpson's Brentwood barbecue, right after this... We CUT TO a MUSICAL MONTAGE of preparations for the events around town.</utterance>
   <speaker>BACK TO SCENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As the MUSIC swells, Carson turns the TV off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was watching that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miranda points at the headphones -- she can't hear him.</context>
      <utterance>If I hear one more Beach Boys song, I'll shoot myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, if we were having sex once in a while, you wouldn't need to ride that fucking bike every morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Carson dresses, we get a LOOK at their bedroom -- Miranda's nightstand has two neat stacks of periodicals on it, with Los Angeles magazine and Psychology Today on the top of them. Carson's nightstand is overflowing with books and magazines about other cities and states: Wonderland Washington; Magnificent Oregon; Welcome to North Carolina."</context>
      <utterance>Be right with you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you gotten any sleep lately?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shop's gonna tow the car in -- goddamn ignition's trashed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson watches as she carefully picks the dead leaves off the rose bushes.</context>
      <utterance>Take mine. I'll ride in with Diane.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She continues, then glances at the article Carson is reading.</context>
      <utterance>You ask me, those suckers are a lost cause.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean it's not for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't chase car thieves in my underwear. C'mon, you'd die of boredom if we ever sold this house and moved.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even for what it's worth now.</context>
      <utterance>I'd die of shock, from finding anyone dumb enough to buy the place.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lots of people bought at the top of the market...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sure cheers me right up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson just looks at her. Reaching for the salt, he winces from the cut in his side.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know why we even talk about it. The city's not the problem. So we move. It wouldn't matter. What's that saying: "Wherever you go, there you are."</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you're current on your tetanus booster. Was it worth it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson glances at his watch and gets up.</context>
      <utterance>One cut... two assholes in the hospital... Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask for a transfer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miranda tries to return to tending her roses. But instead, she sadly watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>They're not gonna transfer me. You know damn well why I was bumped down to guard duty...  My outstanding people skills.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>turns to Mrs. Han:</utterance>
   <speaker>JOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we give Lisa a ride?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joy rolls the window up and the SOUND of cursing disappears.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Joy... Sam...</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent -- I can't hear him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The glass is an inch thick.  Armor-plated. Bulletproof. Bomb- proof.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfect car for L.A.  Starts, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ROBBINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, Dave the Computer Man! Actually escaped the office!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm doin' field upgrades. Gives 'em a chance to hose out my cage. He glances through the window at Colonel Lee.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the fuckin' gargoyle?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sabatini makes the jerk-off sign with her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Their Chief of Security, Colonel Lee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Chuckles," as we're inclined to call him.  Friggin' graveyard shift...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love to know what dope made it the Bureau's job to give full-time protection to foreign consulates.  Cup a mud?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if you made it. Why don't you get Sabatini to brew the java? She's the alleged chick.</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Carson?</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On his way. Some creeps tried to rip off his Mustang last night.  They cut the ragtop.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dave takes three PCMCIA computer cards from his attachˆ case.</context>
      <utterance>Motherfuckers...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Latest and greatest. Wireless network link-ups.</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, slow down, I'm gonna pee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ingrates.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambassador Han nods. The FBI agents run up. To them:</context>
      <utterance>[You must stay here.]</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The agents look at each other -- holy shit! Colonel Lee's car SCREECHES to a stop. Sabatini stands in front of it.</context>
      <utterance>Someone took my family!</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colonel Lee shoves a big, ugly Tokorev 7.62x25mm-caliber pistol in her face as he's opening the car door.</context>
      <utterance>You got no jurisdiction outside this property!</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit!  Yank his fuckin' leash!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colonel Lee jumps into the car and it screeches away, almost running Sabatini over.</context>
      <utterance>My men are going!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The agents rush back to their guardhouse. Dave's government Dodge is blocking theirs.</context>
      <utterance>It's a white telephone van, driving west on Washington Boulevard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dave tosses them to Robbins. Sabatini shoves Dave into the back seat. He looks at her, dumbfounded.</context>
      <utterance>Keys!</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're ridin' shotgun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROBBINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cherry?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sabatini grabs the red flashing light, puts it on the dashboard.</context>
      <utterance>Under the seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Siren?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know! I'm never in a fuckin' hurry..!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson looks like he's been punched in the stomach.</context>
      <utterance>Someone snatched Han's family! White phone van, westbound on Washington!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sabatini takes a small two-way MOTOROLA RADIO out of her pocket and throws it through her window to Carson. Dropping it in his lap, he punches the gas. Robbins floors Dave's piece-of- shit Dodge, trying to keep up.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a secure radio!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CO-WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone's been to Nordstroms, big time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clothes make the man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CO-WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But does the man make enough for the clothes?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walther's SECRETARY rushes in.</context>
      <utterance>The man makes payments on his Visa.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Walther... priority line!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Diplomatic Liaison Earl Walther... What's the nature of your emer --  Aw, Jesus... not today...  I'll inform channels and get a copter in the air. For God's sake, keep it quiet. Do what you can, but don't endanger civilians or the family!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Real easy, until he narrowly MISSES a bunch of cars when SCREECHING around a corner.</context>
      <utterance>You bet -- nice and easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the Secretary of State on the horn.  I know he left already. I'm familiar with the concept of time zones. Find his ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robbins, Sabatini... Chopper's on its way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check it out! Ahead, on the right!</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think it's them?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over at Colonel Lee, whose car is pacing his.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... but it seems too easy... I'll move up; he won't suspect a civilian car. Stay back, then get on his ass when I signal. We'll box him in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the Mod Squad gets in your way, don't be shy about getting 'em out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Copy that one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson shoves Colonel Lee out of his way, hard.</context>
      <utterance>You should not have interfered!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colonel Lee comes back, ready for a fight. Carson is happy to oblige, but Robbins grabs Carson's arm.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in no mood...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now, ONLOOKERS have begun to gather, as LAPD black-and whites and helicopters converge on the area.</context>
      <utterance>Forget about him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does anyone need to use the rest room? This will be your last opportunity for a few hours.  Very well. Mrs. Han, Sam, Joy, please sit here.  And you... what is your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still holding the Beretta, he grabs a polo shirt from the closet and pulls it on. As the family sits in the chairs:</context>
      <utterance>Lisa...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a pair of handcuffs out of his pants pocket. He tries to handcuff Lisa, hands behind her back, but she resists.</context>
      <utterance>No, Mrs. Han, this one. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There. No taping your mouths, no restraints. Please remain still while I explain. The meters on the left indicate sound pressure -- Decibels. There are microphones on your chair backs. If you raise your voices above certain level, putting your meter in the red zone for more than one sustained second, the circuit will be closed.  The right meters indicate motion. There are pressure sensors inside the armrests and seats. The sensors don't like to get wet, so I hope you were honest about not needing to use the loo. If you make any excess movements, or try to leave your chair, the circuit will be closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at her sound meter, which jumped close to the red.</context>
      <utterance>I don't understand...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens if the circuit closes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He uncovers the other item atop the TV -- a one-pound brick of C-4 high explosive with the detonation mechanism jammed into it. Mrs. Han gasps and begins to PANIC.</context>
      <utterance>Kaboom...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They nod. Tears roll down Joy's face.</context>
      <utterance>Easy... deep breath...  Do each of you understand?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carson?  Walther. Who told the Ambassador?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His Security Chief.  There was a civilian with them -- fifteen-year-old girl from across the street. We're trying to reach the parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it...  Look, Mrs. Han was the North Korean Premier's niece! We're hearing rumors they're gonna make a major issue out of what happened here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not so sure what happened here. Something smells. Asshole was acting like he wanted us to spot him...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>Ambassador Han comes down the stairs, his face tight with repressed emotion.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Walther?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ambassador Han... my deepest --</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just answers.</context>
      <utterance>-- I have no wish for condolences.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the Butler sprints across the foyer. He shoves the cordless phone into Ambassador Han's hands. Ambassador Han listens to the phone, then takes in a sharp breath and sits on the steps.</context>
      <utterance>As soon as we have any to give...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yoon..?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson is elated. Robbins, Sabatini and Dave rush out. Walther pulls out a cell phone and hits a speed-dial key.</context>
      <utterance>Start a trace!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Secretary... they're alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are tapping our phones?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you didn't know. And I'm Meryl Streep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the phone from her, takes a breath to compose himself.</context>
      <utterance>We are not hurt. But this man is very serious --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to remember the feeling you had when you thought your family was dead, and use it to inform the choices you're about to make.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say you want to talk to the kids...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to know my children are all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVAL</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Javal hangs up. Stunned, Ambassador Han stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Be in front of a television in two minutes. Tune it to channel four. You'll get the picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Carson, Ambassador Han, Colonel Lee and Walther hurry to the office in the back of the house, Carson's radio crackles:</context>
      <utterance>There is a television in my office.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBINS</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're screwed on the trace -- he's on a cell phone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Play the tape back. I might be able to pull the electronic serial number out of the subcarrier.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask Dave if he knows how to find the phone's serial number.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, great idea...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAVAL</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>CLICK. Ambassador Han looks around, feeling totally helpless. Carson says nothing, trying not to show how uneasy he feels.</context>
      <utterance>I am not a terrorist. Your countries' political posturing means nothing to me. So do not waste time trying to negotiate.  The Federal Reserve Bank of Los Angeles can furnish ten million dollars U.S. by 2:00 PM. The required denominations are in the instructions, as is the method of packaging. Be in your car at 3:00 PM, and drive north on Highland Avenue. I will call with where to leave the money, which you will do at 3:30. If I am unmolested, I will call again at 4:00 with the family's location and the method for removing them from their... predicament. Could you please refer to page one?  Any deviation from these instructions and my device will fulfill its function at exactly 5:00 PM.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>P'yšngyang must approve the ransom...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. The FBI's top Hostage Negotiator is on the way --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walther glares at Carson, then continues to Ambassador Han:</context>
      <utterance>-- Goddamn Negotiator's the last thing we need! This asshole sound like he was interested in bargaining?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Numb, Ambassador Han nods.</context>
      <utterance>We have people who are experts in these situations. We really feel it would be best if you let them coordinate everything...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get on it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You're gonna just pay up, count on his good nature to return the family?!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the President's intention to keep this quiet, move forward with the Summit, and work with the North Koreans. Jesus, you've already embarrassed the shit out of us over the phone surveillance --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They tap our fucking phones!</context>
      <utterance>-- They know their phones are tapped!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not the point! The point is not acknowledging it!  We got an international incident brewing, with a country we were practically at war with last year! Our best Negotiator is gonna run point. If you got a problem, you can take the goddamn rest of the day off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Consulate is my responsibility.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson is stunned. (OS), we hear a CHOPPER approaching.</context>
      <utterance>Not any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson shoots a disgusted look at the others, then leaves.</context>
      <utterance>That's the Negotiator. You do the briefing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm wondering whether to believe him when he says he's strictly motivated by money.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see one word of Peoples'- Liberation, Holy-Jihad, Revolutionary whatever-it-is-we're-pissed-off-about- this-week bullshit in this entire letter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still want to check the MO against known politicals, terrorists --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Already doing it. We're coordinating with the Secret Service, the NSA and the CIA.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walther comes in and looks at Carson.</context>
      <utterance>Have someone talk to the LAPD, give them a cover story for the media about the crash on La Cienega.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This surprises Ambassador Han and Colonel Lee.</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me Doctor Knoll is your wife?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she'd changed her name when we got married, I wouldn't have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so enjoying this opportunity to finally work together...</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, forget I asked.  The cash will be here in an hour.  Any thoughts on the kidnapper's thoughts?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything indicates he's working alone. And his concerns do seem to be solely about the money... so I agree that he's only using the Summit and the tension with North Korea to create extreme motivation to pay the ransom.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will bring the money to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hostages are citizens of the People's Republic of Korea --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Hey, do I go to the torture chambers in your prisons, tell you how to do your job?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson glares coldly at Walther.</context>
      <utterance>All right, you're outta here! Is this the same insubordinate crap you pulled at Beverly Thrift?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll coordinate the drop.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps that is better. Inspector Carson knows the terrain --</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walther looks at Miranda. She nods her assent.</context>
      <utterance>-- Then he can come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's settled.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Americans leave the room.</context>
      <utterance>But it means we can get on with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...They've got the Premier agreeing to the hard-line position -- He hears footsteps approaching .</utterance>
   <speaker>OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He angles skyward a tiny dish-shaped antenna on the Device. On its screen it says COMPRESSING... SCRAMBLING... UPLINKING... After it's finished, the Operative snaps it closed and puts it into a false bottom in his attachˆ case. He disappears just before a GUARD rounds the corner.</context>
      <utterance>More to follow...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to be home by now, take the kids to the rally in Boyle Heights.</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's helping Walther stack packs of THOUSAND-DOLLAR-BILLS into a series of small plastic bags, tying each one off when it's the size of a brick. They then put the individual bags into two larger bags. Robbins rubber-bands a matchbook-sized HOMING TRANSMITTER in between two packs of cash. He then hollows out a dime-sized space inside a different pack of money with a razor knife. He puts a tiny, SECOND homing transmitter in the space. Carson checks some hand-held receivers. Miranda crosses to him.</context>
      <utterance>We got a cabin in Big Bear. By now, L.A. was supposed to be a brown blotch in the rear-view mirror.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll expect a homing device --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I expect him to expect it. He'll check the cash with an RF detector...  Meaning he'll find this one.  This only has a quarter-mile range, but on a frequency too low to detect.  And I doubt the asshole will have an X-ray machine or a metal detector.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why must you always refer generically to criminals as "assholes?"</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gosh, you're right. It could undermine their self-esteem and spoil their chances for rehabilitation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She returns to listening to an AUDIO TAPE:</context>
      <utterance>You been reading my magazines in the bathroom again?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVAL</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"And my device will fulfill its function at exactly 5:00 PM..."</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's really exhibiting pressured speech... big effort here to sound calm. Same with his vocabulary... if he were in control, he wouldn't feel such a need to sound that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell me if we can use it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we needle him he could get sloppy and give us an opening, but I'm not going to risk it. This is the worst kind of perpetrator: anything makes him deviate from his carefully- scripted plan, he could become extremely volatile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we have back-up if the bleeper fails?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing but physical surveillance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson looks at her as the thought of it hits him.</context>
      <utterance>It's real important we don't lose him. He didn't go through all the trouble of designing that bomb not to use it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it ain't gonna happen.  Not again...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is the big crisis?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF STATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just received a missive from the North Korean attachˆ. They say the kidnapping is a U.S. plot to provoke and humiliate them during the Summit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SENIOR INTELLIGENCE OFFICER refers to his notes.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. They're just ticked because we don't want the Chinese dragging their asses into the treaty talks.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTELLIGENCE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a covert operative in place. He reports the hard-liners and moderates in the High Command are arguing about how to respond, should the Premier's niece and her children should be killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Respond?! Christ. What about the damn Premier?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF STATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's weak. He has to look tough to save face, keep control of hard- liners... otherwise he risks a coup.</utterance>
   <speaker>CIA CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is a real possibility. Most of those old-fart Generals don't want to -more- CIA CHIEF  be part of the Summit any more than we want them to. They're mad as hell he even talked to the Chinese.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to deal with this right now! Get our diplomats on it. Tell the North we'll pay the ransom for 'em... Placate 'em! And make damn sure we get that family back in one piece. Who's in charge in L.A.?</utterance>
   <speaker>FBI CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Bureau, Sir. We have a crack team in place.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF STATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a Diplomatic Liaison from State, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CIA CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And this did happen on his watch...</context>
      <utterance>What about your man stationed at the Consulate...  Carson? He was demoted from the FBI Hostage Program, couple years back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FBI CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no way he could've prevented this abduction! Besides, I've got one of my top Negotiators in charge --</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Whatever. I want a total news blackout and I want this over with, quickly! Without giving those Commie little bastards any excuse to shit all over my Summit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, please go ahead...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVAL</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah... this must be one of those professionals --</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I'm only here to see that everyone gets what they want --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAVAL</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Miranda hands the phone to Ambassador Han.</context>
      <utterance>-- I've got my shotgun in little Lisa's mouth, and I will pull the trigger in five seconds unless you put the Ambassador on the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The drop is at the DeMille barn, across from the Hollywood Bowl. You're to leave the money in the center of the parking lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit... no way we can set up a stake- out in... -more- CARSON   Four minutes. Call the Park Rangers at the Bowl. Have them clear the area of civilians.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, Pete... we're dealing with a customer with a lot of rage.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must've bought a house same time we did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Which way's he heading?</context>
      <utterance>Fuck! Okay, stay back. It's not like he'll be hard to see in that truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Carson hangs a U-turn.</context>
      <utterance>Toward the freeway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're made! Gotta grab him!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right... Carefully...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Carson hugs the shoulder, moving through the heavy traffic, until he spots what he was looking for: The Biker Club, riding in formation up ahead. Carson cuts in front of them and slams on the brakes. He jumps out and grabs one of the Biker's machines by the handlebars, wrestling it to a stop. While pulling its BURLY OWNER off it:</context>
      <utterance>Turn around!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, the other BIKERS have come to help their friend. They pull guns, knives, chains... They're stopped by Sabatini, who appears holding her MP-5 machine pistol. The Biker yells at Carson as he drives way:</context>
      <utterance>FBI. Call our office, they'll take care of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a taxpayer! I'm a goddamn dentist!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson fishes out his two-way.</context>
      <utterance>Just don't kill yourself, you piece of shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helicopter or two would be nice!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fingerprint it.  He's not gonna tell us where to find the hostages... -more- CARSON   Meaning we got exactly 80 minutes to figure it out for ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Figure it out?! With what?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robbins is still trying to process what just happened.</context>
      <utterance>Miranda! We need a copter, pronto!  Get back to his van. There were no plates, but check the VIN, look it over, then meet us at the Consulate.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Scrounge us some bodies: National Guard, State Troopers, CHPs, local PD's, meter maids --</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- They're gonna search the whole city in a goddamn hour..?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't need you to tell me how fucked we are!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson looks like he's going to explode. Before he can reply:</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!! Every time you're on a case something explodes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson would love to get into it, but he lets it slide. He looks Sabatini, wandering aimlessly with Javal's severed hand.</context>
      <utterance>Stop! The clock's running! Arguing is a luxury we can't afford! -more- MIRANDA   What's done is done. There'll be plenty of time to point fingers later.</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson grabs one of the expensive pens from Ambassador Han's desk, SNAPS it in half, and hands it to her. In the b.g. she stands at the credenza, inks the hand's fingers and thumb and rolls them onto a piece of letterhead paper.</context>
      <utterance>I need some fuckin' ink!!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Good question. All eyes go to Miranda.</context>
      <utterance>This is impossible! How can you even begin to find them?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her head is spinning. She looks at Carson.</context>
      <utterance>Well, the normal procedure is to negotiate with the perpetrator...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's take stock. We've got a picture of where he hid the family, and recordings of his calls --</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- That's right! We can send them to our experts for analysis...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same with his fingerprints. But that means we need high-quality image and data transmission. We can piss away ten minutes coptering this shit to our offices in Westwood, or we can use your surveillance equipment.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is a diplomatic facility --</context>
      <utterance>There is no surveillance equipment.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to go. Ambassador Han turns to Colonel Lee.</context>
      <utterance>-- You want to play games, fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take them upstairs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson takes the page with the fingerprints from Sabatini. The Espionage Agents back away from her and Javal's hand.</context>
      <utterance>South Korean Consulate's just down the street -- want to take a listen? Colonel Lee pulls the phones away from him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around. Then, shrugging, she tosses it into a wastepaper basket.</context>
      <utterance>Shitcan that thing, will you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a digital scanner?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Analog.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might want to drop a few bucks at Radio Shack and get with the decade.  Dave -- get in here. Bring your computer, a city map, and the tapes of the ransom calls.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>He's also HEARD, faintly, through the laser eavesdropping unit by the window. Carson notices, but doesn't comment.</context>
      <utterance>On my way...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colonel Lee begrudgingly obliges. Carson dials a phone.</context>
      <utterance>Colonel, you saw the perp. Describe him to the Ambassador, see if it's anyone he knows.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Carson in L.A. There's a set of prints coming over. Narrow the search criteria: Male, thirties, Caucasian... French, Belgian, Swiss, maybe Canadian. Try kidnappers and bombers first. We need an answer in fifteen minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FINGERPRINT TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That yellow air out there finally rot your brain?! It's impossible!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dazzle me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got one of the best sound guys right here in town...  Newman in Audio Analysis...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Newman's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dave comes into the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson looks at Miranda and hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>He quit, couple weeks ago. Opened a bed and breakfast in Wyoming.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn... they get HBO? I'd sure like to see the fight tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get those tapes transferred to a sound guy. We need ambient and background analysis, the whole enchilada.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enchilada -- you saying that because I'm Mexican?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... 'cause you're fat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Photo enhancement... Isn't there some amazing tech with the LAPD --</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Bronsky. Transferred to Seattle PD a month ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus H. Christ...</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd send it to Langley. Let the CIA earn their keep.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson tosses Javal's bloody, unlabeled prescription bottle to Miranda. She looks it over, runs her finger inside, tastes the dust on her fingertip.</context>
      <utterance>Do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amphetamines.</context>
      <utterance>Given his behavior, this orange residue... I'd say Desoxyn, 25 mg.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any significance?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's consistent with the lone wolf scenario: A handful of these is pure bravery-in-a-bottle, 'til the psychosis and paranoia kick in.  We could check pharmacy records, on the remote chance he got them legally... if we had a couple of weeks, that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the Bureau on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it. It's a waste of manpower.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sabatini looks at them -- which will it be? Miranda frowns and nods her okay, then spreads the L.A. map out on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Look, goddammit, you start skipping no-chance-in-hell leads, we can all quit and go to the beach right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He grabbed the family at 8:30. The last certain visual we had was just before his van went into the alley on La Cienega at 8:42. He called the Consulate at 9:30.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That gives him about fifty minutes to get to his location, move and secure the hostages, and activate his time bomb.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws a circle on the city map: Beverly Hills to downtown, Hollywood to Inglewood.</context>
      <utterance>He probably waited a while to pad the time -- he wanted us know the family was still alive...  ...So these crazy bastards wouldn't throw a premature shit hemorrhage, but he didn't want to call too soon, either. I say they're within 15 to 20 minutes, via surface streets, of where we last saw them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat while this sinks in.</context>
      <utterance>The most densely-populated part of the L.A. basin. This narrows it down to about 200,000 dwellings.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was traveling west --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Bet he doubled back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, that's total conjecture --</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I'd trust his instincts when dealing with maniacs. He is deeply disturbed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're telling me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF STATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...North Koreans have gone ballistic, accusing us of botching the ransom drop on purpose.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're still harping on that "American plot" nonsense.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meaning?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say the death of the Premier's niece and her family would justify immediate retaliation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone in the room looks at one another.</context>
      <utterance>Are they out of their fuckin' minds?! What kind of retaliation?</utterance>
   <speaker>CIA CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're threatening to pull a Saddam Hussein: remember the Scuds he lobbed at Jerusalem during Desert Storm?  They're talking about firing a missile into Los Angeles --</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- A goddamn WHAT??</utterance>
   <speaker>INTELLIGENCE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best guess is an AS-15, medium-range cruise -- their version of our Tomahawk, launched from offshore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The AS-15 is gyro-guided. It will find the city, but it's not too accurate beyond that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICE PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still, for their purposes it's perfect: Hit somewhere in L.A., take out a city block or two...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF STATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the eyes of the world it's a measured response -- like what Reagan did to Qaddafi. But actually striking at an American city would be a huge psychological victory for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe I'm hearing this!  So if we know it's coming, we can knock it out of the fuckin' sky!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These weapons fly subsonically, below radar... we don't have the defenses in place... If we'd had the time to deploy a string of Patriot anti- missile batteries across the coast --</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone's silence answers his question.</context>
      <utterance>-- You're saying we got all this lousy hardware and can't stop one goddamn missile??</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want an immediate search for all ships within range.</utterance>
   <speaker>FBI CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We better inform the other leaders, stall on the Summit --</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no reason to panic yet -- they can't launch until after the family's confirmed dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>CIA CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Intelligence Officer illustrates his explanation with FOOTAGE and DIAGRAMS on a nearby COMPUTER SCREEN:</context>
      <utterance>Afraid that's not the case...</utterance>
   <speaker>INTELLIGENCE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The North Korean Premier holds what we call a "Brinksman Switch." He's able to destroy a missile in flight, right up to the moment before it achieves its target.</utterance>
   <speaker>CIA CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our Op says they've timed their retaliation to hit right after 5:00.</utterance>
   <speaker>FBI CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if the family turns up okay, they'll just make it self-destruct.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! I really don't need this today!</utterance>
   <speaker>VICE PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han and her kids are safely returned?</context>
      <utterance>We're forgetting one thing here: the family. Intelligence is sure the North will abort their attack if Mrs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CIA CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely. Their whole game depends on claiming a legitimate provocation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still, we should let them know there'd be a response... if it comes to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to turn 'em into a radioactive parking lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF STATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the problem: we can't. We're the last superpower. Our hands are tied by politics, alliances, goddamn stacks of treaties... most we could do is give 'em a "measured response" back again, or everyone starts crying that we're the bullies.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, I miss the Cold War. Russians wouldn't have dreamt of pulling a stunt like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And don't tell me any more bad news!</context>
      <utterance>Believe me, the North drops one in my fuckin' city, I'm dropping ten in theirs. Get some bombers in the air.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maybe he was a political.</context>
      <utterance>Cute.  He signed the name of the Allied Commander during the Korean War.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. The phony ice cream truck, the booby-trapped chairs... he could've -more- MIRANDA  done it without half that stuff. But this was going to be the score of a lifetime... he was showing off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's got those kinds of skills: Electronics, vehicle customizing, computers, explosives?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Military. Cop, maybe. Shit, your average high-school student if they're so inclined. My guess is our perp used off-the-shelf equipment for everything except the C-4, and that's only slightly harder to get than crack or heroin, if you know who to ask.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The red light on the camera goes off. Bobbi turns to the Pilot.</context>
      <utterance>This is Bobbi Marchfelder, your Eye in the Sky... back to you, Brent...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cameraman and the Pilot sigh at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, dickhead... I was backlit that entire segment!  Keep... the sun... to my left!!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's new on the kidnapping rumor?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAMERAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nada. Total news blackout.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go back over the hill.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWS PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got the valley traffic report in fifteen --</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes an industrial-sized bottle of Mylanta out of her purse. It's fitted with a water-bottle DRINKING SPOUT. She takes a huge swig and grimaces.</context>
      <utterance>-- "Stalled vehicle! One lane closed! Sig alert..!" I'll improvise!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you lookin' at? I was the morning anchor in Houston! And I'm one break away from getting out of this stupid fuckin' whirlybird!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard him -- for money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if something goes wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to the kidnapping site.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colonel Lee also heads for the door. Carson looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>I want to talk to the witnesses.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They leave. Dave, meanwhile, paces, phone in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Great, we'll hire a bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I know it's privileged information, goddammit! Lemme talk to a supervisor... You are a supervisor... Lemme talk to your goddamn supervisor... I told you, I'm with the FBI...  Cellular company says he was using a phone with a cloned number.</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big surprise. Have 'em send a list of the numbers called on the account.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm trying to get. They're saying I need a subpoena.  Don't put me on hold... Don't...  I'm listening to Michael fuckin' Bolton!</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walther! Get on the horn to Justice and deal with this!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROBBINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot of the components are made by the same manufacturer -- a car security company.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jump a copter to the Consulate. See if the manufacturer sells to the public. Find out what shops use their stuff; put people on the phones with a description of the perp.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>YOUNG COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inspector! Look at this...  "Dragon's Breath..?"</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve-gauge shell filled with magnesium and ignition powder. Shit's worse than napalm -- Geneva Convention outlawed it for warfare.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how did he get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy -- you can buy 'em mail order.  Where's the Consulate's car?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... apparently it was stolen...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stolen!? What is it with you people --</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- What's this "you people" shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He means all of us "you people."</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find it! How many bulletproof Mercedes could be cruising around Crenshaw?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be surprised...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate this fuckin' town.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wasted trip: Witnesses say he was working alone, and he was a vicious son of a bitch. Old news.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And our car was stolen.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I felt safer when I was the Ambassador to Libya.</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Image enhancements came back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We going steady?</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sun position tells us the windows are facing northeast.  Here's the best -- look at the glass on the prints hanging in the background. There's a reflection of a reflection, out on the street: the corner of a billboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like the wheel of a car.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We talked about these billboards, when we were car shopping! Four- door... they make a wagon, too.  Something Japanese... God, what was it? Toyota... Mazda... Honda... You thought it had no character.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>C'mon, think, dammit!!</context>
      <utterance>I thought that about all of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're stumped, and bitterly frustrated. To Sabatini:</context>
      <utterance>You think!! You were there, too!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, Dave and Robbins are calling car alarm shops:</context>
      <utterance>Call the outdoor advertising companies. Get the location of all the billboards for Japanese cars within our search parameters.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Peerless Auto Security. We need to know whether you've sold a large quantity of these components to any one customer, or whether you'd had any stolen recently...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what the hell does "Kipchak" mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTELLIGENCE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He really doesn't want to be the one telling the President about this.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, it's a code name... for weapons using the Yersinia Pestis bacillus...</utterance>
   <speaker>INTELLIGENCE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>and it killed half the population.</context>
      <utterance>Kipchaks were Asian nomads. In 1347 they attacked a Genoese fort, and catapulted infected corpses over the walls. The Genoese who survived carried the disease back to Europe...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Intelligence Officer looks at the CIA Chief.</context>
      <utterance>Get to the goddamn point, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>CIA CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President goes nuts.</context>
      <utterance>Seems the missile is armed with a warhead carrying the Pneumonic Plague.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Black Plague?! Every time I talk to you fuckin' guys it gets worse! What happened to this "limited retaliation" shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF STATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The North Koreans insist the missile carries a conventional payload. They say we're trying to trick them into aborting the attack.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Especially since the uplink from our Op in P'yšngyang was unencrypted.</utterance>
   <speaker>CIA CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We think one of the Hard-liners switched the warhead without the Premier's knowledge. But he's not about to take our word for it, and he's too weak to risk the humiliation of backing down.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They use a biological weapon on American soil, they have to know we'll respond!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF STATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe they don't think we got the guts. Maybe they want a war, 'cause they think they can whip us, like what happened in 'Nam. Look who we're dealing with: a teetering, outlaw regime, and inside it, some wild-ass renegades working their screwy agenda!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are we doing in L.A.?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've deployed Marines from Pendleton and Twenty-Nine Palms, Army from Ft. Irwin, put 'em in protective suits, but it's 40 minutes before they're on the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Intelligence Officer demonstrates with another of his</context>
      <utterance>All right. Assuming the worst... What'll happen?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>INTELLIGENCE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The warhead vents the plague bacteria above the target area, infecting about 50,000 people. First symptoms are vomiting, lymph nodes become swollen; temperature rises to 105ƒ. Victims turn deep purple from lung hemorrhaging, usually die the same day.  There are treatments -- streptomycin and tetracyclines -- but we'd be overwhelmed by the numbers and its extreme contagiousness.</utterance>
   <speaker>CIA CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long beat as everyone tries to contemplate the unthinkable.</context>
      <utterance>We could have 500,000 infected in a week, who knows how many after that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna toast those fuckers! Have the Summit leaders been warned?</utterance>
   <speaker>FBI CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>'til we give the all-clear.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir... no one's landing in L.A.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're sure it's safe if we can get 'em to destroy the missile in flight?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTELLIGENCE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bacteria can't survive the heat of an explosion.</utterance>
   <speaker>CIA CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suggest none of this go any further -- not even to the agents working to find the family. Word leaks out to a city of 12 million people there's rocket full of the Plague coming at 'em, you'll create a panic of biblical proportions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say what?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps someone will decide it is foolish to incur the wrath of North Korea.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, the U.S. is behind the whole thing. And we're knocking our heads, trying to find your people, just for show.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carson...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's grab a few beers, kick back 'til five o'clock rolls by. Then maybe we can have a war over it. I think that's a great idea, seeing as how you fuckers have needed your clocks cleaned for fifty years now!</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambassador Han and Walther keep Carson and Colonel Lee from going at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Why wait until five?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pete!  Christ, you're self-indulgent! There's nothing but anger and cynicism left inside you, so they're all you can express any more. No wonder everyone in the Bureau thinks you're such a nutcase!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm not the only one with a rep around the office... "Dr. Knoll-It- All."</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been dying to tell me that... She walks away. Carson immediately regrets saying it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miranda...  Shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>INSTALLER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jerry's outta here!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTALLER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some cop's asking if we sold a bunch of Peerless parts.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTALLER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk to Javal!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTALLER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Javal's off today.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTALLER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude's off a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTALLER #2</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man's Canadian, dickweeds!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTALLER #1</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Carson rushes over to the phone. To the others in the room:</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna have to call back on Monday...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone shut up!  Guy on vacation, the Canadian --</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTALLER #1</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Yeah, Javal...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six foot, sandy hair, spooky eyes?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTALLER #1</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zombie Eyes! You know the man? Carson and Miranda look at each other. Bingo!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a full name, address, anything you got!</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTALLER #1</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Shit, he's our best installer.</context>
      <utterance>Paul Javal... hang on, we'll look it up... This an immigration thing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ESPIONAGE AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inspector Carson, extension 666...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson hurries over, grabs the phone. We SEE him punch the button for x666.</context>
      <utterance>That's appropriate...  In 30 seconds you're gonna give me Paul Javal's shoe size.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carson...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatta you got?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ambient background sound is normal city stuff, but there's a distinct echo pattern. Your people are in or near a high-rise that's at least eight floors tall. And there are other high-rises nearby.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How high up are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way to extrapolate that from the sample you gave us.  One more thing: There's an emergency siren approaching at 17 seconds into the second call, passing the location at 33.5 seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay -- high-rises in our search area. Eight stories or higher.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Downtown, Century City, Westwood corridor, Museum Row, Mid- Wilshire... North of Sunset Strip there's a few...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sabatini! What about that billboard?</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing yet! Everyone's left their goddamn offices already!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>LAPD will have a record of all emergency vehicles running Code 3 at 9:32 AM. Get their starting point and their destination.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And have them narrow their foot- searches to areas around high-rises.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's that fuckin' address?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, we hear the high-pitched whine as Dave's MODEM connects with another computer. Dave's fingers fly across the keyboard, and in a moment, a PICTURE of Javal appears: hair longer, bearded... but the eyes are unmistakable.</context>
      <utterance>I'm still holdin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's on our hit parade. Interpol passed us his records when he entered the country.  French by birth... looks like a total scumbag.</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that redundant?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raised in Quebec. Moved to Europe; served some short stretches, petty shit... arrested for kidnapping, no conviction. Did four years in France for blowing bank vaults. Moved to U.S. last year. Clean since then.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get his Driver's License number; Social; bank accounts; charge cards; club memberships... find out what movies he rented. Get whoever's closest to the Auto Shop to get in there, interview everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This sure was a ballsy move for a car-alarm installer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn, noticing that Ambassador Han has overheard.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, he watched the news... Everyone knows the U.S. will do anything to avoid trouble with a mad-dog country.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ambassador --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Quit apologizing for me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quit giving me reasons to!</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miranda gives Carson a "your turn to be gracious" look.</context>
      <utterance>On occasion, my wife has been known to kick my ankle under the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not exactly what Miranda was hoping for. Dave hands Carson a piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds like her aim's a little low.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Address, according to the Auto Shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson and Miranda grab their jackets, then she stops.</context>
      <utterance>Apartment 1060! He's in a high-rise! Sabatini -- you're with us.  She's got the field experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson looks again at the address...</context>
      <utterance>There still could be accomplices. If there are, they'll hear us in the helicopter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a TV station a couple blocks away. We'll land on their pad.  K-EYE. Clear it with 'em. Have a SWAT team assemble, but tell 'em to hang back unless we need 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, great, the media...  It's the goddamn traffic girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Traffic person.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't get into that right now...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson grabs the ENG camera, pops the videotape out of it and crushes the tape.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you expect to use my station's facilities and not even tell us --</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miranda is utterly aghast. She reaches under Carson's jacket and takes the handcuffs off his shoulder rig. She grabs Bobbi by the arm and gets her in a half-Nelson.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you, the Barbie Corporate Ass-Lick model?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The STATION MANAGER comes running out of the building.</context>
      <utterance>Guess what, Sister... you're about to spend the next five years in a penitentiary for interfering with a federal investigation.</utterance>
   <speaker>STATION MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bobbi! I promised we'd respect their news blackout!</utterance>
   <speaker>STATION MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get an exclusive later, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This works out, I'll play the fuckin' banjo for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miranda and Colonel Lee immediately get out of the car and run off, leaving Sabatini to contend with it.</context>
      <utterance>We're hoofing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To park the fuckin' car!</context>
      <utterance>'She's got the field experience'...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They lower their weapons.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa... FBI..!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell you get here so fast?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAT TEAM #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're shootin' a cop movie down the street. We're workin' as extras.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terrific. Who else is here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAT TEAM #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three officers on the roof, next building over, and two in the tenth- floor hallway.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell 'em to be cool. We're going up.  Give me your master key.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAT TEAM #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feds going up -- Anglo male and female; Asian male.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her friend sits up. Miranda holds her finger to her lips and shows them her FBI shield.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck..!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson cranks open their window and steps out onto the foot- wide, ornamental balcony.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins to protest. He shoots her a look that silences her.</context>
      <utterance>Wait here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colonel Lee walks over to Sabatini.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>SABATINI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Carson?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sabatini starts down the hall. Colonel Lee stays where he is.</context>
      <utterance>Inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He punches Colonel Lee in the jaw. Colonel Lee slams against the wall, then comes back at Carson, hitting him in the throat.</context>
      <utterance>I said keep everyone back!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miranda and SWAT Team 2 pull them apart.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kneels next to Sabatini, and closes her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of my sight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marchfelder.</utterance>
   <speaker>STATION MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You dated the Mayor, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need a traffic ticket fixed?</utterance>
   <speaker>STATION MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try to confirm something for us. There's an incredible buzz on the Internet -- someone picked up a classified message on a U.S. Intelligence frequency. We think it's authentic!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the status?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBINS</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wilshire and West PD Divisions had seven vehicles running with sirens at 9:32. They're getting the routes from the officers now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances over at Miranda. After a beat:</context>
      <utterance>Hurry it the hell up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should've known she'd come up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pete --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- "Should've." Shit, there's a familiar word.  That day... I was there soon enough. We should've rushed 'em, before they could finish setting up...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson looks out the window, not hearing a word she says...</context>
      <utterance>The Bureau never would've let you. They want it by the book: talk them out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve bodies -- only the hostages.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were a greenhorn. It wasn't your decision. You can't keep living as such a raw nerve, never sleeping --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away. She takes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>-- Those kids were ten years old!  Same age as the Han boy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing Beach Boys MUSIC on the TV's and radios on the surveillance console, Carson angrily punches them all off. Suddenly, Miranda looks at him:</context>
      <utterance>C'mon! Who's pulling Javal's bank records? What about cross-referencing possible aliases? We got 33 minutes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Camry! The billboard! Toyota Camry!  Where are the numbers for the outdoor ad companies?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parker Center's making those calls.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn the fuckin' camera on! DO IT!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAMERAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's why they got a news blackout!</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's true... probably is true.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs and turns the CAMERA on.</context>
      <utterance>I'll rip your miserable eyeballs out! NEWS IS OUR FUCKIN' JOB!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finally got the call list from Javal's phone. Most aren't his; they're from the legit user who didn't know his number was cloned.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to the bottom of the list, work back through the last 12 hours. Dave jumps to the bottom, points at a number.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's the call to the Consulate --</utterance>
   <speaker>965-5000.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rest are dupes... all from the other guy...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dave highlights a number: 213-965-5666.</context>
      <utterance>Wait... go back... the one at seven this morning...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colonel Lee STRAFES the room and backs toward the door. The BULLETS trace a line across the room. One of the North Korean Espionage Agents is HIT. He slams against the console. Carson tackles Ambassador Han and shoves him onto the floor, while popping off several ROUNDS in Colonel Lee's direction. Robbins also dives for cover, pushing Walther down first. Robbins takes a BULLET in the shoulder. Miranda is HIT. The impact tumbles her over the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Get down!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go..!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he HEARS, on a nearby car's FM RADIO:</context>
      <utterance>Shit, it's like a Godzilla movie out here!</utterance>
   <speaker>FM NEWSCASTER</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...These words, which have terrified the city:</utterance>
   <speaker>RECORDING OF BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Stunned, Carson looks over at Ambassador Han, who buries his face in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>...A biological weapon, allegedly containing the deadly Pneumonic Plague, is approaching Los Angeles...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miranda..!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard. I'm in the copter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to get out of here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't... My kids...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>He squeezes his eyes shut... After a long beat:</context>
      <utterance>Listen: the best way to help them is to stay at your computer. If any information comes in, holler. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...The Colonel hired Javal, made it look like he was working alone. Then he made sure Javal got killed, so we'd never find your family -- and they'd have an excuse to drop their bomb. But what's in it for 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are men in my government whose power depends on North Korea staying as it is: Socialist, repressive, isolated from the world. They'll resort to anything, even war, to keep it that way. They have the Hitler Syndrome: if their country cannot exist the way they want it, they would rather see it destroyed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VREELAND</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>FBI, this is Major Vreeland. Discontinue your pursuit, we're gonna box his ears from up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative -- his car's armored! And we need the bastard alive!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VREELAND</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got the situation in hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of yours?  What the hell do you need heat- seeking rockets for in L.A.?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There could be another riot...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Han.</context>
      <utterance>And they call me Mr. Overkill.  Dave, what do you know about...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strela-2...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strela-2 anti-aircraft rockets?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm with ya... Strela-2. Perenosniy zenitniy raketniy kompleks. Russian factory index 9K-32-M2 --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Skip the goddamn trivia! I need range, guidance, arming method, anything we can work with...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- You don't "work with" rockets, Peter!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay back. LAPD's putting up a roadblock.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That Kraut-mobile have any weaknesses you'd like to tell me about?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so -- they said it was solid as a rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Carson moves forward, Colonel Lee's window opens enough to allow the barrel of his AMD-74 machine gun to poke through. Carson shoves Ambassador Han's head down and ducks. Colonel Lee STRAFES the Volvo. Carson looks up just in time to see... A pickup truck, ahead, stalled on the shoulder. Carson slams on the brakes, but it's too late... The Volvo CRASHES headfirst into the back of the truck. The Volvo's AIRBAGS deploy, stopping Carson and Ambassador Han from plowing into the dashboard. After a beat:</context>
      <utterance>No shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe I'm still alive...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambassador Han looks at Carson, wondering if he's putting him on. The car is a twisted mess. Carson can't get the door open.</context>
      <utterance>This were a Hyundai you wouldn't be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pry his door open with a crowbar. Carson climbs onto the roof of his car. Grimacing from pain, he looks around.</context>
      <utterance>Get me out of here...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody see him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>The Paramedics pry the passenger door open and help Ambassador Han out. Carson looks at the ambulance. He's getting an idea...</context>
      <utterance>Still heading north on the 110.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dave... You're sure those rockets are heat-seeking?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Classic IR, reflective optical system. How come?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson climbs into the back of the ambulance.</context>
      <utterance>Just keep working your leads...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something small and nimble. Anybody... come in low, from the south... I'm on an ambulance by the 9th Street exit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you out of your mind?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get this fuckin' thing in the air!  Out! Not enough room for four.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAMERAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I supposed to do when the plague comes, hold my breath?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Switch to a secure channel.  What on earth are you thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make him open the sunroof. Someone can shoot tear gas or a percussion grenade inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pete, you haven't gone... suicidal or anything on me, have you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. I couldn't stand making so many people happy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You?! I wanted a police copter!</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell me what to do. I flew two tours in 'Nam.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he doesn't go unless I go!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong-o...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>surfaces, sputtering and screaming:</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson replies by tossing her industrial-sized bottle of Mylanta out after her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a respected electronic journalist, you fuckin' prick!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Pilot swings the helicopter in the other direction, and the rocket FOLLOWS the flare, streaking past the helicopter. A few seconds later, the rocket EXPLODES in midair behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fucking lunatic!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hope you got more flares than he's got rockets.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VARIOUS ANGLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson climbs up the embankment from Sixth Street to the 101... The downed L.A. Cop waves as a pair of ambulances drive up, lights flashing and sirens WAILING. Carson runs alongside one of the ambulances, pulling the driver's door open before it's stopped. The Paramedic is the one who helped him and Ambassador Han out of the Volvo. Carson yanks him out of his ambulance.</context>
      <utterance>As Miranda comes down from the sign...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're completely deranged! Playing chicken with rockets!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what the hell were you doing out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>Carson turns, surprised and annoyed to see Ambassador Han, his arm bandaged, lying in the cot in the back.</context>
      <utterance>What are both of you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lights and SIRENS going, they rush into the 110/101 interchange. Ahead, Colonel Lee's Mercedes is driving through the cars that are parting like the Red Sea for him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, for Christ's sake... Hold on!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if we can pry him out with...  Twelve minutes to go, I doubt he'll be very cooperative.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson glances up at the sign showing the upcoming exit: Glendale Blvd - Echo Park. A thought is forming...</context>
      <utterance>I'll just use my outstanding people skills.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That car's like a rock, right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns as his MODEM squawks and another download comes in.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit -- Knoll-It-All's turned into Dirty Harriet!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure there were no accounts in the other names I gave you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson's not so sure, but they're completely surrounded by military and law enforcement personnel. He releases his grasp. Miranda removes her heel. Then, with lightning reflexes, Colonel Lee grabs Vreeland's Rock Island Arsenal Colt .45 Auto from its snap-holster.</context>
      <utterance>Let him up.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson dives back onto him. But he twists his arm around and PULLS the trigger -- with the muzzle underneath his own chin. Carson, Miranda and Ambassador Han are SPRAYED with his blood.</context>
      <utterance>Victory!</utterance>
   <speaker>WIDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson, dogged, kneels next to Colonel Lee's body and searches through his pockets, looking for something, anything.</context>
      <utterance>Dumbfounded everybody looks at each other...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else come through?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a hint. We're screwed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context>Shaking his head, Dave glances at his computer...</context>
      <utterance>Not yet...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>fumbles to scroll back to the check.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! One of Javal's alias accounts: check for an apartment rental!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're shittin'... Where?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During this, outside:</context>
      <utterance>I'll try him in his car again...</utterance>
   <speaker>WESTEC GUARDS</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tenants -- leave your apartments at once... Take the stairs...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must know we're here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer.</context>
      <utterance>Help!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look over at her as she lights it. After a beat, Mrs. Han understands... She hesitates, then:</context>
      <utterance>Mother... Sam...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joy drops the lighter to the floor, then swats it with her foot to Mrs. Han. She does the same, passing it to Sam, who's sitting closest to the window. With one eye on the VU movement meter, Sam kicks the lighter, sliding it across the carpet toward the curtains.</context>
      <utterance>Do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miranda points to a wisp of SMOKE above one of the towers.</context>
      <utterance>Apartment number would be real helpful, gang...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come around, and spot the FIRE in the apartment's window. It is nine stories up, four stories below the top floor.</context>
      <utterance>There!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs one of the refrigerator handles and pulls, but it won't come loose. Lisa cries out in frustration.</context>
      <utterance>Okay... work with me here!</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson spots Javal's toolbox. In it, he finds a socket set handle, which he levers in between the refrigerator handle and the door. He rips one handle loose, then the other. Carson turns his attention to the booby-trapped chairs. Lisa sits on the floor, frantically pulling her handcuffed hands around her feet so they're in front of her, then runs for the front door. Just as she reaches it:</context>
      <utterance>Hurry, please hurry...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to go out the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you disarm the bomb?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the meters on the electronic units.</context>
      <utterance>Too risky. Let's concentrate on getting you out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sound detectors?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sam covered them with chewing gum.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson looks at Sam, impressed, then peers under the chairs.</context>
      <utterance>High-tech problem, low-tech solution.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pressure sensors. Use 'em in convertibles: Bad guy sits on your seat, he sets the alarm off. These are rigged backwards -- get up, you set 'em off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You a bomb expert?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson looks around, thinking. He spots the roll of duct tape on the table, grabs it and unrolls a long piece.</context>
      <utterance>Nope. But I've had some car alarms in my day.  For all the goddamn good they do...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wraps the armrest with tape, cinching it tight.</context>
      <utterance>Slide your arm forward... Watch the meter... Keep the pressure on the armrest with your elbow...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson feels for the sensor in the seat, finding it buried under Mrs. Han's thighs. He runs a long piece of tape around the seat and wraps it tightly. He tries to lift Mrs. Han, but the meter moves to the red.</context>
      <utterance>Low-tech solution...  Lean back... Carefully.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode>VO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it going in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wraps another piece of tape around the seat, and tries again to lift her. This time it works!</context>
      <utterance>Nag, nag, nag...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get out of here!</context>
      <utterance>Release the cable from your side!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come over the railing! Grab onto the harness!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tear the hook loose!</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll pop the winch buckle!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try it anyway!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was that on the phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Bureau.  They want me back on the hostage team.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miranda smiles, then looks at him, surprised, as he crouches down and helps her turn the soil around the rose bushes. They work in silence. Then, tentatively, she leans over and kisses him. Soon they're in each other's arms, holding tight...</context>
      <utterance>Told 'em I'd sleep on it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Working with you today was certainly... interesting, Inspector.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slips her out of her robe and they fall onto the bed. It is a tender, romantic moment... Until, (OS), a CAR ALARM goes off. Miranda bolts up.</context>
      <utterance>It's my outstanding people skills.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carson ignores the ALARM -- and Miranda's comment. He pushes her back onto the bed and turns off the bedside lamp. All of the books and magazines about other places to live spill from his nightstand, onto the floor...</context>
      <utterance>I hate this fucking town...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
