<movie id="469" title="Rush Hour 2">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The HORRIFIED GIRLS speed off, and Carter turns to Lee, who is driving and singing to his radio.</context>
      <utterance>Deng wa lu yun cai-shen wu.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I warned you about playing that shit when I'm in the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was my CD. Don't you ever touch a Chinese man's CD.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see the way those girls drove off? I did you a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those girls drove off because of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I did was invite them for a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You invited them to get naked and sacrifice a small goat.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said that? Which word was "goat?" Lee picks up his CD case.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You owe me a copy of the Beach Boys Greatest Hits, Volume Two.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be giving me attitude, Lee. I've been here three days and we haven't done shit. We haven't been to a club, haven't even talked to a girl. I'm on vacation, and I want some mu-shu.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mu-shu? You're hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter flips through the dictionary. A CALL COMES in over</context>
      <utterance>Not Mu-shu. Mu-shu. I want to see some women. Now stop playing dumb and show me the shu!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SUPERINDENDENT CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee, there was a bombing at the American Embassy. Two American translators were killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any leads?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERINDENDENT CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We think it's Ricky Tan. If you don't want to take the case, I'll understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee hangs up the cell phone.</context>
      <utterance>It's my responsibility.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee smiles at Carter.</context>
      <utterance>What was that? Did you just pick up a case? Did we just take another damn case on my vacation?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not. My Superindendent invited us to a club tonight. Big party.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be messing with me, Lee. I will kick your ass. I'll hit you so hard you'll end up in the Ming Dynasty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carter, would I lie to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm talking about. A real Hong Kong night club. You want an Altoid?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter looks at Lee. Fixes his collar.</context>
      <utterance>You better take one. Your breath has been a little funky all day. Let me look at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just relax and don't worry about a thing. I'll hook you up in there. You got condoms?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter dances through the door, Lee follows.</context>
      <utterance>Take this. It's a Magnum. You can fold it in half.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll meet you at the bar in ten minutes. They don't like tourists in here, so try to blend in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blend in? I'm two feet taller than everyone here. Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee walks off, trying not to be seen as Carter steps up to the bar, takes a seat next to TWO CHINESE THUGS.</context>
      <utterance>Bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The thugs ignore Carter as he motions to the stage, where the OLD MAN continues to sing.</context>
      <utterance>How you boys doing tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The thugs continue to ignore Carter.</context>
      <utterance>That is the worst singing I've ever heard. That sounds like something you'd hear in prison after lights out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carter, get off that stage!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter resumes singing, really getting down. Moonwalking to the EDGE of the STATE where Lee PULLS HIM OFF.</context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding, they love me. I'm a star, Lee. A god to these people!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a gangster bar, we're here undercover.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you were lying.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it, why are you ruining my night? I'm just starting to have fun.  Well fine then, go ahead, pull your badge and do your thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we're here for information, to find out where a man named Ricky Tan is. We must tread softly and keep our ears open.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tread softly? Who taught you how to roost a bar?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carter, you don't understand. These men are Fu-Cang-Long Triads. Part of the most deadly gang in China.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, are you crazy? You think that scares me? I'm from L.A. We invented gangs. We were having gang wars before anybody even thought about it. We get royalties from other gangs. Now gimme your badge and gun and I'll show you how it's done.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You are a civilian. In China, I am Michael Jackson, and you are Toto.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Lee can react, Carter has lifted Lee's badge and gun. Carter bounds back on stage, pulls the plug on the music and fires three SHOTS into the ceiling, silencing the bar.</context>
      <utterance>You mean Tito. We had Toto for dinner last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just said you're their worst nightmare - and to line their mothers up for a milking.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, Lee gets on stage. More looks from the Chinese as Carter speaks, Lee translating.</context>
      <utterance>Shit. C'mon, get up here and help me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nobody moves. Carter fires two more shots in the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, all the Triads and ugly women go to that side, all fine ass women on this side.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nobody moves.</context>
      <utterance>Let's try this again. Who here knows Ricky Tan, raise your hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nobody moves.</context>
      <utterance>Who here is named Lee? Raise your hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The crowd still hasn't moved. Except in the back, where Lee spots several GANGSTERS leaving. As Lee runs off stage --</context>
      <utterance>Now I know you're lying.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I come back and catch y'all singing Michael Jackson and you're all going to jail.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter jumps to grab hold of the scaffolding. NOT EVEN CLOSE. He backs up -- he's gonna take a running start! ABOVE - LEE REACHES 4 GANGSTERS. They all tear off the LENGTHS OF BAMBOO and square off. The clatter of wood against wood as they beat at each other. Wrestling over his pole, Lee FLINGS TWO of the GANGSTERS over the edge. BELOW, Carter has hold of the bottom rung, STRAINING MIGHTILY to pull himself up. Just as he gets his chin above the bar... snap! It BREAKS and he drops. Then... WHAM! WHAM! The two gangsters CRASH LAND ON EITHER side of CARTER. HE takes one look at their pain.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on, Lee. I'm coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He dashes into the stairwell. ABOVE, the last two GANGSTERS come at Lee. He stomps down, levering up floor boards, which SEE-SAWS them off-balance. With the advantage, he BATTERS them with his bamboo pole and knocks them off. He climbs after the GANGSTER LEADER. ON HU LI and the GANGSTERS Coming over the crest of the hill, seeing Carter climbing up the hill.</context>
      <utterance>Forget this...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I wanted was a little mu-shu.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter looks down at a rancid dumpster below them.</context>
      <utterance>Try to land on your feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The POLE BREAKS</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe I flew ten-thousand miles for this shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lied to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sorry. I got somebody's old chopsticks stuck in my ass, so don't tell me you're sorry. Just take me home.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter takes this in. Can't believe his own bad luck.</context>
      <utterance>No time. There was an explosion at the American Embassy today -- two American translators were killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that Ricky Tan, he's the one who blew up the Embassy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you right now, I'm tired of this shit. There's two billion Chinese - let one of them be your partner.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Master Fu barks out a barrage of SHAOLIN FIGHTING STANCES.</context>
      <utterance>This won't take long.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER FU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like well-trained army, the students YELL AND KICK HARD.</context>
      <utterance>Dragon kick!</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER FU</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The students YELL and form an "X" with their arms. Master Fu notices Carter and Lee watching from the back.</context>
      <utterance>Lotus block!</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER FU</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>No response. The students exchange baffled looks.</context>
      <utterance>Twisting Tiger!</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER FU</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D (CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Lee may be a big rusty, but he puts on a shit-kicking move that leaves the students blown away. Lee smiles, basking in the glow... ...until he sees Master Fu's disappointment.</context>
      <utterance>Twisting Tiger!</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER FU</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't I teach you to always arch your back?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Lee follows Master Fu, Carter stands in front of the 12 YEAR OLDS, who sit motionless around a fighting circle. Carter starts stretching his legs, warming up.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter throws a series of QUICK PUNCHES, but the kids have no reaction.</context>
      <utterance>I was watching you kids. My name is Carter, LAPD, and I'm a third degree black belt. At least that's what I tell the girls at the Holiday Health Spa where I work out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>THE KIDS DON'T MOVE, no reaction. Carter continues to throw punches.</context>
      <utterance>Let me give you kids some tips. The key to Kung Fu is the follow through. Why don't you stand up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The kids still don't move. Carter, working up a sweat from shadow fighting, takes off his JACKET, DRAPING IT over the HOLY BUDDHA behind him -- a mistake. He swings back around to face the kids and NEVER SEES THE KICK that sends him flying back onto the mat. He looks around and sees ALL of the kids STANDING, in FIGHTING POSITION.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, kick me, hit me. I'll show you how to block. Come on, stand up, give me your best shot -- try to kick right to my head.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's pretty good. Which one of you kids did that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need your help, Master. I'm seeking a man who used to train with you. He's become a killer - the worst kind of animal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER FU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the b.g., we see the kids leaping acrobatically over Carter from all sides. Carter, frustrated, tries to grab the kids out of the air as they fly by, but they elude him. They disappear O.S. Lee and Master Fu walk another moment, Master Fu lost in thought.</context>
      <utterance>Animals kill only from hunger or fear. The man you seek is lower than a serpent.  ...he kills for money.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER FU</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was the best I ever trained, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ricky Tan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER FU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Your father.  Your father and Ricky Tan were my favorite students... and for such awful things to happen as they did -- Lee cuts off Master Fu's reminisces -- he's obviously uncomfortable.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AGAIN IN THE B.G., Carter and the flying kids go zipping by in the other direction, disappear O.S. Master Fu pats the SOIL around a struggling plant.</context>
      <utterance>How do I find Ricky Tan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER FU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A seeding spends its entire life reaching towards Heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, Master, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER FU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The answers you seek can be found in Heaven on Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heaven on Earth? Master, I don't understand.  A temple, where Heaven is on Earth? A mountain, where Earth reaches for the --</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER FU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee bows to Master Fu, slowly turns to walk back down the pathway.</context>
      <utterance>It's a massage parlor downtown. "Heaven on Earth." You will find your answers there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER FU</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Lee puts a few bills in the jar, heads down a pathway. Master Fu walks over and takes the cash.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! Put a c-note in the jar.</utterance>
   <speaker>MASTER FU</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheap bastard...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's how you use the LAPD choke hold. Now start practicing and don't make me come back here!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carter...you ready to have some fun!?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just follow my lead and act like a tourist.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am a tourist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>HOSTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee bows, followed by Carter.</context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon, gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My friend is on vacation, from America. I want to show him a good time.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOSTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you American?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOSTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bring American money?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hostess takes Carter by the arm, walks over to a HIDDEN SLIDING DOOR - slides it open to reveal TWENTY BEAUTIFUL WOMEN. Carter truly is in Heaven.</context>
      <utterance>Never leave home without it.  Lee, this one's on me. You save your money.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOSTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get massage from Chinese girl before?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's my first time.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOSTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter looks like a kid in a candy store.</context>
      <utterance>You pick any girl for you and your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any girl? Okay. Let's start with that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOSTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, she's very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee elbows Carter.</context>
      <utterance>She is nice. But I am very tense. I'm gonna need a lot of massages. I'll take that one, too. How you doin', baby? And...that one in pink. She can do my feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said I could pick any girl I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hurry up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! You don't break in front of a black man in a buffet line.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOSTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friend have big appetite.  Please put these on and wait upstairs in the quiet room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LEE doesn't respond. LEE IS STARING AT SOMEONE ON THE FAR SIDE OF THE ROOM. A man who radiates a unique blend of sophistication and brutality.</context>
      <utterance>Now I'm on vacation. I knew you'd come through, Lee.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over there -- that's Ricky Tan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Ricky Tan? He's four feet tall. I'll go over with you right now, shake him down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a very dangerous man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a dangerous man. You're not gonna ruin my massage because of some midget in a house coat.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee gets up from a chair, hurriedly exits. Carter looks at RICKY TAN -- sitting quietly in his chair with his LAPTOP COMPUTER on his knees. Carter makes a decision, gets up and walks towards him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm calling for back up!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tan looks up for a moment, a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Ricky Tan, I've been looking all over for you. Get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm busy at the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said get on your feet!</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you, Detective Carter, right? You're Lee's American friend. Enjoying your visit?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tan laughs, goes back to his laptop. CARTER GRABS THE LAPTOP from Ricky and throws it across the room - SHATTERING IT against the wall. Ricky glances at his men who are seated around the room waiting to move.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Lee's new muscle, his right arm -- and don't let the robe fool you. This is the only color they had left. Now get up!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Having heard the commotion, Lee arrives by Carter's side, breathless, as Tan looks up, surprised.</context>
      <utterance>I told you to get on your feet!</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee, I've missed you, brother.  I heard about the two Americans, I'm so sorry, you must be under great pressure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must come with me for questioning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go. I've got girls and chicken and hot oil waiting for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nod of Ricky Tan's head, and TEN LARGE MEN in robes and towels spring out of reclining chairs -- menacingly facing Lee and Carter. A beat...</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to pay you for that laptop.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's no problem. But I must excuse myself, inspector.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Chief Inspector, he got promoted. Tan bows to Lee and Carter.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Tan starts to exit, Lee and Carter move to intercept him. But they are blocked by TAN'S MEN. Lee grabs one of the men's towels and pulls it off. The man covers his naked body. Lee is grabbed by one of the other henchmen, but he escapes and begins kicking ass, using the towel and his own robe to block and wrap another man's arms -- blocking, kicking, and punching everything in sight -- all the while managing to keep his privates covered with a towel, his robe, or some other found object. Carter, meanwhile, uses his quick hands to send several men flying back -- grabbing a towel of one of them.</context>
      <utterance>Congratulations. And good day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn you got a small ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look at my ass!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT STERLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chin, you have been ordered by the Ministry of Public Security to assist the FBI and Secret Service with our investigation, to provide us with whatever we need. If you have information, it belongs to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERINDENDENT CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is still Hong Kong.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT STERLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two Americans have been killed on United States Government property -- this is our investigation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERINDENDENT CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chief Inspector Lee will brief your people...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT STERLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SUDDENLY ALL EYES turn as Carter and Lee enter the bullpen. Out of breath, still robed: Lee covering himself with a trash can lid, Carter using a red construction cone.</context>
      <utterance>No. He will report to me. Do we understand each other?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT STERLING</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERINDENDENT CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is...Chief Inspector Lee. The detective in charge of our investigation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT STERLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put a diaper on him, Chin. I want to talk to the great Inspector Lee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back to Heaven on Earth. I need my damn passport back. I'm going home.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Go home. Who needs you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you mad at me? You needed back-up, so I backed you up. I was about to take out Ricky Tan and those bodyguards.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop! I'm sick of your bullshit!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My bullshit? I'm not the one who goes to a karaoke bar filled with gangsters! I'm not the one who goes to massage parlors to bust crime lords!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my job!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're pathetic, man. When's the last time you had some fun? When's the last time you took a night off, had a date?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have plenty of dates.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? When's the last time you had some Mu-shu Let's hear it, Lee, when was it? Year of the rat?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You would never understand my life. You're not Chinese.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men look at each other for a long BEAT. Lee quickly walks out, slamming the door behind him, leaving Carter half dressed.</context>
      <utterance>And you ain't black!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SUPERINDENDENT CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee, this is Special Agent Sterling from the United States Secret Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Secret Service? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I'm about to tell you cannot leave this room. The men who were killed yesterday were not American translators. They were undercover U.S. customs agents trying to break a Triad smuggling ring. We don't know what they're transporting out of Hong Kong, but whatever it is, it got the agents killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can we help?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay the hell out of our way.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can get to Ricky Tan.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know all about Tan. That's why we're leaving him out there as bait. We think this is a lot bigger than just Ricky Tan and his Fu-Cang-Long Triads.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN DIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it true, Carter? Are you in Hong Kong right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hong Kong? I'm not in Hong Kong. I'm in Hollywood -- right at Sunset and Vine, two minutes from the station. How about I pick you up right now and take you to dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN DIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nine-thirty in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I say dinner? I meant diner. Biscuits and gravy, you love that shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN DIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what happened yesterday, Carter? I was officially nominated for the Commissioner's post for the LAPD. There was a dinner last night, two hundred LAPD officers were there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two hundred cops? Was Mario Sanchez there? He owes me money.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN DIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've waited my whole life for this job, but I don't have a shot in hell of getting it. Do you know why?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it because of the hookers, sir? You tell them there's no crime in being lonely.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN DIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Carter. The reason I'm screwed is because the entire department is about to find out the stolen credit cards we impounded were used to buy two first class upgrades to Hong Kong. And what the hell is Heaven on Earth?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Carter walks out the DOOR, he brushes past HU LI, who is standing in the hallway disguised as a FED EX DELIVERY PERSON. Carter checks her out as he exits.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I'm working on a big case over here -- and by the time I get back they're gonna make you Governor. Captain, you there? Hello? Shit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The OLD WOMAN stares at Carter, starts motioning to her CAGES filled with birds.</context>
      <utterance>How you doing? Can you direct me to the Heaven on Earth massage parlor?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Woman takes out a bird, holds up a HATCHET.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't eat live birds. I like my birds dead and deep fried. You ever been to Popeyes?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, don't do that, I had a big lunch. I'm warning you, I'm a police officer -- just put the blade down and let the bird go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shan-shui cao guo-jiu, pao gai niu tao zi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wish to spank my sister with a ping pong paddle?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No man, I was just asking...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the man walks into his store, Carter runs off. Pause. Carter strolls back INTO FRAME, peering into the store to see if it's worth staying...</context>
      <utterance>Wait here. I'll go see if she's awake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All he wanted was some mu-shu.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERINDENDENT CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay, Lee?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I have to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cab Driver continues to stare at Carter.</context>
      <utterance>Follow that limo.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The driver slowly turns, holding out his hand. Carter fishes in his pocket hands the cab driver a wad of cash.</context>
      <utterance>You understand what I'm saying? Follow that car! Where it goes, you go! This is a chase -- we are chasing that limo!  We are still parked -- we're not moving! This is the opposite of chasing -- drive the car or I will kill you!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAB DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you speak my language.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SUPERINDENDENT CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee, we just got a call from the harbor patrol. Ricky Tan is throwing a little party on his boat tonight. Victoria harbor. If you don't want to...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you tell Sterling?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERINDENDENT CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him find out on his own. I want the Hong Kong police handling this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee hangs up. A look of intensity. He CRANKS the RAP MUSIC up, a man on a mission.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay here. I'll be right back. You understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAB DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter steps out of the cab, which immediately drives off, leaving him alone on the docks. Carter looks around the dock -- a pull up valet station parking fancy cars, RICH PEOPLE getting on the boat as their names are checked off a list by two DOORMEN.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I understand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DOORMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Invitation, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm with the band. I'm the lead singer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The band has been playing over an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Carter walks past the doorman --</context>
      <utterance>I got held up at a wedding in Tai Koo. Ricky here yet, I need to get his requests.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last party all he wanted was Sting -- not one person danced. Tonight I'm doing Superfreak, I don't care what he says. Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter turns back to the doorman, grabs him by the collar.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Tan is not to be disturbed by the help.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter cuts a smoking DANCE MOVE.</context>
      <utterance>Help? I'm not the help, man -- I'm the star. That's my band up there -- I control the mood, the groove, the atmosphere.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Carter walks onto the ship, starts singing to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Can you do that?  That's why you're down here and I'm up there. Now this is my party -- don't forget it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you doing, baby? My name is Prince Mubutu from Nigeria.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isabella Molina, from San Juan. That seat is taken.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>San Juan! You must know my good friend Pedro Martinez Hernandez Hector Elizondo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, you looked like you traveled in the best circles. But hey, I understand. Make yourself at home, Isabella. Champagne, caviar, whatever you want. My ship is your ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is your ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. I'm the owner, the Captain -- you can call me El Capitan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>El Capitan?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to play games with you, Isabella. I like you. I can see myself with you -- in one of those bathrooms over there in about five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm very tempted. It's such a beautiful yacht. What's it called?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Called? What's my ship called?  Well...it's called the S.S. Minnow Johnson.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The S.S. Minow Johnson. Funny, the name on the back was "Red Dragon."</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red Dragon? You sure about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure, because this is my friend's yacht. And it's his party.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friend's ship?  Oh, man. I must've walked onto the wrong yacht. I knew there was a reason my keys didn't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVEN REIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's your friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody who got on the wrong yacht.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a second. You're Steven Reign? You're big time. You own all them big hotels. What are you doing in Hong Kong?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVEN REIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just in town for the weekend, taking in the sights.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter nods, waves. Steven Reign and Isabella walk away. Carter's watching.</context>
      <utterance>Enjoy the party, Mr. Carter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ricky Tan. Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>BODYGUARD #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's asking?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Hong Kong Police. He killed a detective today and he's not getting away with it. Now where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee slowly turns around and looks at Carter, who is standing right behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Tell us! And don't play games or we'll kick your lying ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carter?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who died?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Detective Yu? Never met him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not Yu. You!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you understand the words that are coming out of my mouth?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody understands the words that are coming out of your mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>BODYGUARD #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee and Carter turn to see FOUR BODYGUARDS standing in front of them with GUNS in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Get your hands in the air.</utterance>
   <speaker>BODYGUARD #1</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ricky Tan is expecting you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Shaq, hit a damn free-throw! You can do it, big guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tan turns off the TV, turns to Lee.</context>
      <utterance>Shit! He still doesn't follow through. I just lost five grand.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Hu Li hesitates, upset at being dismissed.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't we go on the deck, get some air...and some privacy.  Leave us alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you have your partner wait for us outside?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't his partner, I'm a tourist. I got proof. See, I got a mini-bar key.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter pulls Lee aside.</context>
      <utterance>I'll meet you on the main deck in ten minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, leave you alone so he can cap you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay, you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the hell should you believe him? He had us beat up. Naked. That's nasty shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember I told you my father was a policeman?  Ricky Tan was his partner for ten years.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Despite what people suspect...what you suspect --</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricky Tan hears the steel in Lee's voice, acknowledges it.</context>
      <utterance>Don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... if your father were alive, I would be turning to him now.  I didn't blow up the American Embassy, but I believe some of my people did. My enemies are trying to frame me.  There is a war going on within the Triads -- and I am going to lose. My name has been written into the book of death.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The police can protect you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody can protect me. I'll make a deal with you, Lee. But only iff you'll get me out of Hong Kong.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me why they killed the customs agents.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hu Li BURSTS onto the deck, flanked by FOUR BODYGUARDS. Ricky Tan screams something at Hu Li in Chinese. Hu Li screams back as SHE EMPTIES HER GUN INTO RICKY'S CHEST. Tan falls back, over the rail, and into the water. Lee MOVES TOWARDS HU LI, but the four bodyguards are on Lee, attacking from all sides. Hu Li exits as Lee tries to fight off the bodyguards.</context>
      <utterance>There is a ship, in the Hong Kong Harbor...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT STERLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite a night, Inspector. Ricky Tan was our only bait, and now he's gone. You finally got your revenge - at the expense of a U.S. Government investigation.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What "revenge" is he talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT STERLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if the Fu-Cang-Long paid you to get rid of Tan, or whether it was a pure vendetta killing -- but you're off this case. I don't ever want to see you again, you got that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you, Secret Service Man, what are you --</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL AGENT STERLING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay out of it, Carter. You're going back to L.A.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sterling walks away disgusted.</context>
      <utterance>Fine with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERINDENDENT CHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee nods a respectful but bitter acknowledgment. Chin motions for two uniformed Hong Kong police officers to approach.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Lee, but my orders are to fully cooperate with the Secret Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERINDENDENT CHIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Escort Detective Carter to the airport --</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hong Kong police officers produce HANDCUFFS. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Hell no.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Carter stalks off.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. But don't expect me to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter gets in Lee's face. The two men look like they're about to come to blows.</context>
      <utterance>Don't push me, Carter. I'm in no mood for your bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna do about it, grasshopper?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bitch slap you into Bangkok.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me your best shot, you flat assed mama's boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be talking about my mama. Or my ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard your mama pulls a rickshaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. She's a school teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not very good at this, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good at what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat while Lee considers what to say.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five years ago, my father was Chief Inspector working a big international smuggling case.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee waits a beat, then drops the bombshell.</context>
      <utterance>Ask me if I give a shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter is suddenly all ears, listening intently now to Lee.</context>
      <utterance>Ricky Tan killed my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He found out his partner, Tan, had been working for the Triads all along.  Before my father could prove it, he was killed in the line of duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell did Tan get away with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the evidence against him disappeared, the smuggling case was unsolved. Tan resigned and went over to the Triads openly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee's caught, fibs badly.</context>
      <utterance>This is about your Daddy's death? Hell, Lee, you know my father died on the job. You could have told me...  This is about more than all that, isn't it? This is about your Daddy's last case, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, that would be crazy --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You thought the "Customs Agents get blown up" and "smuggling" and "Ricky Tan" and you put it all together and came up with a five year old case. That's why you didn't tell me what we were doing...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you'd think it was crazy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee inclines his head, stiffly, turns and walks toward his car. Carter watches him. Finally he rolls his eyes and yells.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I know. I am sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are you getting on the plane or not?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, we still got time to order the Kosher meal. Always get the kosher meal, they bring it first.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter steps close, and for a second we see the man and the cop beneath the attitude.</context>
      <utterance>I cannot go to LA...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sounds impossible --</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said --</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter turns, walks away without looking back.</context>
      <utterance>-- but if somebody gave me the chance to square up my father's death, I'd go to hell to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to figure out why they killed your Daddy, get on the plane.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why LA?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess you're going to have to trust me on this one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should go back. Ricky Tan mentioned a boat in Hong Kong Harbor...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee, let me introduce you to the Carter Theory of Criminal Investigation: Follow the Rich White Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Follow the Rich White Man?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost, but you've got to say "Rich White Man" all run together like it's one word.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Follow the RichWhiteMan...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad. Now every crime, somewhere, has a rich white man taking his cut. Every single one. Now in our case, we know the rich white man is Steven Reign.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big hotel billionaire. He was on Ricky Tan's boat ordering Hu Li around just before Ricky got smoked.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know he's our man?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because when the shooting started he was way too cool. See most white people, when there's shooting, they either hide in a toilet or start screaming high pitched like "Aaaahhh!!! Aaaahh!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sound like that all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Black people keep their cool when the shit goes down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. But not like Asians. We never panic.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, what about when Godzilla was coming? You people were screaming your asses off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell me where I can find this Steven Reign.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The same place you find all RichWhiteMen.  Gefilte Fish. Lox and bagel. I love this stuff. Here, try it with a smear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's definitely the woman from Ricky Tan's boat, and she's staying in his suite at his hotel, I told you this would work out. They still just talking?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just left. Kissed her on the cheek.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll be back soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee lowers the binoculars, turns to Carter, who is trying to sleep on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Look at her. Now, wake me in an hour, I'll take over.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carter, there's something I have to tell you. You were right about what you said in Hong Kong. All I do is work. Never take a day off. It's all I have right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I didn't mean to call you pathetic.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The truth is, I haven't had any mu-shu in six months.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You pull a muscle or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My fiancee left me over the summer -- a month before our wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Lee. Why did she leave you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a long story.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me guess, she couldn't handle the cop thing -- never knowing if you were dead or alive. I've seen it a million times.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It was my singing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter stares at Lee for a long BEAT.</context>
      <utterance>She hated my voice. Said it drove her crazy. I sang to her all the time - in bed - in the shower - I thought she liked it. She finally told me it was driving her crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LEE LIFTS THE BINOCULARS - turns back to the building.</context>
      <utterance>Lee, maybe it's best if we don't discuss our personal lives. Let's die curious.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's she doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Lee's eyes go wide as Isabella drops her coat and starts to unbutton her blouse.</context>
      <utterance>Lee? You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's just standing around -- not doing much.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just don't fall asleep. Sooner or later something's gonna happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isabella starts to remove her blouse. Lee starting to sweat as he watches her undress.</context>
      <utterance>I'll try to stay awake. It's so boring.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slow down, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee lowers his binoculars, steps away from the window.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I said nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it hot in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hot? I'm freezing my ass off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna go in the hall and get a bucket of ice. You want some ice?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee stares at Carter, looks dazed.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's getting undressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme the binoculars.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's not right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee hands Carter the binoculars, then turns his back as Carter watches to the window.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme the binoculars or I will shoot you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's she doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, sweet glory hallelujah...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to hear this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skirt just came off. She's in black bra and panties -- Victoria Secret Spring Catalogue, page 27 -- wait a sec - there's a tattoo on her left thigh... it looks like Snoopy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Snoopy? I love Snoopy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee steps in front of Carter, blocking his view.</context>
      <utterance>She just took her hair down. Now she's going for the bra -- the clasp is in front -- she's using both hands.  You better get that ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isabella suddenly drops undressing and walks back to the living room to pick up the PHONE. We see her clearly now in bra and panties.</context>
      <utterance>That's enough. We shouldn't be doing this!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee backs off, and Carter steps back to the window. He sees Isabella hang up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>This is our job. We took an oath as police officers. If we don't do this, who will? Firemen?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a sec - what the hell is that between her legs?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's reaching into her panties -- something is strapped to her leg. Oh, God...please don't let it be a dick.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't believe this shit -- it's a microphone. Lee, she's wired...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's walking back towards the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pick it up!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your turn!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter picks it up, starts running with it through the hall, heading for the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>I don't need a turn!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter is about to throw it in, when HE SEES AN OLDER COUPLE</context>
      <utterance>Throw it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOTEL GUESTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want us to hold the elevator?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter is still holding the bomb, doesn't know what to do with it --</context>
      <utterance>Get the hell away from here!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter throws him the bomb, and Lee runs to the stairs --</context>
      <utterance>Stairs!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee looks horrified as he hangs onto the package, has no choice but to throw it back to Carter.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of the building!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roof!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! There's people down there!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's people up here!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get it out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee takes the bomb, quickly ROLLS IT across the roof -- Lee and Carter diving to the ground once again as the bomb slides to the center of the roof - COMING TO A STOP RIGHT IN FRONT OF ISABELLA. She's wearing a bathrobe now, clearly pissed off as she slowly bends down and picks up the package.</context>
      <utterance>Take it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee and Carter stand and face Isabella - watch as Isabella begins to open the package.</context>
      <utterance>Get on your feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't do that!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isabella opens the package, removing a stack of a HUNDRED</context>
      <utterance>It's a bomb.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, no bomb. Now stay away before I throw you both in jail for obstruction.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Throw us in jail? I'm about to bust you right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm an undercover agent for the United States Secret Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isabella opens her bathrobe -- WE SEE a small BADGE pinned to her bra.</context>
      <utterance>How do we know you're not lying? Let me see your badge.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me see it again?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can help you. I'm a detective in Hong Kong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who you are, Inspector Lee.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you know I'm not walking away from this case.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to get out of sight. Come down to my suite.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I've been working this case for months now...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's your story?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee examines the stack of HUNDRED DOLLAR BILLS from Hu Li's package. Carter checks out the suite, pocketing some of the food from the mini fridge.</context>
      <utterance>They think I'm a crooked customs agent.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this a payoff?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's a sample. You guys ever heard of the Superbill?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a myth. Some kind of counterfeit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's much more than a counterfeit. 14 out of 15 world banks can't tell the difference. The paper is Crane linen blend -- and the bills are printed on U.S. Intaglio presses.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How're they getting into the U.S. Mint to use the presses?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In 1959, the United States was very friendly with the Shah of Iran. We wanted his oil, so for the Shah's birthday, the government gave him a gift -- a U.S. Treasury Intaglio press. The only one to ever leave the country. Five years ago Ricky Tan bought that press on the black market.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee and Carter exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>Five years ago?!  That's right before he left the force.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't hard to spot the fakes until this past year. Then Tan got hold of one of a kind Swiss made hundred dollar plates -- and started making superbills.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Hu Li killed him for the plates.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isabella lights a HUNDRED DOLLAR BILL on fire, and it burns</context>
      <utterance>Yes. They've printed and shipped one hundred million dollars, and there's only one way to spot a fake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They use an optical transfer ink from India that burns red -- the real ink burns black.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are they going to do with a hundred million dollars in funny money?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isabella thinks for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>The real question is, where are the plates? If we can find the plates, we can stop the whole operation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Carter nods.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe that's where you can help us. Carter, this is your city, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Lee nods.</context>
      <utterance>And Lee, you know Hu Li and the Triads?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Isabella opens the door to let Lee and Carter out. They exit quickly, trying to hide their excitement. CAMERA STAYS on Isabella as she takes out her CELL PHONE, punches in a number.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, find out where Hu Li's keeping the plates.  Welcome aboard, gentlemen. From this moment on, you're working for the United States Secret Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERLING</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sterling.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee and Carter are officially out of the Secret Service's way...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Secret Service Agent Carter. This is my calling, Lee. Give me six months and I'll be in Washington protecting a white guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We both know you would never take a bullet for someone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't know that. What are they gonna do, try and shoot the President during the interview? I'll bet Isabella can pull some strings. You saw the way she was staring at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She never even looked at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just jealous 'cos the girl picked me. I'm tall, dark and handsome, you're third world ugly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not third world ugly. Women like me, they think I'm cute. Like Snoopy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter's had the last word, he gets into the Vette. Lee reluctantly gets in, too.</context>
      <utterance>Snoopy is about six inches taller than you. I'm sorry, Lee, you never had a chance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny looks up at Carter. A cool, appraising glance.</context>
      <utterance>Kenny! How you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Kenny follows as Carter opens a door to --</context>
      <utterance>How's the action tonight? The house making out okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny grabs Carter's shoulder, pulling him aside.</context>
      <utterance>This is where I say I'm LAPD in a loud voice, they all scream and run and shit. Watch. It's real funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hear you got your ass kicked in Hong Kong, James.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?? Where'd you hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got my sources.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I got mine, meaning you. Nice how that works out.  I'm serious this time, I'm closing this place down.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>James, you see my kids back there? You know how much I'm paying for private school? How can you come in here with this attitude, you being little Chang's godfather?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little Chang is gonna have to go visit his daddy in jail if you don't cooperate.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jail!? James, you better back off. Badge or no badge, I'll kick your ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny takes a step back and throws a lightning fast martial arts move. Lee gets in front of Carter to protect him -- countering Kenny's move.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to see you try.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny throws out another precision martial arts sequence -- Lee BLOCKS -- Kenny ends in an advanced fighting stance.</context>
      <utterance>We're on, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They switch to Chinese.</context>
      <utterance>That's a good Twisting Tiger -- where did you learn that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Master Ching taught me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Praying Mantis school, in Bejing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee smiles, Carter looks back and forth from Lee to Kenny.</context>
      <utterance>No. Freddy Ching's, in Crenshaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing hanging out with Baby Duck?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby Duck?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what we all used to call him when he was a kid -- cause he was always quacking. Never shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee and Kenny laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I heard that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I need some info and I don't have time to play around.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this about the funny money?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been asking loud questions in all the wrong places all morning. How come you always save me for last, James? When are you gonna learn. Shit don't happen I don't know about.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So tell me what you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know Teddy Wu is cranking out a pretty good double sawbuck -- but you knew that too, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny considers this for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We already been there. This is big, Kenny. Benjamins. Secret Service calls 'em superbills. Banks can't even tell the difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of my regulars lost fifty thousand dollars at the table here last week. I was about to send my boys down to tune his ass up, when the guy comes in and pays off the whole thing. Including the vig -- brand new sequential hundred dollar bills. I knew something was wrong. Cause this guy's got a regular job, no way he comes up with fifty grand in cash. But I tested the bills, infrared. The whole thing. And they checked out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you still have the bills?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still have my lunch money from third grade.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny pushes a Chinese painting aside to reveal a WALL SAFE. He opens the safe and hands Carter a $100 bill. Carter checks it out.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme see 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter takes out a LIGHTER and holds the flame to it.</context>
      <utterance>See. It's perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Kenny's question is answered as the BILL BURNS BRIGHT RED.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew it. The guy's name is Zing. He works at the kitchen at Reign Plaza.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter and Lee move for the door.</context>
      <utterance>All right, Kenny. Thanks. You're off the hook. For now.</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you guys don't want to stay and have a bite? My wife's got the best mu shu this side of Compton. Carter and Lee exchange a look as we CUT TO:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HU LI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hu Li savors the moment.</context>
      <utterance>The great Chief Inspector Lee -- I will be remembered for ridding the Triads of your petulance.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter starts to leave, and Hu Li trains her gun on him, freezing him in his tracks. Isabella slowly walks several feet, ending up behind Lee as she speaks.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you just said I have no business being here, 'cos I was just leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hu Li looks at Isabella, nods an acknowledgement. BANG! Lee falls. Isabella's knocked him out from behind with the butt of her gun. BANG! Carter drops to one knee as Hu Li POUNDS him across the jaw with her fist.</context>
      <utterance>Hu Li, I think there's someone who will want to talk to them first.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hu Li lunges forward and KICKS Carter, sending him backwards.</context>
      <utterance>...oh, that's a filling right there. That's gonna cost you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HU LI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WORKERS pick up Lee, bring him to the back of the truck.</context>
      <utterance>Put them in the truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WORKERS start towards Carter. He holds up his hands.</context>
      <utterance>I should kill you right now, but I'm gonna let you live, 'cause you're fine, and maybe you can be reformed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As Carter walks towards the truck by Hu Li, they exchange a look of sheer hatred. As soon as he passes by her, Hu Li COLDCOCKS Carter with her gun.</context>
      <utterance>No more hitting. I'll get in the truck myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the first thing I told you -- never trust nobody. How could you fall for that shit? I knew she was dirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She saved our lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee looks disappointed.</context>
      <utterance>For how long? Face it, Lee, she's playing both sides.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, man I'm sorry. I know you got a thing for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhh, my head hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm about to be killed and you "Shhh" me! This wasn't my case, Lee. Ricky Tan didn't kill my father, the Fu-Cang Long are not in South Central. I didn't have to help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you help me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee thinks about this for a BEAT.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not used to having a partner.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are not partners. Between your daddy, my daddy, and the beating I just took, as far as I can tell all partners get you is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well we're not friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got that right. And we ain't brothers. Maybe we should just end this right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't talk to you, you don't talk to me. We'll die in peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you in the next world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe in reincarnation. So I won't see you in the next world.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe in heaven. You people believe in heaven?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. We have heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it the same heaven, or is it a Chinese heaven?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a Chinese heaven?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it might be like those five foot and under basketball leagues. They don't let everybody in.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we should stop talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine by me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You thinking about that girl that dumped you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she was the right girl, you'd be thinking about her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind your own business.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was the sex?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was no sex. She was very traditional. We were waiting until we were married.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding. No sex? Nothing? No mu-shu?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No mu-shu.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about a little king pao chicken?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kung pao chicken. Never.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steamed dumplings?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once in a while, steamed dumplings. But only when she was drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's rough, man. If I don't get steamed dumplings once a week, I go crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me the truth, Carter. Do you think I have a good voice?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee turns away from Carter.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it. It doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As long as you're asking...I think you have a pretty good voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew it. What does she know. You want me to sing something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That depends. How do the Fu-Cang-Long usually kill their victims?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll probably torture us first, shock our privates, then put two bullets in our eyes and one in the back of the head.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee clears his voice.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. Sing your ass off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you happen to see the most beautiful girl in the world...and if you did, was she crying, crying...hey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's focus. Every opponent has a weak spot. You ignore everything around you, and put all your energy into one perfect strike.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter opens the crate -- it's filled with SUPERBILLS, about $1,000,000 worth. He tosses a stack to Lee.</context>
      <utterance>I'll remember that next time I'm fighting a box.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Benjamin.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Benjamin?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Benjamin Franklin, he discovered electricity.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Chinese man discovered electricity.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No Chinese man discovered electricity.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes he did. He also invented the bicycle.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter pockets two stacks of superbills. Lee looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Now that I believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The truck lurches.</context>
      <utterance>You never know. Besides, I always wanted to die rich.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're slowing down. This must be it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>End of the line.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been a good friend, James Carter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no you don't. Don't you be getting corny on me, Lee. I'll kick your ass from here to Compton.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could never kick my ass. You mama's boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you talk about my mama.  That's more like it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vegas...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A TEN-STORY DRAGON. Fire shoots from its nostrils every 60</context>
      <utterance>Lee. I just got an idea how someone could launder a hundred million dollars in cash. They both turn around and come FACE TO FACE WITH:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red Dragon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee and Carter watch as limos pull up to the front of the hotel -- it's like a HOLLYWOOD PREMIERE. The richest of the rich are making their way inside.</context>
      <utterance>That was the name of Ricky Tan's boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a second. We can't go in like this. Look at this place, we gotta look fly. We gotta Mac out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is Mac out?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter and Lee start to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Follow me my Asian brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just stay down wind, because I think you stepped in some serious rat shit down there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter flashes his biggest smile as he pulls out a stack of superbills.</context>
      <utterance>May I help you gentlemen?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter puts his hand on Lee's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Black. 42-long. Nothing touches this body but pure silk. And get my partner something from the children's department.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter takes his hand off Lee's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Would your partner like silk as well? I personally like it when a couple matches.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couple? No, you got it wrong, there's no couple here. Just two single police officers working a very dangerous case.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. We have lots of big men chasing us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He WINKS as he walks off, and Carter looks at Lee.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure all the boys are chasing you two. Don't worry, I'll make you guys the bell of the ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the last time I go shopping with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That looks exactly like my Uncle Darrell.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buddha is the symbol of luck and good fortune.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are moving through the MAIN ENTRY HALL lined with TERRA COTTA CHINESE SOLDIERS - posed and dressed for battle. RICKSHAWS and BICYCLES take people through the hotel. The MAIN CASINO is roped off and empty. People crowded around the perimeter - a sign reads:</context>
      <utterance>Buddha is the symbol for fat and lazy. The man has the biggest tits in Asia.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LIGHTS DIM - a spotlight comes on and finds STEVEN REIGN on the balcony overlooking the ENTRANCE.</context>
      <utterance>$50,000 buy in -- EVERYBODY'S A WINNER!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVEN REIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reign smiles, flips a switch -- the CASINO COMES TO LIFE. Fireworks, bright lights, endless rows of tables, dealers waiting. A BAND PLAYS on a stage in the casino lounge. Chinese ACROBATS perform suspended from the ceiling and on the balconies above. Applause all around as the FLAME shoots out of the dragon's nostrils and the acrobats perform. Carter and Lee walk down the red carpet.</context>
      <utterance>A thousand years ago, a small, wealthy village in China hired a young Dragon to guard their treasure in a cave, hoping to scare off potential bandits. Their plan worked quite well, until the people of the village started sneaking the Dragon extra food -- hoping to make him bigger and stronger. The Dragon ate so much and grew so big -- that he eventually got stuck inside the cave -- and the treasure was stuck behind him for all eternity.  Ladies and gentlemen, I have found that lost treasure. It is here, inside the greatest casino in the world! Welcome to the Red Dragon, where everybody is a winner!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring us some twelve-year old scotch...  Get us a box of your finest cigars.  Give me ten dollars in nickels.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dice ROLLING on a craps table.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAPS DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see BLACKJACK DEALERS BUSTING - paying out CUSTOMERS. Hundred dollar slot machines paying out jackpots. GAMBLERS winning all over the casino. Then going to the main cage and exchanging their chips for SUPERBILLS.</context>
      <utterance>Winner! Seven!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As people pour into the casino, Steven Reign is making his way through the crowd, shaking hands and posing for pictures.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this place, Lee. The biggest front in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carter...here comes the rich white man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Carter walks off, a WOMAN grabs Lee and pulls him onto the dance floor.</context>
      <utterance>Wait here. I'll handle this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put your arms around me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isabella grabs him around the waist, pulls him close.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ASIAN BAND sings STRANGERS IN THE NIGHT as Lee tries his best to slow dance. An intimate moment between Isabella and Lee, her face nestled in the crook of his neck, hiding her face.</context>
      <utterance>Hold me close. There's cameras everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last time you needed my help I ended up in the back of a truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee starts to get into the music, moving his hips in a slow, sensual rhythm.</context>
      <utterance>I'm undercover. I had no choice. You have to trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You move well.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just trying to make it look real.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee looks over her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Look over there. That's the eye in the sky room.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Behind me is the soft count room. We're pretty sure the plates are back there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you go get them?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm wrong then my cover is blown.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stevie, how's it going my man? Somebody get a picture, we can use it for a mug shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVEN REIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Detective Carter, you always seem to show up where you don't belong.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lemme ask you something, Steven. And I want the truth. Is there any way I can date your daughter? Just dinner and a movie, maybe go listen to some jazz...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVEN REIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vegas has been my town for 30 years. I crawled out from under the first rock. Do you really think you can intimidate me here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right, you're a smart guy. Most counterfeiters only get ten cents on the dollar. But this is an even swap. Pure genius.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVEN REIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reign walks off with his men. Carter watches him leave.</context>
      <utterance>You play games with me, Detective, and you'll lose every time. Don't forget. The odds are always in favor of the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Secret Service almost busted Reign at his casino in Macao, but the place burned down before we could move in.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I know I can trust you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee dips her, holds her in his arms for a long BEAT.</context>
      <utterance>Dip me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm asking for real now -- will you help the Secret Service?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee holds her for a long BEAT, their lips almost touching. He finally lets her go, and she disappears into the crowd. Carter walks up, sees Lee standing alone on the dance floor.</context>
      <utterance>No.  But I'll help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee, what the hell are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dancing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dancing? I'm out here trying to strong arm Steven Reign, putting my life on the line, and you're up here dancing with some bimbo. Did she have a friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee motions to the room, where WE SEE a SECURITY GUARD standing in front of a small door.</context>
      <utterance>It was Isabella. She says the plates are in the soft count room.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isabella? Are you crazy, man? She almost got us killed. She's setting you up again!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm going to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter looks around the casino.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a second. There's guards all over the place. You'll need a distraction.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go to the craps table, make a big scene. When security comes over, you make your move.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try to keep them busy for five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give it my best shot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CRAPS DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter throws a HUNDRED THOUSAND in $100 BILLS onto the table.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, you're aware that we require a fifty-thousand dollar buy in to gamble here this weekend?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DEALER pushes 100K worth of CHIPS in front of Carter.</context>
      <utterance>I saw the sign, I can read. Now gimme a hundred-thousand in chips. And a Diet Coke and some wash-n-dries. Let's move, people, I came to play.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAPS DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are five hundred dollar chips.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you give me five-hundred dollar chips because I'm black?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAPS DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I just assumed...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You assumed a brother coming in here can only afford five-hundred dollars a roll, is that right? Are you a racist?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAPS DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PIT BOSS gets on his walkie-talkie.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone else at the table has thousand dollar chips, but the black man gets the nickel, is that it? Did my people survive two-hundred years of slavery so you could send us back to the cotton fields with five-hundred dollar chips? Do I look like Chicken George to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIT BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Floor security, we have a problem at table nine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answer me one question. How come Ben Vereen isn't performing here at the hotel? Is Ben Vereen not good enough for you people?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIT BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lionel Ritchie is performing here tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lionel Ritchie hasn't been black since the Commodores.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIT BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter watches as Lee moves past the guard and makes his way into the soft count room.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, you're going to have to calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BIG CROWD has gathered as the Security Guards try and push their way through. The pit boss picks up the phone, calls upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>I have a dream, where black people and white people can gamble together without getting different chips!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Carter starts clapping, and the confused crowd joins in as the Security Guards move in.</context>
      <utterance>Sing with me! "We shall overcome!"</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Now in the spirit of brotherhood, let's play craps!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GUARDS make their move. And Lee starts to fight them down the hall, using the cart as a shield as he RAMS into TWO MORE GUARDS, fights them off as he turns the corner toward the casino door -- but he gets slammed to the ground by a right cross. Hu Li threw the punch, a roll of quarters in her hand as she stands over him with FIVE TRIAD SOLDIERS. She holds a knife to Lee's throat.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. How's it going? You guys have change for a twenty?</utterance>
   <speaker>HU LI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the small grenade in Lee's mouth, tapes it shut. She holds the detonator in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Open your mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>HU LI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a ying-tao grenade, Inspector. Please follow me or I'll blow 32 teeth into your brain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CRAPS DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Winner six!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAPS DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two-hundred thousand!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter turns to the MAN next to him, who wears a traditional AFRICAN ROBE and is standing with a giant blonde escort.</context>
      <utterance>Two-hundred thousand dollars? Who wants a hundred dollars?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, your highness, have a hundred dollars. The Viagra is on me tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>GAMBLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not royalty, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say that, we're all royalty. My great grandmammy was Queen Nephertit -- we probably cousins, man. How much you got on the table?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAMBLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One million.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter turns to a BIG TEXAN who is standing with a GORGEOUS YOUNG GIRL who is falling out of her dress.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we definitely cousins now. Who wants to blow on my hand for luck?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Marlboro man, you mind if your lady blows on my hand for luck?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEXAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not my lady. She's my niece.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GIRL blows on the dice, and Carter stares down at her.</context>
      <utterance>Can I come over for Thanksgiving? Come on, baby, give me some luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice blowing. When's your next birthday, I'll be the cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEXAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, buddy, watch yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter throws the dice.</context>
      <utterance>Don't threaten me. I got friends in this town that will bite off your ears. Just sit tight, because I've got the dice and I am on fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAPS DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The table erupts as Carter grabs the dice.</context>
      <utterance>Winner, seven!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let it ride!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricky Tan - alive and well, turns around and stares at Lee. Isabella is standing next to him. Lee is shocked at the sight of Ricky Tan alive.</context>
      <utterance>Imagine a business where people hand you money. And you hand them back absolutely nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ricky Tan walks toward Lee, starts to smile.</context>
      <utterance>Now that's a true American dream. Thanks to a few pieces of metal and a very greed driven US Customs agent.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Lee stares at Isabella for a BEAT. Hu Li motions to one of the monitors.</context>
      <utterance>Look at you, you're ridiculous. You know it didn't have to be like this. But it's too bad! Like father, like son.</utterance>
   <speaker>HU LI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricky Tan looks at one of the MONITORS, sees Steven Reign walking down a hallway, about to walk into the PENTHOUSE</context>
      <utterance>He's going for the plates.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricky Tan shifts his attention back to Lee.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this old fool, what does he think he's doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's almost impossible to find a partner that's trustworthy and loyal. Wouldn't you agree, Lee?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CRAPS DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Winner! Four, winner!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several TRIAD SOLDIERS dressed like SECURITY GUARDS approach Carter's table.</context>
      <utterance>I'm up a hundred and fifty-grand. That's a Ferrari. Do they sell those here in the gift shop? Somebody cash me out!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIT BOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, we'd like to escort you to the cashier.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they walk toward the door marked "VIP ROOM", Carter glances at the MEN, knows he's in deep shit.</context>
      <utterance>That would be great. Don't want any of these rich white people to jump me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricky Tan walks out. Hu Li holds the detonator up to Lee, plays with the button.</context>
      <utterance>Chai Hu Li.  Have fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isabella cocks the gun, spins back and kicks the detonator from Hu Li's hand -- slamming her against the wall and sticking the gun under her chin.</context>
      <utterance>It's time to end this, Inspector.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Hu Li WHIPS her KNIFE around, catches Isabella across the hand -- the GUN SLIDING across the room near the detonator -- the TWO WOMEN fight around it. Lee watches them almost step on it - dives to the floor and rolls toward the detonator. He's about to grab it when:</context>
      <utterance>Don't move! United States Secret Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE TRIADS OPEN THE DOOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're about to move in.</utterance>
   <speaker>HU LI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Triads go for the detonator -- as Lee gets to his feet, KICKS Hu Li's legs out from under her. One of the Triads about to pick up the detonator - but Lee gets to him first. He fights with one hand tied behind his back. Hu Li and Isabella fight it out in the EYE IN THE SKY ROOM. Lee gets kicked towards the Eye In The Sky WINDOW.</context>
      <utterance>Get the detonator!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guards restrain him.</context>
      <utterance>Lee!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He SLAMS THE RACK OF CHIPS ACROSS THEIR FACES -- chips flying as the GUARDS hit the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme ask you something. Any of you ever felt $500,000 before?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't feel so good, does it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter and Lee see each other. They have the same simultaneous though:</context>
      <utterance>Black man gets on a hot streak and you're all trippin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Lee's eyes BUG - he sees it too, feet STAMPEDING past it! A high heel misses it by a fraction of an inch. He LUNGES for it, manages to CRADLE it in his taped hands when -- WHAM! He is BUMPED and it FLIES AWAY. The second it hits the floor, it is KICKED, skittering down the red carpet. ABOVE...the victor emerges in the Eye in the Sky Room. Hu Li STEPS OUT on the PAGODA ROOF and JUMPS DOWN. The DETONATOR ROLLS right past Hu Li. As she bends to PICK up the detonator, Lee knows he won't get there in time. Horrified, he SCREAMS at CARTER through the tape. Hu Li lifts the detonator. Carter finally pulls the TAPE OFF Lee's face. Lee SPITS the grenade into the air.</context>
      <utterance>This can't be good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hu Li HITS the TRIGGER just as it lands on a roulette table.</context>
      <utterance>Bomb!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me you had a bomb in your mouth?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you didn't!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hand on Carter's arm. THIS IS SERIOUS.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I did. I said MMMMMM!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ricky Tan is alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee jumps up, SPRINTS toward the elevators at the dragon end of the casino.</context>
      <utterance>We have to get to the Penthouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter stuffs his pockets with chips, then races after Lee. But halfway up the carpet. Carter stops. Lee turns to see what is holding him up. Hu Li SURVIVED the blast and Carter has turned to face her.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go after Ricky. I got this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carter...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee turns and runs off past the dragon. Unfortunately, FIVE TRIADS block his path. In a flurry of PUNCHES, Lee makes short work of them, and races toward the elevators.</context>
      <utterance>Just GO!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She pulls off her jacket, prepares to fight him in her undershirt.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna hold you back this time just because you're a woman. I'm gonna pretend you're a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She takes a sword from a Terra Cotta statue, SWINGS IT AROUND like a master.</context>
      <utterance>A very beautiful man with a perfect body who I'd like to take to the movies.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Quick, Carter reaches for a fighting stick off a Terra Cotta soldier. WHOOSH! She SLICES IT IN HALF. Carter reaches for another. SLICE! She's toying with him.</context>
      <utterance>I may have been absent the day we went over this in karate class.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps in, too weak and starts to fall. Lee grabs her and holds her in his arms. HE gently helps her down.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know which side you were on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DING! The elevator doors open. Isabella holds up a ROOM KEY - the key to the SUITE. Lee takes the key, backs away and steps into the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>Now you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ISABELLA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The elevator doors close.</context>
      <utterance>I'll try to get backup. Be careful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>American's love to gamble. Don't they, Mr. Reign?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVEN REIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm cutting our deal short. I'm leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And my plates?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVEN REIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reign shows Tan the gun in his belt. Grabs the bag and starts to walk toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>They stay with me. I'm sure you won't have a problem with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I enjoyed that little story you told about the Dragon and the treasure. My mother used to tell it to me all the time. Do you know the moral of that story, Mr. Reign?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVEN REIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tan grabs Reign from behind and stabs him with a knife.</context>
      <utterance>Greed will imprison us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee BURSTS through the suite door - watches as Reign falls dead to the floor. Ricky takes the black bag off the desk.</context>
      <utterance>I hate that fortune cookie shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricky Tan looks down at the gun in Reign's belt.</context>
      <utterance>Put the plates down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>WEAK in the KNEES, Carter looks to the SOUND ON HIS CHEST. He reaches through the slice in his jacket. Instead of a hand covered in blood, it comes out with a THICK WAD OF CASH!</context>
      <utterance>When are you people gonna learn? Don't mess with the brothas!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Carter runs for the elevator.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Benjamin!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just like your father, Lee. All these years hiding behind his badge. I wanted to help him, to share with him, but he was too afraid of change. When you think about it, I didn't really kill him. I just put him out of his misery.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put the plates down. It's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricky glances at the gun in Reign's belt.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think it's over. There are casinos all over this country. Let me make you a rich man, Lee. Don't make the same mistake he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you reach for that gun, I'm going to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ricky makes a play for the gun, but Lee is much too fast, taking the gun and pushing Ricky against the wall just as Carter bursts in the room.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you remember? I'm already dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee has the gun pressed to Tan's head. We've never seen him like this before.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ricky, how's it going man? What's up, Lee?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like me to tell you how your father died?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee doesn't respond. He keeps an eye on Ricky.</context>
      <utterance>Lee, you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee's finger is on the trigger -- he wants to pull the trigger but can't.</context>
      <utterance>He never begged for his life. Or tried to make a deal. All that he asked me, just seconds before I pulled the trigger, was that I promise not to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lee, wait a second. It's not worth it, man. He's making you do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's worth it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have it in you, Lee? Or are you gonna spend the rest of your life hiding like your father?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee is trying to pull the trigger, but he can't.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Lee. He's going to jail. You won, now just put the gun down.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY TAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tan takes the black bag and swings it toward Lee -- the plates hit him across the face and knock him down.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I thought.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they turn to the door -- Hu Li is walking toward them, bleeding and half-dead. She has ANOTHER BOMB IN HER HAND. This one twice the size of the one from earlier.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know about you, but I need a wine cooler.</utterance>
   <speaker>HU LI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll go together, Inspector.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hu Li hits the switch - starts to smile. Lee and Carter turn and RUN for the OPEN WINDOW.</context>
      <utterance>Please tell me she just asked for a ride to the airport.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We made it, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee and Carter look up to see the VERSACE SALESMAN and FOUR OF HIS FRIENDS sitting in the back of the limo staring at them. The BOYS are all drinking champagne and dressed for a night on the town.</context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERSACE SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee and Carter exchange looks as the limo stops in front of the hotel.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there is a God after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIMO DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In front of the hotel WE SEE FIRE TRUCKS, AMBULANCE, POLICE CARS and Isabella and Sterling arresting TWENTY TRIADS.</context>
      <utterance>Here we are. The Red Dragon hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERSACE SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're all going gambling and then to see Siegried and Roy. I hope you two are feeling lucky!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw that. She kissed you, didn't she? You played it cool, though. Walking away, never looking back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee and Carter watch as she gets on the plane.</context>
      <utterance>She's going home to New York. I need some ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That your gate down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm this way. I guess this is goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess so. Thank you, Carter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter steps back, BOWS TO LEE. Lee SHAKES CARTER'S HAND like a brother. The two men smile. Turn to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>You take care of yourself, Lee.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee pulls a BADGE from his pocket. Hands it to Carter.</context>
      <utterance>Carter, wait. There's something I want you to have.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father's badge? No way, man. I can't take this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter takes the badge. Smiles.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. I can finally let it go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter pulls out a WAD OF CASH.</context>
      <utterance>In that case, I got something for you. I picked it up at the hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About fifty grand. I won it at the tables.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Carter. I can't take this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter pulls out another wad of cash.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay, I got lots more.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They owe us, man. That's the least they can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This money is evidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee looks back toward Isabella.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Lee. Stop being a cop for five minutes and live it up. There must be something you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always wanted to go to Madison Square Garden. See the Knicks play.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New York City?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First class.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Plaza Hotel?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little Mu-shu.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other, smile.</context>
      <utterance>Some Kung-Pao?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could use a little vacation.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Lee and Carter start to walk away together, the MUSIC SWELLS. "WAR" starts to PLAY. They dance their way through a crowd of people, their arms raised as the two friends make their way through the airport.</context>
      <utterance>Amen to that, brother.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
