<movie id="473" title="Saving Private Ryan">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OMAHA BEACH, NORMANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>June 6, 1944</utterance>
   <speaker>0600 HOURS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>HUNDREDS OF LANDING CRAFT Each holding thirty men, near the beaches.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CLIFFS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the far end of the beach, a ninety- foot cliff. Topped by bunkers. Ringed by fortified machine gun nests. A clear line-of-fire down the entire beach.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEN LANDING CRAFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make their way toward the base of the cliffs. Running a gauntlet of explosions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>A FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure is CAPTAIN JOHN MILLER. Early thirties. By far the oldest man on the craft. Relaxed, battle-hardened, powerful, ignoring the hell around them. He smiles, puts a cigar in his mouth, strikes a match on the front of DeLancey's helmet and lights the cigar. DeLancey tries to look away but Miller grips him by the jaw and forces him to lock eyes. Miller smiles. DeLancey is terrified. Delancey Captain, are we all gonna die? Miller Hell no, two-thirds, tops. Delancey Oh, Jesus... Miller I want every one of you to look at the man on your left. Now look at the man on your right. Feel sorry for those to sons-of-bitches, they're going to get it, you're not going to get a scratch. A few, including DeLancey, manage thin smiles. Miller releases his grip on DeLancey who moves his jaw as if to see if it's broken. Miller pats him on the cheek and moves on to the bow.</context>
      <utterance>Pushes through the men. Puts himself in front of DeLancey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks over the gunwale at THE HELL</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what they have to do. Start up the ropes. Into the teeth of the German defenders.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back-straps his Thompson sub-machine gun. Starts climbing with the first group.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CLIFF FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking turns firing up at the Germans.</context>
      <utterance>The Americans swarm up the ropes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HALF-WAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another way to die.</context>
      <utterance>An American private is HIT. FALLS, taking two others with him. All three land on the rocks below.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEAR THE TOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Free climb, scrambling up the rocks.</context>
      <utterance>Less steep. They leave the ropes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sees an open gap. Deadly. Beyond is a protective overhang. With a clear line to the top.</context>
      <utterance>Joins half-a-dozen pinned down men. Others bottleneck behind them. Miller scans the route and the defenders.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller motions to six men huddled near him.</context>
      <utterance>That's the route.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SIX MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take an instant to get ready. Then SCRAMBLE into the gap.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE SIX MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SARGE, mid-twenties, experienced, Miller's right arm and best friend, dives into the rocks next to Miller. Sarge That's a goddamned shooting gallery, Captain.</context>
      <utterance>Are CUT TO RIBBONS by MACHINE GUN FIRE. All KILLED. They fall to the rocks below.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the only way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turns to the next half-dozen men.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reiben smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Turns, looking for the next six. His eyes fall on Sarge and REIBEN who is a cynical, sharp, New Yorker.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, can I put in for a transfer?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, meet me at the top, we'll start the paperwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE THIRD SIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moves into place. Sarge and Miller exchange a look. They both see the madness of what they're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER AND THE OTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OPEN UP on the Germans.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THE TWO GRENADES EXPLODE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Putt out the two worst machine gun nests.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crosses the gap. His men follow.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRING.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abandoning the perimeter defense of the bunkers. The Germans are CUT DOWN. MILLER motions to WADE, a small, wide-eyed, demolition man who's struggling under the weight of half-a dozen satchel charges.</context>
      <utterance>TWO DOZEN GERMANS FIRE BACK as they retreat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wade Captain, I love it when you say that. Miller, Sarge, Reiben and Jackson cover Wade as he races to the first of three bunkers. Dodging bullets from inside. Wade tosses a SATCHEL CHARGE into a gun port. A HUGE, MUFFLED EXPLOSION, rocks the bunker.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Wade, your turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER AND SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Survey the field.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell were you doing? Drawing fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worked, didn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tryin' to get yourself killed?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarge shakes his head at Miller, then he looks over the cliff at the scores of men, their shattered, burning bodies covering the rocks and the beach below. He's clearly affected. Miller coldly glances at the dead and wounded. Then he moves on, leading his surviving men toward the two remaining German bunkers. The SOUNDS OF BIG GUNS and MACHINE GUNS FIRE surround him. DISSOLVE TO:</context>
      <utterance>Don't need to, the Krauts go that covered.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>A CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Older than the others, sad-eyed, adds a sheet of paper to a large pile in his out-box.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE SHOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An outgoing telegram. It reads: "We regret to inform you...killed in action...heroic service..." This is the paperwork of death.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pulls out a file. Reads. Finds something troubling. Quickly shuffles through some other papers. Finds what he's looking for. Rises from his desk and hurries out of the office.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GENERAL MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One-armed colonel All four of them were in the same company in the 29th Infantry but we split them up after the Sullivan brothers died on the Juneau.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One-armed colonel No, sir. He was dropped about thirty miles inland, near Ramelle. That's still deep behind German lines. General Marshall hardens.</context>
      <utterance>Any contact with the fourth brother, James?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL MARSHALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if he's alive, we're going to send someone to get him the hell out of there. That's just what the General's staff wanted to hear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ! What the hell are we swimming in?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fertilizer, Captain, I think we're in a cranberry bog.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of the frying pan, into the fucking latrine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller barks to his RADIOMAN.</context>
      <utterance>Look at the bright side, the Krauts sure as hell don't want to advance and hold this cesspool.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MORE EXPLOSIONS. They all duck. Reiben's worried.</context>
      <utterance>Get Fire Control, we need some artillery... Radioman Trying, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, what if they send some other company into Caen ahead of us while we're pinned down here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, we're the only Rangers this side of the continent, we've got to be first into Caen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who cares?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I care. Don't you know what Caen's famous for, Sarge?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frogs?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lingerie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE GERMAN FIRE diminishes for an instant. Miller, Sarge and Reiben immediately rise and POUR FIRE at the German positions. GERMAN MACHINE GUN FIRE RESPONDS and they duck down again.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? So?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you ever heard of employee discounts? My uncle sells shoes, gets twenty-five percent off everything in the line, got a closet filled with the best looking shoes you ever seen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just picture some French number been spending all day, every day, making cream-colored, shear-body negligees with gentle-lift silk cups and gathered empire waists, what the hell you think she wears at night?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reiben, how the hell do you know so much about lingerie?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another pause in the German shelling. Reiben rises and BLASTS HIS B.A.R, then ducks as the GERMANS RETURN FIRE.</context>
      <utterance>Lingerie is my life, sir. My mother's got a shop in Brooklyn, I grew up in it, from the time I could crawl, we carry Caen lingerie, it's the best there is, it's all I been thinking about since the invasion.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a war on, good chance they're not still making lingerie in Caen.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Captain, they'll always make lingerie, it's one of the three basic needs of man -- food, shelter, silk teddies. Miller Dream on, private.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Radioman Captain, I've got Command, they want you back at H.Q., right away.</context>
      <utterance>Happy to, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MORTAR SHELL EXPLODES VERY CLOSE. After the debris stops falling, Sarge and Reiben rise, spitting out sludge. Reiben looks dubiously at Miller.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe the war's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay at it until you get fire control.  Keep 'em down, wait for the navy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller waits for a pause in the MORTAR BARRAGE, then scrambles out of the crater and takes off in a crouch-run.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller goes deeper into the H.Q. bunker where he finds a dozen officers with as many aides, runners and radiomen. Very busy. A field map dominates the center of the small space. The men in the room note Miller, a few nod to him respectfully. He's clearly someone special. COLONEL SAM ANDERSON is in command, talking on a field-phone. He's about fifty, firm and steady, the calm at the eye of the storm. He sees Miller and motions for him to wait.</context>
      <utterance>Miller, Company B, Second Rangers. Major Go on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lieutenant Captain, here's your company address list.</context>
      <utterance>...I understand your problem, but if we don't get those tanks off-loaded by 0600, we're going to have an entire division up at Caen with its ass hanging out of its pants... A LIEUTENANT steps up to Miller and hands him a sheet of paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lieutenant For letters to the families of your killed-in- action. Miller hands the list back to the Lieutenant.</context>
      <utterance>My what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find a chaplain.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anderson hangs up, speaks to an AIDE.</context>
      <utterance>...alright, let me know when.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colonel Anderson turns to Miller.</context>
      <utterance>Have the Second and Third Regiments hold at St. Michel until we get those tanks. Aide Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Report.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sector four is secured, we put out the last three German one-fifty-fives, found them about two miles in from Ponte du Hoc.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Resistance?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A company, Wehrmacht, no artillery, we took twenty-three prisoners, turned them over to intelligence.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Casualties?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An instant of SILENCE, all hear, none look.</context>
      <utterance>Fourty-four, twenty one dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They didn't want to give up those one-fifty-fives, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a hard assignment, that's why you got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are your men now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pinned down, a mile east of here, waiting for some help from the navy guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sending Simpson to take over for you, the division is going to Caen, you're not coming with us, I have something else for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a Private James Ryan who parachuted in with the Hundred-and- First near Ramelle. I want you to take a squad up there. If he's alive, bring him back to the beach for debarkation. Take whoever you need, you've got your pick of the company.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A private, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the last of four brothers, the other three were killed in action. This is straight from the Chief of Staff.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, sir...I...I...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spit it out, Captain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other officers freeze, listening without turning. Colonel Anderson glares at Miller.</context>
      <utterance>Respectfully, sir, sending men all the way up to Ramelle to save one private doesn't make a fucking, goddamned bit of sense.  Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller considers the question, then smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You think just because you hold the Congressional Medal of Honor, you can say any damn thing you please to your superior officers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colonel Anderson looks as if he's about to bit Miller's head off, then he smiles, too.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir, more or less.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Continue.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, I'll give you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller Shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>The numbers don't make sense, sir. His brothers are dead, that's too bad, but they're out of the equation. Sending men up there is bleeding heart crapola from three thousand miles away. One private is simply not worth a squad. Colonel anderson This one is. He's worth a lot more than that. Which is why I'm sending you, you're the best field officer there is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colonel Anderson listens with amused tolerance, but it's time to get back to business.</context>
      <utterance>Yes and no, sir, what about Morgan? Fine officer, regular church goer, writes poetry, he might like a mission like this.  And he's taller than me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller knows when to back off. He salutes.</context>
      <utterance>That's enough, Captain, you have your orders. Major Thomas will fill you in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller and Colonel Anderson exchange a private look.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller joins Major Thomas at one of the smaller map tables. Colonel Anderson watches Miller for an instant, then notices the other officers in the tent watching. A glare and they go back to work.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crouch-runs and dives into a crater with Sarge.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put on your traveling shoes, Sarge, we're heading out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Caen?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish. You and I are taking a squad up to Ramelle on a public relations mission.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You? Leading a squad?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some private up there lost three brothers, got a ticket home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the company?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simpson.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simpson? Jesus Christ on a fucking pogo stick!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want Reiben on B.A.R; Jackson with his sniper rifle; Beasley, demolition.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beasley's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Wade. Translators?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fresh out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Talbot?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty minutes ago. Miller Damn, I'll go see if I can find another one. You get Reiben, Jackson and Wade, meet me at transport.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They wait for a lull in the firing, then scramble out of the crater and crouch-run in opposite directions.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strides through the chaos, avoiding the passing vehicles. He sees his men and walks toward them. Reiben hurries up to Miller, pleading.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, sir, you can't take me to Ramelle, I gotta go to Caen, sir, please, I told you, they make Caen lingerie there, it's beautiful, it's the best there is, it's...oh, please, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I need a B.A.R. man, you're the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not, Kaback is, honest. Or what about Faulkner? Or that little guy with the glasses?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me, you're the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller jerks his head for his men to follow and he strides off toward the Supply Sergeant's table. Sarge falls in next to Miller.</context>
      <utterance>But, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get a translator, Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a line on one.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSPORT OPERATIONS TABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chaos. Vehicles THUNDERING by. The Supply Sergeant juggles runners and paperwork. Miller steps up to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant, I need a truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPPLY SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sir, fresh out of trucks, how 'bout a '38 Ford Roadster, hard-top, red with black interior.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>White-walls?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPPLY SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(to the Private)</context>
      <utterance>No white-walls, sir, there's a war on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A half-track, anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPPLY SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sir. Division is using everything on wheels to get up to Caen.  How come you guys aren't going? Miller ignores the question. He spies a jeep.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about that jeep?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPPLY SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's General Gavin's. His lap dog told me if anyone breathes on it, I'll get busted and if anyone so much as touches it with their little finger, I'll get court marshaled. If you were to take it, they'd shoot me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cap'n, does that mean we got to walk all the way up to Ramelle?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPPLY SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's at Ramelle beside a lot of Germans.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A paratrooper named Ryan. He's going home, if he's alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPPLY SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senator's son?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Supply Sergeant grunts as if punched in the belly.</context>
      <utterance>No, three brothers of his were killed in action. Command wants him out of there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPPLY SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller looks at him, noting his reaction coldly. The Supply Sergeant shifts his eyes toward General Gavin's jeep.</context>
      <utterance>Damn...I got a couple brothers...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham Yes, sir.</context>
      <utterance>I understand you speak French and German.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham A slight one in French. My German is clean. It has a touch of the Bavarian.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have an accent?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham knows enough geography to know what that means. Upham Uh, sir, there are Germans up at Ramelle.</context>
      <utterance>Good, you've been re-assigned to me, we're going to Ramelle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham Lots of them.</context>
      <utterance>That's my understanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham Sir, I've never been in combat. I make maps. I translate.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have a problem with that, Corporal?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham But, sir, I haven't held a gun since basic training.</context>
      <utterance>I need a translator, all mine have been killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller looks at him closely, not sure if he's joking. Upham I'm writing a book and I... Miller's expression gives him his answer. Upham Uh, how about a pencil?</context>
      <utterance>It'll come back to you. Get your gear. Upham hesitates. Upham Sir, may I bring my typewriter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller shoos him off.</context>
      <utterance>A small one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham scurries away. Miller sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Go, go...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, can I ask you a question?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, Reiben.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller doesn't raise his eyes from the map.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you planning on putting Private Ryan, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller points out a turn to Sarge.</context>
      <utterance>It's just that it's kind of crowded back here, I was wondering if you're expecting to have more room on the way back?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarge makes the turn. Miller folds up the map and pockets it.</context>
      <utterance>Left.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we've got a straight shot, due north, to Ramelle, twenty-six miles, two villages between here and there, St. Mere, then Bernay. We'll take the jeep as far as we can, then go on on foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We in radio contact with anybody up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody put the wrong crystals in every one of the Hundred-and-First's radios the night before the drop, not one of them works. We're going in blind.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I usually like surprises.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we likely to run into?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fucking mess, two maybe three Kraut divisions, no fronts, no lines, the drops were completely fouled up, we've got little pockets of paratroopers all over the place, trying to hang on. Command says we hold St. Mere, but north of that, it's all Krauts. Even if Ryan's where he's supposed to be, he's more than likely dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell of a mission.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep, hell of a mission.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wade It's not my turn.</context>
      <utterance>You want to shoot him, or should I?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackson?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham Miller?</context>
      <utterance>Hell, no, last time I shot a corporal, Cap'n Miller near bit my head off. Upham reacts to the metion of Miller's name.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller sighs, he knows what's coming.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want anybody to shoot him, that's an order. He speaks French and his German has a touch of the Bavarian. Upham Sir, are you Captain John Miller?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, I gotta tell you, the irony of this mission is fucking killing me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, how so?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should be on my way to Caen, sir. It's like Beethoven, the guy's one of the greatest composers ever lived and he goes deaf. Go figure, I mean, who'd he piss off? And here I am, the Beethoven of ladies foundation garments, one step away from Caen, the center of the known lingerie universe and instead, I'm going to Ramelle to save some fucking private who's probably already dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's to be a bright side, look for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, you know what Ramelle is famous for? Cheese. The rest of the company is going to Caen and we're going to the goddamned cheese capital of France. There is no bright side.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's always a bright side.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm listening, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wade Hell, I don't mind going to Ramelle, as long as there's something up there for me to blow up.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I, for one, like cheese. Wade pipes up cheerfully.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're a happy idiot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOTTLENECK OF AMERICAN VEHICLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A LIEUTENANT is roadmaster. Miller calls to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lieutenant Bad, sir. There're some eighty-eights hiding somewhere, knocking the hell out of our traffic.</context>
      <utterance>How's the road up to St. Mere?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller nods to Sarge who floors it. They take off, spraying gravel behind them. Ext. St. Mere Road - day The jeep barrels down the road, fast. The road is pock-marked with craters. They pass the wreckage of a pair of American jeeps. Direct hits. Sarge swerves around them without slowing.</context>
      <utterance>Anybody getting through? Lieutenant The lucky ones.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, this is better than Coney Island!</utterance>
   <speaker>A HUGE BUMP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bounces Reiben up and slams his back down on his shovel. He HOLLERS IN</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>AN EIGHTY-EIGHT SHELL SCREAMS IN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lands right behind them. BLOWS A NEW CRATER</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SARGE FLOORS IT. Everyone hangs on.</context>
      <utterance>Sarge?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER SHELL EXPLODES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty yards ahead of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Directs Sarge off the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've got the road zeroed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yanks the wheel, driving the jeep off the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE JEEP BOUNCES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The jeep tears along the rutted field.</context>
      <utterance>Off the shoulder. Nearly throwing everyone out. Somehow they hang on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER EXPLOSION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just behind them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE DRIVES MADLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not slowing down. Trying to avoid the biggest ruts and bumps.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER EXPLOSION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close on their side. Showers them with debris.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've got a hell of a spotter somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER EXPLOSION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even closer. The jeep's PEPPERED WITH SHRAPNEL. They BARREL THROUGH the smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>S-curves, Sarge.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turns shallow curves without slowing down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MILLER IGNORES IT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the only one who does.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham is very nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Captain, they got us zeroed.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all ignore him.</context>
      <utterance>That's bracketing, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know about bracketing. I read about it. The next one is going to land right on us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Captain...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE TIRES SCREAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bit more progress. It's almost out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Captain...</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE MORE PUSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The jeep rocks back in, deeper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Instantly take off. Away from the jeep. As fast as they can.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SHELL SCREAMS IN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The men hit the dirt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barely out of the BLAST PERIMETER. STUNNED by the concussion. SHOWERED with dirt, rock and debris.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is first up. Sarge and the men struggle to their feet. Hear MORE INCOMING. Miller grabs Upham by the collar and pulls him up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>THE EXPLOSIONS STOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reiben looks back through the trees at THE JEEP, which is nothing more than a burning carcass. He shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>THE MEN ALL STOP Panting. Struggling to catch their breath. Check their body parts. Everything's there. They have their weapons, most of their gear.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General Gavin is going to be very irritated at you, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stands on the edge of the woods, almost in a trance.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller, far away, quickly shifts his eyes and ears from position to position.</context>
      <utterance>Sssssh!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarge quickly opens up the map case. The men are dead silent, frozen in place.</context>
      <utterance>Sarge, maps.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarge quickly starts vectoring on the map. Miller snaps out of it.</context>
      <utterance>Two eighty-eights, just under two- and-a-half miles, that way, vector from the jeep, through those two trees at the base of the hill. The mortars came from behind that rise, there, four of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wade instantly starts cranking it up. Upham is amazed.</context>
      <utterance>Wade, the radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can tell all that, just by the sound, sire?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not all. There were nine gunners on the eighty-eights, one had a broken heel on his boot, two had bratwurst for supper last night, one of them is named Fritz, the other, Hans, maybe, I don't know, it's hard to tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarge finished vectoring.</context>
      <utterance>Corporal, you have just seen one of Captain Miller's many God-given talents. If, by some miracle, you survive, you will witness many more of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it, sir. We gonna go take care of those eighty-eights?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what we're here for.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller takes the handset from Wade and the map from Sarge.</context>
      <utterance>I've got command, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Baker Charley One, fire mark, sector three, foxtrot quadrant, four- three by baker-three. Two eighty- eights. Tell our boys to come in low from the east in case the Krauts have ack-ack. Good hunting. Over. A VOICE ON THE RADIO SIGNS OFF through the static. Wade packs up the radio. Miller folds up the map. Jackson Sir, wouldn't take us but a minute to put out them eighty-eights.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right, Captain, it might be kind of dangerous for those flyboys.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller heads off without pausing or looking back. The rest of the men don't like it, but they follow. Upham trails, amazed at Miller.</context>
      <utterance>Tell that to Private James Ryan. We've got our orders. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, where are you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham smiles lamely and moves on to Jackson.</context>
      <utterance>Get lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, where are you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You writin' a book or somethin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact, I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wade overhears and smiles at Upham.</context>
      <utterance>Figured.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Wade, that's spelled, W-A-D-E, I'm small but wiry, with piercing, steel-gray eyes, and a rough-hewn but handsome face, I'm from Colorado, my father's a mining engineer, don't you take notes?</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Demolition, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Since I was nine years old. They got a lot of explosives around mines. Me and my little brother could get into any warehouse you ever saw. Damn, we had fun!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Jackson. I'm from West Fork, Tennessee. My pappy's a preacher. Him and his two brothers got a ministry, The Blessed Church of the Wandering Gospel.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In West Fork?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the back of a nineteen and thirty- one stretch Hudson with a big ole' trailer.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't make jokes about things of, or related to, the preaching of the Holy Gospel, including the ministerial calling of my family.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So they travel around from place to place and preach?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got us a tent, forty-two feet across, eighteen feet at center, hundred-and-ten foldin' chairs. Circuit's eleven towns, covers all 'a Hasset County and most 'a Weller County. I expect that upon completion of my military service I will be joinin' said ministry.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all shake their heads. Miller's out of earshot.</context>
      <utterance>What about the Captain? Where's he from?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You figure that out, you got yourself one nice prize.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over three hundred bucks, last I heard. Wade Company's got a pool, five bucks gets you in, whoever guesses where the Captain's from and what he did as a civilian gets it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The whole kit and caboodle.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But everybody's heard of him, he won the Congressional Medal of Honor, he saved a dozen men.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody must know where he's from, what he did for a living.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody probably does.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just ask him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Captain prefers not to discuss certain aspects of his life, in particular, everything up to and including his enlistment in the United States Army.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reiben shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>I've been with him since Anzio. I'm closer to him that I am to my own brother but I don't even know what state he's from. Somewhere in the Northeast as near as I can figure. I don't even have a clue what he did for a living as civilian.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's gonna win the money for the simple reason that the Captain never was a civilian. They assembled him at O.C.S. out of spare body parts from dead G.I.'s. I know this for a fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got somethin' against the Cap'n?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all nod in assent, no argument there.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, no. I think he's the best officer in the whole goddamned army, bar none.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller walks on ahead, unaware of their conversation. Upham watches Miller, with even more curiosity.</context>
      <utterance>You got that right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, my feet are most uncomfortable. If I'd 'a known we was gonna have to walk all the way to Ramelle, I never would 'a volunteered for this here mission.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't volunteer, Jackson.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I most likely would have, sir, had I been given the opportunity.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we find Ryan and he's still alive, that son-of-a-bitch is gonna carry this goddamned B.A.R. back to the beach for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Army life is too dang easy, my feet have gone soft. Back home, we go out squirrel huntin', I walk forever and a day and then some, don't even raise a blister.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what a B.A.R. weighs? Nineteen and a half pounds, not counting ammo.  And you think these things are comfortable? They may look good but they weigh twelve pounds each, that's thirty-six pounds, right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what? I've got three satchel charges, six gammon grenades, a dozen- and-a-half pineapples, and all my regular gear. You don't hear me complaining.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's because, as I have pointed out on numerous occasions, you are a happy idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I just happen to take the Captain's advice and look at the bright side of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's easy, it runs in my family, take my grandfather, for example...</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Christ, now we gotta listen to that grandfather thing again.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As I was saying, before I was so rudely interrupted, my grandfather got old, as grandfathers tend to do. He needed someone to take care of him. We move around all the time, going from one mine to another, so we had to put him in a home. Nice enough place but kind of depressing. But not for Granddad. He just convinced himself he was on a cruise ship, going to Tahiti, he had his own cabin, first class, with room service. It just so happened that the weather was always lousy, so he never bothered to go up on deck. Happiest guy you ever saw until the day he died.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think he really believed it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who knows? It worked.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, you convince yourself you got a pack full of feathers and goddamned Private James Ryan can carry my fucking gear.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reiben, you can be very unpleasant to be around sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want unpleasant? Just wait, I can do much better than this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham, feeling bold and a bit naughty, decides to give it a shot.</context>
      <utterance>Look at Upham, you don't hear him complaining.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, as a matter of fact, I was just thinking... The men roll their eyes, expecting the worst.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men are stunned.</context>
      <utterance>That I'm so fucking tired of this goddamned walking, I'd pay a thousand dollars to see that bastard Ryan crawl on his belly over an acre of broken glass to hear my great-aunt Martha fart through a field-phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, he's a natural!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham wiggles with pride. Upham Positive, sir, I'm certain I'd remember. Miller eyes Upham respectfully and nods to the men.</context>
      <utterance>Upham, are you sure you've never been in combat?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk on.</context>
      <utterance>He's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller smiles, situation normal.</context>
      <utterance>Cap'n, my feet are most uncomfortable.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson gathers himself, takes off. GERMAN BULLETS BLAST, kicking up the cobblestone behind him. Jackson zig-zags and makes it to the cover of the far side.</context>
      <utterance>Stay low.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller nods to Upham.</context>
      <utterance>Dang! That was close!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham, scared shitless, doesn't move. Miller speaks to him very gently.</context>
      <utterance>Your turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham's frozen. He can barely breathe. Miller sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Zig-zag, change your pace a couple times, you'll be alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham nods. Miller gathers himself, takes a deep breath. CLOSE SHOT: MILLER'S HAND quivers.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'm going to draw fire for you.  But if I do, you goddamned well better go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks to Upham</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham nods, still terrified.</context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham runs.</context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GERMAN BULLET WHIZZES PAST Miller's ear. UPHAM gets to the far side. MILLER DUCKS BACK around the corner. Reiben and Wade don't even react to what Miller has just done. Sarge is pissed. He shakes his head at Miller, like an irritated parent.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, that guy can move.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn fool.  Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, he's fast!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the other side of the street, crouches in a doorway with Jackson. Upham is a bit in shock, less from the nearness of the bullets than from what Miller just did for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GERMAN BULLETS TRAIL HIM, shattering the cobblestones, inches behind him. HE MAKES IT across. Calls back to Sarge.</context>
      <utterance>DASHES across the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>UPHAM, tries to thank Miller.</context>
      <utterance>Bring 'em over.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller ignores him, motions to Sarge, Reiben and Wade.</context>
      <utterance>Captain, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One at a time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ducks out of the doorway and crouch- runs down the block. He passes a:</utterance>
   <speaker>BOMBED OUT BUILDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some badly wounded G.I.'s are being treated next to the dead. Blood puddles have spread out onto the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>Out of the line of fire. A dozen dead American soldiers lined up on the ground. The battered, bloody bodies, only partially covered by ponchos.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sees the dead and wounded, shows no reaction. Runs to:</utterance>
   <speaker>AN ALLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captain hamill Fundamentals, short runs, double up at the corners, one man close, one man wide. Be careful. Go. The squad takes off. Captain Hamill sees Miller. The two captains glance at the bars on their shoulders, then speak familiarly. Captain hamill How was the road in?</context>
      <utterance>Captain Hamill and his men are bunched there, out of the line of fire. He's sending off a squad to continue their door-to-door.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One by one, Miller's men join them in the alley.</context>
      <utterance>We had a jeep until a few hours ago, a nice one, it had a cute little flag with a couple of stars on it. Captain hamill Oh, what a shame.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captain Hamill points across a wide field toward a distant chateau that has a private chapel with a fifty-foot steeple. Captain hamill That's where your boy is. We've been trying to get him since this morning. He killed two of my men trying to get close enough for a shot. Miller eyes the distant steeple.</context>
      <utterance>We called in a strike on the eighty- eights that took it out, but it's the Kraut spotter that counts, wherever the hell that bastard is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson steps up. Miller points to the steeple. Jackson knows what he's supposed to do. He puts down his M-1 and takes off the long, zippered, leather sheath, strapped to his back. He spits a massive bullet of tobacco juice, then calmly and methodically unzips his leather case and pulls out a very unusual, long-barrel, rifle. Miller and his men give him some room. Hamill and his men, along with Upham, watch curiously. Jackson opens a two-foot tripod with a flick of his wrist, sits down and carefully attaches the rifle to it. Then he takes a scope from a narrow wooden box and mounts it. He adjusts the eye-piece and clicks in the bolt-action. Upham is fascinated.</context>
      <utterance>Jackson.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson pulls back the bolt and loads a single, over-sized shell.</context>
      <utterance>What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-ought-six, Norton long-barrel with dual-groove, parallel rifling, elevated three-glass scope and a single-throw hammer.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Army gave you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be a hell a shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson sights on a tree about a thousand yards away and FIRES. Evaluates. Calibrates the scope. He re-loads. Jackson FIRES AGAIN. Evaluates. Perfect. He wipes the dirt and sweat from his forehead, puts his eye to the sight and waits, absolutely motionless.</context>
      <utterance>Not where I come from.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That must be four thousand yards.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty-two-hundred, I figure.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson doesn't dignify that with an answer but he looks back with an expression that clearly says, "What are you, some kind of fucking idiot?" Reiben puts himself between Upham and Jackson.</context>
      <utterance>You take account of the wind?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson keeps his eye to the scope and his finger on the trigger.</context>
      <utterance>Dang right, he take 'count of the wind, ain't ya'll ever heard a Kentucky windage?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reiben, how many time I got to tell you, I'm from Tennessee.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson FIRES. Waits. A tiny smile. He starts taking apart the rifle. A very impressed Captain Hamill barks to his radioman. Captain Hamill Get a hold of Command, tell them the St. Mere road is open. The Radioman cranks up his radio. Captain Hamill turns to Miller. Captain Hamill How far back is the rest of division?</context>
      <utterance>They got squirrels there, too, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captain Hamill Goddamn it, I was afraid of that. We're in a lot of trouble up here, and it's gonna get worse before it gets better. How many men did you bring?</context>
      <utterance>Very far, they're not coming this way, they're going to take Caen first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captain hamill Shit, are you the guys going up to find Private Ryan?</context>
      <utterance>Five, but we not staying, we're on our way to Ramelle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captain hamill Command radioed, wanted to know if he came in with the early wounded or dead. Several of CAPTAIN HAMILL'S MEN, among them a GENTLE-FACED PRIVATE, prick up their ears at the mention of Private Ryan. Captain hamill We're supposed to tell you, they intercepted a German transmission after you left. The Krauts have two companies on their way to Ramelle to take back that bridge, they'll be there sometime late tomorrow.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you know about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captain Hamill If Ryan's alive, you'd better get him the hell out of there before those Krauts show up.</context>
      <utterance>Wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captain hamill You don't, until tonight, we're hemmed in real tight. After dark you try to slip out to the east. If you tip-toe, stay off the main roads and roll a few sevens, you've got a fair chance of making it up to Ramelle by tomorrow night. Miller processes the information. Captain Hamill shakes his head. Captain hamill Tough, huh? Three brothers? Miller shrugs. Captain hamill We sure as hell could use your help here, but I understand what you're doing?</context>
      <utterance>How do we get out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captain hamill Good luck.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captain hamill I mean it. Find him. Get him home. Miller is a bit taken aback by Captain Hamill's forceful sincerity. Then he shakes it off and motions to his men.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller nods to Captain Hamill, then, as he moves to the head of the alley, Miller passes Upham.</context>
      <utterance>Let's find someplace to hole up.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I'm sorry about what happened,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you could have gotten killed and</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off, crouch-running back down the block. Upham watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>Like I said, it was nothing.  Don't bunch up.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see what he did, back there? He stepped right into the open, so I could get across.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, that was no big deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They can't kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like hell they can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wade's right, it's some kind of scientific, magnetic thing, I can't explain it, but I've seen it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men are equal parts joking and admiring. Sarge is neither.</context>
      <utterance>We all have, he's got nine lives, or he's bulletproof, or some damn thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarge takes off after Miller.</context>
      <utterance>No one's bulletproof. No one.  C'mon, stay low.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, could you please explain the math of this mission to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, what do you want to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sir, in purely arithmetic terms, since when does six equal one? What's the sense in risking six guys to save one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ours is not to reason why.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind, don't worry, we'll pick up this kid, high-tail it back to division, everything'll work out fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd much rather die in Caen than Ramelle, sir. It's a personal thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reiben, there's a fairly good chance you're not going to die at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy for you to say, sir.  Fucking James Ryan, I'd like to wring his fucking neck.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Reiben, think of the poor bastard's mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I got a mother. Jackson, you got a mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last I knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller smiles. Reiben eyes him and reconsiders.</context>
      <utterance>Wade, Sarge, Corporal Insect, all of us, hell, I'll bet even the Captain has a mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe not the Captain, but the rest of us have mothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have orders, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I have an opinion on this matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd love to hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems to me, Cap'n, this mission is a serious misallocation of valuable military resources. Miller Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller nods.</context>
      <utterance>Well, sir, by my way a thinkin' I am a finely made instrument of warfare. What I mean by that is, if you was to put me with this here sniper rifle anywhere up to and includin' one mile from Adolf Hitler, with a clear line of sight, war's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson, continue.</context>
      <utterance>Reiben, I want you to listen closely to Jackson. This is the way to gripe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. It seems to me, sir, that the entire resources of the United States Army oughta be dedicated to one thing and one thing only, and that is to put me and this here weapon on a rooftop, smack-dab in the middle of Berlin, Germany. Now I ain't one to question decisions made up on high, sir, but it seems to me that saving one private, no matter how grievous the losses of his family, is a waste of my God-given talent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wade?</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, I don't mind this mission, sir, as long as there's something up at Ramelle for...</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...for you to blow up, yeah, yeah, we heard that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Upham?</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarge?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reiben eyes Miller.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just here to keep a bunch of numb-nuts, including one certain, frequently suicidal, tempter-of-fate, from getting themselves killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller looks at Reiben, shocked.</context>
      <utterance>And what about you, Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reiben, what's the matter with you? I don't gripe to you. I'm a captain. There's a chain of command. Griping goes one way, up, only up, never down. You gripe to me, I gripe to my superior officers. Up, get it? I don't gripe to you, I don't gripe in front of you. How long you been in the army?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller considers his response.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir, I apologize.  But if you weren't a captain, or if I were a major, what would you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reiben rolls his eyes. Miller plays it straight, with no obvious sarcasm.</context>
      <utterance>In that case, I would say this is an excellent mission, with an extremely valuable objective, worthy of my best efforts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In addition, as I pointed out earlier, I have a fondness for cheese and I hope to have the opportunity to sample some of the Ramelle products, when we arrive there, to see if they live up to their excellent reputation. Moreover, I feel heartfelt sorrow for the mother of Private James Ryan and I'm more than willing to lay down my life, and the lives of my men, especially you, Reiben, to help relieve her suffering. The men thoroughly enjoy the performance.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, if you were not a captain, I would compliment you, now, for being an excellent liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men all learn forward expectantly, believing they're about to find out Miller's home town. Miller smiles.</context>
      <utterance>But I am a captain. If I were not a captain, I would thank you for the compliment and tell you that the ability to lie comes from being a top-notch poker player, which I am, having learned at the side of my mother who is, by popular acclaim, the best poker player in...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men ease back, disappointed.</context>
      <utterance>...my home town, which shall remain un-named.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any further thoughts on the subject?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir, as a final note, I'd like to say, fuck our orders, fuck Ramelle, fuck the cheese capital of France and while we're at it, fuck Private James Ryan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men wince and laugh. Miller checks his watch and gets serious.</context>
      <utterance>I'll make a note of your suggestions but I'll leave that last one to you, especially if he's already dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men know when to can it. Without another word, they all settle down into the debris, close their eyes and try to follow Miller's order. Upham looks around at these strange men, then, a simple, hard glare from Miller makes him follow suit. Miller looks at his men, then pulls out his map case and his flashlight. He turns it on, in the dim glow of the light, he studies his maps while his men rest.</context>
      <utterance>We move out in two hours, try and get some sleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller keeps his eyes on the maps.</context>
      <utterance>You ever going to open those letters?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not normal, not reading letters from home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when have things been normal?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got me. Afraid of bad news?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller looks at Sarge. A moment passes between the two of them, then miller takes refuge in the maps. Sarge looks at the men.</context>
      <utterance>Good news?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think they'll be alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're fine. As long as they can gripe, they'll be alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller considers the question, doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>And what about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They guys here aren't going to be able to hold out until battalion shows up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Command isn't going to let them withdraw and the Germans sure as hell aren't going to let them surrender.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three for three.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we stayed, we could make a difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit in silence for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>You never know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope this boy Ryan is worth it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you're the one kidding yourself.  Hell of a mission.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller looks at his watch, rises and barks at the men.</context>
      <utterance>Yup, hell of a mission.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grumbling, the men get up and start shouldering up their gear.</context>
      <utterance>Rise and shine, boys. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EVERY MAN THERE IS TRANSFIXED.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILLER stares at his hand, forcing it to stop. Their eyes go back to the BLAZING SKY.</context>
      <utterance>Frozen in place. The lights play on their faces. MILLER looks down and sees his hand quivering. SARGE notices, says nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Makes you feel small, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham's face shows more fear than awe.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't take this.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't made for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham manages a slight smile. Miller watches the lights for a moment more, then he pretends to shrug it off.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Upham, God'll protect you, this shit's gonna keep him up all night, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captain Hamill is next to snap himself out of it. He points the way. Captain hamill Along the wall, about thirty yards, there's a gate, on the other side, a drainage ditch, stay low until you clear the second field, then you'll hit the woods. As Miller and his men shoulder their gear and prepare to move out, on of Captain Hamill's men, the Gentle-Faced Private who was so interested in the talk of Private Ryan, steps up with a couple bandoleers of B.A.R. ammo. He offers them to Reiben. Gentle-faced private Here. Reiben looks at the bandoleers and is about to give a smart- ass response, when a look at the Gentle-Faced Private's vulnerable expression stops the comment dead. Gentle-faced private My older brother was killed at Guadalcanal...these might come in handy. Reiben takes the ammo.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go, this ain't what they pay us for.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller steps over, takes the bandoleers from Reiben and hands them back to the Gentle-Faced Private.</context>
      <utterance>Just what I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captain Hamill nods to the Gentle-Faced Private who takes the ammo back.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, but you may need these more than us, or Ryan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller and his men head off along the wall into the darkness, lit intermittently by the distant flashes. Captain Hamill and his beleaguered men, watch them go with dread and a strange bit of hope.</context>
      <utterance>Let's move out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A couple of weeks. It started in Portsmouth when they brought us down for loading.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it getting worse?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It comes and goes. It stops when I look at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may have to find yourself a new line of work, this one doesn't seem to agree with you anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarge looks at Miller, closely, evaluating him, they walk on.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be alright.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like a Renoir.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Do you know Sibelius' Fourth Symphony, The Normandy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been humming it.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seemed appropriate.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know classical music?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you from, Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham smiles, caught.</context>
      <utterance>What's the pool up to?</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over three-hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you what, if I'm still alive when it hits five-hundred, I'll let you know and we'll split the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's the way you feel, why don't we wait until it's up to a thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham looks closely at Miller and sees that he means it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't expect to live that long.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller takes a last look at the view and allows himself to feel an overwhelming wave of sadness. Then he turns himself back into a commander and barks at Upham.</context>
      <utterance>Five hundred, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller strides away. Upham watches him, trying to figure him out, then he simply follows him.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go, private.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five nights ago, he found this paratrooper caught in a tree with a broken leg. The leg got infected. Last night he went to Ville Cholet to get a doctor. The doctor refused to come and when he got back, this is what he found. The Krauts must have shown up while he was gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham gently asks. The FARMER ANSWERS.</context>
      <utterance>Did he see any sign of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but he heard firing, just east, less that a kilometer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller heads off without glancing back. The men hesitate. Sarge jerks his head for them to move out. They do so. Upham squats down and speaks softly to the Farmer, puts his hand on the man's shoulder, then rises and follows the others.</context>
      <utterance>Thank him and tell him we're sorry about his loss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the shadow by those two trees.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My guess, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller eases back from the edge of the field into the cover of the brush. He stands and takes off his pack.</context>
      <utterance>A machine gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I've got an idea, let's go around.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't leave it here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We left them eighty-eights.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham steels himself and steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>They don't send planes to put out machine guns.  Two flank runners with surpressing fire. I'm going right, whoever goes left has to be fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I ran the 220 in high school.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller takes Upham's measure. Wade laughs with a sneer.</context>
      <utterance>He's fast, Captain, I saw him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How fast?</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-four-five.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, that's nothing, I ran twenty- two flat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wade joins Miller in peeling off his extra gear. Upham is impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Wade goes left.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wade takes a grenade from Upham's chest strap.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-two flat?</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller points the others to their firing positions.</context>
      <utterance>I would have won the states if some bastard hadn't tripped me in the finals.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they take their positions, Miller and Sarge speak quietly, out of earshot of the men.</context>
      <utterance>Sarge, Upham, here. Jackson, Reiben, ten yards, either side.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller looks at the two dead paratroopers.</context>
      <utterance>Rule of thumb, Captain, says you ought to detail this one, instead of going yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? What rule of thumb is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about I go right, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarge hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>How about you take your position?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarge nods.</context>
      <utterance>How about you shut up and take your position?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarge finds a spot. Miller joins Wade. Miller waits near Upham as the other men settle into their firing positions.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't need it, I'm a cat, I've got five lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The men said, nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do they know?  I had nine, but I feel through the ice when I was seven, my brother pulled me out. Then I used one when a grenade landed in my foxhole in Sicily, it was a dud. I figure one on the beaches, one on the cliffs and two getting here.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That only leaves three.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller sees that the men are in position. He nods to Wade.</context>
      <utterance>Plenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller and Wade take deep breaths. Miller Now.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SPRINTS MILLER HITS THE DIRT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullets SMASH into the ground all around Miller.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLAMS in another. FIRES.</context>
      <utterance>FIRES A LONG BURST from his Thompson. No effect. Pissed. POPS THE CLIP.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten more yards. Too slow. A deadly row of BULLETS KICK UP DIRT toward him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Makes it to the far side. Scrambles up the roots. Dives through the brush.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WADE IS HIT. HEAVY BULLETS RIP APART HIS BELLY. He spins. Goes down. SARGE, UPHAM AND THE OTHERS are horrified. FIRE at the nest.</context>
      <utterance>On a slight rise. Can't hit the dirt. A line of bullets. Desperately sprints.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SARGE AND THE OTHERS POUR FIRE at the nest.</context>
      <utterance>STRUGGLES through the hedgerow. Stumbles onto the path. Rolls to his feet, running. Swings his Thompson into firing position. Racing toward the nest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tearing along the path. Sees a German rifleman. FIRES A BURST. CUTS HIM DOWN. Runs over the body without breaking stride.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>TEARS THROUGH THE TREES. BLASTS his Thompson. CUTS DOWN two more German riflemen. Grabs a grenade. Pulls the pin.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE NEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Germans see Miller coming. Wheel from Sarge. Too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE GRENADE EXPLODES. The four Germans in the nest are</context>
      <utterance>THROWS the grenade, VEERS and DIVES.</utterance>
   <speaker>KILLED.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SARGE hollers to the others.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>REIBEN AND UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop instantly. Turn toward the perimeter of the field.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roots through his medical kit as he runs. Dropping and scattering inessentials behind him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wide-eyed. Not even writhing. Too much pain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pours sulfa powder.</context>
      <utterance>Pulls Wade's hands from the wound.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About to pour his sulfa. Sees the wound. Stops. Knows it's fatal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Throws the sulfa aside. Quickly pulls out a morphine pack.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fumbles with a second sulfa bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sulfa, more sulfa...</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both know.</context>
      <utterance>Frozen in agony. Looks at Miller. Sees him preparing the morphine shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...morphine...make it a double...huh...Captain...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SHOVES THE NEEDLE into Wade's neck. Thick vein. Pumps the morphine straight to Wade's brain. Motions impatiently to Sarge.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More morphine, hurry up, come on, come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hesitates. Then drops his sulfa. Fumbles in his pack. Finds the morphine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Snatches the morphine from Sarge. Quickly and efficiently prepares a second shot. He's done this before.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On guard, glancing back. Pissed off.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it...Goddamn it...Goddamn it...</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freaked out. Trying to keep his eyes on the perimeter. Can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gives Wade the second shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WADE LOCKS EYES WITH MILLER. Looking at him without blame, without forgiveness. Drifts with the morphine. Then: WADE</context>
      <utterance>Feels the effects of the first shot. He sees Upham and manages a pained smile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it...Goddamn it...Goddamn it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller stares at his hand and steadies it before the men see. He picks up the dogtag and pockets it. Then Miller carefully re-packs the un-used morphine and sulfa, rises and picks up his Thompson. Upham shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Is silent. Motionless. He gently closes Wade's eyes. His hand quivers slightly as he unclips one of Wades dogtags. He fumbles and drops it. Sarge notices.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller SLAMS A FRESH CLIP into his Thompson.</context>
      <utterance>That was no twenty-two flat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller turns and walks away without looking back. The men hesitate, then slowly follow him.</context>
      <utterance>He lied. Let's move out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck Private James Ryan, fuck him, just fuck the goddamned son-of-a- bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shut up, this is the most fucked up mission I ever heard of. Goddamned Ryan, fuck the little bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just shut up, Ryan didn't kill Wade.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller motions to them curtly.</context>
      <utterance>The hell he didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shut up. Miller falls in step to Sarge. Speaks quietly, the men don't hear.</context>
      <utterance>Keep it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarge looks at Miller closely.</context>
      <utterance>We've got to find someplace to hole up for a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just find someplace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was the name of that kid at Anzio, the one who got his face burned off?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vecchio.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Vecchio, I couldn't remember his name, he was a good kid, remember how he used to walk on his hands and sing that song about the man on flying trapeze?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know why I'm such a good officer? Because of my mother. Have I ever told you about her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bits and pieces.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's the best poker player you ever saw. My father used to go to these Saturday night games and lose his shirt. Finally, my mother gave him an ultimatum, either she gets a regular seat at the table or she locks him in every Saturday night. He squawked and so did his buddies but after a while they gave in and from the first night she sat down, she never lost. She could read those cocky bastards like they were playing open hands. And he bluffs? He had sixteen levels of bullshit. Her eyes, the tone of her voice, her bets, her jokes, the way she sipped her coffee, she was a master. She won more money on shit hands than anyone in the history of the game. Every Saturday night, my father would lose two, three hundred bucks and she'd win it all back and then some. And I'd stand there, glued to her shoulder, from the time I was five years old, watching every hand, every move, studying how she did it.  That's why I'm such a good officer, I can look at a man's face and tell you exactly what he's holding, and if it's a shit hand, I know just what cards to deal him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what about your own hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem. A pair of deuces? Less? So what? I bluff. It used to tear me apart when I'd get one of my men killed, but what was I supposed to do? Break down in front of the ones who were standing there waiting for me to tell them what to do? Of course not, so I bluffed, and after a while, I started to fall for my own bluff. It was great, it made everything so much easier. Sarge Is that why your hand's been shaking?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lie to your men.</context>
      <utterance>It could be worse. You know the first thing they teach you at O.C.S.?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not in so many words, but they tell you you can have all the firepower in the world and if your men don't have good morale, it's not worth a damn. So if you're scared or empty or half-a-step from a Section Eight, do you tell your men? Of course not. You bluff, you lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how do you bluff yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simple, numbers. Every time you kill one of your men, you tell yourself you just saved the lives of two, three, ten, a hundred others. We lost, what, thirty-one on the cliffs? I'll bet we saved ten times that number by putting out those guns. That's over three hundred men. Maybe five hundred. A thousand. Then thousand. Any number you want. See? It's simple. It lets you always choose mission over men.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except this time, the mission IS a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the rub. I liked Wade. Who's Ryan? If they're both standing in front of me and I have to shoot one or the other, how do I choose? Look at my hand, there it goes again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, I've got to tell you, I think you're about used up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're right, Keith.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The question helps Miller pull himself back together. He looks at his hand and forces it to stop shaking again.</context>
      <utterance>You want me to take over?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but if I get any worse, you'll have to relieve me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They share a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Just what I want to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know Wade was the eleventh of the twelve, you're the last one still alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't let yourself get killed, if you do, they might make me give back the medal and then I won't be able to lip off to colonels anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake their heads at the madness of it all. Miller Hell of a...</context>
      <utterance>I'll do my best.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Miller picks up his Thompson and looks around, re-orienting himself. He's about ninety-five percent there.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for drawing that machine gun off me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarge allows himself a slight smile.</context>
      <utterance>But, that's my personal brand of stupidity, I feel kind of proprietary about it, if you do it again, you're busted.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller jerks his head for Sarge to follow. They head back to the men.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up. We're moving out.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you said we had an hour, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men get up. Jackson is a bit slow.</context>
      <utterance>Well now I'm saying we're moving out. Get off your ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's the matter with you, Jackson?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I ain't feeling so chipper on account of Wade.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one responds.</context>
      <utterance>Who's Wade?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men exchange looks. Jackson speaks for them.</context>
      <utterance>I said, who the hell is Wade?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I understand what you're doin', but I respectfully request permission to grieve in my own manner.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll grieve the way I tell you to goddamned grieve. There is no Wade, there was one, but he died a long time ago, he's been dead for so long you can hardly remember his name, you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I understand. I don't like it, but I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men pick up their equipment and prepare to move out. Sarge and Miller exchange a silent look. Miller shakes his head to himself, amazed that the men still allow this shit to work. He knows they have no choice.</context>
      <utterance>Good, now get your goddamned gear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what the best possible thing that could happen is?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller laughs. Miller I'll bite, Reiben.</context>
      <utterance>Yep, you step on a rusty nail, get lockjaw, never say another word as long as you live.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've given this a lot of thought, sir. The best thing that could happen is, we find Ryan and he's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sir, consider the possibilities. A: Ryan is alive. We have to take him back to the beach. Knowing you, you don't let him carry my gear, even though he really should, and we all get killed, trying to keep him alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except for the last part, that one's not bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>B: Ryan is dead. He's been blown up by the German equivalent of Wade, whose name I know you don't want me to mention. There's nothing to find. The biggest piece is the size of a pea. We wander around, looking for him until the Germans pick us off, one after another.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And him.</context>
      <utterance>Neither do I, sir. C: And this is the worst one, we find Ryan and he's wounded. Not only does he not carry my gear, we have to carry his gear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we accomplish the mission.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. But what if he dies on the way back? you see what I'm saying, sir? The best possible situation is, he's dead, we find his body, more or less intact, we grab one of his dog-tags and high-tail it back to the beach, or better yet, we head over to Caen and catch up with division.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has anyone ever told you, you're officer material?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one smiles, but they trudge a bit less.</context>
      <utterance>That's a mystery to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Miller stops dead. He listens, hearing something the others don't hear. He motions for them to freeze, they do. The SOUND grows louder. It's an OMINOUS RUMBLE.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like we're going to beat those Kraut companies to Ramelle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GERMAN FLANK SQUADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry along the fields on either side of the road, trying to keep up with the vehicles. MILLER AND HIS MEN Catch a glimpse of an approaching German Flank Squad. They flatten themselves into the mucky water. Ready their weapons. Prepare to fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GERMAN SQUAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Approaches the bridge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is just about to open up on them.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GERMAN SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sees his Flank Squad lagging behind and CALLS to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GERMAN PRIVATES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obey. Hurry after the rest of the convoy.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder where they're going.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson, at the mouth of the culvert, motions that the coast is clear. They head out.</context>
      <utterance>Same place we are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scans the Germans with his binoculars.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like tea time, maybe they're Brits.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sure hope so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then they hear an OMINOUS RUMBLE, deeper and more threatening that that of the convoy. The sound gets LOUDER and LOUDER. Miller and his men exchange looks. They know that sound, they don't like it.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think they're waiting for, Captain?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COME.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cover me.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if our guys open up, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're only allowed to shoot at Germans, that's one of the rules.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller takes a breath, then DASHES out into the open, toward the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>Have it your way, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GERMAN SNIPERS OPEN UP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullets SMASH INTO THE GROUND around Miller.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER'S MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>POUR FIRE at the German positions,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forrest Ryan?</context>
      <utterance>Things are tough all over. We're looking for a Private James Ryan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forrest Go get Ryan.</context>
      <utterance>Is he here? Forrest motions to one of the paratroopers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode>TO MILLER</mode>
      <context>Miller doesn't answer. Jackson leaps over the barricade and scrambles to them.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want him for, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson cranks up the five-thirty-five. Miller turns to Forrest.</context>
      <utterance>Jackson, get a hold of command.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pause to FIRE, covering Sarge, the last of Miller's men to leap over the barricade. Forrest Eleven, sir. We started with thirty-six. The bridge was easy to take but the Krauts have been coming back at us ever since. They must want it intact or we'd be long gone. Jackson speaks into the radio handset, repeating Miller's hailing I.D. No response.</context>
      <utterance>How many men do you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forrest Sir, what do you want with Ryan? Miller doesn't answer, he looks past Forrest and sees:</context>
      <utterance>Keep trying.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIVATE JAMES RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dashing from cover to cover, making his way toward them. Ryan is an American classic, nineteen years old, earthy, handsome, sharp, cocky. Though he's exhausted, unshaven, and smeared with dirt and blood, he's very alive. His eyes shine, his face has a spark. You can't help but love this kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER'S MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All watch Ryan run toward them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, that's Ryan.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes remain glued to Ryan as he makes it to the barricade. He salutes Miller.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like a flaming asshole to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller looks at Ryan for a moment, amazed that he's finally face-to-face with him. Ryan waits. Miller hesitates, searching for words. Then he speaks gently but clearly. Miller Private, I've got some bad news for you. Your brothers have been killed in action. The life instantly drains from Ryan. His breath comes hard. Somehow he remains upright. Ryan All three?</context>
      <utterance>I'm Ryan, sir. You wanted to see me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryan sways. Miller grabs him and eases him back, leaning him against some sandbags.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE PARATROOPERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are stunned at the news. They look at Ryan, there's nothing else they can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER'S MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also look at Ryan, but then, one after another, they turn away, adverting their eyes, looking a their own boots, the debris on the bridge, the sky, anything other than Ryan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryan weakly waves Miller off. Miller motions to his men and the paratroopers to move away. They do so, giving Ryan a little room. Forrest Three brothers, the poor son-of-a-bitch.</context>
      <utterance>We've been sent to get you out of here. You're going home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forrest But, sir, our orders are clear, we're to hold this bridge until we're relieved by forward elements of the Twenty- ninth Division.</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant, we're moving out and I'm taking you and your men with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forrest Sir, you can't do that, these orders are from command.</context>
      <utterance>I'm giving you new orders, Sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A VOICE from behind them speaks simply, clearly, firmly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to leave you and your men here to get killed. Get them together, we're moving out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They all turn and see Ryan standing there. Miller is about to automatically rip Ryan a new asshole for contradicting him, but he quickly calms himself, gently touches Ryan on the arm and speaks softly to him.</context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryan jerks away from Miller.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Private, you're going home.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes are on Miller and Ryan. Miller remains patient.</context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Private. I'm sorry about your brothers but staying here and getting yourself killed isn't going to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, if the Krauts are holding this bridge when division shows up, our guys are going to be sitting ducks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That news clearly affects Ryan and the other paratroopers, but Ryan holds his ground. Ryan Sir, I'm still not going. Miller speaks with restrained, but growing, anger.</context>
      <utterance>This bridge cannot be held. The Germans have two companies less than three miles from here. They have tanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryan stands eye-to-eye with Miller.</context>
      <utterance>Private, if you want to commit suicide, that's your choice, but you're going to have to wait until after I get you back to the beach. And you're not going to take these men with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller starts to boil over.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not leaving, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you aren't, you're comin' with me if I have to drag you every inch of the way. You hear me, Private?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller grabs Ryan by the lapels and shakes him. Ryan doesn't resist.</context>
      <utterance>I hear you sir, but I'm not leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryan speaks softly.</context>
      <utterance>Listen you little son-of-a-bitch you're coming with me or I'll...I'll...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller considers it. Then REIBEN SPEAKS UP from behind Miller.</context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do, sir, shoot me?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller slowly turns and glares.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, excuse me, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller's more amazed than pissed off. Reiben smiles.</context>
      <utterance>So, what are a few tanks, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right, we can't shoot him...well, we could but we'd get in an enormous amount of trouble. And he's right about the bridge, it's a hell of a lot more important than he is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller turns his glare on Jackson.</context>
      <utterance>Cap'n...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller does a slow burn.</context>
      <utterance>Seems to me, we got us a opportunity, here, to kill two birds with one stone. Command seems to think keepin' this boy alive is worth somethin'. If we was to do that and hold this bridge, good chance we'd get us a bucket full of medals. I might even get me one 'a them big, fancy ones like you got, so's I could sass any officer in the whole dang army, you included.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to stay, too, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't count.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forrest We weren't planning on going anywhere, sir. Reiben smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I do and personally, I'd rather get the hell out of here, but somebody's got to stay and take care of you and these pin-head privates of yours. Miller looks at FORREST AND THE PARATROOPERS.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller's eyes almost pop out of his head. Miller The vote? What the hell are you talking about? We don't vote. This isn't a democracy. This is the army, I give orders, you follow them. We don't vote!</context>
      <utterance>See, Captain? The vote's unanimous.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir, of course, sir, I was merely speaking hypothetically. IF this was a voting situation, then the vote would have been unanimous. But of course, it's not a voting situation, you're the captain, and you give the orders, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all quickly nod.</context>
      <utterance>You're goddamned right, I give the order. Vote! Jesus Christ! Listen to me, you little pissant pieces of shit, I am the ranking officer here and what I say goes, is that clear?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller looks from face to face.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, sir. All the others Yes, sir. Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's what they wanted to hear. Miller doesn't give them time to enjoy it, he immediately starts barking orders.</context>
      <utterance>In that case...  I vote we stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all hurry off, except for Ryan who locks eyes with Miller for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Reiben, the B.A.R., there. Jackson, get up on the bridgekeepers hut with your sniper rifle. Sarge, you and Upham move that machine gun so it can cover the left flank, it's worthless where it is. Forrest, I want a full inventory of all your weapons, ammo and ordnance. Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryan salutes.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah. I want you right next to me, no matter where I go, you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller shakes his head at himself and strides off to check the defensive perimeter with Ryan at his side.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, come with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it? Reiben looks at the sparse array of weaponry.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller sighs, worried.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, can I change my vote?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>A GERMAN SNIPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Falls from a window on the edge of town, dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller eyes the buildings near the bridge head. He speaks to Sarge who holds several satchel charges.</context>
      <utterance>Sits beside Jackson with a pair of binoculars, searching for another target. The German sniper fire has subsided for now. Ext. bridge - day Miller watches as Ryan and several other paratroopers dig a series of trenches across the street, leading to the bridge. Reiben, Jackson and Upham, stone-faced, watch Ryan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarge, see what you can do to make those buildings inhospitable.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then they hear the sound of A BIG GUN FIRING IN THE DISTANCE. They all turn at the sound.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller nods.</context>
      <utterance>Eighty-eights, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can tell what the gunners had for dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forrest Just south of town. The Krauts have a two gun emplacement, we saw it on the way in. That's how we knew they wanted the bridge intact, they didn't blow the crap out of us.</context>
      <utterance>Those guns are close.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham listens to the eighty-eights with particular interest.</context>
      <utterance>Let's hope they don't change their mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if we had ten times the men and a lot more ammo, we might stand a chance, but not against those tanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to hope like hell the tanks were on their way somewhere else.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe Caen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's hope, because we're sure as hell not going to do any damage to them with what we have here.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about our grenades?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are Tigers, they have six-inch armor, they don't even notice grenades.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would they notice and eighty-eight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, you got one?</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller is stone-faced, then he smiles.</context>
      <utterance>The Germans do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham runs off. Sarge shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Upham, go find Jackson, he and I are going hunting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of the mouth of babes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Upham, you've got to learn the difference between whining and griping. You can't just rely on natural ability, you've got to study and practice.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There you go again, that's whining, that's not okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's better, but you've still got a long way to go. Talk to Reiben, he's a natural and works at it, he'll give you some pointers.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave him to me, Captain, I'll have him pissing and moaning with the best of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RYAN Steps up to Miller.</context>
      <utterance>See to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to go, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, private, I want you to stay here, keep your head down, don't do anything brave or stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't they the same thing, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reiben, I don't know what I'd do without you. Sarge, keep Ryan close to you and alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller checks Jackson and Forrest.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forrest Yes, sir.</context>
      <utterance>You ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller, Forrest and Jackson prepare to move out.</context>
      <utterance>You betcha, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'all come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reiben, are you makin' fun 'a the way I talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson shoots him a glare, then he follows Miller and Forrest into the darkness. Sarge, Ryan and the other watch them go.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, no!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryan nods. Then, with some difficulty, he makes the trip from Iowa back to France. He turns to Sarge. Ryan What was the name of the guy who got killed coming up here?</context>
      <utterance>Private, I'm sorry about your brothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wade.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wade. Huh, he died coming up here to keep me alive...I never met him...he didn't know me from Adam, strange. What was he like?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A good man, kind of cheerful, Reiben, here, used to call him a happy idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like hell, I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My brothers would be mighty pissed off at me, if they knew I let some guy get killed trying to keep me alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't let anybody get killed, you didn't even know we were coming up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others nod in agreement. They look closely at Ryan.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, I know, but...  Goddamn it all...</utterance>
   <speaker>A SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller sees Jackson easing up behind another sentry. Miller nods to Jackson. They move at the same moment. Behind the sentries. SLIT THEIR THROATS.</context>
      <utterance>It's Miller. Easing through the darkness. Closer to one of the sentries.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEHIND THE EIGHTY-EIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forrest removes the wheel-blocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>A GERMAN SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Approaches. He sees Forrest. Just as he's about to open up with his sub-machine gun, Miller grabs him from behind, STABS him, eases the body silently to the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER AND JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Together they attach the eighty-eight's carriage to the German's truck.</context>
      <utterance>Join Forrest at the eighty-eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER GERMAN SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rounds a corner. Sees them. OPENS</utterance>
   <speaker>UP WITH HIS SUB-MACHINE GUN.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forrest DIVES, FIRES BACK.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHER GERMANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Race over, FIRING.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILLER frantically attaches the eighty-eight to the truck. FORREST CUTS DOWN, several more Germans.</context>
      <utterance>Covering them, OPENS UP. Kills the advancing Germans.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WINDSHIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glass flies everywhere, cutting Miller on the face and hands.</context>
      <utterance>Is shattered by bullets.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORREST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spraying the Germans with his Thompson.</context>
      <utterance>In the back of the truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER FLOORS IT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Germans FIRE at the truck and trailing eighty-eight. MILLER, JACKSON AND FORREST Drive into the night. The Germans FIRING after them.</context>
      <utterance>The truck DRIVES through the Germans.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller fumes. he sees Reiben, Sarge and Upham, shrugging, clearly not pissed at Ryan.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do that again.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller GROWLS.</context>
      <utterance>I won't need to sir, it's already here, behind the barricade so...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller glares at Ryan, then strides off.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'm we got that eighty-eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, Ryan, what do you think of him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ain't half-bad, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're quiet for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ain't Wade.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes keep coming back to Ryan.</context>
      <utterance>Nope, he ain't Wade.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crouch-runs through the shadows and stops at the bridgekeepers hut.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller points, directing Reiben to the forward machine gun nest.</context>
      <utterance>Reiben...</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REIBEN jumps down and moves forward. MILLER runs across the bridge and joins Sarge and Ryan in the rear machine gun nest.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You set? Sarge nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller and Sarge exchange a look. Then Miller slips off to check the others.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REIBEN AND UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manning the forward machine gun nest.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Behind the sandbags, on top of the bridgekeeper's hut.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RYAN AND SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manning rear machine gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the bridgehead, waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOUND FROM DOWN THE ROAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All eyes turn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OPENS UP with the MACHINE GUN.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GERMANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least fifty of them, advancing on the bridge. Running from cover to cover. A squad pushing a French truck, using it as a shield.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calmly picking off the attacking Germans.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GERMAN INFANTRYMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make their way down the streets. Along the riverbank. Through the houses. There are GERMANS FIRING from all directions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grabs the B.A.R., stands and fires.</context>
      <utterance>Sees Reiben and Upham being cut off.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN AND UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Running out of ammo. See that there's nothing else they can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reiben rolls out of the nest, carrying the fifty caliber. Upham follows, carrying the ammo boxes. They run as fast as they can.</context>
      <utterance>Time to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RYAN IS FIRING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the rear MACHINE GUN. Drops several Germans.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMANS EVERYWHERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They swarm over the first barricade.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>FIRES A BURST into a German's belly. HITS another with the stock of his Thompson.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HAND-TO-HAND FIGHTING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller KILLS TWO MORE WITH A BURST.</context>
      <utterance>Half a dozen Germans break through.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KILLS the German.</context>
      <utterance>Is jumped on by one. Upham FIRES.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Struggling with a pair of Germans.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>FIRES. Drops one of the Germans on Miller with a head shot. Cuts open Miller's face with bits of skull.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leaps onto the final German attacking Miller. That German raises his rifle on Ryan.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM AND REIBEN AND JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All see it. SIMULTANEOUSLY SHOOT the German.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE STUNNED GERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About to kill Ryan. Torn apart by bullets from three directions.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like hell you did, I got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON SMILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILLER SLAMS in a fresh clip. FIRES an arc. DROPS four Germans. Sees an oncoming RUSH OF GERMANS. BARKS to Reiben and Upham:</context>
      <utterance>He got him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sees them in deep trouble. Leaves Ryan firing the rear machine gun. Grabs the B.A.R. ADVANCES, FIRING COVER. Exposed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BULLETS EVERYWHERE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MILLER, REIBEN, UPHAM make it to the barricade. Dive over.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE OTHER AMERICANS FIRE for all they're worth. Trying to cover Sarge. Too many Germans.</context>
      <utterance>Sees they've made it. FIRES A FINAL BURST. Races for cover. A trail of bullets right behind him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE AMERICANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Desperately trying to cover him.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GERMANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open up with a volley.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is almost there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>THE GERMANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REIBEN, UPHAM, JACKSON, RYAN fire at the retreating Germans.</context>
      <utterance>Who killed Sarge are killed. The others back off for now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grabs Sarge and pulls him over the barricade. Sees that he's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GERMANS RETREAT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Around the corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stunned, lays Sarge down, kneeling next to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch, start to gather.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it...Goddamn it...Goddamn it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hesitate.</context>
      <utterance>Get back to your positions!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They follow the order. All except Ryan, who doesn't move. He can't take his eyes off Sarge.</context>
      <utterance>Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't move. He just stares at Sarge's body.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks at Miller, sees him growing weak, starting to sway. He gently tries to move Miller aside.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller looks up at Ryan, then back at Sarge's body. Miller grows cold, making the same startling transformation he made as he kneeled over Wade's body.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of Sarge...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But this time it doesn't work. He can't make it stick. The hard expression, disappears. He drifts, utterly lost. He's called his own bluff.</context>
      <utterance>Sarge? Who's Sarge?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly, Miller's men turn to him.</context>
      <utterance>English teacher, Addley, Pennsylvania.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you say, Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I teach English at Addley High School in Addley, Pennsylvania.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll be goddamned, I knew it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like hell, you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, what about our deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I changed my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I coach the baseball team, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kiddin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all sit in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all nod, except Ryan who doesn't know what Miller's talking about.</context>
      <utterance>You know that cruise ship Wade's grandfather was on?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder if his cabin is still available?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where are you?</context>
      <utterance>That's not where I am. Miller No?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all share Reiben's dream for a moment. Then Jackson smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in a dressing room with Mrs. Rachel Troubowitz, our super's wife. She's an easy forty-four, double E, but I've convinced her she's a thirty- eight D and I'm watching her try and squeeze herself into a side-stay, silk-ribboned, three-panel girdle with s Helf-lift brassiere.  She's having a devil of a time, getting into that thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? I'm walking with my hound, Lucy, it's about an hour 'fore sunrise and we're out huntin' coon. I got me a flask of pure Kentucky mash whiskey...</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackson, how many times I got to tell you, you're from Tennessee.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upham smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I am, but I like imported whiskey. So there I am and I hear the biggest ole' coon you ever did hear, 'a rustlin' right there in front of me. That ole' boy comes right out of the brush, I got a clear shot and he knows he's 'bout to meet his maker. I aim, I got my finger tight on the trigger and then I just smile and say to that ole' coon, go on, now, you get out 'a here. Then I sit down on a hollow log and take me a right long pull a' that mash whiskey.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I kind of like Wade's idea about the cruise ship. I've never been to Tahiti.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller smiles. He knows exactly where he is.</context>
      <utterance>What about you, Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in my backyard, lying in my hammock, with my arm around my wife, listening for the sound of breaking glass.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say what, Cap'n?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, I've got the best house in all of Addley. It's not the biggest house, but it's got the best location, right next to the junior high baseball field. The garage windows face left field. The guy who owned the house before me had these heavy screen S put over them. The first thing I did when I bought the place was take off those screens. Two-hundred-twenty- two yards from home plate to my garage windows. It takes a hell of a junior high kid to hit a ball that far. I look at my garage windows as a Motivator and a way to scout the kids coming up, the ones who are going to give us a shot at the state championship. I lay there in my hammock and every time I hear the sound of breaking glass, I know we're one step closer to winning it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't that get kind of expensive, Cap'n?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's worth it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're all silent for a moment. Then Miller turns to Ryan.</context>
      <utterance>To each, his own.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ryan sighs.</context>
      <utterance>How about you, James?</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all nod. Miller tears off a piece of bread and passes it to Ryan who tears off a bit and passes it on. They all eat in silence.</context>
      <utterance>I'm home, playing basketball with my brothers, it's evenin' time, we're trying' to get in a few more points before it's too dark to see the ball. That's where I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here they come.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>FIRES a burst. Germans drops.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>FIRES a burst. More Germans drop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>FIRES again. More Germans drop.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GERMANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start working their way to the tops of the nearby buildings. Making their way along the riverbanks.</context>
      <utterance>Take positions in the building near the bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN AND RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forward. Reiben FIRING. Ryan feeding the ammo belt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hears that. Doesn't hesitate. He grabs a pair of ammo boxes. RUNS toward Reiben and Ryan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEVERAL GERMANS ZERO UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BULLETS TRAIL UPHAM. He's outrunning them. Almost there.</context>
      <utterance>OPEN UP on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>UPHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>TAKES HALF-A-DOZEN SLUGS. Torn apart. Stumbles the final few steps to the machine gun nest. Falls on the sandbags, giving Reiben and Ryan the ammo. UPHAM'S DEAD.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RYAN AND REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then RYAN AND MILLER converge at the eighty-eight. THE FIRST TANK APPEARS Huge. Terrifying. Clanking. Trailed by two German infantry platoons.</context>
      <utterance>Immediately grab the machine gun and ammo and race back to the rear nest.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GERMAN INFANTRYMAN SPOTS JACKSON. Hollers into the tanks voice-tube.</context>
      <utterance>On the bridgekeeper's hut. Picking off German soldiers who follow the tank.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stops. Grinds its gears. Turning it's turret towards the bridgekeepers hut.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILLER AND RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lowering the barrel to point blank.</context>
      <utterance>SEE JACKSON DIE. A bare moment to react. Then, they turn their attention back to the eighty-eight. Frantically turning the aiming cranks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK AGAINST EIGHTY-EIGHT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which can fire first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER AND RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Win the race.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Races through the debris. Trailed by BULLETS.</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RYAN jumps behind the second machine gun. Opens up. Helping to cover Miller.</context>
      <utterance>With the machine gun. Covers Miller. Keeping most of the German infantry down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Throws the satchel charge under the tank. Rolls off the edge of the bridge. Lands on the embankment below.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE LAST TIGER TANK EXPLODES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MILLER SCRAMBLING UP THE EMBANKMENT, back onto the bridge, hears something over the SOUNDS OF FIRING.</context>
      <utterance>MILLER, RYAN, REIBEN continue FIRING. Almost out of ammo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AN AMERICAN SHERMAN TANK APPEARS from over the rise. Then</context>
      <utterance>More tanks... Ryan Lot's of them The fear on their faces turns to resignation. They know that they are dead men. They settle into their positions, and prepare to fire and die. They wait. The RUMBLE GETS LOUDER AND LOUDER. THEN MILLER'S FACE STARTS TO CHANGE...a hint...of a smile...then a real smile...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE ADVANCING TROOPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Major Report, Captain.</context>
      <utterance>Run onto the bridge and start to secure the position. A SERGEANT and a few of HIS MEN look around, curiously eyeing Miller, Reiben and Ryan, battered and bloody, standing among the bodies. A MAJOR strides up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sergeant and several other soldiers overhear.</context>
      <utterance>Miller, Company B, Second Rangers, that's Private Richard Reiben and that's Private James Ryan, Hundred- and-First Airborne.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the soldiers speaks quietly to another. Soldier That's him, that's Ryan. The Major puts his hand on Ryan's shoulder. Major Command is looking for you, son. You're going home. Ryan looks up, tired. He nods.</context>
      <utterance>Ryan?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REIBEN AND RYAN watch silently.</context>
      <utterance>Walks to the bodies. He kneels down next to Sarge and looks at him for a long moment. Then, with a steady hand, he takes one of Sarge's two dog-tags. Then he does the same to Jackson and Upham.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller takes a last look at the bridge and the bodies, then he shoulders his gear. Miller Let's move out. Reiben and Ryan gather up their gear. They walk with Miller down the road, away from the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>Stands and walks back to Reiben and Ryan. He hands the dog-tags to Ryan who grips them tightly and nods in thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAMERA CRANES UP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The three dirty, bloodied, tired men walk down the road, ignored by the fresh troops marching in the opposite direction.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Private.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Upham and Jackson, what were they like?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Upham? Good kid, smart, he was writing a book.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>REIBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and he was fast, too, ran the 220 in twenty-four-five.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackson was from West Fork, Tennessee, he was going to be a preacher, his father and uncles have a traveling ministry out of the back of a stretch Hudson.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Sarge?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He was the best friend I ever had. (smiles) Lemme tell you about Sarge... They walk on, disappearing in the distance among the hundreds and hundreds of American soldiers who are marching down the road and over the bridge. Fade out.</context>
      <utterance>Sarge?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
