<movie id="474" title="Schindler s List">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLERKS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>BEWILDERED RURAL FACES coming down off the passenger train. FORMS being set out on the folding tables. HANDS straightening pens and pencils and ink pads and stamps.</context>
      <utterance>...Rossen... Lieberman... Wachsberg...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERKS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>TYPEWRITER KEYS rapping a name onto a list. A FACE. KEYS typing another name. Another FACE.</context>
      <utterance>...When your name is called go over there... take this over to that table...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERKS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A MAN is taken from one long line and led to the back of another. A HAND hammers a rubber stamp at a form. Tight on a FACE. KEYS type another NAME. Another FACE. Another NAME.</context>
      <utterance>...you’re in the wrong line, wait over there... you, come over here...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERKS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As a hand comes down stamping a GRAY STRIPE across a registration card, there is absolute silence... then MUSIC, the Hungarian love song, "Gloomy Sunday," distant... and the stripe bleeds into COLOR, into BRIGHT YELLOW INK.</context>
      <utterance>...Biberman... Steinberg... Chilowitz...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter is gesturing to a table across the room where Schindler, seemingly unaware of the SS men, drinks with the best-looking woman in the place.</context>
      <utterance>From the gentleman.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I know him? His sergeant doesn’t. His girlfriend doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sergeant makes his way over to Schindler's table. There's a handshake and introductions before -- and the lieutenant, watching, can't believe it -- his guy accepts the chair Schindler's dragging over. The lieutenant waits, but his man doesn't come back; he's forgotten already he went there for a reason. Finally, and it irritates the SS man, he has to get up and go over there.</context>
      <utterance>Find out who he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His girlfriend watches him cross toward Schindler's table. Before he even arrives, Schindler is up and berating him for leaving his date way over there across the room, waving at the girl to come join them, motioning to waiter to slide some tables together.</context>
      <utterance>Stay here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me get this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler's already got his money out. Even as he's paying, his eyes are working the room, settling on a table where a girl is declining the advances of two more high-ranking SS men.</context>
      <utterance>No, put it away, put it away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SS OFFICER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SS OFFICER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Oskar Schindler. He's an old friend of... I don't know, somebody's.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind Schindler, the door to another apartment closes softly. A radio, somewhere, is suddenly silenced.</context>
      <utterance>Stern?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the door of this apartment, a man with the face and manner of a Talmudic scholar, finally nods in resignation, like his number has just come up.</context>
      <utterance>Are you Itzhak Stern?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler offers a hand. Confused, Stern tentatively reaches for it, and finds his own grasped firmly.</context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern stares at the cognac Schindler's offering him. He doesn't know who this man is, or what he wants.</context>
      <utterance>There's a company you did the books for on Lipowa Street, made what, pots and pans?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler looks puzzled, then shrugs, dismissing it.</context>
      <utterance>By law, I have to tell you, sir, I'm a Jew.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He keeps holding out the drink. Stern declines it with a slow shake of his head.</context>
      <utterance>All right, you've done it -- good company, you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler nods, takes out a cigarette case.</context>
      <utterance>It did all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers Stern a cigarette. Stern declines again.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know anything about enamelware, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just the accountant.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler lowers his voice as if there could possibly be someone else listening in somewhere.</context>
      <utterance>Simple engineering, though, wouldn't you think? Change the machines around, whatever you do, you could make other things, couldn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waits for a reaction, and misinterprets Stern's silence for a lack of understanding.</context>
      <utterance>Field kits, mess kits...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Stern does understand. He understands too well. Schindler grins good-naturedly.</context>
      <utterance>Army contracts.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once the war ends, forget it, but for now it's great, you could make a fortune. Don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern smiles despite himself. The man's manner is so simple, so in contrast to his own and the complexities of being a Jew in occupied Cracow in 1939. He really doesn't know. Stern decides to end the conversation.</context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the contracts and I'm sure you'll do very well. In fact the worse things get the better you'll do. It was a "pleasure."</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs loudly, uproariously. But then, just as abruptly as the laugh erupted, he's dead serious, all kidding aside --</context>
      <utterance>The contracts? That's the easy part. Finding the money to buy the company, that's hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern stares at him curiously, sitting there taking another sip of his cognac, placid as a large dog.</context>
      <utterance>You know anybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jews, yeah. Investors.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jews can no longer own businesses, sir, that's why this one's for sale.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs; it sounds more than fair to him. But not to Stern.</context>
      <utterance>Well, they wouldn't own it, I'd own it. I'd pay them back in product. They can trade it on the black market, do whatever they want, everybody's happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pots and pans.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know anybody who'd be interested in that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>They should be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't recognize it? Maybe that's because it's not what I asked for.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You asked for shoe polish.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My buyers sold it to a guy who sold it to the Army. But by the time it got there -- because of the cold -- it broke, the whole truckload.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'm responsible for the weather?</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked for metal, you gave me glass.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not my problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goldberg doesn't bother; he pockets his little notepad and intones a response to the priest's prayer, all but ignoring Pfefferberg.</context>
      <utterance>Look it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goldberg glances to Pfefferberg for the first time, and, greatly put upon, takes out his little notepad again and makes a notation in it.</context>
      <utterance>This is not your problem? Everybody wants to know who I got it from, and I'm going to tell them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flips the pad closed, pockets it, crosses himself as he gets up, and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Metal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The clerk, satisfied with the figures, is about to hand over to Pfefferberg some outlawed Polish notes from an envelope when Schindler comes in from the street. The clerk puts the money away, gets Schindler his room key, waits for him to leave so he can finish his business with Pfefferberg... but Schindler doesn't leave; he just keeps looking over at Pfefferberg's shirt, at the cuffs, the collar.</context>
      <utterance>Let's say this is what you give me. These are fees I have to pay some guys. This is my commission. This is what I bring you back in Occupation currency.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pfefferberg nods, Yeah, thanks, and waits for Schindler to leave; but he doesn't. Nor does he appear to hear the short burst of muffled gunfire that erupts from somewhere up the street.</context>
      <utterance>That's a nice shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pfefferberg knows he should say 'no,' let that be the end of it. It's not wise doing business with a German who could have you arrested for no reason whatsoever. But there's something guileless about it.</context>
      <utterance>You don't know where I could find a shirt like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have any idea what a shirt like this costs?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The clerk tries to tell Pfefferberg again with a look that this isn't smart.</context>
      <utterance>Nice things cost money.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler takes out his money and begins peeling off bills, waiting for Pfefferberg to nod when it's enough. He's being overcharged, and he knows it, but Pfefferberg keeps pushing it, more. The look Schindler gives him lets him know that he's trying to hustle a hustler, but that, in this instance at least, he'll let it go. He hands over the money and Pfefferberg hands over his notepad.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, ten or twelve. That's a good color. Dark blues, grays.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he writes down the information, Pfefferberg glances to the desk clerk and offers a shrug. As he writes --</context>
      <utterance>Write down your measurements.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to need some other things. As things come up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CZURDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Other SS and Army officers share the table with Czurda. Schindler, too, nice blue shirt, jacket, only he doesn't seem to be paying attention; rather his attention and affections are directed to the blonde next to him, Ingrid.</context>
      <utterance>The SS doesn't own the trains, somebody's got to pay. Whether it's a passenger car or a livestock car, it doesn't matter -- which, by the way, you have to see. You have to set aside an afternoon, go down to the station and see this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CZURDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>sees something odd across the yard. Two horses, saddled-up, being led into the garden by a stable boy.</context>
      <utterance>So you got thousands of fares that have to be paid. Since it's the SS that's reserved the trains, logically they should pay. But this is a lot of money.  The Jews. They're the ones riding the trains, they should pay. So you got Jews paying their own fares to ride on cattle cars to God knows where. They pay the SS full fare, the SS turns around, pays the railroad a reduced excursion fare, and pockets the difference. He shrugs, There you have it. Brilliant. He glances off,</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler gets up from the table. Scherner, his wife and daughter and son-in-law stare at the horses; they're beautiful. Schindler appears, takes the reins from the stable boy, hands one set to the bride and the other to the groom.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scherner hails a photographer. As the guy comes over with his camera, so does just about everybody else. Scherner insists Schindler pose with the astonished bride and groom. Big smiles. Flash.</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing more sacred than marriage. No happier an occasion than one's wedding day. I wish you all the best.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OWNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I go to the bank, I go in, they tell me my account's been placed in Trust. In Trust? What are they talking about, whose Trust? The Germans'. I look around. Now I see that everybody's arguing, they can't get to their money either.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX REDLICHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is true?</utterance>
   <speaker>OWNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max looks at the man not without sympathy. He's never heard of such a thing. It's really a bad deal. But then --</context>
      <utterance>I'll take you there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX REDLICHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The owner of the place just stares at Redlicht.</context>
      <utterance>Let me understand. The Nazis have taken your money. So because they've done this to you, you expect me to go unpaid. That's what you're saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX REDLICHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man doesn't answer. He watches Max get up and cross to the front door where he says something to two of his guys and leaves. The guys come in and start carting out anything of any value: cash register, a chair, a loaf of bread...</context>
      <utterance>That makes sense to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EINSATZ NCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one does anything for a moment. The liberals from the street seem to say with their eyes, Come on, we're all too sophisticated for this; the others, with the beards and sidelocks, silently check with their rabbi. One by one then they file past and spit on the scroll. The last two, the rabbi and Max Redlicht hesitate. They exchange a glance. The rabbi finally does it; the gangster doesn't. After a long tense silence.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to spit on it. I want you to walk past, spit on it, and stand over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX REDLICHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Einsatz NCO glances from Max to the rabbi and smiles to himself. This is unexpected, this rift.</context>
      <utterance>I haven't been to temple must be fifty years.  Nor have I been invited.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX REDLICHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max admits it with a shrug.</context>
      <utterance>You don't approve of the way I make my living? I'm a bad man, I do bad things?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX REDLICHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. The Einsatz NCO glances away to the others, amused.</context>
      <utterance>I've done some things... but I won't do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>EINSATZ NCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nobody answers. He turns to Max.</context>
      <utterance>What does this mean? Of all of you, there's only one who has the guts to say no? One? And he doesn't even believe?  I come in here, I ask you to do something no one should ever ask. And you do it?  What won't you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>EINSATZ NCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out a revolver and shoots the old gangster in the head. He's dead before he hits the floor.</context>
      <utterance>You, sir, I respect.</utterance>
   <speaker>EINSATZ NCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and walks away. The other Einsatz Boys pull rifles and revolvers from their coats and open fire.</context>
      <utterance>The rest of you... ...are beneath his contempt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pfefferberg, with his wife Mila, at the head of a line that seems to stretch back forever, flicks at Goldberg's OD armband with disgust.</context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ghetto Police. I'm a policeman now, can you believe it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They consider each other for a long moment before Pfefferberg leads his wife past Goldberg and into the ghetto.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I can.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets them think about it, pours a shot of cognac from his flask, offers it to Stern, who brought this group together and now sits at Schindler's side. The accountant declines.</context>
      <utterance>For each thousand you invest, you take from the loading dock five hundred kilos of product a month -- to begin in July and to continue for one year -- after which time, we're even.  That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVESTOR 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not good enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not good enough? Look where you're living. Look where you've been put. "Not good enough."  A couple of months ago, you'd be right. Not anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVESTOR 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Money's still money.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler lights a cigarette and waits for their answer. It doesn't come. Just a silence. Which irritates him.</context>
      <utterance>No, it isn't, that's why we're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He caps his flask, pockets it, reaches for his top coat.</context>
      <utterance>Did I call this meeting? You told Mr. Stern you wanted to speak to me. I'm here. Now you want to negotiate? The offer's withdrawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVESTOR 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do we know you'll do what you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The investors study him. This is not a manageable German. Whether he's honest or not is impossible to say. Their glances to Stern don't help them; he doesn't know either. The silence in the room is filled by the muffled singing next door. One of the men eventually nods, He's in. Then another. And another.</context>
      <utterance>Because I said I would. What do you want, a contract? To be filed where?  I said what I'll do, that's our contract.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler turns from the wall of glass to face his new accountant.</context>
      <utterance>The standard SS rate for Jewish skilled labor is seven Marks a day, five for unskilled and women. This is what you pay the Economic Office, the laborers themselves receive nothing. Poles you pay wages. Generally, they get a little more. Are you listening?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that about the SS, the rate, the... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Jewish worker's salary, you pay it directly to the SS, not to the worker. He gets nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern hesitates, then nods. The look on Schindler's face says, Well, what's to debate, the answer's clear to any fool.</context>
      <utterance>But it's less. It's less than what I would pay a Pole. That's the point I'm trying to make. Poles cost more.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I hire Poles?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man tries to hand over documentation supporting the claim along with his Kennkarte to a German clerk.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over there, other "non-essential people" are climbing onto trucks bound for unknown destinations. The teacher reluctantly relinquishes his place in line.</context>
      <utterance>Not essential work, stand over there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands over a piece of paper. The clerk takes a look, is satisfied with it, brushes glue on the back of a Blauschein and sticks it to the man's work card.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a metal polisher.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The world's gone mad.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SCHERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd never ask you for money, you know that. I don't even like talking about it -- money, favors -- I find it very awkward, it makes me very uncomfortable --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, look. It's the others. They're the ones causing these delays.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What others?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scherner thinks he understands what Schindler's saying. Just in case he doesn't --</context>
      <utterance>Whoever. They're the ones. They'd appreciate some kind of gesture from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scherner nods. Yes, they understand each other.</context>
      <utterance>I should send it to you, though, don't you think? You can forward it on? I'd be grateful.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'd be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Done. Let's not talk about it anymore, let's have a good time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler goes to the wall of windows, his favorite place in the world, and looks down at all the activity below. He pours two drinks from a decanter and, turning back, holds one out to Stern. Stern, of course, declines. Schinder groans.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes over and puts the drink in Stern's hand, moves behind his desk and sits.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dismisses them with a shrug; he's never had much use for either. But the third -- he raises his glass to the accountant. Stern's glass stays in his lap.</context>
      <utterance>My father was fond of saying you need three things in life. A good doctor, a forgiving priest and a clever accountant. The first two...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern slowly raises his glass.</context>
      <utterance>Just pretend for Christ's sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler drinks; Stern doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KLONOWSKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A series of realizations is made by each of them, quickly, silently, ending up with Klonowska looking ill.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emilie begrudges him a glance to the bedroom, catching the girl just as she looks up -- embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>She's so embarrassed -- look at her --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what, you'd like her.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oskar, please --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What --</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to like her just because you do. It doesn't work that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face is complete innocence. It's the first thing she fell in love with; and perhaps the thing that keeps her from killing him now. Klonowska emerges from the bedroom thoroughly self-conscious.</context>
      <utterance>You would, though. That's what I'm saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>KLONOWSKA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes Emilie's limp hand. Schindler sees her to the door, lets her out and returns to the table, smiling to himself. Emilie's glancing around at the place.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye. It was a pleasure meeting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods; he's proud of it. He studies her.</context>
      <utterance>You've done well here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Careful of the pavement --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doorman shoots a glance to Schindler that asks, clearly, Really? Schindler opens the passenger door of the Mercedes for his wife, and the doorman helps her in.</context>
      <utterance>-- Mrs. Schindler.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a charade, all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't know, but she does know him. And all these signs of apparent success just don't fit his profile. Schindler lets her in on a discovery.</context>
      <utterance>A charade? How could it be a charade?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waits for her to guess what the thing is. His looks says, It's so simple, how can you not know?</context>
      <utterance>There's no way I could have known this before, but there was always something missing. In every business I tried, I see now it wasn't me that was failing, it was this thing, this missing thing. Even if I'd known what it was, there's nothing I could have done about it, because you can't create this sort of thing. And it makes all the difference in the world between success and failure.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>War.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, even as his eyes roam the room and find and meet the eyes of a German girl dancing with another man.</context>
      <utterance>I feel like an old-fashioned couple. It feels good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I stay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's not the answer she's looking for and he knows it.</context>
      <utterance>It's a beautiful city.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I stay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's not it either.</context>
      <utterance>It's up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler stares out at the lights of the city. They look like jewels.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He promises her nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Promise me no doorman or maitre 'd will presume I am anyone other than Mrs. Schindler... and I'll stay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every other time it's been all right. This time when I weigh the truck, I see he's heavy, he's loaded too much. I point this out to him, I tell him to wait, he tells me he's got a new arrangement with Mr. Schindler --  -- that you know all about it and it's okay with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the surface, Schindler remains calm; underneath, he's livid. Clearly it's not "okay" with him.</context>
      <utterance>It's "okay" with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How heavy was he?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern and Schindler exchange a glance. Then --</context>
      <utterance>Not that much, just too much for it to be a mistake -- 200 kilos.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The foreman nods.</context>
      <utterance>You're sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WOMAN AT DESK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move past her without a word and into the back of the place, into a storeroom. They stride past long racks full of enamelware and other goods. A man glances up, sees them coming. He's one of Schindler's investors, the one who questioned the German's word. The man's teenage sons rush to their father's defense, but Pfefferberg grabs him and locks an arm tightly around his neck. Silence. Then, calmly --</context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you or anyone acting as an agent for you comes to my factory again, I'll have you arrested.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVESTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a mistake? What was a mistake? How do you know what I'm talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>INVESTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, it wasn't a mistake, but it was one time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and walks away. Pfefferberg lets the guy go and follows. The investor's sons help their father up off the floor. Gasping, he yells.</context>
      <utterance>We had a deal, you broke it. One phone call and your whole family is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>INVESTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- but Schindler and Pfefferberg are already gone, coming through the front office and out the front door --</context>
      <utterance>I gave you money.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you feeling, all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, everything all right at home?  Mila's okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well, then, Schindler can't imagine what could be wrong. He pats Pfefferberg on the shoulder and leads him away.</context>
      <utterance>She's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could try to read this or I could eat my lunch while it's till hot. We're doing well?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better this month than last?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any reason to think next month will be worse?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No chance of that. Satisfied, Schindler returns the report to his accountant and starts to eat. Stern knows he is excused, but looks like he wants to say something more; he just doesn't know how to say it.</context>
      <utterance>The war could end.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler gives his accountant a long-suffering look.</context>
      <utterance>There's a machinist outside who'd like to thank you personally for giving him a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler's silence says, Is this really necessary? Stern pretends it's a tacit okay, goes to the door and pokes his head out.</context>
      <utterance>He asks every day. It'll just take a minute. He's very grateful.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An old man with one arm appears in the doorway and Schindler glances to the ceiling, to heaven. As the man slowly makes his way into the room, Schindler sees the bruises on his face. And when he speaks, only half his mouth moves; the other half is paralyzed.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Lowenstein?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWENSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to thank you, sir, for giving me the opportunity to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler shakes the man's hand perfunctorily and tells Stern with a look, okay, that's enough, get him out of here.</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome, I'm sure you're doing a great job.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWENSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The SS beat me up. They would have killed me, but I'm essential to the war effort, thanks to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWENSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I work hard for you. I'll continue to work hard for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's great, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWENSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God bless you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWENSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler is dying, and telling Stern with his eyes, Get this guy out of here. Stern takes the man's arm.</context>
      <utterance>You're a good man.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Mr. Lowenstein.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWENSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He saved my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWENSTEIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God bless him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They disappear out the door. Schindler sits down to his meal. And tries to eat it.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ever do that to me again.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern knows what he means. And Schindler knows he knows.</context>
      <utterance>Do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>Close the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TOFFEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's got nothing to do with reality, Oskar, I know it and you know it, it's a matter of national priority to these guys. It's got a ritual significance to them, Jews shoveling snow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lost a day of production. I lost a worker. I expect to be compensated.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOFFEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>File a grievance with the Economic Office, it's your right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would it do any good?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOFFEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler knows it's not Toffel's fault, but the whole situation is maddening to him. He shakes his head in disgust.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOFFEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler gets up, shakes Toffel's hand, turns to leave.</context>
      <utterance>I think you're going to have to put up with a lot of snow shoveling yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOFFEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A one-armed machinist, Oskar?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Toffel nods, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>He was a metal press operator, quite skilled.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern, who has been keeping a low profile, hands the gentlemen each a set of documents.</context>
      <utterance>Unlike your radiators -- and your boxes -- my products aren't for sale on the open market. This company has only one client, the German Army. And lately I've been having trouble fulfilling my obligations to my client. With your help, I hope the problem can be solved. The problem, simply, is space.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like you to consider a proposal which I think you'll find equitable. I'd like you to think about it and get back to me as soon as --</utterance>
   <speaker>KUHNPAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man glances to Stern, and back to Schindler, his look saying, This is wrong, having a Jew present while we discuss business. If Schindler catches his meaning, he doesn't admit it. Kuhnpast almost sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me -- do you really think this is appropriate?</utterance>
   <speaker>KUHNPAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can appreciate your problem. If I had any space I could lease you, I would. I don't. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOHNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me neither, sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a long stunned silence. The Germans can't believe it. After the initial shock wears off, Kuhnpast has to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to lease your facilities, I want to buy them. I'm prepared to offer you fair market value. And to let you stay on, if you want, as supervisors.  On salary.</utterance>
   <speaker>KUHNPAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nobody is kidding.</context>
      <utterance>You've got to be kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>KUHNPAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sets it down, gets up. Hohne gets up. They return the documents to Stern and turn to leave. They aren't quite out the door when Schindler wonders out loud to Stern:</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You try to be fair to people, they walk out the door; I've never understood that. What's next?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christmas presents.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The businessmen slow, but don't look back into the room.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens her eyes and smiles. Schindler is holding a poodle in his arms. She comes around to kiss him. He sets the dog on the desk. Stern, across the room, watches blank-faced.</context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GESTAPO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Schindler, Stern and Klonowska turn to the voice. Two Gestapo men have entered unannounced.</context>
      <utterance>Oskar Schindler?</utterance>
   <speaker>GESTAPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler stares at them in disbelief. Stern quietly slips one of the ledgers on his desk into a drawer.</context>
      <utterance>We have a warrant to take your company's business records with us. And another to take you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't wait for their approval. He scribbles down some names -- Toffel, Czurda, Reeder, Scherner. Underlining Scherner, he glances to Klonowska. She understands.</context>
      <utterance>Am I permitted to have my secretary cancel my appointments for the day?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GESTAPO CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man slowly shakes his head 'no' to Schindler's offer of a cigarette. Schindler tamps it against the crystal of his gold watch.</context>
      <utterance>You live very well.</utterance>
   <speaker>GESTAPO CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler lights the cigarette and drags on it, all but ignoring the man.</context>
      <utterance>This standard of living comes entirely from legitimate sources, I take it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GESTAPO CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As an SS supplier, you have a moral obligation to desist from blackmarket dealings. You're in business to support the war effort, not to fatten --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the young guard five times the going price.</context>
      <utterance>Chances of getting a bottle of vodka pretty good?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAFFEN GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard turns to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He peels off several more bills and hands them over.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pajamas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GESTAPO CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler ignores the man completely. Reaching the front doors, the clerk turns over the D.E.F. records to their owner and offers his hand. Schindler lets it hang there.</context>
      <utterance>I'd advise you not to get too comfortable. Sooner or later, law prevails. No matter who your friends are.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You expect me to walk home, or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>GESTAPO CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring a car around for Mr. Schindler.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are no less than forty able-bodied Jewish laborers working on the docks, any one of which would be better suited to the task. The Gestapo man calls to one of them.</context>
      <utterance>If you'd return the ledgers to my office I'd appreciate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy just stares. Finally he heads off with the ledgers. The poodle bounds out past him and over to Schindler. He gives the dog a pat on the head.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me -- hey --  They're working.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's essential. Without him, everything comes to a grinding halt. If that happens --</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Itzhak Stern?  He's on the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The clerk shows him the list, points out the name to him.</context>
      <utterance>He is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's on the list. If he were an essential worker, he would not be on the list. He's on the list. You can't have him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler pulls out a small notepad and drops his voice to a hard murmur, the growl of a reasonable man who isn't ready -- yet -- to bring out his heavy guns:</context>
      <utterance>I'm talking to a clerk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, the list is correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't ask you about the list, I asked you your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Schindler writes it down, the clerk has second thoughts and calls to a superior, an SS sergeant, who comes over.</context>
      <utterance>Klaus Tauber.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The gentleman thinks a mistake's been made.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sergeant takes a good hard look at the clothes, at the pin, at the man wearing them.</context>
      <utterance>My plant manager is somewhere on this train. If it leaves with him on it, it'll disrupt production and the Armaments Board will want to know why.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he on the list?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The list is correct, sir. There's nothing I can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May as well get your name while you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name? My name is Kunder. Sergeant Kunder. What's yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sergeant takes out a pad. Now all three of them have lists. He jots down Schindler's name. Schindler jots down his and flips the pad closed.</context>
      <utterance>Schindler.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks away, back toward his car. The clerk and sergeant smile. But slowly, slowly, the smiles sour at the possibility that this man calmly walking away from them could somehow arrange such a fate...</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant, Mr. Tauber, thank you very much. I think I can guarantee you you'll both be in Southern Russia before the end of the month. Good evening.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CLERK &amp; SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Soon it seems as if everybody except Schindler is yelling out the name. As they reach the last few cars, the accountant's face appears through the slats.</context>
      <utterance>Stern! Itzhak Stern!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guards yank at a lever, slide the gate open. Stern climbs down. The clerk draws a line through his name on the list and hands the clipboard to Schindler.</context>
      <utterance>Open it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Schindler signs three or four forms, the guards slide the carriage gate closed. Those left inside seem grateful for the extra space.</context>
      <utterance>Initial it, please.  And this...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler returns the clipboard. The sergeant motions to another who motions to the engineer. As the train pulls out, Stern tries to keep up with Schindler who's striding away.</context>
      <utterance>It makes no difference to us, you understand -- this one, that one. It's the inconvenience to the list. It's the paperwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler silences him with a look. He's livid. Stern glances down at the ground.</context>
      <utterance>I somehow left my work card at home. I tried to tell them it was a mistake, but they --</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler turns away and heads for the car. Stern hurries after him. They pass an area where all the luggage, carefully tagged, has been left -- the image becoming BLACK and WHITE.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. It was stupid.  Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KNUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The look Goeth gives Knude tells him to refrain, if he would, from offering tactical opinions.</context>
      <utterance>This street divides the ghetto just about in half. On the right -- Ghetto A: civil employees, industry workers, so on. On the left, Ghetto B: surplus labor, the elderly mostly. Which is where you'll probably want to start.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course that's entirely up to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HUJAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth watches the woman moving around the shell of the building, pointing, directing, telling the workers to take it all down. He goes to take a closer look. She comes over.</context>
      <utterance>She says the foundation was poured wrong, she's got to take it down. I told her it's a barracks, not a fucking hotel, fucking Jew engineer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGINEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth considers the foundation as if he knew about such things. He nods pensively. Then turns to Hujar.</context>
      <utterance>The entire foundation has to be dug up and re-poured. If it isn't, the thing will collapse before it's even completed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's hard to tell which is more stunned by the order, the woman or Hujar. Both stare at Goeth in disbelief. He gives her the reason along with a shrug --</context>
      <utterance>Shoot her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hujar unholsters his pistol but holds it limply at his side. The workers become aware of what's happening and still their hammers.</context>
      <utterance>You argued with my man.  Shoot her.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUJAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth groans and takes the gun from him and puts it to the woman's head. Calmly to her --</context>
      <utterance>Sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fires. She crumples to the ground. He returns the gun to his stunned inferior and, gesturing down at the body, addresses the workers.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>That's somebody who knew what they were doing. That's somebody I needed.  Take it down, re-pour it, rebuild it, like she said.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>HUJAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hujar glances off, interrupted by Schindler's arrival. Although he's never been here, the industrialist comes in like he owns the place. All but Goeth rise.</context>
      <utterance>Your machinery will be moved and installed by the SS at no cost to you. You will pay no rent, no maintenance --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He works his way around the table, patting Bosch and Madritsch on the back -- he knows them -- shaking Hujar's hand, who he doesn't know. He reaches Goeth.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, come on, sit --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth takes a good long look at the handsomely dressed entrepreneur and allows him to shake his hand.</context>
      <utterance>How you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We started without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler takes a seat, shakes a napkin onto his lap, nods to the servant holding out a bottle of champagne to him.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth watches him. The others watch Goeth.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss anything important?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUJAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was explaining to Mr. Bosch and Mr. Madritsch some of the benefits of moving their factories into Plaszow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler clearly doesn't care, but nods as though he did. He drinks. Goeth just watches him with what seems to be growing amusement. He nods to Hujar to continue.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, good, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUJAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler laughs out loud, cutting Hujar off. Hujar glances over to Goeth nonplussed.</context>
      <utterance>Since your labor is housed on-site, it's available to you at all times. You can work them all night if you want. Your factory policies, whatever they've been in the past, they'll continue to be, they'll be respected --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's not sorry at all, and starts in on the plate of food that's set down in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, they told me you were going to be trouble -- Czurda and Scherner.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth slowly shakes his head no... then smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You're kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks great, though, doesn't he? I have to know -- where do you get a suit like that? what is that, silk?  It's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs like, those are the breaks, too bad. Goeth just smiles. The others watch the two of them, unsure how they're supposed to react.</context>
      <utterance>I'd say I'd get you one but the guy who made it, he's probably dead, I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler nods pensively, perhaps in agreement, perhaps at some other thought. There's a silence, broken finally by --</context>
      <utterance>Something wonderful's happened, do you know what it is? Without planning it, we've reached that happy point in our careers where duty and financial opportunity meet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I go to work the other day, there's nobody there. Nobody tells me about this, I have to find out, I have to go in, everybody's gone --</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're not gone, they're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice echoes into silence. An acquiescent shrug from Goeth finally. And a nod; Schindler's right.</context>
      <utterance>They're mine!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every day that goes by, I'm losing money. Every worker that is shot, costs me money -- I have to get somebody else, I have to train them --</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to be making so much money, none of this is going to matter --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's bad business.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of the boys went crazy, what're you going to do? You're right, it's bad business, but it's over with, it's done.  Occasionally, sure, okay, you got to make an example. But that's good business. Schindler pours himself another shot from the bottle, nurses it. He's in a foul mood. They study each other, trying to determine perhaps who's more powerful. Eventually --</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scherner told me something else about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, what's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That you know the meaning of the word gratitude. That it's not some vague thing with you like with some guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth tries to put the situation in perspective:</context>
      <utterance>True.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler admits it by not disagreeing. Goeth thinks about it, nods to himself again, then frowns.</context>
      <utterance>You want to stay where you are. You got things going on the side, things are good, you don't want anybody telling you what to do -- I can understand all that.  What you want is your own sub-camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any idea what's involved? The paperwork alone? Forget you got to build it all, getting the fucking permits, that's enough to drive you crazy. Then the engineers show up. They stand around and they argue about drainage -- I'm telling you, you'll want to shoot somebody, I've been through it, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth mulls it over, his shrug saying "maybe, maybe not." A silence before --</context>
      <utterance>Well, you've been through it. You know. You could make things easier for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's the word Goeth was waiting to hear.</context>
      <utterance>I'd be grateful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SS OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have the Poles beat the Czechs, you have the Czechs beat the Poles, that way everybody stays in line.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs, Too bad, what're you going to do? The SS guy has to think. Yeah, that's a problem. Two huge leashed dogs yank another SS man across their path.</context>
      <utterance>All I have is Jews.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LEO JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- she's seventy years old, she's been there forever -- they bomb her house. Everything's gone. The furniture, everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler, with yet another girl on his arm, endures the officer's lies while sweeping the room with his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God she wasn't there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler looks at him for the first time, knowingly.</context>
      <utterance>I was thinking maybe you could help her out. Some plates and mugs, some stew pots, I don't know. Say half a gross of everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She run an orphanage, your aunt?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler's girl excuses herself to get a drink.</context>
      <utterance>She's old. What she can't use maybe she can sell.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want it sent directly to her or through you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler nods, Done. Both watch his date across the room getting a drink. As usual, she's the best-looking on there.</context>
      <utterance>Through me, I think. I'd like to enclose a card.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEO JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whatever tolerance Schindler's had up to this point with John leaves his face; the looks he gives him now is pure contempt.</context>
      <utterance>Your wife must be a saint.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GOETH'S GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not a soldier?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>CZURDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone laughs.</context>
      <utterance>There's a picture. Private Schindler? Blanket around his shoulders over in Kharkov?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happened to what's his name -- up in Warsaw -- and he was bigger than you, Oskar.</utterance>
   <speaker>CZURDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toebbens.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Happened to Toebbens. Almost. Himmler goes up to Warsaw, tells the armament guys, "Get the fucking Jews out of Toebbens' factory and put Toebbens in the army," and -- "and sent him to the Front." I mean, the Front.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's true. Never happen in Cracow, though, we all love you too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another round of laughs, only this time it's forced. Everybody knows it's true, but you don't say it out loud, and Schindler knows better. Goeth gives him a look; they'll talk later.</context>
      <utterance>I pay you too much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You held back Stern. You held back the one man most important to my business.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's important to my business.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want for him, I'll give it to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Come on, let's go inside, let's have a good time. Goeth heads back inside. Schindler stays outside, finishing his cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>I want him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He discreetly hands over to the accountant some cigars scavenged from the party. From another pocket, he retrieves and hands over some tins of food -- all valuable commodities. From another pocket, perhaps not so valuable, but then who knows, a gold lighter. Regarding this last item --</context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This, I don't know, maybe you can trade it for something.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler shrugs, It's the least I can do. The two stand around a moment more before Schindler shrugs again, Sorry I can't do more. He reaches out, pats Stern on the shoulder, and, turning to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got to go, I'll see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler comes back, but, out of embarrassment or -- maybe he wants to get back to the party -- waits with some impatience for Stern to tell whatever it is he wants to tell him. Lowering his voice --</context>
      <utterance>Oskar --</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a guy. This thing happened. Goeth came into the metalworks --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not daring to look up, all the worker sees of Goeth is the starched cuff of his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>What are you making?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVARTOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rabbi-turned-metalworker gestures with his head to a pile of hinges on the floor. Goeth nods. And in a tone more like a friend than anything else --</context>
      <utterance>Hinges, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got some workers coming in tomorrow... Where the hell they from again?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yugoslavia.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs apologetically and pulls out a pocket watch.</context>
      <utterance>Yugoslavia. I got to make room.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Goeth times him, Rabbi Levartov works at making a hinge as though his life depended on it -- which it does -- cutting the pieces, wrenching them together, smoothing the edges, all the while keeping count on his head of the seconds ticking away. He finishes and lets it fall onto the others on the floor. Forty seconds.</context>
      <utterance>Make me a hinge.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again the rabbi works feverishly -- cutting, crimping, sanding, hearing the seconds ticking in his head -- and finishing in thirty-five. Goeth nods, impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Another.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He understands perfectly. So does Levartov; he has just crafted his own death in exactly 75 seconds. Goeth stands him against the workshop wall and adjusts his shoulders. He pulls out his pistol, puts it to the rabbi's head and pulls the trigger... click.</context>
      <utterance>That's very good. What I don't understand, though, is -- you've been working since what, about six this morning? Yet such a small pile of hinges?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annoyed, Goeth extracts the bullet-magazine, slaps it back in and puts the barrel back to the man's head. He pulls the trigger again... and again there's a click.</context>
      <utterance>Christ --</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slams the weapon across Levartov's face and the rabbi slumps dazed to the floor. Looking up into Goeth's face, he knows it's not over. As Goeth walks away --</context>
      <utterance>God damn it --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEVARTOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler has to think a moment before he can figure out who the grateful man is.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. You're welcome.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one confesses. Goeth nods, All right, takes a rifle from a guard and shoots one of the workers at random. With this added incentive, he waits for someone to tell him who stole the chicken. No one does.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody knows who stole the chicken. A man walks around with a chicken, nobody notices this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs, Okay, points the rifle at another worker -- and a boy of fourteen, shuddering and weeping, steps out of line.</context>
      <utterance>Still nobody knows.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth goes over to the boy, and, like a distant relative to a small child, tries to get him to look at his face.</context>
      <utterance>There we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was you? You committed this crime?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy nods, weeps, screams --</context>
      <utterance>You know who, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's pointing at the dead man. And Goeth astonishes the entire assembly of workers and guards by believing the boy. He returns the rifle to the guard and walks away. Hujar stares after him, then knowingly at the boy.</context>
      <utterance>Him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Krause.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS KRAUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can tell now she doesn't know him. He seems relieved. He leads her past Klonowska's desk and into his office.</context>
      <utterance>How do you do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pernod? Cognac?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS KRAUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pours himself a drink, warms it in his hands, smiles, clearly take with her.</context>
      <utterance>No, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The grace with which she's carried herself up to this point seems to evaporate as she struggles to find the words she wants.</context>
      <utterance>So.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS KRAUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler's face changes like a wall going up, a mask of indifference like in the portrait of Adolf Hitler on the wall behind him.</context>
      <utterance>They say that no one dies here. They say your factory is a haven. They say you are good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who says that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS KRAUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler glances away from her. He seems weary suddenly, depressed.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS KRAUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler glances back at her, his face hard, cold, and studies her for a long, long moment before --</context>
      <utterance>My name is Regina Perlman, not Elsa Krause. I've been living in Cracow on false papers since the ghetto massacre.  My parents are in Plaszow. They're old. They're killing old people in Plaszow now. They bury them up in the forest. I have no money. I borrowed these clothes. Will you bring them here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him, frightened and bewildered. She feels tears welling up.</context>
      <utterance>I don't do that. You've been misled. I ask one thing: whether or not a worker has certain skills. That's what I ask and that's what I care about, get out of my office.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hurries out.</context>
      <utterance>Cry and I'll have you arrested, I swear to God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern has hardly had time to look up from the work on his desk.</context>
      <utterance>People die, it's a fact of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern's look is all innocence, but Schindler knows better.</context>
      <utterance>He wants to kill everybody? Great. What am I supposed to do, bring everybody over? Is that what you think? Yeah, send them over to Schindler, send them all. His place is a "haven," didn't you know? It's not a factory, it's not an enterprise of any kind, it's a haven for people with no skills whatsoever.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I don't know what you're doing? You're so quiet all the time? I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you losing money?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not losing money, that's not the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What other point is --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Schindler tries to settle down. Then --</context>
      <utterance>It's dangerous. It's dangerous, to me, personally.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to understand, Goeth's under enormous pressure. You have to think of it in his situation. He's got this whole place to run, he's responsible for everything that goes on here, all these people -- he's got a lot of things to worry about. And he's got the war. Which brings out the worst in people. Never the good, always the bad. Always the bad. But in normal circumstances, he wouldn't be like this. He'd be all right. There'd be just the good aspects of him. Which is a wonderful crook. A guy who loves good food, good wine, the ladies, making money...</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And killing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll admit it's a weakness. I don't think he enjoys it.  All right, he does enjoy it, so what? What do you expect me to do about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But it isn't Stern who needs convincing; it's Schindler himself. It's doubtful he even realizes this, but it's clear to Stern. Schindler sighs either at the predicament itself, or at the fact that he's allowed Stern to place him right in the middle of it. He turns to leave, hesitates. He conducts a mental search for a name and eventually comes up with it:</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing you can do. I'm not asking you to do anything. You came into my office.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He unstraps his watch, hands it to Stern.</context>
      <utterance>Perlman, husband and wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Give it to Goldberg, have him send them over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It seems almost as though this temptation toward restraint, this image Schindler has brush-stroked of the merciful emperor, holds some appeal to Goeth. Perhaps, as he stares out over his camp, he imagines himself in the role, wondering what the power Schindler describes might feel like. Eventually, he glances over drunkenly, and almost smiles.</context>
      <utterance>They don't fear us because we have the power to kill, they fear us because we have the power to kill arbitrarily. A man commits a crime, he should know better. We have him killed, we feel pretty good about it. Or we kill him ourselves and we feel even better. That's not power, though, that's justice. That's different than power. Power is when we have every justification to kill -- and we don't. That's power. That's what the emperors had. A man stole something, he's brought in before the emperor, he throws himself down on the floor, he begs for mercy, he knows he's going to die... and the emperor pardons him. This worthless man. He lets him go. That's power. That's power.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amon the Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STABLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir, I'm almost done.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Goeth waits, patiently it seems, whistling to himself, the stable boy tries to mask his confusion.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth steps past him to take a look. The worker is almost shaking, he's so terrified of the violent reprisal he expects to receive.</context>
      <utterance>I have to report, sir, I've been unable to remove the stains from your bathtub.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you using?</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soap, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The worker hasn't a defense for himself. Goeth's hand drifts down as if by instinct to the gun in his holster. He stares at the worker. He so wants to shoot him he can hardly stand it, right here, right in the bathroom, put some more stains on the porcelain. He takes a deep breath to calm himself. Then gestures grandly.</context>
      <utterance>Soap? Not lye?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The worker hurries out with his pail and cloth. Goeth just stands there for several moments -- trying to feel the power of emperors he's supposed to be feeling. But he doesn't feel it. All he feels is stupid.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, go on, leave. I pardon you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are fifteen thousand people here --</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goeth says there's twenty-five.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are fifteen. He wants to say sixteen, seventeen, all right, maybe he can get away with it, but ten thousand over? It's stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stern, do me a favor, get out of here. You want to argue about it, go tell Goeth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Stern slowly shakes his head 'no.'</context>
      <utterance>So you'll be rid of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's the irony -- bad as it is, evil as Goeth is, it could get worse. Schindler understands.</context>
      <utterance>If Plaszow is closed, they'll have to send us somewhere else. Where -- who knows? Gross-Rosen maybe. Maybe Auschwitz.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands over to Stern some negotiable items and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll talk to somebody. I'll take care of it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he done that's so bad -- take money? That's a crime? Come on, what are we here for, to fight a war? We're here to make money, all of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOFFEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's taking money and there's taking money, you know that. He's taking money.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The place produces nothing. I shouldn't say that -- nothing it produces reaches the Army. That's not all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'll talk to him about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a friend of yours, you want to help him out. Tell me this, though -- has he ever once shown you his appreciation? I've yet to see it. Never a courtesy. Never a thank you note. He forgets my wife at Christmas time --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got no style, we all know that. So, we should hang him for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOFFEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's stealing from you, Oskar.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course he's stealing from me, we're in business together. What is this? I'm sitting here, suddenly everybody's talking like this is something bad. We take from each other, we take from the Army, everybody uses everybody, it works out, everybody's happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler glances away to the floor show, nods to himself. Glancing back again, he considers the SS men with great sobriety.</context>
      <utterance>Not like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His thinly veiled threat of exposure escapes neither SS man. The air seems thicker suddenly.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, in some eyes it doesn't matter the amount we steal, it's that we do it. Each of us sitting at this table.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't deserve your loyalty. More important, he's not worth you making threats against us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The threat still stands, despite Schindler's assurance otherwise, and they all know it. So does Scherner's threat back to him, and they all know that, too. But Schindler just grins, and, glancing away --</context>
      <utterance>Did I threaten anybody here? I stated a simple fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, let's watch the girls.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FACTORY GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates. She's surrounded by SS uniforms and swastikas and holstered guns. Schindler smiles; this is a beautiful girl.</context>
      <utterance>...On behalf of the workers... sir... I wish you a happy birthday...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her on the mouth. The smiles on the faces around them strain. Stern glances to heaven. Amon cocks his head like a confused dog. The kiss is broken, finally, and Schindler smiles again with impunity.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl backs away nodding anxiously; all she wants now is out before someone -- her, Schindler, both of them -- gets shot. Henry Rosner nudges Leo and they begin another song. And the party tries to resume.</context>
      <utterance>Thank them for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Goeth glances up, finds Poldek among the group taking off their clothes. Pfefferberg appeals to him with a look that asks, Do I really have to go through this, and Goeth turns to a clerk.</context>
      <utterance>Commandant, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pfefferberg is motioned away from the others; he's okay, he doesn't have to be put through this indignity. He calls out to the Commandant again --</context>
      <utterance>My mechanic.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth thinks about it a moment before he nods, Yeah, okay, sure. A clerk accompanies Pfefferberg and, making a notation on the way, finds Mila.</context>
      <utterance>What about my wife?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried to call you, I'm running a little late, this is taking longer than I thought. Have a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances away at the train. The idling engine only partially covers the desperate pleas for water coming from inside the slatted cars.</context>
      <utterance>I got a shipment of Hungarians coming in, I got to make room for them. It's always something.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins. Schindler watches as another car is loaded. It's like they're climbing into an oven.</context>
      <utterance>They're complaining now? They don't know what complaining is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth stares at him blankly, then with a What-will-you-think- of-next? kind of look, then laughs uproariously and calls over to Hujar --</context>
      <utterance>What do you say we get your fire brigade out here and hose down the cars?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring the fire trucks!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUJAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hujar heard him, he just doesn't get it. Finally he turns to another guy and tells him to do it. STREAM OF WATER CASCADE onto the scalding rooftops. The fire trucks are there, the hoses firing the cold water at the cars on the people inside who are roaring their gratitude.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And amusing, not just to Goeth, but to the other SS officers standing around as well. Oskar moves away to talk with one of the firemen. At full extension, apparently the hoses still only reach halfway down the long line of cars. He returns to Goeth.</context>
      <utterance>This is really cruel, Oskar, you're giving them hope. You shouldn't do that, that's cruel.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth finds this especially sidesplitting, and hollers --</context>
      <utterance>I've got some 200-meter hoses back at D.E.F., we can reach the cars down at the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE D.E.F. HOSES have arrived and are being coupled to Plaszow's. As the water drenches the cars further back, the people inside loudly voice their thanks, and the guards and officers outside grin at the spectacle.</context>
      <utterance>Hujar!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The joke takes on new dimension when, from the back of the D.E.F. trucks, boxes of food are unloaded. Accompanied by the laughter of the SS, Schindler moves along the string of cars pushing sausages through the slats.</context>
      <utterance>What does he think he's saving them from?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth is almost hysterical. But slowly then, slowly, the amusement on his face fades. His friend moving along the cars bringing futile mercy to the doomed in front of countless SS men, laughing or not, is not just behaving recklessly here, it's as though he were possessed. The water rains down on the last car.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not saying you'll regret it, but you might. I want you to be aware of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GESTAPO 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler glances beyond them to a point outside his office, to Klonowska. She nods, she knows what to do, she'll make the phone calls, call in the favors.</context>
      <utterance>We'll risk it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snuffs out his cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>All right, sure, it's a nice day, I'll go for a drive with you guys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth tries to read the guy behind the desk, but his face is like a wall.</context>
      <utterance>He likes women. He likes good-looking women. He sees a good-looking woman, he doesn't think. This guy has so many women. They love him. He's married, he's got all these women. All right, she was Jewish, he shouldn't have done it. But you didn't see this girl. I saw this girl. This girl was very good-looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth shifts in his chair; he knows he's not getting anywhere with this guy. He switches tacts:</context>
      <utterance>They cast a spell on you, you know, the Jews. You work closely with them like I do, you see this. They have this power, it's like a virus. Some of my men are infected with this virus. They should be pitied, not punished. They should receive treatment, because this is as real as typhus. I see this all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the silence that follows, Goeth realizes he has made a serious error in judgment. This man sitting soberly before him is one of that rare breed -- the unbribable official.</context>
      <utterance>It's a matter of money? We can discuss that. That'd be all right with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SS COLONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're offering me a bribe?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the man stands up and salutes, which thoroughly confuses Goeth since Goeth is his inferior in rank. But he isn't saluting Goeth, he's saluting the officer who has just stepped into the room behind him.</context>
      <utterance>A "bribe?" No, no, please come on... a gratuity.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The colonel sits back down. Scherner pulls up a chair next to Goeth.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Amon.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scherner smiles and allows Goeth to shake his hand, but it's clear, even to Goeth himself, that he has fallen from grace.</context>
      <utterance>Sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SS OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's drunk, morose; it seems unlikely he'll be on his feet much longer. Indeed, as Henry and Leo Rosner begin the son -- an excessively melancholy tale in which a young man commits suicide for love -- the field officer staggers over to a chair in the corner of the crowded room and slumps into it.</context>
      <utterance>I want to hear "Gloomy Sunday" again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHERNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth laughs too loud, drawing a weary glance from Scherner. Schindler smiles good-naturedly. He's out, a little worse for wear perhaps, a little more subdued than usual. Taking him away from the others, taking him into his confidence --</context>
      <utterance>We give you Jewish girls at five marks a day, Oskar, you should kiss us, not them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE THIN GRAY SS OFFICER is back in front of the musicians, swaying precariously, a drink in his hand --</context>
      <utterance>God forbid you ever get a real taste for Jewish skirt. There's no future in it. No future. They don't have a future. And that's not just good old- fashioned Jew-hating talk. It's policy now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SS OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again they play the song. Again he staggers across the crowded room to his chair in the corner, paying no attention to the visiting Commandant from Treblinka or anybody else --</context>
      <utterance>"Gloomy Sunday" again.</utterance>
   <speaker>TREBLINKA GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs like it's nothing, or with modesty, it's unclear. Goeth is dully impressed; Schindler, only politely so.</context>
      <utterance>-- We can process at Treblinka, if everything is working? I don't know, maybe two thousand units a day.</utterance>
   <speaker>TREBLINKA GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AGAIN THE GRAY OFFICER wavering before Henry and Leo. This time they don't wait for him to ask for it --</context>
      <utterance>Now Auschwitz. Now you're talking. What I got is nothing, it's like a... a machine. Auschwitz, though, now there's a death factory. There, they know how to do it. There, they know what they're doing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth shakes his head, dismayed. Schindler joins him and stares at a pyre of bodies built by masked and gagging workers, layer upon layer.</context>
      <utterance>Can you believe this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's always something. He glances off. The pyre has reached the height of a man's shoulder. The workers move around it dousing it with gasoline.</context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to live my life, they come up with this? I got to find every body buried up here? And burn it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You took my workers.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're taking mine. When I said they didn't have a future I didn't mean tomorrow.  Auschwitz.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs at the unfairness of it all, the dissolution of his kingdom. His glance finds his man, Leo John, over at the stream.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tight on the gleeful boy with a tadpole in his hand. Behind him, smoke from the pyre rises into the sky.</context>
      <utterance>This is good. I'm out of business and he's catching tadpoles with his son.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, how you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRINNLITZ GUY 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler, the clothes, the car, the suitcases, the great difference between their respective stations in life. Somehow their old ne'er-do-well friend has managed to do quite well, and it amazes them. Across the square, Emilie has noticed him; and he, her. But neither makes a move toward the other. Finally she walks away; which Schindler interprets correctly to mean, Yes, check into the hotel. He tips the porter extravagantly and turns back to the guys from the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me buy you a drink.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRINNLITZ GUY 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oskar - my friend Lena.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do?  What can I get you, what're you drinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRINNLITZ GUY 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing's changed. Then again, something has changed, hasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things worked out. I made some money over there, had some laughs, you know. It was good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRINNLITZ GUY 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you're back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures to the bartender to refill his friend's and his date's drinks, pats the guy on the shoulder and wanders over to the next table.</context>
      <utterance>Now I'm back, and you know what I'm going to do now? I'm going to have a good time. So are you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy has to think; not because he doesn't know, but because his old friend Oskar is so many things it's hard to know which description to use. Finally --</context>
      <utterance>Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRINNLITZ GUY 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a salesman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want these people.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth considers his friend, greatly puzzled. Below them lies the camp, still operating, at least for now, until the shipments can be arranged.</context>
      <utterance>These people, my people, I want my people.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you, Moses? What is this? Where's the money in this? What's the scam?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good business.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is "good business" in your opinion. You've got to move them, the equipment, everything to Czechoslovakia -- it doesn't make any sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look --</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not telling me something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good for me -- I know them, I'm familiar with them. It's good for you -- you'll be compensated. It's good for the Army. You know what I'm going to make?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Artillery shells. Tank shells. They need that. Everybody's happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth finds this whole line of reasoning impossible to believe. He's sure Schindler's got something else going on here he's not telling him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler admits it with a shrug.</context>
      <utterance>You're probably scamming me somehow. If I'm making a hundred, you got to be making three.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you admit to making three, then it's four, actually. But how?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth studies him, searching for the real answer in his face. He can't find it.</context>
      <utterance>You did, but you didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, all right, don't tell me, I'll go along with it, it's just irritating to me I can't figure it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth thinks about it in the silence. Then a slow nod to himself. He's going to make some money out of this even if he can't figure it out. He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>All you have to do is tell me what it's worth to you. What's a person worth to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's one worth to you? That's the question.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE KEYS typing ‘PFEFFE- PFEFFERBERG'S face, tight. MILA'S face, tight. CURRENCY, hard Reichmarks, in a small valise. As Goeth looks at it, he mumbles to himself --</context>
      <utterance>Poldek Pfefferberg... Mila Pfefferberg...</utterance>
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MOVING DOWN THE LIST of names, forty, fifty. The sound of the keys. Stern pulls the sheet out of the machine, rolls in another, types a name. EQUIPMENT BEING LOADED onto trucks outside Madritsch's Plaszow factory.</context>
      <utterance>A virus...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madritsch is shaking his head ‘no' to Schindler's appeal to make his own list, to get his workers out.</context>
      <utterance>You can do the same thing I'm doing. There's nothing stopping you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADRITSCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE KEYS typing another name -- A FACE, a man, A FACE, a woman, A FACE, a child -- COGNAC SPILLING into a glass. The glass coming up to Schindler's mouth, hesitating there.</context>
      <utterance>I've done enough for the Jews.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A NAME -- A FACE -- one of the original D.E.F. investors. ANOTHER NAME -- ANOTHER FACE -- another of the Jewish investors.</context>
      <utterance>The investors.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STERN GLANCES UP with a look that asks Schindler if he's sure about this one. He is. The keys type SZERWITZ -- TIGHT ON THE FACE of the investor who stole from Schindler, the one he threatened to have killed by the SS, and the faces of his sons -- THREE OR FOUR PAGES of names next to the typewriter. Stern, trying to count them, estimates --</context>
      <utterance>All of them. Szerwitz, his family.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four hundred, four fifty --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE TRUNK OF SCHINDLER'S MERCEDES yawning open. He takes a small valise from it and heads for Goeth's villa. THE KEYS typing ROSNER -- TIGHT ON Henry Rosner, the violinist. TIGHT ON his brother, Leo, the accordionist. SCHINDLER AND BOSCH, the other Plaszow industrialist. The same appeal Schindler made to Madritsch; the same answer, ‘no.' MOVING DOWN another page of names.</context>
      <utterance>More.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About six hundred --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>THE SOUND OF THE KEYS OVER the face of a boy, the "chicken thief." Over THE FACE OF A GIRL, the one who hid in the pit of excrement. Over the FACES we've never seen.</context>
      <utterance>More.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight hundred, give or take.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern heard him and stops typing, glances over.</context>
      <utterance>That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern resumes where he left off, but then hesitates again. There's something he doesn't understand.</context>
      <utterance>You can finish that page.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It doesn't sound right. And Schindler doesn't answer. He's avoided telling Stern the details of the deal struck with Goeth, and balks telling him now. Finally awkwardly --</context>
      <utterance>What did Goeth say? You just told him how many you needed?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler shrugs like it's no big deal, but Stern knows it is.</context>
      <utterance>I'm buying them. I'm paying him. I give him money, he gives me the people.  If you were still working for me I'd expect you to talk me out of it, it's costing me a fortune. Stern had no idea. And has no idea now what to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern is really overcome by what this man is doing. What he can't figure out is why. Silence. And then --</context>
      <utterance>Give him the list, he'll sign it, he'll get the people ready. I have to go back to Brinnlitz, to take care of things on that end, I'll see you there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern turns back, does as he's told. Schindler drinks. Nothing but the sound of the typewriter keys. And then nothing at all. The page is done. The rest will die.</context>
      <utterance>Finish the page.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks out over his audience, the citizens of Brinnlitz, local government officials, many of them appearing bewildered by him or the "situation" that has arisen.</context>
      <utterance>This is my home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His estranged wife is there. So are the guys he was drinking with.</context>
      <utterance>I was born here, my wife was born here, my mother is buried here, this is my home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone seems to breathe sighs of relief as if they've been waiting for him to say this, to dispel the disturbing rumors they've heard.</context>
      <utterance>Do you really think I'd bring a thousand Jewish criminals into my home?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The noise begins, his audience's angry reaction. Raising pitch of his own voice --</context>
      <utterance>These are skilled munitions workers -- they are essential to the war effort --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He barely gets it all out before the protests drown him out. The uproar reaches such a clamoring level there's no point in his continuing.</context>
      <utterance>-- It is my duty to supervise them -- and it is your duty to allow me --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PRISONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I on the list?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He knows what the prisoner means and the prisoner knows he knows. He means Schindler's List.</context>
      <utterance>What list is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prisoner knows that, too, and discreetly turns over to Goldberg a couple of diamonds from the lining of his coat.</context>
      <utterance>The good list? Well, that depends, doesn't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Poldek, how's it going?  You know about the list? You're on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I'm on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pfefferberg glances up from his work and studies the blackmailing collaborator for a long moment.</context>
      <utterance>You want to stay on it? What do you got for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I got for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pfefferberg suddenly attacks him with the wrench in his hand, beating him across the shoulders and head with it.</context>
      <utterance>Takes diamonds to stay on this list.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goldberg goes down, tries to scramble away on his knees, the blows coming down hard on his back.</context>
      <utterance>I'll kill you, that's what I got for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOLDBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes it outside the garage and runs.</context>
      <utterance>All right, all right, all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GESTAPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friend Amon Goeth has been arrested.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to hear that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GESTAPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are some things that are unclear. We need to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The looks on their faces tell him he's not going anywhere.</context>
      <utterance>I'd love to, it'll have to wait until I get back. I have to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, okay, let's talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>GESTAPO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Breslau.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>These guys are serious.</context>
      <utterance>Breslau? I can't go to Breslau. Not now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>YOUNG DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She could lie, and he'd have killed her for it. She could tell the truth, and he'd have her killed for that, too.</context>
      <utterance>How old are you, Mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor nods pensively, understandingly, it seems. Then --</context>
      <utterance>Sir, a mistake's been made. We're not supposed to be here, we work for Oskar Schindler. We're Schindler Jews.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances around hopelessly. One of the SS guards who accompanied the women from Plaszow speaks up --</context>
      <utterance>And who on earth is Oskar Schindler?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLASZOW GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor nods again as if the information were valuable, as if it meant something to him. It doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>He had a factory in Cracow. Enamelware.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles to himself and gets on with the "examination," this woman to this line, this other one to that.</context>
      <utterance>A potmaker?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INVESTIGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything you say will be held in confidence. You are not under investigation. You are not under investigation. Mr. Goeth is. He is being held on charges of embezzlement and racketeering. You're here at his request to corroborate his denials. Our information onto his financial speculations comes from many sources. On his behalf there is only you. We know you are close friends. We know this is hard for you. But we must ask you --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He stole our country blind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler seems to think about the offer as he nurses his drink. It's "tempting."</context>
      <utterance>You're right, a clerical error has bee made.  Let me offer you this in apology for the inconvenience. I have a shipment coming in tomorrow, I'll cut you three hundred from it. New ones. These are fresh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The train comes, we turn it around, it's yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ones on the list in Hoss' hand. Silence. Then:</context>
      <utterance>I appreciate it. I want these.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why, because you get to know them? Because you begin to see them as human beings? Schindler suddenly has the awful feeling that the women are already dead. Hoss misinterprets the look.</context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't get stuck on names.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, it creates a lot of paperwork.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points across to the women's train, then down to the boys.</context>
      <utterance>These are mine. They're on the list. These are my workers. They should be on the train.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard glances from the frantic gentleman to the anxious brook around him. These are essential workers?</context>
      <utterance>They're skilled munition workers. They're essential.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler is nodding his head, trying to think. The women are shrieking their sons' names. The guard, who heard it all, every excuse imaginable, is just turning away when Schindler thrusts his smallest finger at him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard stares at him dumbly. This he hasn't heard.</context>
      <utterance>Their fingers. They polish the insides of shell casings. How else do you expect me to polish the inside of a 45 millimeter shell casing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes meet Liepold's, hold his icy stare, then return to the guards, most of whom look like tired middle-aged reservists.</context>
      <utterance>Under Department W provisions, it is unlawful to kill a worker without just cause. Under the Businesses Compensation Fund I am entitled to file damage claims for such deaths. If you shoot without thinking, you go to prison and I get paid, that's how it works. So there will be no summary executions here. There will be no interference of any kind with production. In hopes of ensuring that, guards will no longer be allowed on the factory floor without my authorization.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he steps away he gestures to some kitchen workers. They tear open cases of schnapps and begin setting the bottles out on the tables.</context>
      <utterance>For your cooperation, you have my gratitude.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it going?</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. It's taken a while to calibrate the machines, but it's going good now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler nods. Then frowns. He leans down and taps at the crystal of one of the gauges.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The worker kneels down, takes a look. It looks right to him. Reaching over, Schindler changes the calibration of the machine with a cavalier adjustment to a knob -- and all the gauge readings shift.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't right, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wanders off. The worker stares after him. He's just screwed up settings that took weeks to get right. Schindler comes up to another worker, Levartov, the hingemaker. He's at a machine buffing shells.</context>
      <utterance>There. That looks right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it going, Rabbi?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVARTOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler nods, watches him work, eventually glances away.</context>
      <utterance>Good, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Levartov, following Schindler's gaze, nods uncertainly.</context>
      <utterance>Sun's going down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is Friday, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEVARTOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Levartov just stares. It's been years since he's been allowed, indeed inclined, to perform Sabbath rites.</context>
      <utterance>You should be preparing for the Sabbath, shouldn't you? What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler heads off. The rabbi keeps staring. Schindler gestures back to him, offering casually --</context>
      <utterance>I've got some wine in my office. Why don't we go over there, I'll give it to you. Come on, let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Levartov looks around. Finally, he hangs up his goggles and follows after Schindler.</context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There, he's said it. But the bewildered look on Emilie's face wonders, That's what was hard for you to say?</context>
      <utterance>I want you to come work for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's the only woman he's even known who could make him nervous just sitting across a table from him, saying nothing.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have to live with me, I wouldn't ask that.  It's a nice place. You'd like it. It looks awful. You get used to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right --  We can spend time together that way. We can see each other, see how it goes -- without the strain of -- whatever you want to call it when a man, a husband and a wife go out to dinner, go have a drink, go to a party, you know. This way we'll see each other at work, there we are, same place, we see how it goes... His voice trails off. A shrug adds, What do you think? She doesn't answer, but she does love him. He loves her, too. It really is a shame they're not right for each other and never will be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like the doormen and waiters of Cracow, Stern too never imagined Schindler was married and has trouble hiding his astonishment now. He extends his hand to her.</context>
      <utterance>Itzhak Stern, Emilie Schindler. My wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It sounds strange to Stern hearing Schindler actually say it. He's never said it before.</context>
      <utterance>Stern is my accountant and friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's not sure what she's going to do there, she's not a nurse or a doctor.</context>
      <utterance>Emilie's offered to work in the clinic. To... work there.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's very generous of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler nods, looks around, shrugs, offers his arm to his wife, perhaps to take her on a tour of the place.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a pleasure meeting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Schindlers leave. Stern sits back down at his desk and smiles. He's never seen Schindler so uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>Pleasure meeting you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you fix it? The radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. Pfefferberg plugs it into an outlet and switches it on. It works perfectly. A waltz.</context>
      <utterance>How should I know? It's broken. See what you can do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler sifts through the glasses still in the box, comes up with a particular pair and holds them proudly. Not quite sure what he's seeing is real --</context>
      <utterance>Stern.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They arrived.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern allows himself a smile, a rare thing for him. Schindler carefully slips the new glasses onto the accountant's face. He looks around the clinic, Stern, eventually settling on Emilie, crystal clear, standing near a picture on the wall which, in other circumstances, he'd find less than reassuring: Jesus, his heart exposed and in flames.</context>
      <utterance>They arrived, can you believe it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler nods soberly. Then dismisses the problem with a shrug.</context>
      <utterance>We've received a complaint from the Armaments Board. A very angry complaint. The artillery shells, the tank shells, rocket casings -- apparently all of them -- have failed quality-control tests.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's to be expected. They have to understand. These are start- up problems. This isn't pots and pans, this is a precise business. I'll write them a letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're withholding payment.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Stern is worried about it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, sure. So would I. So would you. I wouldn't worry about it. We'll get it right one of these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a rumor you've been going around miscalibrating the machines.  I don't think that's a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern slowly shakes his head 'no.'</context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler eventually nods, in agreement it seems.</context>
      <utterance>They could close us down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern's not sure he sees the logic. Whether the shells are manufactured here or elsewhere, they'll still eventually reach their intended destination, into the hearts and heads of Germany's enemies.</context>
      <utterance>All right. Call around, find out where we can buy shells and buy them. We'll pass them off as ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what you're saying, but I don't see the difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't? I do. I see a difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll lose money. That's one difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's another difference. The main one. The only one Schindler cares about. Silence. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Fewer shells will be made.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stern, if this factory ever produces a shell that can actually be fired... I'll be very unhappy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Liepold swings the gun around at the voice, pointing it for a moment at Schindler, who is striding toward him, then aims the barrel back at the boy's head, and yells --</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves a document at Schindler, throws it at him. Schindler doesn't bother picking it up. Instead, pointing at the boy, he yells to Liepold --</context>
      <utterance>Department W does not forbid my presence on the factory floor. That is a lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liepold is so startled by the command, he doesn't shoot. He doesn't lower the gun, though, either.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot him. Shoot him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His finger is on the trigger, Liepold is torn, frustrated, hating the situation he has created. As the moments without a blast stretch out, both and Schindler begin to settle down.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot him without a hearing. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler glances to the boy. Then at the silent Hilo beside him. Part of it is blackened from an electrical fire. To the boy, concerned --</context>
      <utterance>He sabotaged the machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy, too terrified to speak, nods.</context>
      <utterance>The machine's broken?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEPOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The prisoner is under the jurisdiction of Section D. I'll preside over the hearing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liepold glances to him. He seems almost distraught by the destruction of the machine, Schindler.</context>
      <utterance>But the machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liepold isn't sure that's correct, but he has no documentation, at least not on him, to refute it.</context>
      <utterance>The machine is under the authorization of the Armaments Inspectorate. I will preside over the hearing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JANEK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Commandant Liepold was watching me trying to figure it out. I switched it on and it blew up. I didn't do anything. All I did was turn it on. Gone tonight is Schindler's usual shop-floor familiarity. He studies the boy solemn-faced.</context>
      <utterance>I'm unfamiliar with the Hilo machines. I don't know why I was assigned there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're not skilled at armaments work, you shouldn't be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler dismisses the defensive comment with a wave of his hand and gets up. He comes around and paces slowly before the boy. Eventually, Janek dares to speak again --</context>
      <utterance>I'm a lathe operator.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler glances up at him distractedly.</context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler stops, looks to the panel, and back to the boy.</context>
      <utterance>I did adjust the pressure controls.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler slams the back of his hand so hard across Janek's face, the boy almost falls. He's stunned. So are the others at the table. They've never seen such violence from the Direktor. He roars --</context>
      <utterance>I know that much about them. Somebody had set the pressure controls wrong. I had to adjust --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler's hand comes up again and Janek recoils, expecting another blow. Schindler manages to hold it.</context>
      <utterance>The stupidity of these people. I wish they were capable of sabotaging a machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A guard escorts the prisoner away. The panel members glance among themselves. Is that it? Schindler faces them and groans in dismay.</context>
      <utterance>Get him out of my sight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's not at all nice. He feels out of place, a feeling he's not accustomed to. Fortunately, a man in uniform, someone Schindler can relate to, approaches cheerfully, his hand outstretched.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't this nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oskar, good of you to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding, I never miss a party. Police Chief Rasch, my wife Emilie.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man lives well.</context>
      <utterance>You have a lovely home. It is nice. Big.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, you don't have a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. Schindler goes off in search of the bartender. Rasch watches after him.</context>
      <utterance>Wine?</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your husband's a very generous man.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's always been.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasch calmly nurses his drink, his eyes revealing nothing of what's going on behind them, except that the statement requires some elaboration.</context>
      <utterance>I need guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of these days the Russians are going to show up unannounced at my gate. I'd like the chance to defend myself. I'd like my wife to have that chance. My civilian engineers. My secretary.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're losing the war, aren't we.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It kind of looks that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pistols?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasch smiles faintly. Yes, he's familiar, as are officials throughout much of Europe, with the gratitude of Oskar Schindler.</context>
      <utterance>Pistols, rifles, carbines ...  I'd be grateful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Above the rim of the tank, amid rising steam, Schindler's head appears. Then disappears. Stern climbs a set of rungs on the tank, reaches the top and finds inside, lolling in the steaming water, Schindler and the blonde stenographer from the trial.</context>
      <utterance>Stern.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neither Schindler nor the blonde seems the least bit embarrassed. Only Stern. He tries hard to pretend the girl isn't there, but he just can't.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll talk to you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler floats over closer to him, waits for him to report whatever it is he has come to report, leans closer. Finally, quietly --</context>
      <utterance>No, no, what, what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler thinks long and hard...</context>
      <utterance>Do you have any money I don't know about? Hidden away someplace?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence except for the gently lapping water. Half-joking --</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern glances away, doesn't answer, just stares off. And a slight, slight smile, a gambler's philosophical smile upon being purged of his wealth, appears on Schindler's face.</context>
      <utterance>Why, am I broke?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The priest nods; he seems relatively empathic. He offers an alternative --</context>
      <utterance>It's been suggested I cremate them in my furnaces. As a Catholic I will not. As a human being I will not.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's an area beyond the church reserved for the burial of suicides. Maybe I can convince the parish council to allow them to be buried there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The priest knows that. But he also knows that the provisions of Canon Law regarding who can and cannot be buried in consecrated ground are narrow.</context>
      <utterance>These aren't suicides.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are victims of a great murder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler appears beside Stern, glances down. He's lost weight, Goeth. The old suit he wears seems too big for him. Alone down there he seems disoriented.</context>
      <utterance>What's he doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably looking for a handout.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GOETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the guards?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goeth stares at him bewildered. Then again at the worker who spit. Then at other workers, the resolve in their eyes. They know he has no power here, and sense he has no power anywhere. His own eyes drift to a woman with yarn in her lap, knitting needles in her hands. Is this a dream?</context>
      <utterance>The guards aren't allowed on the factory floor. They make my workers nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler good-naturedly throws an arm around Goeth's shoulder and leads him away. The workers watch as the two Germans disappear out the factory doors.</context>
      <utterance>I'll discipline him later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is not his intention to elicit celebration. Indeed, his words, echoing and fading in the factory, echo the doubts they all feel.</context>
      <utterance>The unconditional surrender of Germany has just been announced. At midnight tonight the war is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not by Untersturmfuhrer Liepold. He stands with his men, dying to lift his rifle and fire.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow, you'll begin the process of looking for survivors of your families. In many cases you won't find them. After six long years of murder, victims are being mourned throughout the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's looking at the guards, thanking them, which thoroughly confuses the workers. Just when they thought they knew where his sentiments lay, he's thanking guards.</context>
      <utterance>We've survived. Some of you have come up to me and thanked me. Thank yourselves. Thank your fearless Stern, and others among you, who, worrying about you, have faced death every moment.  Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Or is he attempting to adjust reality, to destroy the SS as combatants, to alter the self-image of both the guards and the prisoners? Moving across the SS men's faces, they remain inscrutable. Schindler turns his attention back to the workers, and, not at all like a confession, but rather like simple statements of fact:</context>
      <utterance>You've shown extraordinary discipline. You've behaved humanely here. You should be proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That worries the workers. Whenever he leaves, something terrible always seems to happen.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a member of the Nazi party. I'm a munitions manufacturer. I'm a profiteer of slave labor, I'm a criminal. At midnight, you will be free and I will be hunted.  I'll remain with you until five minutes after midnight After which time, and I hope you'll forgive me, I have to flee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>among your people, I ask us to observe three minutes of silence. In the quiet, in the silence, drifting slowly across the faces of the workers -- the elderly, the lame, teenagers, wives beside husbands, children beside their parents, families together -- it becomes clear, if it wasn't before, that both as a prison and a manufacturing enterprise, the Brinnlitz camp has been one long sustained confidence game. Schindler has never stood still so long in his life. He does now, though, framed by his giant Hilo machines, silent at the close of the noisiest of wars, his head bowed, mourning the many dead. When he finally does look up he sees that he is the last to do so. The faces, few of which he recognizes, are all looking at him. He turns to speak to the guards along the wall again.</context>
      <utterance>In memory of the countless victims</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Apprehension spreads across the factory like a wave. Pfefferberg tightens his grip on the pistol under his coat. His ragtag irregulars do the same, the rest of their ersatz "arsenal" concealed behind a machine. To the guards:</context>
      <utterance>I know you've received orders from our Commandant -- which he has received from his superiors -- to dispose of the population of this camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guards hold their weapons, as they have from the moment they arrived here tonight, at attention, waiting it seems, to be given the official order from their Commander, Liepold, who appears ready to give it.</context>
      <utterance>Now would be the time to do it. They're all here. This is your opportunity.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...you could leave. And return to your families as men instead of murderers. Long, long silence. Finally, one of the guards slowly lowers his rifle, breaks ranks and walks away. Then another. And another. And another. Another. When the last is gone, the workers consider Liepold. He appears more an oddity than a threat. He is more an oddity than a threat. And he knows it. He turns and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Or...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LEVARTOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler sees a list of signatures beginning below the typewritten text and continuing for several pages. He pockets it, this new list of names.</context>
      <utterance>We've written a letter trying to explain things. In case you're captured. Every worker has signed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern steps forward and places a ring in Schindler's hand. It's a gold band, like a wedding ring. Schindler notices an inscription inside it.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler slips the ring onto a finger, admires it a moment, nods his thanks, then seems to withdraw.</context>
      <utterance>It's Hebrew. It says, 'Whoever saves one life, saves the world.'</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stern isn't sure he heard right. Schindler steps away from him, from his wife, from the car, from the workers.</context>
      <utterance>I could've got more out...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could've got more... if I'd just... I don't know, if I'd just... I could've got more...</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't.</context>
      <utterance>Oskar, there are twelve hundred people who are alive because of you. Look at them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'd made more money... I threw away so much money, you have no idea. If I'd just...</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There will be generations because of what you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't do enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>STERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schindler starts to lose it, the tears coming. Stern, too. The look on Schindler's face as his eyes sweep across the faces of the workers is one of apology, begging them to forgive him for not doing more.</context>
      <utterance>You did so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rips the elaborate Hakenkreus, the swastika, from his lapel and holds it out to Stern pathetically.</context>
      <utterance>This car. Goeth would've bought this car. Why did I keep the car? Ten people, right there, ten more I could've got.  This pin --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He completely breaks down, weeping convulsively, the emotion he's been holding in for years spilling out, the guilt consuming him.</context>
      <utterance>Two people. This is gold. Two more people. He would've given me two for it. At least one. He would've given me one. One more. One more person. A person, Stern. For this. One more. I could've gotten one more person I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From above, from a watchtower, Stern can be seen down below, trying to comfort Schindler. Eventually, they separate, and Schindler and Emilie climb into the Mercedes. It slowly pulls out through the gates of the camp. And drives away.</context>
      <utterance>They killed so many people...  They killed so many people...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PARTISAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all over.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTISAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you doing? You're free to go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The partisan shrugs, Suit yourself, and wanders back toward the trees with his friends.</context>
      <utterance>When the Russians arrive. Until then we're staying here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RUSSIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is it? This one man? The workers wait for him to say more. He waits for them to move, to leave, to go home. Finally --</context>
      <utterance>You have been liberated by the Soviet Army.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUSSIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few of the workers come out from behind the fence to talk with him.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been in Poland?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUSSIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just came from Poland.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Russian has to think. Eventually he shrugs, 'no,' not that he saw, and climbs back onto his pony to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Are there any Jews left?</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where should we go?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUSSIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs and gives his little horse a kick in the ribs.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Don't go east, that's for sure, they hate you there.  I wouldn't go west either if I were you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Russian looks confused, glances off. The quiet hamlet of Brinnlitz sits there against the mountains not half a mile away.</context>
      <utterance>We could use some food.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUSSIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Of course it is. But the idea that they could simply walk over there is completely foreign to them. The Russian rides away.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't that a town over there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's Poldek Pfefferberg out in the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, how you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. How's it going?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Things don't look so great. Schindler isn't penniless, but he's not far from it, living alone in the one room behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Things are great, things are great.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm having a drink, come on in, we'll have a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean where have you been? Nobody's seen you around for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been here. I guess I haven't been out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought maybe you'd like to come over, have some dinner, some of the people are coming over.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pfefferberg waits out in the hall as Schindler disappears inside for a minute. The legend below appears:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Yeah, that'd be nice, let me get my coat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCHINDLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mila's good?</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kids are good? Let's stop at a store on the way so I can buy them something.</utterance>
   <speaker>PFEFFERBERG'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't need anything. They just want to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHINDLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their voices face. Against the empty hallway appears a faint trace of the image of the factory workers, through the wire, walking away from the Brinnlitz camp. And the legend:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know. I'd like to pick up something for them. It'll only take a minute.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
