<movie id="476" title="Scream 3">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stab 3: Return To Woodsboro. Pah. What's next, Friday The 13TH PART 15:</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON DOES BROADWAY?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben's phone rings. He answers it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up, B.D. with the B.D.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hardly as large as I'd like it to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christine?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Jennifer Love Hewitt. Of course it's me, silly. And I feel like an ass standing in this theater lobby all by myself. Where are you babe, the movie starts in twenty minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm stuck on the freeway. I think there was some big accident. It could be a little while so I don't want you to start freaking if I don't get there at exactly,  Eight thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I'm saying is I'm gonna be royally p.o.'d if you don't catch my acting debut.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I bet you did such a great job.</context>
      <utterance>Oh I wouldn't miss it for the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did. Hon, although I got a total of six minutes screen time, they're the best six minutes of the movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heh heh I bet they are babe. I bet they are. Look, my battery's dying . . .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright Hon, talk to you when the lights go down. Ben smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben hangs up. He reclines back in his seat. Camera slowly pans out the windshield revealing the huge traffic pile up awaiting him. He's not going anywhere.</context>
      <utterance>Sure thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this point we know who the caller is. It's the nightmarish deep voice we've all come to know and hate from the first two films. It's never sounded so evil. So sexy.</context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well what number are you trying to reach?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you got the wrong number, buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, wait. Don't hang up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Asshole, Can't talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben smiles.</context>
      <utterance>But your voice sounds so familiar.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well ya got me. That's me. I'm Ben Damon.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? You're such a talented actor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voice seems to have changed tones. It now sounds a lot harsher, angrier if you will.</context>
      <utterance>Now let's see you act your way out of this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NOTE: At this point we intercut shots of the empty lobby and halls of the PLAZA THEATER. A POV shot standing outside the LADIES ROOM door.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, I'm standing right outside the LADIES ROOM door at the PLAZA THEATER. Your girlfriend Christine is in there. She's all alone. Everyone's in the auditorium waiting for the film to start.  I've got my knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More of a game really.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of a game?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem to be familiar with the STAB movies. Here's how we play. I ask you a question. You get it right, your girlfriend lives. You answer wrong, she dies.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear to God if you lay a finger on her I'll fucking kill you!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben groans. He bangs his head against the steering wheel, if only he'd have paid attention to Christine he might have known this.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe so, but right now, we play the game. First question, Your girlfriend's counting on you, Name your girlfriend's character in STAB 2?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Don't you know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's CICI! Cici's the name of the character she plays in the movie!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good. Now we play ROUND 2.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! But I did everything you said to do!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. And you beat ROUND 1. Now we're taking the game to a whole new level. Meet me beneath the Hollywood sign in ten minutes. I'll have your girlfriend. We'll be waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good bye Ben.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't you want her to live?</context>
      <utterance>You're not playing by the rules Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear to God if you lay one hand on her!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The killer hangs up. Ben looks ahead, traffic is picking up. He puts the SUV into gear, peels out the nearest opening, narrowly avoiding collision. His car screeches down the off ramp.</context>
      <utterance>No! You listen to me, if you're not where I want you in fifteen minutes I'll hollow her out. Do you understand? IN THE B.G. we hear CHRISTINE's horrific screaming.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HIS CELL RINGS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben answers the call.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben makes a disgusted face, tosses the bat into the bushes. He approaches the sign, keeping his eyes trained in all directions.</context>
      <utterance>Very good. You follow directions well. Now for the final part of the game. Put down the bat and approach the sign, slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Closer than you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright I'm here. What the fuck do you want from me?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To see your reaction.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben passes under the huge, pallid "H" in the sign. What seems at first like a gentle raindrop, beads down Ben's forehead. He rolls back his head, his legs turning to jelly, his eyes widening in horror.</context>
      <utterance>Reaction to what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA pans across the audience. Many of them are dressed as the GHOST. A sea of white screaming faces. Very eerie and unsettling.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning Hollywood. And today officially starts the Summer movie season. Opening the box office this week is Jeff Bridges and Tim Robins in Arlington Street, Eugene Levy and Jason Biggs in American Pastry, and Tori Spelling and David Schwimmer in STAB 2, based off my best selling book the WINDSOR MURDERS.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I see a lot of the audience has dressed to the occasion. Today we have director of the upcoming STAB 3: RETURN TO WOODSBORO, Roman Bridger. Why don't we give Mr. Bridger a nice welcome to the set of Total Entertainment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning Gale. Pleasure to be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a pleasure to finally meet you, Roman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well it's a honor to be here amongst so many fans of the genre. And I must say that any of you worried that Jerry Rapp, or Tori or David not returning to complete the STAB trilogy, have no fear, Roman is here. Aided with my excellent cast of newcomers I believe we're going to pull off one of the best Stabs yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roman, from your enthusiasm it certainly seems that way.  Honestly though,  tell us, what's your favorite scary movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A eclectic hush falls over the crowd. Roman appears somewhat sinister in this light. Gale gazes deeply into Roman's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Honestly, my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your life?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roman smiles. The true costumed horror film buffs in the audience break into applause. Gale, somewhat distracted, other what not caring what this second rate director has to say, gazes at a costumed individual at the far corner of the set, watching from a half-open exit door. Now it could be just her imagination running away with her and her atmosphere but it almost appears as if the figure is pantomiming slitting his throat with a gleaming blade. A LOUD BUZZING O.S. Gale is startled out of her skin. She looks up at a sign hanging over the stage. THE WORD "COMMERCIAL BREAK" is illuminated in flashing red light. Gale sighs, looks back to the exit. The GHOST is gone. She turns to Roman.</context>
      <utterance>Well if you were in my shoes, dealing with those big Time Sunrise Studio producers like I do on a daily basis, you'd watch how quick your life goes from a Walt Disney picture to a Tobe Hooper flick.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you excuse me for a moment?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale bolts for --</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Miss Weathers. Allow me to introduce myself, MARK KINCAID, L.A.P.D.  Are you familiar with the actor Ben Damon, or the actress CHRISTINE PERKINS?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I interviewed Damon once for the show. He was a real obnoxious fuck. Any way, the second one, Christine Perkins, she had a part in Stab 2, didn't she? She was playing CICI.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>bodies looked like something out one of the Stab films.</context>
      <utterance>Both of them were found brutally murdered this morning under the Hollywood sign. Autopsy reports having come back to me yet but the</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So is that why you're here? Is that why you're holding me from my show, to tell me about some brutal homicide I'm not even involved in?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish that was all Miss Weathers, but there's more. The killer left a note.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Detective Kincaid reaches into his back pocket, pulls up a newspaper clipping in a ziplock evidence bag. He holds the bag up For Gale to see. EXTREMELY CLOSE on the ARTICLE . . . "MAUREEN PRESCOTT, MOTHER AND WIFE, FOUND BRUTALLY RAPED AND MURDERED IN BEDROOM". A b/w photo of Sidney's mother Maureen stands hauntingly before the camera.</context>
      <utterance>A note?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Sidney Prescott's mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Kincaid flips the article over. Someone has scrawled in black marker across the back "SIDNEY".</context>
      <utterance>There's more.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've tried to get in touch with Sidney Prescott, but she's keeping herself very well hidden. You're my one and only hope in finding her. Her life may be in grave danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I honestly don't know where Sidney is. After Windsor she dropped off the face of the Earth. The only other person that might know is, (gale hesitates), not going to talk.</context>
      <utterance>I'd love to help, really I wouldn't mind being sliced at again by a maniacal psychopath, but</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who would that be?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Dew, did you hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody iced Ben Damon and his girlfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>making movies in the hills, the next day you're posing for the coroner downtown on a slab. Dewey's obviously gotten a lot colder since the last film. He walks past a clique of STAB 3'S MAIN CAST: There's: SARAH DARLING: 30, playing a 25 year old bimbo. Very hot. Very blonde. Ample cleavage. ANGELINA TYLER: 20. Extremely nadve looking. She won her part in STAB 3 playing Sidney through a phone in radio contest. She's timid, with short dark hair. Out of the entire cast, she is the closet to Sidney, they got. And also the loveable TYSON JACKSON: late 20's, African-American, all attitude. The three flip through pages of the STAB 3 script, conversing freely about the production.</context>
      <utterance>That's Hollywood Tom. One day you're</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit I am getting so fed up with these re-writes. It's like every five minutes there's a new script. God, and you just know this all because of STAB 2's script winding up on the internet two months after it wrapped shooting.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And still the film is Number One at the box office this weekend. Beat out American Pasty and Arlington Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Jeff Bridges is getting tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah I think it's doing so damn well because one of it's players got iced. I just hope none of us end up dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh that's right. Those poor poor people. God Ben Damon was such a hottie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that CICI chick wasn't that bad either but I'm really concerned about my safety now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? The murders were a completely isolated incident.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you give that script a rest? It's like a friggen umbilical cord to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just saying, though. What if there's someone out there stalking actors? Huh? Then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's always someone out there stalking actors. Look at that woman from the Commish.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Melinda McGraw?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, the other one. The one who played his wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who you're talking about. Rebecca something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah I think. Anyway, point is, she had a stalker. Sonny Bono had a stalker. David Letterman had one too. So did Heather Langenkamp, Brooke Sheilds, Jody Foster, --</utterance>
   <speaker>TYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom walks into frame, sits down next to Angelina, subtly putting his arm around her. She shoves him away.</context>
      <utterance>Listen Miss ingnue, your cheering me up to much, Give it a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What'd I do? Relax your crack sweetheart I didn't rip those two fucks up last night. Jeez.  So what are you doing tonight? Totally repulsed, Angelina gets up, races off set.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom leans back seductively, his crotch in full view, staring at Sarah with bedroom eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Talk about moody.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Got any plans for later?</context>
      <utterance>And how about you good looking?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah, following suit laid by Angelina, scampers off set. Tom looks up at Tyson, smoke blowing out his nostrils.</context>
      <utterance>Eww yeah, finding a guy to have sex with that doesn't look like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyson races off set. Tom laughs, covers his face.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no. I ain't into that shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pair come to a halt on the driveway of what is supposed to be the Macher Residence. Everything from the smashed beer bottles in the garage, to the boat on the driveway is mimicked to a perfect t. Even a foam dummy Of TATUM RIELLY dangles from the doggy door, head squashed a bloody mess. GALE stares at the swaying dummy, haunted.</context>
      <utterance>Djr vu-do.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well well, someone dies and Gale Weathers comes running. What a shock. GALE looks up. DEWEY stands beside her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm with the L.A.P.D. Are you aware of last night's Events?</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Rielly? My name is Mark Kincaid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey stares daggers through Gale. There is a real bitter coldness between the two.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. A real tragedy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>this is about Sidney. We need to know where she is.</context>
      <utterance>Dewey, personal lives and pasts aside,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promised Sid I'd keep her in seclusion. I promised her nobody would ever find her. If you don't mind Detective, I'd like to approach her with this on my own and see what she'd like to do about it. Kincaid nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>should die, I'm going to have to get a warrant.</context>
      <utterance>That's fine Mr. Rielly, but if anyone else</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey walks off camera. Kincaid puts his hand on Gale's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Understood.  If you'll excuse me Detective.  Gale.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale nods as Kincaid disappears into the backdrop of the set. A Shrill voice</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to have a little chat with the producers. Don't wander off. I may need you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can assure you that security on the set will be at an all time high. Again, the deaths are sheer tragedy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'd hate to see the production shut down.  I myself am a big STAB fan.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUDDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You've got just the right face.</context>
      <utterance>Really?  Have you ever thought about acting?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am kind of dedicated to my job. Although I do enjoy taking acting classes on my weekends. I grew up around these studios anyway. I know my way around. My Uncle was a screenwriter for PARAMOUNT.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Kincaid can finish, Gale buts in.</context>
      <utterance>Really, what was his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me Detective, I think we have some business to attend to.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get that woman out of here.</context>
      <utterance>GALE WEATHERS?! What are you doing here? No press on the set!  No press, no press on set!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GAURD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. Milton.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Milton nods his head, flags down the guard. He walks away.</context>
      <utterance>No, Mr. Milton, Miss Weathers is with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well then, I guess I'll be leaving then.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh come on! Why the hostility?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen Lois Lane, I love your show and all but last month I happened to catch your little segment on me and how my wife left me because I'm a sex addict who enjoys screwing fifteen year old girls. It was a real eye opener my lawyers are still thinking about bringing to your superior's attentions.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Milton storms off camera, Buddy following close behind. Gale looks up at Kincaid.</context>
      <utterance>They're the ones who approved it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright Kincaid, no where to?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I go to the police station and do my job, and you go back to being Gale Weathers.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. I thought you wanted me to stick around.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kincaid hands Gale his card, begins to walk out of the building.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Miss Weathers, if there's a problem, give me a call. Here's my card. I'm always there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. Can I even get a ride home?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Left behind in her wake are five bloody streaks running downthe glass. The streaks begin to bleed, as if each wounds themselves. They bleed right through the glass. Sidneyreaches out to touch them when suddenly -- THE GHOST springs up behind the window, shatters the glass panewith his fist. SIDNEY screams --</context>
      <utterance>Mom!</utterance>
   <speaker>AWAKENING IN BED FROM HER NIGHTMARE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SID crawls out of bed, disappearing out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Her dog's barking wildly. THE WINDOW is fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Laura in Monterey reporting in for work.</utterance>
   <speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright Laura I'll patch you right in to a call.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A click. A woman's voice comes on the other line. It sounds very familiar.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, hi I'm Laura, I'm a trained counselor. How can I help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura I think I just killed somebody.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh I'm sure. I've killed someone!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I need to call you. Just you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, your voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you want to know how you can help, Sidney?  Are you listening to me, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the fuck is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sid reaches for the remote control, flips on a small TV lying across the office.</context>
      <utterance>It's mother, Sidney, now be a good girl and turn on the news. DO IT!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney shuts off the TV as a familiar voice cuts through the din:</context>
      <utterance>The mutilated bodies were discovered late last night by the L.A.P.D, prominent actor Ben Damon was slated for a role in the upcoming STAB 3: RETURN TO WOODSBORO --</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you?</context>
      <utterance>Do you think it's over Sidney?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>W-what do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I want to finish the game.</context>
      <utterance>I want to finish what I started.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sick fuck I'm tracing this call as we speak! The police are gonna nail your ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For instance, Maureen Prescott.</context>
      <utterance>Let them try. You'll never find me. I've already gotten away with murder before.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You didn't kill my mother. Billy Loomis and Stu Macher did.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>leading up to this moment. WELCOME TOTHE FINAL ACT.</context>
      <utterance>Heh. So you think Sidney. So you think. It's all been building up to this Sid. Every STAB. Every SCREAM. Every ounce of blood that's been spilled has all been</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The final act? Well let's play asshole!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Come to Hollywood. STAB 3's going to cutting corners cast-wise. And I've got my eyes set on a technical advisor named Dewey Rielly. The killer laughs coldly. Sidney wanes.</context>
      <utterance>No. We play in my court this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Click. The killer hangs up. Sid's left trembling. She rips the headset out of the phone, reaches into her desk for a loaded.38 special. She stands up, and peers out her office window.</context>
      <utterance>Great. A spirited one. I'll be seeing you real soon Sidney. Real soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah walks down a hallway.</context>
      <utterance>STAB 3. Oh God I've gotta get myself a better agent.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah passes Roman Bridger's office. It's half-open.</context>
      <utterance>Anybody home?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah continues further down the hall when suddenly -- TYSON comes reeling out of a doorway, a huge knife jutting out his back, blood trickling down his mouth. Sarah lets out a bloodcurdling scream while Tyson breaks into hysterics.</context>
      <utterance>Doubt that.  Anyone here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan, a bearded, middle aged make-up effects guy steps out behind Tyson, slaps him a high-five.</context>
      <utterance>Stan! My man does great work.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where's Roman?</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you very much! Tyson go to hell! What the hell are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roman and everybody else went home for the night. I'm here for a make-up test.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make-up. You need it.  Hey, Roman isn't here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn. He called my roommate and told her he had some important things he wanted to go over with me in his office tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stan pantomimes the "blow job" gesture. Tyson laughs, slaps him another high- five. Sarah makes a disgusted face as the two men leave the offices. Sarah sighs, ducks into Roman's office.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah I bet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings scaring the shit out of Sarah. She drops the award, causing it to smash against the edge of the desk, snapping the head clean off. Sarah hesitates, answers the call, putting it on speaker phone.</context>
      <utterance>For the honorary field of directing and cinematography in music videos. How to the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit.  Hello? Director's office.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarah, it's Roman, I'm sorry I'm running late, I'm still on the 405, I'm about 10 minutes away.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah tries fixing the award with some scotch tape.</context>
      <utterance>Oh it's no problem, I'm just... looking at your music video awards.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, since I got you on the phone, let's talk about your character.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What character? I'm Candy, the chick who gets killed second. I'm only in two scenes!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not happy with your part.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not happy that I'm 35 playing a 21 year old. I'm not happy that I have to die naked! And I'm not happy that my character is too stupid not to have a gun in the house after her boyfriend's been cut into McNuggets.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um hmm... umhmm great, so let's run the lines.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh, fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Page 22, Candy's big moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Page 22.. Ring ring. Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>clothes. See! I don't' understand why I have to start the scene in the shower! The whole shower things been done, 'Vertigo' hello! And I mean, my boyfriend just died, why am I showering?</context>
      <utterance>This is Candy. Hang on, let me get some</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we just read the scene? Candy, is that like candy cane or candy apple?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever. Come on, who is this? I think you have the wrong number.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you know my favorite name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hanging up right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Sarah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roman that's not the line.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is in my script.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>lines when there's a new script every 15 minutes?</context>
      <utterance>Has there been another goddamn rewrite? How the fuck are we supposed to learn our</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not just a new script, it's a new movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause, then a familiar dark natured noise enters our ears, the killer's sinister voice.</context>
      <utterance>My movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah tosses down the phone, bolts out of the office.</context>
      <utterance>It's called, Sarah gets sliced like a fucking pig. Still in character, Sarah?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's STAB 3, Miss Weathers. It looks like we're going to be getting a warrant to speak with Miss Prescott anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. Sarah Darling.  I interviewed her too. God, it's happening again isn't it Detective?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale's eyes light up. She grabs Kincaid's shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Yes well we have a suspect, so don't get that worried.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not at liberty to tell you that Miss Weathers. You're no longer working with the L.A.P.D. I don't even know why you're standing in here right now. By all means I should have you thrown out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you won't. You're a good man detective. We think alike. I know you need my help. And I know you know I need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In my fifteen years as a homicide detective I've never met a single soul as pushy and brazen as you are Miss Weathers.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, call me Gale.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale smiles. DETECTIVE TOM WALLACE, Kincaid's cohort and partner. He's in his late thirties. Family man. Wallaceenters frame with a folder in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Deal, but I'm still Detective Kincaid,ok?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark, Bridger's in custody. We traced his phone records. He's the last person to speak to Sarah Darling before she died. Or at least call her home.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, Roman's your suspect?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Diane Sawyer, this here is classified information. Why don't you go investigate the bad meat at the A.P. This is police work, not Pulitzer material.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, fuck off.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, cool it Wallace. She's working with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bridger, you didn't tell us you spoke with Sarah Darling before she died.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's because I didn't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute! I never called her! I never told her to go anywhere!</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roommate says she knows your voice, Mr. Bridger.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she wasn't speaking with me! Look, I did not call Sarah Darling!</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarah Darling said you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone is trying to ruin my movie. Someone wants to kill my movie!</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, look at it this way, if anything this'll be something interesting to put on the director's commentary for when the film hits DVD.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I doubt they were stabbed to death and I strongly doubt the killer of them left messages on the scene for the police to find. Camera pans through a two-way mirror into . . .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They found another note?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. Another News clipping. Another one about Sid's mom. Dewey, whether we like it or not it looks like we're going to have to go back into our past.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This has nothing to do with you Gale.</context>
      <utterance>You mean OUR past as in Me and Sid.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This has everything to do with me Dewey. I was the one who brought the nation's attention to this shit anyway. I'll be damned if I'm gonna sit around and pass on the buck again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you really mean it this time Gale?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey, I got into this shit cause the police came looking for ME. Not cause I'm out to make the SUNRISE STUDIOS SLASHINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Look, let's get something straight</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would the police come to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again, I am the author of the definitive book on the Woodsboro murders.!  What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you'd never leave Woodsboro, 'The only place that's real!' But now you're here. Not with me. Dewey, I took care of you. I waited until you were well. I couldn't stay there, I mean, it's like dog years, one year in Woodsboro is like seven everywhere else.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it's off to London for a week? New York for a month? L.A Forever?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with just being Gale Weathers? I liked her!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It didn't work Dewey. We tried, we're different.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You used to say that was our strength.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dewey, you're not just here because of that second rate K-Mart, straight-to-video version of me, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brace yourself, Gale, all of this is actually not About you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of what Dewey? You do know something, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Off the record.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The boys said no. She wouldn't give her name. A month later, the station gets broken into, the file room ransacked.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone stole Sid's file?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already removed it. I think someone on the film was trying to find Sid, and that's the only reason I came here. To make do a little private investigating of my own and make sure no one here was planning anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, this is too good!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got my suspicions but still, nothing you say can ever make me take my eyes off one person.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Dewey doesn't answer. Again, he's staring daggers through Gale. Years and years of bottled up resentment is finally surfacing.</context>
      <utterance>And who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jennifer needs me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jennifer?! Wait, where are you going off to?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey races out the room. Gale pauses, stares at the interrogation. Wallace has reduced Roman to tears. It's pathetic. Gale bolts after Dewey.</context>
      <utterance>I'm on duty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop following me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I happen to work for the police god dammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not a detective.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither are you, Magnum P.I.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gale, your engine's still running.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey shakes his head in disgust, disappears into the house. Gale runs back to shut off her car. From out of the bushes lunges -- TOM PRINZE, loaded off his ass, still holding a half-filled bottle of JOHNNY WALKER BLACK LABEL SCOTCH in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gale Weathers. What a surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's a shocker.</context>
      <utterance>Tom Prinze, tanked as usual.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey I really liked that piece you did on me last month. The one where you said my car accident was caused by me drinking and drugs, and how I faked the tire blow-out just so my insurance wouldn't sky rocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stage the news to boost ratings.</context>
      <utterance>Heh, well, that's TV journalism for ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale pushes Tom's chest. Stopping him.</context>
      <utterance>Really, cause that stunt lost me the lead role in Roman Polanski's latest picture. Huh, what a coincide I was picked up by Roman Bridger. Well, not exactly the Roman I wanted. Get my point? STAB 3 is bullshit. Fuck, because of your big mouth I'm here, drinking piss water SCOTCH with Second rate fucking celebrities like Jennifer Jollie and yourself!  Hey, I just got an idea. Maybe I should Have a look at your break line. That your car over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we should go inside. I have to have a talk with the cast. ALL OF YOU.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom and Gale walk into the house. Something stirs in the bushes.</context>
      <utterance>You mean what's left of us.  Yeah I'm running on empty anyways. Gotta refuel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You! How can I ever get any fame playing you!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dewey, what the hell is she rambling about now? What's wrong Jen, see yourself on one of those USA NETWORK winners you did and realize how badly you suck at acting?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't you see? The killer is choosing his victims as they die in the script! Ben Damon's character was the first one to get offed. So was his girlfriend - but she wasn't cast yet so his real girlfriend was killed - then Sarah Darling's Candy, and now me!</context>
      <utterance>God damn you Gale Weathers!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone is silent. Dewey nods his head. Gale rips the script from Jennifer's hands.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a second, whoa! Calm down! Number one there were five different versions of the script given out. Ben Damon was given a fake script because he was only being offered the role. It only had fragments of real scenes from the actual script. And what, I die in STAB 3?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know right. It was kinda weak. That's cause Will Kennison only wrote a rough treatment of it. The script was written by some new guy. He wrote Arlington Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A teary-eyed Angelina Tyler rises up from the couch, approaches the group.</context>
      <utterance>Still that was a much better movie, I saw it at the premiere last week. God, what the hell am I getting sidetracked with this shit for?! We've gotta get down to business.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom throws his arm around Angelina, squeezes her tightly.</context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? Because of this shit I'll probably never act in a Hollywood film again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom whips out a joint, pops it in his mouth. He lights it, walks around the side of the house. A noise catches his attention. A low, muffled squealing.</context>
      <utterance>Angelina! Hey! Where the hell are you? I was only playing! Hey look, I can really get you a bit part! Just come on out! Ok?  Damn it. There goes my chances of getting some head from her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom turns to a guest house. The door is half open, darkness spilling out. Tom smirks, steps inside.</context>
      <utterance>Aaaangelina?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GHOST slashes open Tom's arm. Tom screams, backs up into the kitchen. The ghost grabs him by the throat, begins choking him mid-air. He slowly begins to lift him off his feet, angling the knife, readying to make the kill blow. Tom gags. He can't even scream, the killer's crushing his voice-box, causing a trickle of blood down his lips.</context>
      <utterance>You fucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE GHOST brings the knife down, piercing Tom's heart, pinning him to the closet. Tom kicks around for a moment before finally going limp. The GHOST steps back, admiring his work.</context>
      <utterance>Fucker!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! Where the hell are Tom and Angelina?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Screw them. Look, what's important is that we stick together. No matter what. If anyone is next it's you or me Jen.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Sidney?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a knock at the door. The three are startled. Dewey looks at the front door.</context>
      <utterance>What about her?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll get it.</context>
      <utterance>Ssh. Maybe it's Tom or Angelina.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if it's the killer?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jennifer sticks her tongue out at Gale. Dewey reaches into a holster tucked away under his jacket, drawing up his 9mm.</context>
      <utterance>Oh use your brain drama queen! Do the killers ever knock on the fucking door? Ever see Jason do that before burying an axe in some big titted blonde's head? Or maybe Michael or Chucky? Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I'm prepared for anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey nods his head, slowly makes his way towards the door. Gale and Jennifer huddle together, follow close behind.</context>
      <utterance>Amen boy scout, now answer the fucking door!</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you smell something?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey, Gale, and Jennifer race for the French doors in the living room leading outside to the pool and backyard. A PHONE RINGS somewhere in the house.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry! Everyone out the back way! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit it's my cell!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jennifer answers her cellular.</context>
      <utterance>Answer it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Jennifer. Wanna play a little game?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale rips the phone out of Jennifer's hands.</context>
      <utterance>It's him! It's the killer!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen you sick bastard, what the fuck do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your favorite scary movie Gale?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno but I can tell you that your's will be the home video footage of me sticking my foot up your ass! Now come out and fight like a real man you pussy!</utterance>
   <speaker>GHOST</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>THE GHOST comes running out of closet, knife swinging wildly. Jennifer screams, races for the patio door. The ghost lunges for Gale. Dewey draws up his gun, fires. BLAM! BLAM! BLAM! BLAM! BLAM! BLAM! The GHOST takes six slugs In the chest. He goes smashing through a coffee table, motionless. Dewey backs into Gale's arms, smoke rising fromthe muzzle of the gun.</context>
      <utterance>I just might!</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's dead!</context>
      <utterance>God damn it you two! Run! Hurry!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! He's not dead! He's still breathing! Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey turns Gale towards the patio door. A noise O.S. Dewey pauses, turns around --</context>
      <utterance>Gale he's dead. Come on. Let's get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GHOST IS GONE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dewey looks to the patio door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever it is, now is taking credit for Maureen Prescott's murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we know who killed Maureen Prescott, Billy Loomis and Stu Macher. I mean, they even told Sidney how they did it!</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She accused Cotton Weary of murdering her mother, and he was sent away for it! Maybe there is a third killer. Sidney Might know something Kincaid's eyes appear as if questioning Dewey.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but, if I'm not mistaken, you said in your book that Sidney got it wrong before.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I don't know where Sidney is. And even if there was a third killer, Sidney doesn't know about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four? There are five.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben Damon. Christine Perkins. Sarah Darling. Tom Prinze. That's four, last time I learned how to count.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Angelina Tyler? She was there too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kincaid seems to be getting a morbid charge out of all of this. He smirks ever so nefariously at Dewey.</context>
      <utterance>Police are still searching through the debris. Could be days before we find her . . . that is, if she's even there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, look. We all know that this has something to do with 'Stab 3'. What we do not know is why the killer keeps leaving articles about Maureen Prescott.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This time, we found a picture too.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, there was more this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY/GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kincaid holds up a second ziplocked evidence bag. Within is a blurry 5x4 of MAUREEN PRESCOTT exiting a motel room with COTTON WEARY. Kincaid turns it over. Also, written on it's back is 'I KILLED HER'</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>the picture, COTTON WEARY, is out of the country on business. His alibi checks out. Seems he's got a TV show in Australia, 100% COTTON. It's supposedly the biggest thing down under since Yahoo Serious, but that's besides the point.</context>
      <utterance>Before you jump to conclusions, the man in</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does this have to do with Sid?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who knows more about Maureen Prescott than her own daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well Sid's dad couldn't help you and he was married to Maureen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a threat, Detective?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When it's a threat, you'll know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a threat?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boys, boys, why don't we compare our gun calibers later? The issue is Maureen Prescott!</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong, this issue is Sidney Prescott! And either Mr. Riley is going to obstruct justice or is going to put me in touch with her. So, where is she?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here? I told you to stay hidden! It's not safe for you up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well it's not safe for me up there either. The killer found me Dewey. He called me last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figured I'd be safe If I was at least up here with the people I care about.  Now where's this Kincaid guy the news is talking about? I found this place from a FOX 5 TV NEWS REPORT. Heh.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey walks Sid into Kincaid's office.</context>
      <utterance>Follow me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Detective Kincaid?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What Rielly?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's someone here who wants to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! Sidney, you ran fast or what? Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a change, instead of an exchange of fists, the two share a warm hug.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Gale. I'm glad you're all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid, this is detective Kincaid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to finally meet you, Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The killer called her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? When?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you know, the usual small talk, "What's new, how ya been, how do you want to die?"</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney, do you have any idea how he could've gotten your number?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He could've monitored the calls on a scanner. Did you call her from the set?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have her number stored in your memory?  Phone memory!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Yeah, I guess I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has anyone else every used your phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just Jennifer.  And you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm the cop here. You're in my office, Riley. Sidney notices the clippings and the photograph of Maureen.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The killer leaves a newspaper clipping at each murder, Sidney. Recently he's also left a photo of your mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me? This is my mother, Dewey. Why didn't you say something?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was afraid they were bait, something to, ya know, trick you out of hiding.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Detective, I wanna see this studio where all this shit's going down.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright Sid, over there is the STAB 3 Production offices. That's where Sarah Darling was murdered last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A figure lunges out of nowhere, startling all three of them. It's a young, scrawny goth girl in heavy make-up. This is KAREN COLCHECK, 22. She holds something in her hand, a video tape marked SCARY MOVIES 101.</context>
      <utterance>Mm, what a waste of Silicone.  What does my mother have to do with this all Dewey? We're a long way from Woodsboro.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God Karen you scared the shit out of me! What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Karen Colcheck. From Woodsboro.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was Randy's only girlfriend . . . ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney hugs Karen. So does Dewey.</context>
      <utterance>That's me. First and Last.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been a while? You still working at Bradley's?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen holds up the video.</context>
      <utterance>Nope. They opened up a Hollywood Video down the street. It pays better. Anyway, I'm here because I heard on the news about the murders and well, I found this while rooting through Randy's things.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh MY god.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>help save some other poor soul from getting mutilated. If this killer does come back, and he's for real, there are a few things that you gotta remember. Is this simply another sequel? Well, if it is, same rules apply. But, here's the critical thing. If you find yourself dealing with an unexpected backstory, and a preponderance of exposition, then the sequel rules do not apply. Because you are not dealing with a sequel, you are dealing with the concluding chapter of a trilogy.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if you're watching this tape, it means as I feared, I did not survive these killings here at Windsor College. Anyway, the reason I am here is to help you, so that my death will not be in vain. That my life's work, will</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A trilogy?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>but it does exist, and it's a force to be reckoned with, because true trilogies are all about going back to the beginning and discovering something that wasn't true from the get go. 'Godfather', 'Jedi', all revealed something that we thought was true, that wasn't true. So if it is a trilogy you are dealing with, here are some super trilogy rules. One, you got a killer who's gonna be super human. Stabbing him won't work, shooting him won't work, basically in the third one, you gotta cryogenically freeze his head, decapitate him, or blow him up. Number two; anyone including the main character can die. This means you, Sid. I'm sorry, it's the final chapter. It can be fuckin 'Reservoir Dogs' by the time this thing is through. Number three; the past will come back to bite you in the ass! Whatever you think you know about the past, forget it. The past is not at rest, any sins you think were committed in the past are about to break out and destroy you. NUMBER FOUR,Never, ever under any circumstances go running off by yourself, cause if Friday the 13th has taught us anything, it's that the next time we're gonna see you, you're gonna have a fence post jutting out from your back. So in closing, let me say good luck, God Speed, and for some of you, I'll see you soon, cause the rules say, some of you ain't gonna make it. I didn't, not if you're watching this tape.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. It's a rarity in the horror field,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks Karen. You be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karen smiles. She hugs Sidney one more time, scampers away.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry Sid. I got tickets to see Family Feud. I did have a somewhat ulterior motive for driving all the way down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got an idea, I'll hook up with you guys later.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want us to come with you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see nothing's changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geez.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Being Gale Weathers. What the hell are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Gale Weathers!</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's how I see it. I've got no house, no movie, no gun, and I'm being stalked. Because someone wants to kill me? No, because someone wants to kill you. So now, starting now, I go where you go. That way, if someone wants to kill me, I'll be with you, and since they really want to kill you, they won't kill me, they'll kill you. Make sense?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha. Maybe I should join SNL.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Need to get in that building?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No really?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There a story in that building?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Possibly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jennifer opens the door, steps in first. Gale follows, door closing ominously behind them with a loud CLACK.</context>
      <utterance>Gale Weathers would find a way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Basements creep me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>interview. Lifestyles of the Rich and Psychotic.</context>
      <utterance>Really, you know you'd make a fascinating</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look who's talking Moneybags. You got more homes than I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh I wish I got that one on tape. It'd put a smile on my face everytime I'm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two turn the corner, stepping into -</context>
      <utterance>Bitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BIANCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>for TOTAL ENTERTAINMENT. Maybe you've heard of me? Bianca shakes her head "no".</context>
      <utterance>I'm Gale Weathers, author of the Woodsboro and Windsor College murders, and anchorwoman</utterance>
   <speaker>BIANCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whatta you need?</context>
      <utterance>I don't watch TV and I hate books.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BIANCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIANCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>files except studio execs. Can you please go away now?</context>
      <utterance>Listen, I'm busy. Nobody has access to those</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale slaps a twenty dollar bill on the desk. Bianca looks up, a bit insulted, slides the money back.</context>
      <utterance>Well if you won't work for me, will you work for the president?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIANCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The president . . . of the studio.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jennifer turns to Bianca, slides off her ring. She slams the ring onto the desk. It's absolutely stunning.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty dollars? Who are you Nancy Drew?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How can Bianca resist. She smiles, takes the ring, slips it on her finger.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. It's worth three grand easy.  My Gale Weather's will stop at nothing to get the story.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIANCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale reaches for her Twenty. Bianca slaps her hand, takes it, folding it up, sliding it between her cleavage.</context>
      <utterance>Follow me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It may be Maureen Reynolds --</utterance>
   <speaker>BIANCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you'll find neither. Rina Reynolds, however, You will.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rina Reynolds. What a stage name.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIANCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale takes the folder from Bianca, opens it up. Inside are 8x10 headshots of MAUREEN PRESCOTT when she was younger. Behind the pictures is a Xeroxed listing of the films she's starred in.</context>
      <utterance>You should talk, Judy Jurgenstein.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>'Space Psychos' 'Creatures from theSan Andreas Fault'?</context>
      <utterance>What are these movies? 'Amazombies',</utterance>
   <speaker>BIANCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Horror flicks. B-Movies from Milton's heyday.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE/JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIANCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, JOHN MILTON, the horror producer? Those were some of his early flicks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen Dewey I have to go to the bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I mean, remember what Randy said?</context>
      <utterance>Do you want me to come with you Sid?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I'll be ok. I've got my mace. My knife.  These two lethal weapons.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's what we're here for.</context>
      <utterance>Sure you don't need a police escort?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey and Wallace nod. Sid begins to walk towards the soundstage.</context>
      <utterance>No really, I'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, I've got a permit for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The killers!</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ Dewey help me! They tried to kill me in the bathroom!</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wallace whips out his cellular, dials a number. Sidney falls into Dewey's arms, collapsing like a house of cards, crying hysterically.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a second? Killers? There's two of them now? Aw shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah this is Wallace. We got a problem down here on the Sunrise Studios lot. No not another one. At least not yet. Yeah we've had an attack.  Do you need medical assistance?  No. Oh really. Alright, see you in a minute. Wallace closes up his phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I got some good news in a way. Roman Bridger didn't make those calls To Sarah Darling. Police let him go. Here's the bad news: The cellular was cloned, it's untraceable. We now have no suspects.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Dewey and Sidney turn around to see an excited Jennifer and Gale race into frame.</context>
      <utterance>Dew!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney, what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nevermind, what'd you two find?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid, something dawned on me when I wrote the book on your mother's murder. For two years of her life, 1969 up until 1971 she basically disappeared off the face of the Earth.</context>
      <utterance>We did some researching in the archives.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've found out where she went.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was an actress Sidney. Minor B-Movies. But now we have a new suspect in this twisted fucking web . . . John Milton.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The head of the studio?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What a better way to end than with a bloodbath?</context>
      <utterance>It makes sense doesn't it? It's his big grandiose swan song from the genre.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney, what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was attacked in the bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wallace, shouldn't you be investigating the bathroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey nods suspiciously. Kincaid comes rushing into frame.</context>
      <utterance>I'm waiting for back-up. I don't carry bullets in my gun unless I know I'm gonna use em.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They told me that someone was attacked.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ Sidney, what happened? I got a call on my cell from home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what made you think it was Sidney?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid, get in my car. You're coming back to the station with me where it's safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dewey, Jennifer, I think we should pay John Milton a little visit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY/JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agreed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you knew Sidney Prescott's mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just what the hell do you people think you're doing, barging in here like this? I've got important calls to make. I run this studio.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answer the question. You knew Sidney's mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rina Reynolds.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know how many actors have worked for me? Hundreds, thousands.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody said she was an actor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good twist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember her! She was a bit player in a couple of my movies. A nobody! So what does it matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Come on! You have made millions off the story of her murder. You're obsessed with HER and you're obsessed with her DAUGHTER!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Settle down Beavis.  Why don't you tell us the truth?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you know who she was.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>known Maureen Prescott before, I mean as Rina. I couldn't tell anyone. Can you imagine the press?</context>
      <utterance>When we did the first 'Stab" I realized I'd</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now? I mean, murders on your set and still you say nothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get real, that would make me a suspect!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just because you knew her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so! Just what happened to Maureen when she was in Hollywood?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you listen to me, Lois Lane, let it go. It's dead and buried. Daddy took ol' Yeller out behind the barn and shot him in the head a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well how would you like his rotten carcass dug up and drug all over National TV? Why don't you start talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I was well known for my parties, Rina knew what they were. It was for girls like her to meet men, men who could get them parts, if they made the right impression. Nothing happened to her that she didn't invite, in one way or another, no matter what she said afterwards.</context>
      <utterance>It was in the 70's, everything was different.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you saying she was-</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>did take advantage of her!. Maybe the sad truth is, this is not the city for innocence. No charges were brought. And the bottom line is, Rina Reynolds wouldn't play by the rules. You wanna get ahead in Hollywood, you gotta play the game, or go home.</context>
      <utterance>I'm saying things got out of hand. Maybe they</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you know about trilogies?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean like, movie trilogies?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem to like movies, Detective.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me Mark, would you? Cause I'm gonna keep calling you Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call you Mark when you catch the killer, Detective.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you request this case?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they tend to put me on the ones that deal with the business. I grew up here, and I know my way around the studios.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To me Hollywood is about death.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>see what I see day in and day out, the violence that people do to each other, you get haunted. I think you know about that.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a homicide detective, remember? When you</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Go away. To be watching a scary movie in your head, whether you want to or not, watching it alone.</context>
      <utterance>I know what it's like to see ghosts that don't</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ghosts are tough, you can't shoot ghosts.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't arrest ghosts. But the best way to stop being haunted is to be with people. You're here, you're not hiding, you've done the right thing, Miss Prescott.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you know about your mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>time. Like I'm watching my life instead of living in it.</context>
      <utterance>I used to think I had the perfect mom, perfect family. Till I found out I was wrong. She had a secret life, and I tried to understand that, and soon as I thought I had, more secrets. I don't' know who my mom was.  Sometimes I feel like I'm just learning about my mother for the first time. You know, with TV and those movies and what not. God sometimes I feel like I'm just learning about myself for the first</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is that good news?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, how?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kincaid readies himself to leave. He snags up his holstered gun, his car keys, jacket, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Catch him, or kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Detective Kincaid pauses, he leans over Sidney's chair, his penetrating eyes glaring right into hers.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Detective? What's your favorite scary movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kincaid exits, door slamming shut behind him. A beat, then --</context>
      <utterance>My life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God Gale, Dewey was right. Stop getting so nervous and you might stop causing me to gag!</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I think he just went out to kill another cast member.</context>
      <utterance>I think Milton's the killer.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He probably went out to buy more KY JELLY for his jack -off parties he has with his two best friends.</context>
      <utterance>Milton's not a killer. He's a pervert.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rob Reiner and Quentin Tarentino?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you get any of my witty humor? I mean, you did play me for three movies.  His two hands, dingus.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey leans into Milton's office door, slowly opens it. Darkness spills out. The three disappear inside it.</context>
      <utterance>Ssh ladies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John Milton.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna play a game?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on Gale, I'm a pro at this. Dewey leans in, bumping his head with Gale's.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two look at each other and smile. Dewey laughs sweetly. Gale reaches up, rubs his head.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Dewey I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. Let me -- JENNIFER, chimes in. Clearly annoyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale and Dewey can't help gazing into each other's eyes. In an instant it almost seems as if a long lost love has been sparked back to life.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me Gale! What the hell do you think you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey takes the butt of the flashlight, brings it down hard on the locked drawer. The lock's smashed off.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get this drawer open. If it's locked, there must be something inside he's trying to hide.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale slides open the drawer, reaches in. She pulls up a manilla folder. Dewey shines the light on the folder as Gale opens it up and reads what's inside.</context>
      <utterance>Shit. That's gonna leave a mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale's eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>What? What'd you find?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys! I got a bad feeling.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JENNIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys there's someone else in the fucking room!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey and Gale look up and scream as -- THE GHOST rushes out of the shadows. Jennifer bolts for the door. The GHOST jams his knife in her back. She lets out a blood curdling death scream, drops to the floor motionless. GALE and DEWEY share a terrified scream. The killer wipes his blade clean, lunges for them.</context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey jumps in the killer's path. The killer winds back, cracks the base of the knife across Dewey's skull. Dewey drops to the floor unmoving.</context>
      <utterance>Gale run!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLANG! The Killer's blade glistens in the moonlight. He charges for Gale. Gale screams, races out of the office door, slamming it closed on the killer sending him flying onto his back.</context>
      <utterance>Dewey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Gale what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE KINCAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, calm down. I'm going to radio in for backup right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Kincaid spins around. Gale screams. The GHOST comes charging out of nowhere, slashes open Kincaid's throat, stabs him in the chest. Kincaid drops onto the hood of his car, dead. GALE pauses. She's screaming hysterically. The killer raises the knife menacingly.</context>
      <utterance>Not so fast. We're not finished.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't run if I were you Gale. It's only gonna end up with you getting Skewered like a fucking pig. I need you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awfully late time to be doing an interview.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale closes her eyes, cries as the killer stalks towards her.</context>
      <utterance>I need you as bait. For Sidney.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHONE SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um wh-who's calling?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHONE SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um wh-who's calling?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gale, Dewey, whoever, um, call me back, I can only hear myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>{ a click } I only her you too, Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The question isn't who I am. The question is, who's with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid's face floods with fear. She rushes towards the office door when suddenly, the voice draws her back, angrily and cautioning.</context>
      <utterance>Sidney, stay away!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do it! If you do one thing to attract attention, one thing, I'll kill them both. Now, do you have somewhere we can be alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney stands up, goes into an inner office, Wallace's.</context>
      <utterance>Go there.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always hard being friends with you, Sidney. When you're friends with Sidney, you die! Well these friends don't have to, Sidney. It's up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I know their voices are --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the killer haul back and hit Dewey hard.</context>
      <utterance>Don't come here Sidney!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dewey! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want them, I want you! It's simple. You show yourself, they survive, you run, they die!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God! Oh God!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you want to know Sidney? Don't you want to know who killed her? Don't you want to know who killed your mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen Kincaid?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 2</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NO. But Wallace is around.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Click. The killer hangs up. Sidney breaks down crying.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call you, when you're on your way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wallace's keys rest on his desk. Sid ponders, takes them. She stands up when something inside her makes her open Wallace's drawer and dig around. She pulls up a fully loaded handgun. That's the ticket. She closes the drawer, slinks out the side exit.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Click. The killer hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>You follow directions good. Now let's wrap this production. Go to the Sunrise Studios backlot. I'll call you when you get there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, I'm here. Now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're doing real good. Can't you figure it out? I wanna finish this where it all began. Woodsboro.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Click the killer hangs up. Sid pockets her phone. She looks up, and is startled out of fright. Posted alongside the sound stageis a huge production poster for STAB 3 with a life-size GHOST wielding a big knife. Sid knows she's in the right place. The door leading inside is half-open. Sid taps the holstered gun, slowly steps into the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you wanted me here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help me Sid! The killer's got me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dewey?! OHMIGOD! Where are you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid I can see you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you Dewey?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sid bolts through the shattered patio door out onto the backyard set. Seated before a heated in ground pool, tied to a patio chair, beaten and gagged, is DEWEY RIELLY. He's unconscious and almost appears at first glance like STEVEN ORTH from SCREAM. Sid's jaw drops. This can't be possible. She looks down at the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I'm out back. Tied up. Hurry Sid! The killer's looking for you! Quick untie me!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sid screams, dropping the phone out of fright. She turns around coming face to face with --</context>
      <utterance>Good work Sid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GHOST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now it's time to get down to business.</context>
      <utterance>You play a good game Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GHOST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GHOST rushes Sid. She screams, takes off running. She bolts across the darkened set, running straight up the front porch of a mock-up of her own childhood home. She swings open the front door, slams it closed.</context>
      <utterance>Your other half.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid fumbles with the bindings, manages to untie Gale. Gale sits up.</context>
      <utterance>Christ Sidney hurry up! That fucking lunatic is coming!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gale he's got Dewey!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know! He killed Kincaid!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>DEWEY staggers through the living room doorway, gun in hand.</context>
      <utterance>Sidney? Sidney turns around --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney embraces Dewey.</context>
      <utterance>Dewey!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Gale?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've got her!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey unlocks the front door, swings it open. STANDING across the set is THE GHOST, knife raised.</context>
      <utterance>Sid I want you to stay here! I'll be right back! I'm not gonna let them get Gale!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dewey goes to fire. CLICK. CLICK. CLICK. Out of bullets.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it right there you fucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE GHOST winds back, launches the knife. It swirls through space before embedding into Dewey's arm, launching him back through the doorway. Sidney screams. Dewey's unconscious again. The GHOST races for the open door. Sid screams, kicks it closed. Locking and bolting it again. A crash O.S. Sid turns around -- A BODY rolls down the staircase, covered in blood. It comes to a halt at Sidney's feet, an unmoving, rumpled figure.</context>
      <utterance>OH shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>IT'S ANGELINA TYLER.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's been brutally stabbed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BUT ANGELINA'S EYES OPEN. A SICK RICTUS SMILE FORMING on her lips.She pulls out a gun, aims it at Sidney's face.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whatta you say?</context>
      <utterance>Time to sort things out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's you?! All of this is because of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid tries to run, Angelina trains the gun on her. Causing her to stop in her tracks.</context>
      <utterance>No. Not all of it. Sid, someone really wants to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not now.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-un Sid. You're not gonna run off.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The GHOST enters frame, ripping open his costume to reveal a KEVLAR bullet proof vest.</context>
      <utterance>You're not going anywhere Sidney. It's time you came to terms with me, and with mother! Maybe you never knew her at all, Sid. Maybe you can't get past the surface of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slammed the door in my face, Sid. Said I was Rina's child and Rina was dead. And it struck me, what a good idea! So I watched her, made a little home movie, a little family film. Seems Maureen, mom, really got around. I mean, Cotton Weary was one thing, everybody knew about that, but Billy's father, that was the key! Your boyfriend didn't like seeing his daddy in my movies. Didn't like it at all. And once I supplied the motive, all the kid needed was a few pointers. Have a partner to sell out in case you get caught, find someone to frame, it was like her was making a movie.</context>
      <utterance>Roman Bridger, director. And brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the nightmares. All the hell I went through was because of you, you spineless bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a director Sid, I direct. For example, Angelina over there,  She's my partner. I can convince her to do anything. We've been dating since I met her in Woodsboro.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, Angie Crick? From English class?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGELINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>were always my hero. That's why I'm here Sidney. I wanted to make you proud.</context>
      <utterance>That's me Sid. I always idolized you. You</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>a turn-on. You know, in the movies she's you Sid, so every time I jump her bones, I'm doing YOU, technically.</context>
      <utterance>And I kinda keep her around cause it's a bit of</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With the aides of the computer revolution of y2kI've been able to steal your voice. (presses play) Ain't it cool? Listen to what the police are gonna find next to your lifeless, mutilated body.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a second Sid. Don't you go jumping the gun. You haven't seen the best part.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roman continues stabbing himself. In the shoulder. In the side.In the leg. Bleeding and hazed, he hands the gore drenched knife to Angelina.</context>
      <utterance>See Sidney, as amateur as Billy and Stu were, they laid the groundwork for this! See Sidney, they also set the stage for you! Introducing to the world Sidney the victim! Sidney the survivor! Sidney the star!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See Sid, now comes the part where we get away with it! The part where we win! Cause face it Sidney, in this world, the bad guys win!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roman lunges at Sidney. Sid screams, takes off through the kitchen. Gale rolls herself off the couch. Angela runs over and kicks her in the ribs.</context>
      <utterance>God damn it Sidney!</utterance>
   <speaker>GALE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gale barrels into Angelina, tackling her into the coffee table before she has a chance to move. Angelina struggles to raise her knife.</context>
      <utterance>I know all the tricks!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dewey my God I thought you were dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry Sid I'd never leave you like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEWEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch out Sid. Randy said the killer's always superhuman.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGELINA comes racing out of the living room, face a blackened, Kentucky-fried mess. Everyone screams, one epic last scream. Sid raises up the gun, fires, hitting Angelina dead center between the eyes, sending a splash of blood and brain matter onto the wall behind her.</context>
      <utterance>He wasn't superhuman Dewey. He wasn't superhuman at all. THEN A HORRIFYING SCREAM rips through the air.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SID scrunches up her face in anger, pulls the trigger. BLAM! A CLEAN PERFECT</context>
      <utterance>This shit is really getting repetitive, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOT TO ROMAN'S HEAD.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid drops the gun, walks off set.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ what happened? I leave for two seconds to take my kid to the doctor, I come back and it's the fucking WILD BUNCH.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was just something that's been itching to be completed for the past four years.</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE WALLACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wallace nods his thanks as Sidney walks off through the studio gates, the sun rising overhead, as calm and as casually as if nothing's happened. SLOWLY, we crane up to an aerial looking down upon HOLLYWOOD. ANOTHER DAY IS BEGINNING.</context>
      <utterance>Take care Detective. Give my regards to the wife and kids.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
