<movie id="478" title="Se7en">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Somerset does not respond. The MAN, in an ill-fitting real estate jacket, is seated on the hood of a dirty Ford Thunderbird. He holds a check and a booklet of receipts.</context>
      <utterance>Is something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is something the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset still seems distant.</context>
      <utterance>No... no. There's nothing wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that it's any of my business... but, are you figuring on moving out here eventually?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just never seen a man mortgaging an empty house before.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything here still seems... seems so strange to me. All this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man walks over to hand over a receipt. Somerset accepts the receipt, folds it. Somerset smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I'd say this place is about as normal as places get.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset looks back at the house. The man does not understand.</context>
      <utterance>That is exactly what I mean. Strange.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that your car, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST THUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills pauses, switches his beer bottle to his other hand.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck do you care?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The thugs look at each other, gauging. They face Mills.</context>
      <utterance>Does that car belong to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST THUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's my car, alright? Fuck off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The second thug starts the long way round the car.</context>
      <utterance>You're telling me that's your car?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND THUG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills gives a "isn't that silly" laugh, shifts his gaze -- Sees the first thug slide the crowbar so it's held as a weapon.</context>
      <utterance>Well, for some strange reason, I don't believe you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boom, boom... both barrels.</context>
      <utterance>Neighbors heard them screaming at each other. It was nothing new or unusual. But, then they heard the gun go off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did his wife confess? Did she actually speak the words?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When the patrolman got here she was trying to put his head back together. She was crying too hard to say anything.  Crime of passion.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Look at all the passion splattered up on the wall here. Taylor shifts his weight, impatient, annoyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset looks at a coloring-book open on the coffee table. There are crayons beside it. Somerset picks the book up. He flips through: crudely colored pictures.</context>
      <utterance>This is a done deal. All but the paperwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did their son see it happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset replaces the book, digs up a cigarette from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>What kind of question is that? Huh?  He's dead. His wife killed him. There it is. That's all. Anything else has nothing to do with nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAYLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>David Mills enters, dressed in a suit. He looks a bit lost.</context>
      <utterance>You and your fucking questions, Somerset. I'm glad I'm getting rid of you today. You know that, you fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset lights his cigarette, looks to Mills.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... Lieutenant Somerset?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm David Mills... your new partner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a little thrown. I just finished orientation at central, and they dumped me off down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard you brought in two small-timers last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Two real idiots.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since we are just starting out, I thought we could go to a bar. Sit and talk for awhile. That way we can...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset walks, no reply. Mills searches to get a read on him.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, but I'd rather start sniffing for a case, if it's all the same to you. Seeing how we only have a week for this whole transition thing.  I want to get into the shit a.s.a.p., know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I meant to ask you something... when we spoke on the phone. I can't help wondering...  Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I don't follow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills formulates his response.</context>
      <utterance>All this effort you've gone through, to be transferred from Philadelphia to here. It's the first question that pops into my head.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset stops and faces Mills.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here for the same reasons as you, I guess. Or... at least the same reasons you used to have for being here...  ...before you decided to give up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you know me? You just met me two minutes ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I don't understand the question.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's very simple. You've come from the "City of Brotherly Love" to the "City of Brotherly Hate," detective. I've never seen it done that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Maybe I thought I could do more good here than there.  You know, it'd be great by me if we didn't start right out kicking each other in the balls. But, you're calling the shots, lieutenant, so however you want it to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you how I want this to go. I want you to look, and I want you to listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't standing around Philly guarding the fucking Liberty Bell.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, you've never worked homicide in</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills just stares back at Somerset. Somerset walks. Mills rolls his eyes, looks to heaven like, "what'd I do to deserve this?" He follows Somerset.</context>
      <utterance>Well, please do me the favor of remembering it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At what time did you confirm the death?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I said, we didn't touch anything, but we were on scene at like o-five- hundred, so he's had his face in a plate of spaghetti for about half an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You didn't check vital signs?</context>
      <utterance>Wait, wait, wait. You didn't check him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe me, he's gone. Unless he's breathing spaghetti sauce now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. The point is, when you're first man in, you check vital signs.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy's sitting in a pile of his own shit and piss. If he ain't dead he would have stood up by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset steps in, heads Mills off.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Godzilla...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Officer Davis. We'll see you again after we've had a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Davis leaves, eyeing Mills. Mills watches him. Somerset hands Mills a flashlight, takes out surgical gloves.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder what exactly was the point of the conversation you were about to get into?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset snaps one glove over his hand and checks the fit.</context>
      <utterance>And, I wonder how many times Officer Davis there has found a supposedly dead man who didn't really die until Davis was back in the patrol car calling the morgue and eating a powdered donut.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drop it. We have more important concerns just now, don't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine... for now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>PHOTOGRAPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The only light is a murky green illumination from the ceiling. The light bathes an OBESE MAN who is slumped forward in a kitchen chair, face-down-dead in a plate of spaghetti. The sizable kitchen table's green tablecloth is covered with soiled paper plates. The plates hold bits of half-eaten sandwiches, potatoes, donuts and other junk-food remnants. Mills and Somerset turn on their flashlights. Mills points his at the green bulb above. Aluminum foil has been wrapped around the bulb to focus the light on the corpse. Somerset sweeps the room with his flashlight. He goes to the body and kneels beside it. There's a rope tied around the man's wide gut. Mills comes to stand beside Somerset.</context>
      <utterance>Bon appetit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset crouches lower, uses a pen to lift one of the dead man's pants cuffs. Rope is tied around the purplish ankle. Mills examines the knots behind the chair's back. Shines his flashlight on the man's belly.</context>
      <utterance>I guess that makes it homicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset isn't listening, focused on the corpse. He studies the man's head and neck without touching.</context>
      <utterance>Still, he could have tied himself in. To make it look like murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>No wounds. You see anything?</context>
      <utterance>I don't see any blood or bruises yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset stands, points his flashlight: the obese man's stiff hands are clutching utensils. A knife in the left hand, a fork sticking straight up in the right with a hunk of meat hanging skewered. Cockroaches swarm. Mills turns to the sink and stove. Each burner of the stove has a used pot or pan on it. There's food slopped everywhere.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset walks to the room's only window. The window has been painted over with black paint. he touches the window with his pinkie finger. The paint is still wet. Mills goes to a trash can by the refrigerator. The trash can is full to the brim with empty food containers.</context>
      <utterance>I saw a guy once... committed suicide, but he wanted to make sure his family could collect insurance money, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Mills opens the refrigerator. It's nearly empty.</context>
      <utterance>So, this guy took this big knife... and he held it behind him, put the tip of it in his back, and he ran backwards into the wall. Cause, he thought it was going to look like someone stabbed him in the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except, he poked a big fucking hole in the dry wall when he did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you could... spare me the anecdotes for now. Leave the refrigerator open for the light.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you smell? Other than him, and all the food.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset points the flashlight and Mills crouches, pulls up the tablecloth on his side of the table. Two large dead rats lay on the floor beside a metal bucket. Mills grimaces, slides under the table, careful to avoid the rats. He looks in the bucket. He leans back, baffled.</context>
      <utterance>A bucket.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Somerset under the table.</context>
      <utterance>It's vomit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a bucket of vomit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there any blood in it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset stands, perplexed, stares at the dead man. There is a knock at the door. The detectives look to DOCTOR THOMAS O'NEILL, 52, the medical examiner. O'Neill is a frumpy man, seems a bit gone, looking at the green bulb.</context>
      <utterance>Can't tell by looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'NEILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops his bag on the floor, sorts through the contents.</context>
      <utterance>Mood lighting. Very sixties.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills goes to the trash can, pokes the garbage with a pencil.</context>
      <utterance>You think he was poisoned?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, those rats there somehow ate the poison off the floor?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guessing this early is useless.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'NEILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills continues searching the garbage.</context>
      <utterance>You girls have got the forensics guys out there chompin' at the bit. Don't know if we'll all fit in here though.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's room. Light's the problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, three is certainly a crowd in here. And, with four, someone's bound to be stepping on evidence.  Detective Mills, go help the officers question the neighbors.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'NEILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pizza and paperwork, Detective Mills.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to chat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset takes the pads reluctantly, puts them on. He still has the un-lit cigarette hanging from his mouth. Mills climbs into the ring. He holds the ropes open for Somerset, waits. Somerset doesn't want to do this, but he climbs up.</context>
      <utterance>You just hold them up. I do all the work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've seen my files... seen the things I've done?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills motions to Somerset and Somerset holds up the practice pads. Mills starts working them, lightly, warming up.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Impressive work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what's your problem? I've done my time on door-to-doors, and walking a beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it. That doesn't mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THWACK... THWACK... Somerset's very stiff, uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>I did all that shit a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made a decision, because I have to worry about the integrity of the scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills punches a little more aggressively. Somerset's backing, flinching, keeping the pads high. THWACK... THWACK... THWACK...</context>
      <utterance>When I'm on scene, I'm not going to worry whether you think you're getting enough time on the playing field. I'm there to do the work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The badge in my pocket says "detective," just like yours. I've been Homicide for four and a half years.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't count the half-years, unless you</context>
      <utterance>You've worked Homicide for four years, or for five years...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset looks at the broken cigarette in his mouth. He contains his anger. He seems to realize Mills has a point.</context>
      <utterance>You fucked me over today, and you know it. You know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Mills exits. Somerset spits out the broken cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Just don't jerk me off. That's all I ask. It's not much. Don't jerk me off.  Please, do me the favor of remembering that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Tracy looks away from the window to the haggard WOMAN. The school's office is ill-equipped, busy, disorganized.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Mrs. Mills. We don't have anything right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll try to give you a call if we need substitutes next month.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy looks back at the playground: on the other side of a chain-link fence, a butcher in a bloody apron walks down the ramp of a freezer truck. he carries a big, whole, slaughtered pig on his shoulder. The pig's head flops as the butcher walks. Some children stop their games and run to watch the man and the pig corpse pass.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills holds his thumb and forefinger about a quarter of an inch apart to illustrate.</context>
      <utterance>It was okay. I mean... it was certainly better than yesterday. I think Somerset and I came to a small understanding...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...about this big.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sounds interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills throws some oranges in the basket hanging from Tracy's arm. He goes to check out the carrots. Tracy looks up from heads of lettuce to the strange man at the entrance. The strange man hums on, rocking back and forth slowly, his eyes glassy. Customers come and go, paying him no mind. Mills notices Tracy's interest. He keeps comparing carrots.</context>
      <utterance>He is that, if nothing else.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>The strange man suddenly stops humming and looks into the store with a crooked grin.</context>
      <utterance>We started a big homicide case today. I'll spare you the grisly details.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man keeps repeating this, over and over, still ignored.</context>
      <utterance>Name that tune? Anybody name that tune? Name that tune...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks back to the heads of lettuce.</context>
      <utterance>It's... it's like they emptied all the insane asylums into the streets.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Mills nods, his back to Tracy.</context>
      <utterance>That's what it's like. Like they just gave up, and let everyone out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are a lot of frightening people in this city.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are a lot of frightening people in the world. Tracy looks again to the strange man.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name that tune? Anybody name that tune?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills edges past Tracy towards the front of the store, tries to be pleasant.</context>
      <utterance>It seems worse than Philadelphia, because everything is pushed right up against you. In your face.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over apples, thinks that's the end of that.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, honey. I don't want to fight tonight. Okay? Can we just go one night without fighting about something?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not trying to start a fight.  How am I trying to start a fight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're here now. Okay. Are we supposed to pack it all in and go back? How are we going to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I have to act like I love this place? Is that what a "good wife" would do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a lot of pressure on me... I...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm here with you.</context>
      <utterance>And, there's a lot of pressure on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills steps towards the open air entrance. He's watching something. The strange man is still heard offscreen. Tracy reaches to a high wooden shelf, trying to reach a bag of rice, her back to Mills.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets the rice and turns. Mills is not there. She sighs, angry, looks around. She walks towards the entrance and sees him --</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to close my eyes and block everything out, David. I'm not going to act like you delivered us to some sort of paradise. I can't...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy looks at him, charmed, no longer willing to fight.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... I couldn't pass it up. I never had a chance to actually do that. But, we can start the argument right back up where we left off, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy wraps an arm around Mills and kisses him. He holds her.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The strange man starts humming a new tune. An old man tries to get through the aisle where Mills and Tracy are kissing.</context>
      <utterance>That was the theme from tv's Mod Squad. I'm surprised nobody got that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. Excuse me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a long moment, Mills shifts back, sits up. Tracy looks over her shoulder at him as he takes a towel off a chair and stands. Mills wraps the towel around his waist. He leans over to give Tracy a last kiss. She watches him leave the room. She is about to say something, but does not. A light comes on in the other room, leaking through the door.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Santiago reaches into the belly of the cavernous corpse. Mills moves closer beside Somerset, but not too close, trying to hide his disgust. We hear squashy sounds as Santiago works, but we don't see in.</context>
      <utterance>If you take a look here, buddies... I can tell you, it was not a poison. If you can see... I have emptied all of everything out of the stomach. But, look at it, now that I took away the liver.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I move the lungs over. First, see how big this fat son-of-a-bitch stomach is. Now... here is the strange thing, on the stomach. Stretches.  And, here is it distended. Look at the size of that, because of the foods.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see what you're pointing at...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset's looking in, not believing what he sees.</context>
      <utterance>On the stomach. The lines of distention.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor, are you saying this man... ate till he burst?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset walks around the slab, looking the body over.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, well, he didn't actually burst. He was bleeding, inside of himself. And, there's a hemotoma on the outside... on the belly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He died by eating?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset notices something on the partially shaved head. He leans close to look at five or six small bruises on the back of the dead man's head; circular bruises, some darker than others, all about the same diameter as a dime.</context>
      <utterance>Someone punched him, or kicked him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset stands straight, realizes something about the bruises.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, and there is this here... something else you have to look at and see.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Santiago looks amongst tools, buckets and jars of liquid. He picks up a glass jar and shows it to Mills. In the jar: many little bits of blue plastic. Like scrapings.</context>
      <utterance>Most of his stomach contents are in the lab now... but, this. I found these in the fat man's stomach.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills gets Somerset's attention, hands him the jar. Somerset looks at it a long time.</context>
      <utterance>Plastic?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANTIAGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why these were in a fat man's stomach, I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those bruises on the back of the victim's head were caused by the muzzle of a gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, the killer had him at gunpoint, and gave him a choice: eat, or get your head blown off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was force-fed... till his body started rejecting the food. He literally couldn't eat another bite.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, the killer held a bucket under him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset examines the counter tops and wall. Mills gets down on his knees, examines the linoleum floor.</context>
      <utterance>His throat was swollen from the effort. He was bleeding internally. He must have blacked out... and, if you're the killer, you're not going to want to wait around for him to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset gets down, holds the jar against the linoleum.</context>
      <utterance>You kick him, pop him like a fucking balloon.  Somerset, look here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both crawl on hands and knees, study every inch of floor.</context>
      <utterance>Same color and texture.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If this is what that is... it doesn't make sense. It doesn't figure.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always look for one thing to focus on. There's always one singular thing, and it might be as small as a speck of dust, but find it and focus... till it's an exhausted possibility.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are pieces of the floor going to get in the guy's stomach?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset notices deep scratches in the linoleum, fingers the grooves. He takes a piece of plastic from the jar, holds it to the scratches, fiddles with it, fits it in. He looks up to see, these scratches are in front of the refrigerator. It looks like they were caused by the refrigerator having been pulled away from the wall and pushed back at some time.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. Why would so many pieces be inside his stomach unless they were placed there intentionally?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Dear Detectives. Long is the way, and hard, that out of hell leads up to the light."  This is not good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Milton.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset takes out his beeper, looks at the LED window. He looks up at Mills, like they've received very bad news.</context>
      <utterance>It's a quote from a book. Milton's Paradise Lost.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The nude dead man's legs are folded under him as if he were kneeling, and he's bent forward, chin on the floor. His eyes are open, his arms outstretched before him. Mills and Somerset walk to either side of the man. The detective closes the door, bites his thumbnail. The apartment is on a high floor, so it's quiet. Somerset sees the window has been covered with a sheet of yellow gel, stapled in place to produce the colored light. Mills examines the corpse. There's a chair one foot behind the nude man. It's an elegant leather chair, drenched in blood. There's a carving knife on the carpet in the middle of a huge stain of blood under the chair. Mills looks at pieces of cut rope on the floor behind the chair. The rope is knotted. Somerset crouches beside the body. There's a big piece of flesh missing from the man's left side, as if the love-handle had been lopped off. Hundreds of pennies lie scattered under and around the man. The man's hands are palms up, fingers wrapped around more pennies. Mills walks over to examine a scale on the floor between the corpse and the doorway. It's an old-fashioned counter-balance scale with two suspended dishes on a see-saw arm. In the high dish: the hunk of flesh missing from the man's side. In the low dish: a one pound counterweight.</context>
      <utterance>...this is your guy who did this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset stands and walks backwards to view the entire scene from near the door. He looks worried, vaguely frightened. He turns his head, looks to a far wall. Beside a big, abstract, constructivist painting, there's a note pinned up inside a triangular smear of blood.</context>
      <utterance>A pound of flesh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Mills sits back in his chair, arms crossed, seems anxious, doesn't know why they're here.</context>
      <utterance>This victim, Mr. Gold, was tied down nude, holding a carving knife. And he was given a long time... to decide. Where to make the first cut? There's a gun to your head... but, what part or parts of your body are expendable?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Gold tried for the whole pound at once, his love handle. But, he went into shock. Bled to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is the point, Somerset?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at both killings together. This murderer is an artist.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An artist?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He uses colors and symbols. He positions the bodies after death, so he's working with composition. It's been premeditated</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rats and the pennies. The circle and the triangle on the wall. There's something about them... these murders</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You with him, or you just here to watch?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is his stuff, captain. I've been out in the cold most of the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always working overtime up in that big brain of yours, huh? Always cooking.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to know... I want us reassigned. We're declining this case.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This cannot be my last duty here. It's going to go on and on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've left unfinished business before.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything else was taken as close to a conclusion as humanly possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I just say something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also... I don't think this should be Mills' first case.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not my first case, fuckhead!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have anyone else to give this to, Somerset. And nobody's going to</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Somerset wants out, fuck him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would be too much for him, too soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The captain looks at Somerset, then at Mills.</context>
      <utterance>Could we talk about this in private?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not necessary. You're in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills stands. Somerset will not look him in the eye. Mills leaves, slams the door. Somerset seems deflated.</context>
      <utterance>Start picking up the pieces. I'll shuffle some paper and try to get you a new partner.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You win, Somerset. You're out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WORKMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset turns back to typing. The captain steps in, looks at the workman, then drops more papers on Somerset's desk. As always, the neatly groomed captain clenches his jaw. He looks around. Two of boxes on the floor have DETECTIVE MILLS written across them. The captain picks one up, puts it on top of the other. He sits, watching Somerset, starts straightening the forms on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do with yourself out there, Somerset?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get a job. Maybe on a farm. I'll fix up my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you feel it yet?  Can't you feel that feeling... that you won't be special anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset reclines, looks at the captain.</context>
      <utterance>You know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you read in the paper today, about the man who took his dog for a walk? And how he was mugged? And, his wallet was taken, and his watch. Then, while he was still lying unconscious, his attacker stabbed him with a knife in both eyes. It happened last night. Not far from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no understanding of this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset saddles up to the typewriter. Hunt-and-peck.</context>
      <utterance>It's always been like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The captain lays the paperwork down in two neat stacks.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. You're absolutely right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The captain leaves. Somerset looks up now that the captain's gone. He grabs the paper piles and ruffles them back to their disheveled state. He looks at the workman. The workman is looking at Somerset, has a rag in his hand to remove the last remnants of Somerset's name.</context>
      <utterance>You were made for this work, Somerset. I can't believe you're going to trade it all in for a tool belt and a fishing rod. But, I guess I'm wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The workman is startled, continues his work.</context>
      <utterance>Put a little elbow grease into it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He must have left us another puzzle to solve... somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chris leaves and Mills stands to stretch. Something catches Mills' eye. He walks over to the door, curious. At the base of the open door, there's a ball of paper wedged under to act as a doorjamb. Mills puts his glove back on, pulls the ball out. He uncrumples the paper as the door slowly swings shut. The page has a drawing on it, of the sun with waves of heat at its edges. There is a single eye in the center of the sun. An arrow is drawn in dried blood on the back of the closing door. Mills notices this and pushes the door closed. The blood arrow points to the side and up, seems to be pointing to the photo gallery wall. Mills goes to examine the photos. His eyes search each photo... one by one... till he sees it:</context>
      <utterance>We'll keep looking, but we're running out of possibilities.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A framed photo of a falsely pretty, middle-aged woman smiling and wearing pearls. Under the glass, on the photo itself,</context>
      <utterance>Christ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VAGRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spare me a cigarette, money-grip? Spare me a cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks on. We BEGIN to HEAR JAZZ MUSIC.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Last one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mills looks to a t.v. on a table, picks up a remote, increases the volume. On the screen, MARTIN TALBOT, 47, source of the voice, stands before reporters. He's a powerful presence, with a gold tooth in the front of his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>I have voiced the same concerns to our law enforcement officials, and they assure me he is of the highest caliber.</utterance>
   <speaker>A REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As District Attorney, don't you feel some responsibility? Detective David Mills lacks the experience...</utterance>
   <speaker>TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Mills is hanging on every word.</context>
      <utterance>I've always said... I've always said, don't send a boy to do a man's job.</utterance>
   <speaker>TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.,CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, David Mills has a sterling record with the Philadelphia force. I stand behind him one hundred percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell 'em boss. Detective David Mills is a wonderful human being...</utterance>
   <speaker>TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>However... however... let me say this... Mills looks back at the television.</utterance>
   <speaker>TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.,CONT</mode>
      <context>Mills points the remote, turns the t.v. off as reporters crowd Talbot. Mills stares at the blank screen, dispirited. Across the room, Tracy stands in the doorway. Mills does not see her. He looks at the photocopy and sits at his desk. Tracy watches him, great concern in her sad eyes.</context>
      <utterance>If Detective Mills, at any point in this investigation... if he is not pulling his weight, I will be the first in line to pull his plug.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William yanks a painting wrapped in dusty paper, climbs down.</context>
      <utterance>I always figured that's the only reason you and I used to be friends. Because I was a friend of hers.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>William hands the painting to Somerset, walks to a director's chair facing a paint-splashed canvas on an easel. He is a used- up man, bound in an apathy-induced haze. He sits, picks up a squeeze bottle of orange paint from a table of supplies.</context>
      <utterance>Speaking of which...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>William "paints," using the squeeze bottles and by flicking saturated brushes so that the paint flies against the canvas. Most times, he's not even looking at the canvas or colors he's using. He looks over his shoulder at Somerset.</context>
      <utterance>I painted that about five years ago. I always told myself I'd give it to you next time I saw you. Somerset starts unwrapping the painting.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset looks at the unwrapped painting and is hit by a swell of memories. Horribly sad memories. It's a portrait in oils of a pretty, red-headed woman. William shoots red paint with one hand, concentrates on lighting a filterless cigarette with the other.</context>
      <utterance>Things are different these days, pal. You wouldn't believe it...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>William looks at his creation, then calmly kicks the easel over.</context>
      <utterance>People buy my paintings now... they drive down in their BMWs and Rolls Royces. It's the new money generation. I guess they think they're touching the avant-garde...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>William gets up, walks across the wet canvas, leaving footprints. He looks down at what he's done.</context>
      <utterance>There's another thousand dollar William McCracken expression of anarchy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>He laughs. Somerset holds up the delicately rendered portrait.</context>
      <utterance>Make that two thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is she? Have you seen her recently?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset fights the anguish this causes, puts the painting down.</context>
      <utterance>Huh... oh. No. She moved out of the city. Last winter. She married some businessman, or something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good for her.  I'm leaving soon myself. I'm finally getting out.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? What happened to the idealistic super-cop I used to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William grunts, flicks his cigarette away, takes out a bag of pills. He palms a few, notices the judgment in Somerset's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>He became a realist.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William turns his back to Somerset, pops the pills. Out of sight, out of mind. Somerset is disappointed, disgusted.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William smiles like a dolt, laughs a little.</context>
      <utterance>Not that I don't appreciate your recent artistic endeavors... but, what happened to the painter I used to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't remember.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man... can I buy these from you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset lays out photos of the notes, triangle and circle:</context>
      <utterance>They're not for sale.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>William narrows his eyes. Does not know.</context>
      <utterance>What is it? What's the murderer trying to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What picture is he painting?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William has an idea. He ambles over to a row of cabinets where oversized art books are stacked. He hunts through a pile, shoves some books aside.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I've seen things like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William keeps digging, finds one book, finds another. He opens one as he walks back to the drawing table.</context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>William lays a book down, finds a page. He opens it to Somerset. There is a circle to the side of the text. It says GLUTTONY under the circle. Somerset creases his brow, turns the page. William opens another book.</context>
      <utterance>It's church stuff. Christianity.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>William pages through and we catch glimpses of the bizarre, worlds of Hieronymus Bosch. Horrifying religious visions.</context>
      <utterance>When it first started... Christian artwork was all from Bible stories. It was like... nobody had any imagination. It was all... standardized.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.,CONT</mode>
      <context>William shoves the open book to Somerset. Somerset looks: Seven paintings in a circular pattern showing characters giving in to sins. Wicked, grotesque people. Somerset turns the book to examine each painting right side up.</context>
      <utterance>But, later, everyone started painting to tell their own stories... to teach lessons. Guys like Bosch, Bregel the elder... Van Eycks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The seven deadly sins.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what these murders remind me of. Paintings like these.  Gluttony... greed...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Seven deadly sins.</context>
      <utterance>Envy, wrath, pride, lust and sloth.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amen, brother. William goes to continue pulling other books.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset is chilled by all this, immersed in the Bosch book.</context>
      <utterance>I can find more examples. There's lots of paintings like those... painted over hundreds of years.  And you're right... that murderer is an artist.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, it's two down... five to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PREACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John tries to ignore, traffic blocking his escape.</context>
      <utterance>...are you, Sir? Is Jesus Christ your Lord and Master? Do you believe in Him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PREACHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ignore me. Listen to what I have to say. Christ can be your savior!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PREACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally the light changes. John turns and spits in the preacher's face. The preacher recoils as John crosses quickly. John hurries between cars in the crosswalk. The preacher curses from the corner, his voice drowned out in traffic.</context>
      <utterance>Think about God, sir. I can help you let Him into your life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John doesn't hear the barker. Steps up to study fading pictures of naked women massaging happy men. Nudity.</context>
      <utterance>Interesting isn't it, friend? You like that, you like girls, then come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>John's just looking, his face bathed in bright red light, the neon reflected in his thick glasses.</context>
      <utterance>You'll see a lot more inside. You'll see a lot more than that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a second to drink Somerset in. Somerset is surprised, having expected Mills. Tracy is so exquisite that he falters.</context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... I was looking for Mills. David, I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset tries not to drop any books while he digs up his badge.</context>
      <utterance>He's not here right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Mills, my name is Somerset. If I could leave these books for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, come in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David went for a walk. To clear his head. Oh, you can put those here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy motions and Somerset puts the books on Mills' desk. He starts looking through one book, checking paperclipped pages.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>I've marked the most important pages.</context>
      <utterance>Could you tell him... tell him this is his reading assignment. It's urgent.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David should be back any minute.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like some coffee, or a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset sees a medal encased in glass on the desk amongst pens and pencils. He picks it up: it's a medal for valor from the Philadelphia Police Department.</context>
      <utterance>I do have to get going.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least I got to meet you. David has told me a lot about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Good things, I hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. He said you were very smart.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset thinks about this, finds it hard to believe. He goes through his pocket, pulls out a notepad and some paper scraps.</context>
      <utterance>I think he's a bit intimidated by you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lays the various scraps and receipts aside on the desk, sits to start writing on the notepad. Tracy goes to the kitchenette to get a chair.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to leave him a list of specifics. It all relates to the case he's on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two aren't working together anymore. Isn't that so?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To be perfectly honest, Mrs. Mills...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tracy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tracy. David and I weren't exactly what you could call fast friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy brings the chair over by the desk and sits. Somerset looks up from his writing.</context>
      <utterance>That's too bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy nods, leaning forward, semi-conspiratorially.</context>
      <utterance>I doubt your husband shares that opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, Somerset, David is very... determined. I'm sure you've seen, it's not likely he'll ever be compared to Gandhi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a good cop. He just...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset pauses, enchanted by her.</context>
      <utterance>He sees policework as a crusade. That's what he wants it to be, and, that might sound naive, but he's made a conscious choice to be naive.  Believe me, his heart's in the right place.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear you and he were high school sweethearts.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Pretty hokey, huh? But, what girl wouldn't want the captain of the football team as their lifelong mate?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's rare these days... that kind of commitment.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy's smile falters a bit. Somerset notices this. He breaks from her spell, turns to continue writing.</context>
      <utterance>I guess so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... this will only take a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset writes. Tracy looks over the stack of books: Titles on the spines: BOSCH, A HISTORY OF CHRISTIAN ART, BREGEL THE ELDER, etc. Hardcover novels: DANTE'S PURGATORY and THE</context>
      <utterance>Take your time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset looks up. Sees her holding the paper rose. He takes it, slightly self-conscious, looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy tilts her head, looking at Somerset.</context>
      <utterance>My future.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset doesn't know what to say. He pockets the paper rose.</context>
      <utterance>You have a strange way about you, Somerset... I mean in a good way... unusual.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Tracy stands, takes the chair back to the kitchenette.</context>
      <utterance>I apologize. I'll get out of your hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just... it's nice to hear a man who talks like that. If David saw that paper, he'd say you're acting like a homosexual. That's how he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well! I guess I won't be showing this to him then.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset continues writing. Tracy sits at the kitchenette table, watches him.</context>
      <utterance>I suppose not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A figure outside the window knocks on the glass. Mills rolls it down. A COP in raincoat hands a wet paper bag through.</context>
      <utterance>Fucking Dante. Goddamn, poetry writing freak, mother-fuck...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>The cop leaves as Mills quickly rolls the window up and rips the bag open. Inside: Cliff Notes for Dante's Purgatory and The Canterbury Tales.</context>
      <utterance>Good work, Officer. Good work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills puts the box on the large desk. They both settle in, attending to their work. Two men, about five feet apart, each trying not to acknowledge the other's presence. Mills takes out his Cliff Notes, looks to see Somerset is occupied, hides them in a desk drawer. Somerset finishes one form, flips it and looks up. There's a chalk board nailed to the wall. On the chalkboard: 1 gluttony(x) 5 wrath 2 greed(x) 6 pride 3 sloth 7 lust 4 envy The PHONE RINGS. Both men look at it. Phone RINGS again.</context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your name on the door. Mills picks up. Somerset returns to his work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills is confused. He holds the phone out to Somerset.</context>
      <utterance>Detective Mills here.  Honey, I asked you not to call unless...  What... why? Okay... okay. Hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset looks quizzical. Mills shrugs. Somerset takes it.</context>
      <utterance>It's my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset gets up, hangs up, puzzled. Mills is waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?  Yes, well... I appreciate the thought, but... I...  Well, I guess I'd be delighted to. Thank you... goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm invited to have a late supper with you and your wife. And I accept.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills looks at the phone, lost.</context>
      <utterance>Tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why aren't you married, Somerset?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset adjusts his napkin on his lap, thinking.</context>
      <utterance>Tracy. What the hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was close. It just didn't happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It surprises me you're not married. It really does.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>disagreeable. Just ask your husband.</context>
      <utterance>Any person who spends a significant amount of time with me finds me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills grins, but he means it. he sips beer. The conversation lapses into long silence. Somerset concentrates on his plate. Tracy looks at Mills, who eats while watching the basketball game.</context>
      <utterance>No argument.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long have you lived here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too long. Much too long.  What do you think of our fair city?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take the bad with the good, I suppose. It's... it's...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy looks at Mills. Somerset can see it is a sore subject.</context>
      <utterance>It takes time to settle in.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A LOW RUMBLING is HEARD as plates begin to rattle and clatter.</context>
      <utterance>You'll get used to it pretty quickly. There are things in any big city that stand out at first. But...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dishes clatter more. Coffee cups clink against their saucers. Tracy holds her cup to stop it, tries to act like it is nothing, but she is clearly bothered.</context>
      <utterance>Subway train. It's right below us/</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>They wait. The t.v. picture goes fuzzy. The RUMBLING grows LOUDER, knocks something over in the sink. Mills continues eating. Somerset fiddles with his food. The record player skips, then plays on. The RUMBLING finally DIES DOWN, till everything is normal.</context>
      <utterance>It'll go away in a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills laughs, lamely.</context>
      <utterance>This real estate guy... a real scum, brought us to see this place a few times. And, it was nice enough, and the price was right. I was thinking it was nothing, but I started to notice, he kept hurrying us along. I mean what could it be? Why would he only show it like five minutes at a time, before he'd hustle us out the door?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset tries to stay straight, but he can't help laughing.</context>
      <utterance>We found out the first night.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls himself together, but only for a moment. He can't stop it, laughs harder, covering his mouth. Tracy and Mills laugh.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... it's a nice apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, fuck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All television does is teach children that it's really cool to be stupid and eat candy bars all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy takes a pot of coffee to the table and pours.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think I've ever met anyone who didn't have a television.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>That's weird. It's un-American.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about sports?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy brings over a plate of cookies and puts it on the table.</context>
      <utterance>What about them?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go to movies at least.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I read. Remember reading? What's the last book you read, Mills?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills laughs. Burps. he turns to Tracy.</context>
      <utterance>T.V. Guide.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset gives a blank stare. Tracy walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.  I just have to say, I can't respect any man who's never seen Green Acres.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've never seen The Odd Couple? The Flintstones?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Across the room, Tracy turns the t.v. and the record player off. She goes into the bedroom, shuts the door behind her without a word. Somerset and Mills turn to the closed door. They look at each other, then sit for a time. Somerset drinks coffee. Mills drums his fingers on his beeper. Big silence.</context>
      <utterance>I vaguely recall Wilma, and someone named... Dino.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills shakes his head, unloads what he's holding onto a rusty table. He sits in one of two lawn chairs. Somerset sits across from him.</context>
      <utterance>No connection between the two victims?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No witnesses of any kind?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None. Which I can't understand. It's like this guy's invisible.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset takes a picture from the file, the drawing of the sun with an eye at its center. He opens a book, CHRISTIAN SYMBOLS, which is full of illustrations. He starts paging through.</context>
      <utterance>In this city, minding your own business is a perfected science.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset holds the books up to Mills, points to a picture of the sun and eye, same as the drawing Mills found.</context>
      <utterance>At the precinct, Sunday nights, they offer a public crime prevention course. And, the very first thing they teach is that you should never scream "help" if you're in trouble. Scream "fire." Because people don't want to get caught up in anything. But, a fire... that's entertainment. They come running.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The Sun in Splendor with the Eye." It refers to God the father, and to Saint Thomas Aquinas.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which saint is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills takes the book and looks it over.</context>
      <utterance>Aquinas wrote a summary of theology, Summa Theologica. And he wrote about the seven deadly sins.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, what else have you got?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I appreciate being able to talk this out, but... it's my case.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills is pondering, very tired. He unlatches his briefcase, takes a photocopy of the photo of the falsely pretty woman and hands it to Somerset.</context>
      <utterance>So... satisfying my curiosity. I'm still leaving town on Sunday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The eyes were circled. With Mr. Gold's blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is his wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We've questioned her about ten times.</context>
      <utterance>She was away on business. She got back the day he was killed. If this means she saw anything, I don't know what.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, if it's a threat?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We put her in a safe house.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the one thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A breeze fans the pages of the books. The flipping pages reveal views of heaven, hell, adoration, crucifixion and sin.</context>
      <utterance>It's like he's preaching.  The sins were used in medieval sermons. There were seven cardinal virtues, and then seven deadly sins, as a learning tool. The sins distract man from true worship. True faith. Mills is seated at the table with art books open.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like in these paintings, and in Dante's Purgatory, right? But, in Purgatory, Dante and his buddy climb that big mountain...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven Terraces of Purgation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway... pride comes first, not gluttony. And in all the paintings, the sins are in a different order. I can't find a pattern.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset drops his cigarette to the empty street, watching the glowing tip fall. He looks at the woman's circled eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Because there's creativity in the mix. Consider these books as the murderer's inspiration. Or aspiration.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sees himself contributing to the body of Christian work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's punishing these people.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>These murders are like forced attrition.</context>
      <utterance>For all of us to see and learn from.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Forced what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Attrition. When you regret your sins, but not because you love God.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset thinks. He walks from the edge to Mills.</context>
      <utterance>Because someone's holding a gun on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When Mr. Gold's wife found the body, about how long was she in the apartment?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't find it. The door to the apartment was open and a neighbor...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When she got back from a business trip.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you said she found the body.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset thinks, coming up with something.</context>
      <utterance>No. She got back after you and I had already been there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset holds up the photo of Mrs. Gold.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe she is supposed to see something... she just hasn't had a chance to see it yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, look for anything strange or out of place. Anything at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS GOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills helps her go through the photos. He is shaken himself, not wanting to put her through this.</context>
      <utterance>I... I don't understand. Why now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Gold sobs quietly, wipes her tears.</context>
      <utterance>I need your help if we're going to get the guy who killed your husband. If there's anything in these pictures...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS GOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you absolutely sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS GOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>glowing tip fall. He looks at the woman's circled eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I can't do this now... please. ette to the empty street, watching the</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He sees himself contributing to the body of Christian work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's punishing these people.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>These murders are like forced attrition.</context>
      <utterance>For all of us to see and learn from.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Forced what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Attrition. When you regret your sins, but not because you love God.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset thinks. He walks from the edge to Mills.</context>
      <utterance>Because someone's holding a gun on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When Mr. Gold's wife found the body, about how long was she in the apartment?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't find it. The door to the apartment was open and a neighbor...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When she got back from a business trip.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you said she found the body.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset thinks, coming up with something.</context>
      <utterance>No. She got back after you and I had already been there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset holds up the photo of Mrs. Gold.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe she is supposed to see something... she just hasn't had a chance to see it yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, look for anything strange or out of place. Anything at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS GOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills helps her go through the photos. He is shaken himself, not wanting to put her through this.</context>
      <utterance>I... I don't understand. Why now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Gold sobs quietly, wipes her tears.</context>
      <utterance>I need your help if we're going to get the guy who killed your husband. If there's anything in these pictures...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS GOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you absolutely sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS GOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills looks at Somerset. Somerset holds other photos.</context>
      <utterance>I can't do this now... please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset looks at the photos in his hand, hesitant. These photos show Mr. Gold's corpse, not covered in any way.</context>
      <utterance>We have to show her those. There might be something she's missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have her look one last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS GOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. Here... here's something...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Gold points at the constructivist painting on the wall in one photo. The painting is an abstraction of colored squares.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS GOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This painting... in the living room...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS GOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills jerks his head to look at Somerset. Big score.</context>
      <utterance>Why is it hanging upside-down?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset puts the painting down, resting it on its bottom edge. The frame is backed by a thick sheet of brown paper. He points to where the wire used to be screwed into the frame, and to where it has been re-screwed.</context>
      <utterance>This has got to be it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset tears along the edge of the brown paper to get to the space between it and the canvas. He tears out the entire sheet. Mills helps pull it away, but there's nothing there. Empty. Mills looks at both sides of the paper, then tosses it away.</context>
      <utterance>It has to be. He changed the wire to rehang it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset pays the painting down, face up. He pokes his finger on the painted surface. Mills watches as Somerset kneels, takes out a credit card and presses it's edge against the canvas, trying to peel up some of the paint.</context>
      <utterance>It's nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset pushes the painting away, stands, frustrated.</context>
      <utterance>Give it up. The killer didn't paint the fucking thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset backs away from the wall, staring at the space where the painting hung. There is only a nail. He stares intently, then turns and walks out of the room. Mills holds his hands to his temples, furious. SOMERSET can be HEARD from the other room, going through drawers, dropping things. GLASS is HEARD BREAKING. Mills grabs a lamp and throws it on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>He fucked us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset comes back in, holding something. He steps over the lamp and goes to the blank wall space.</context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills watches. Somerset has a woman's make-up compact in hand. He opens it, uses the soft brush to begin applying the red rouge powder to the wall around the nail.</context>
      <utterance>Bear with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, sure. You got to be kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset brushes with wider strokes. He blows, leans very close to the wall to study the powder. Leans closer still. Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up and wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call the print lab. Now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FORENSIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The forensic bites his lip, still studying. Mills and Somerset watch the forensic who works offscreen.</context>
      <utterance>Talk to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, honestly... have you ever seen anything like this? Been involved in anything remotely like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I have not.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORENSIC</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The forensic steps down from a stool. Behind him, where the painting once was, there are fingerprints, clear and distinct. The prints have been left side by side, to form letters which form the words: HELP ME.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I can tell you this, detectives...</utterance>
   <speaker>FORENSIC</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>these are</context>
      <utterance>...just by studying the underloop...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't work for me. I can't believe he wants us to help him stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset doesn't buy it. The technician adjusts a knob.</context>
      <utterance>Who the hell knows? There's plenty of schizoids out there doing dirty deeds they don't want to do. With tiny voices whispering nasty things in their ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen this baby take three days to finish a cycle, so you guys can go cross your fingers somewhere else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really meant what you said to Mrs. Gold. You really believe we'll get him, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I still thought like you. I'm so far gone from that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, tell me what you think we're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All we do is pick up the pieces. We take all the evidence... all the pictures, statements. Write everything down and note what time things happened. We take it all, make a nice, neat pile and file it away. Just in case it's ever needed in a courtroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're unbelievable. In my entire life, you're the oldest man I've ever met.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen even the most promising clues lead to dead ends. Hundreds of times.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen the same. I'm not the country hick-boy you seem to think I am. Somerset takes out a cigarette and lights it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills slumps back, crosses his arms, closes his eyes to sleep.</context>
      <utterance>In this city, if all the skeletons came out of all the closets... if every un- revenged corpse were to suddenly rise and walk again, there would be no more room for the living.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset looks at Mills, puffs the cigarette. The computer is heard: whir - click - whir - click...</context>
      <utterance>Don't try to tell me you didn't get that rush tonight... that adrenalin. Like we were getting somewhere.  And, don't try to tell me it was because you thought we found something that would play well in a courtroom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FIVE hardened POLICE OFFICERS, four men, one woman, sit in chairs facing the captain. They all wear bullet-proof vests with "POLICE" stencil-painted across them. Somerset and Mills sit in back, drinking coffee, still trying to wake up.</context>
      <utterance>His street name is Zero, as some of you know. His prints were found at the scene by Detectives Mills and Somerset.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Zero has a long, long history of mental illness. Serious illness. He was all over your television sets two years ago after he raped and killed a seventy-three year old woman. He got off, as the saying goes, on a technicality. So we watched him on the streets, and he went out of circulation about a year ago.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A red-headed cop, CALIFORNIA, 28, raises his meaty hand.</context>
      <utterance>His last place of residence is still in his name. A search warrant is being pushed through the court as we speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, have the housing cops walk up and ring the doorbell. Problem solved. The cops laugh. The captain clenches his jaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is chatter among the cops. Somerset leans to Mills while the captain continues the briefing.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, California. When you go in, if Zero isn't home, some of his buddies might be house-sitting. And besides using, Zero deals, so, you will be very uninvited guests.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does not seem like our killer, does it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell me. I'm new in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zero does possess the requisite degree of insanity... but, he doesn't have the desire somehow. Our killer seems to have more purpose. More purpose than Zero could ever conceive of.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset wants no part of that.</context>
      <utterance>We'll tag along.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would we?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Satisfy our curiosity?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset pulls out his gun, checks the load.</context>
      <utterance>You ever take one?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Never in twenty-four years. I took my gun out only five times with the actual intention of using it. I never fired it. Not once.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I pulled it once, fired it once. I never took a bullet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills turns a corner, tires screeching.</context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. Somerset opens the window, feels the air on his face.</context>
      <utterance>It was my first one of these. We were a secondary unit, in vice. I was pretty shaky going in. When we busted the door, looking for a junkie, the fucking guy opened fire. One cop was hit in the arm. He went flying... like in slow motion.  I remember riding in the ambulance. His arm was like... a piece of meat. I thought, it's just his arm. But, he bled to death right there anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did the fire-fight end?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I was doing really good in Philly up till then. Lots of simple busts. I've always had this weird luck... but, this was wild.  I got that fuck with one shot... right between the eyes. And the next week, the mayor's pinning a medal on me. Picture in the paper, the whole nine yards.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I expected it to be bad, because I heard about other guys. You know... I took a human life. But, I slept like a baby that night. Somerset eats another antacid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Hemingway wrote somewhere... I can't remember where, but he wrote that, in order to live in a city, you have to have the ability to kill. I think he meant you truly must be able to do it, not just faking it, to survive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like he knew what he was talking about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A black cop hoists a battering ram. The other cops get on both sides of the door. Mills moves front. Somerset hangs back.</context>
      <utterance>This is it. Give it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>The black cop brings the ram forward with a splintering thud. The door flies open. The cops storm in.</context>
      <utterance>Police!! Open the door!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A blond cop goes into another room. Mills kicks the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Sweetheart!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get up now, motherfucker! Now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills pulls the indigo blanket off the bed, reveals the shriveled, sore-covered form of a black man who is blindfolded and tied to the bed with a thin wire wrapped time and time again around the bed. Tubes lead from the stained loincloth around the man's waist and snake under the bed. The victim is partially covered by what seem to be piles of black spaghetti.</context>
      <utterance>I said get up, Sleepyhead!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset pushes past the cops who recoil from the stench.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, fuck me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The black cop touches the black spaghetti. Holds a piece.</context>
      <utterance>Sloth... it's sloth.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell... those are dead worms.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>California points with his gun to the end of the black man's right arm. The hand is gone, severed at the wrist long ago.</context>
      <utterance>Check this out, dick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's him. It's Zero.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone call an ambulance.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The female cop has gone to the wall where the sheet is pinned up. She pulls the sheet aside and finds: fifty-two polaroid pictures; all pictures of Zero tied to the bed, with a date written at the bottom of each. it is a visual history of Zero's physical decay. The blond cop enters from the other room.</context>
      <utterance>Someone call a hearse, more like.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOND COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck is going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset takes out rubber gloves and puts them on.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, California. Get your people out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other cops file out as Mills goes to examine the polaroids under the sheet. Somerset replaces the sheet over Zero's body. California stays by his side.</context>
      <utterance>You heard him. Hit the hall, and don't touch anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset places his finger along Zero's throat.</context>
      <utterance>It looks like he's some kind of friggin' wax sculpture.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills studies the polaroids. Somerset walks to join him.</context>
      <utterance>Somerset, you... you better look here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset looks at the first photo. In it, Zero is bound and gagged, but he is fit, healthy.</context>
      <utterance>All pictures of Zero tied to the bed.  The last one's dated three days ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills kneels and lifts the bottom of the sheet off the floor, finds an open shoebox. On the box: TO THE DETECTIVES.</context>
      <utterance>Mo-ther...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>California leans close to Zero's gaunt, blindfolded face.</context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset leans down beside Mills. Mills looks through the shoebox. Inside are plastic, zip-lock bags. One bag contains small clumps of hair, one contains a yellow liquid...</context>
      <utterance>You got what you deserved, Zero.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>California is still close to Zero's face when suddenly Zero's lips twist. Zero lets out a loud, guttural bark. California jerks back in fear, shouting, falling over a chair. Mills and Somerset reel, standing. They see California on the ground, scared out of his mind, pointing.</context>
      <utterance>A urine sample... hair sample... fingernail clippings. He's laughing at us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills and Somerset look towards the bed. Zero's lips move feebly as he lets out a sick, gurgling moan.</context>
      <utterance>He's alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's still alive!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The way this has gone, I didn't think it was possible, but we may have underestimated this guy. The type of intestinal fortitude it must take... to keep a man bound for a full year. To sever his hand and use it to plant fingerprints.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want him bad. I don't just want to catch him anymore. I want to hurt him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen... we have to divorce ourselves from our emotions here. We have to keep focusing on the small details.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know about you, Somerset, but I feed off my emotions.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills is looking at the floor, burning with anger. Somerset grabs him by the jacket.</context>
      <utterance>He'll string us along all the way if we're not careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Mills pushes Somerset's hand off.</context>
      <utterance>Are you listening to me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a sudden brilliant flash of light and the SOUND of a CAMERA ADVANCING. Mills and Somerset look -- Down the stairs, John is posing as a reporter. He has his camera and flash up, pointed at the detectives.</context>
      <utterance>I hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes another picture, flashbulb flashing. Mills charges downwards, grabs John by his wrinkled clothing.</context>
      <utterance>Say cheese.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John squirms, holds up a laminated PRESS identification pass.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills shoves him and John stumbles a few steps, then falls to the landing below with a thud. His glasses fly off.</context>
      <utterance>I have a right, Officer. I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset steps down and pulls Mills back. John stands.</context>
      <utterance>That doesn't mean anything. This is a closed crime scene now!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do this! You can't...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John gets his glasses, scrambles downstairs, out of sight.</context>
      <utterance>Get the fuck out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Somerset yanks Mills harder, till Mills sits on the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>The public has a right to know!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do those cockroaches get here so quick?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They pay cops for the inside scoop, and they pay well. You can hate them, but you better give them something, or they'll make it all up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... I just...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's alright. It's always impressive to see a man feeding off his emotions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BEARDSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills looks into the oxygen.</context>
      <utterance>A year of immobility seems about right, judging by the deterioration of the muscles and spinal cord. Blood tests show a whole smorgasbord of drugs in his system. Heroin... crack... even an antibiotic which was administered to keep the bed sores from infecting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hasn't said anything, or tried to express himself in any way?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEARDSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills winces, moves away from the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Even if his brain were not mush, which it is... he chewed his own tongue off a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no way he'll survive?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEARDSLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Detective, he'd die right now of shock if you were to shine a flashlight in his eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put them away. I wish you hadn't brought them into the church.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father Bleeker shakes his head, as if he were trying to forget the images. Somerset replaces the murder photos in a file.</context>
      <utterance>I needed for you to see them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There were five principal phases in the development of early Christian art. From Hellenistic through the Renaissance... each period was affected by the decrees of religious leaders.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker walks to an ornate, gold cabinet. He puts on a pair of cotton gloves.</context>
      <utterance>If this killer belongs to a certain branch of the church... if he collects religious art from a certain period, I want to know. I have to narrow it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker crosses himself before using a key to open the cabinet. He takes out an ancient devotional book and a piece of cloth.</context>
      <utterance>The influences on these... things he's done, couldn't have come before the Gothic period. What's in those pictures is presented far too asymmetrically.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Bleeker takes the book to a table. Somerset follows. Bleeker lays the cloth under the book, opens the book, tenderly.</context>
      <utterance>The colors will tell the tale.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset leans to examine Bleeker's illuminated manuscript: Two pages of prayer. The prose is elaborately formed, surrounded by colorful illustrations of the seven deadly sins. Bleeker's finger points to a rendering of a man seated on a rock, guzzling from a jug. It's been painted in orange.</context>
      <utterance>Each sin had a symbolic color. But the specific color designations changed throughout the ages.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.,CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is an example. Gluttony is the sin, and the color is orange. This particular manuscript is preserved from the 18th century.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Bleeker steps away and Somerset gets closer to the pages.</context>
      <utterance>In the murders, gluttony is green. Greed is yellow. Sloth is indigo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, if this murderer is as precise as you say, then you need to find out at what period in history was gluttony green... and so on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do I look? If the colors changed so often?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is one man... Father Stone.  I haven't heard from him for quite some time. This was his passion. He spent his life studying the sins... and preaching against them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zero's landlord said an envelope of cash was in the office mailbox each month. He says, quote, "I never heard a single complaint from this guy and nobody ever complained about him. He's the best tenant I ever had."</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a landlord's dream tenant. A paralyzed man with no tongue.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who pays his rent on time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officer leaves. Mills starts sorting through piles on his desk. He doesn't know where to begin. He sits back in his chair, looks at the collage-like collection of pictures pinned on the walls: photos and diagrams of the murder scenes, the drawing of the sun and eye, color pages and black and white copies of pages from art books. He stares, thinking. He stands, takes a photocopy off the wall. The killer's first note: Dear Detectives, Long is the way, and hard, that out of hell leads up to the light.</context>
      <utterance>Bring me everything as soon as it's transcribed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Milton.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father Stone had a church and congregation of his own. But, he... there were some problems. The church is deserted now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker continues walking.</context>
      <utterance>Problems?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a small orphanage attached to the church, overseen by Father Stone. This was almost thirty years ago.  He was an excellent priest, devoted in every way. Many in his parish demanded his return.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bleeker sees a NUN down the hall, coming towards them.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allegations were made... Stone was accused of abusing the children in his care. But, those charges were</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nun is too close for Bleeker to speak freely.</context>
      <utterance>It was claimed... that the children were beaten. And, punished severely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whites of Stone's eyes have yellowed. He seems to nod. Somerset sits on a stool, close.</context>
      <utterance>Father Stone. I'm a policeman. I'd like to ask you a few questions, if it's alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to ask you about the seven deadly sins.</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sins.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stone reaches out a hand to touch Somerset's face. Stone's extremely long fingernails trail against Somerset's cheek and Somerset tries to hide his revulsion.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, father.</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you one of mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you saved? Do you have God?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stone takes his hand away, seems to be getting angry.</context>
      <utterance>I... I need to ask about the sins. Do you understand what I'm saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stone's weak arms wheel him away, towards a corner.</context>
      <utterance>Are you a sinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Stone bites his lip, moaning, disoriented.</context>
      <utterance>There are sinners here. Even here. And, pain waits for them. Hell is hungry for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset is shocked by the strength and volume of Stone's jagged voice. The nun goes to place a comforting hand on Stone's shoulder. Stone is beginning to cry.</context>
      <utterance>They don't realize... they don't know.  Fuck them all!</utterance>
   <speaker>NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This shouldn't have been allowed.</context>
      <utterance>They shouldn't have let you disturb him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the children?  Where are the children?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you looking for?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just looking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset shines the flashlight against the back altar wall, revealing a wooden carving of Christ crucified.</context>
      <utterance>Saint Jerome Emiliani. The patron saint of orphans.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this still the Lord's house?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Father Bleeker finds this talk insulting and offensive.</context>
      <utterance>And, even if Father Stone was guilty of everything... if he was hurting children here? It's still the Lord's house?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLEEKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills snaps his fingers in Somerset's face, gets his attention.</context>
      <utterance>Our guy's a bookworm, right? And, I know it's a long shot, but you have to give a picture id and current phone bill to get a library card. Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset takes the computer list.</context>
      <utterance>I made two separate lists of books. One relating to the sins... Dante's Purgatory, Canterbury Tales... The Dictionary of Catholicism... all the religious stuff. The second list was books about torture methods, mass murderers... sadomasochism. Whatever our killer might study to do the things he's done. Whatever his other interests are.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills fumbles in his pocket, takes out his pad and reads.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. Everything at the library goes into a computer. So, you can get in the system and cross-reference...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Mills slaps the list in Somerset's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Let's say you take, Dante's Purgatory, call number eight-five-one-D, and... The Biography of the Marquis de Sade, ninety-two S-A-D-E. Put those books in the system, and the computer can give you the name of anyone who's ever taken out both those books. And, it doesn't just give you their name and address, it gives you a complete history of their library reading habits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dario runs up. Somerset puts his hand on his shoulder and makes him walk with him. Mills continues on to his car.</context>
      <utterance>Dario! Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to the Father, this orphanage wasn't around for more than five or six years in the late fifties. So, I want someone to go to the Department of Child Welfare or City Hall and dig up all the records on this place. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>DARIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset releases Dario, who runs to obey. Somerset goes to his own car. Mills is driving to leave, stops, revs the engine. Somerset hands the computer list through the window.</context>
      <utterance>Get a list of every child who attended this orphanage before it shut down. Get it on my desk within the hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>This was your brainstorm?</context>
      <utterance>You thought of this all by yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Is that so hard for you to believe?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a pleasant surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills peels away. Somerset heads to his own car.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not as stupid as I look.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ramirez. Manuel Ramirez.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The lust painting is next. It shows a man standing over a woman. The woman is nude, under a sheet, and the man's features are bizarre, lecherous. He wants that woman. There are apples on the floor and on the bed. The color is red.</context>
      <utterance>No... I don't see any Ramirez.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elinski. Dennis Elinski.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Envy is particularly gruesome. The Devil is seen hovering in the air, wearing a crown, his body orange and slick, wrapped in a cloak of flames. His arms held high, his right hand grips a sword, a bolt of lightning, arrows, wheat, thistles, etc. His left hand, holds a plain globe around which a serpent has wrapped itself. He looks down at several pitiful mortals in a pit of fire. The mortals reach for him, yearn for him, the skin on their bodies is stretched taut over their bones.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Atwater? Paul Atwater.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Wrath shows a man surrounded by vaporous, satanic demons. He stands in a puddle of blood, looking at his hands stained with and dripping blood. Other than the rich red, the color is blue. Mills is at his desk, a good portion of the print-out list draped to the floor. He rubs his eyes, sighing, gets back to it. Somerset, at the temporary desk, studies his orphan list.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, here we go. Listen to the books this guy's been taking out...  Basic Homicide Investigation. Forensic Toxicology... The Encyclopedia of Modern Serial Killers...  Of</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills points to the drawing of "the Sun in splendor with the eye" which hangs on the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit. Somerset...  The Writings of Saint Thomas Aquinas.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aquinas. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills looks at the page... searching...</context>
      <utterance>That's right. Let me have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck... he used a false name.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills sits back, angry. Something strikes Somerset as odd. Familiar. He starts leafing quickly through the orphanage list.</context>
      <utterance>His library card lists him as Jonathan Doe. John Doe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset finds what he's looking for.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ... it's like a sick joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is one boy here. He was abandoned... no one knew who his parents were, so he was named at the orphanage...  John Doe. It's his legal name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's impossible odds that this is him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're focusing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I know. On one little thing. I'm not complaining. I'll follow anything we get and I'll take it any way we can get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach a door, apartment 3A. Somerset knocks. Mills takes out his gun and looks at Somerset to ask "what do you think?" Somerset nods that he should have the gun ready. Mills steps to the side of the door, knocks hard. Waits.</context>
      <utterance>We'll look at him. Ask a few questions. Try to get a feeling whether we should keep tabs on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>GUNFIRE SOUNDS and a bullet slams into door 3A behind Mills. He and Somerset recoil in shock, going to the floor as another bullet explodes, blasting plaster off the wall. The man is HEARD RUNNING back down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Somerset!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Mills jumps up. He moves towards the railing. Somerset sits up and takes out his own gun. The stairwell is silent. Mills peers over the railing into the stairwell's center, gun pointed. A HEAVY METALLIC CLICK is HEARD. Echoes. Mills leaps backwards as bullets begin raining up from below, accompanied by the SOUND of an UZI SUB-MACHINE GUN FIRING. Somerset lays flat as he and Mills crawl away from the railing, which is being shredded along with the floor around it. Bullets soar unceasingly. Mills and Somerset hold their hands over their ears. Pieces of wood and plaster fly everywhere. The uzi stops and the man can be HEARD RUNNING again. Mills gets up, covered in debris. He runs down into the smoky stairwell. Somerset rolls over, gets up more slowly.</context>
      <utterance>It's him! Jesus Christ, we can get this fucker!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you alright? Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other for a long time. Both realizing they came very close to dying.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ONE FORENSIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear he's running around with an uzi in one hand and a book of poetry in the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT THE TOP OF THE STAIRS, two forensics, SARAH and BILLY, wait behind Mills and Somerset. Surgical gloves on all hands. Mills kicks at the door to apartment 3A with all his might. Again.</context>
      <utterance>A real, modern-day renaissance man, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mills enters, tormented, weary. He stands in the projector's bright beam, holds an 8" by 10" print.</context>
      <utterance>Somerset!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He hands a press pass and the photo to Somerset.</context>
      <utterance>Somerset, we had him. Goddamn it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset looks at the photo, a picture of Mills and Somerset on the stairwell of the slum apartment building; the picture John took when he posed as a reporter.</context>
      <utterance>The pass is a fake... we had him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were that close to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset motions to the huge canvas. Mills looks: The painting is frightening collage, thick with paint. The photo of Mills and Somerset has been incorporated in bits and pieces. Duplicate images: enlarged eyes, hands, faces. The faces have been ripped, scratched, mutilated. Grainy eyes with holes jabbed in them are mounted in paint beside chopped broken arms. Mills' head is on Somerset's body, and vice versa. It's like a sick, fragmented vision of a slaughter house floor.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SKETCH ARTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills stands over the artist. Sarah, Billy and two deputy detectives are at work in the room, photographing, searching.</context>
      <utterance>This is the guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make sure it gets around.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKETCH ARTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it. Tomorrow morning, this city's good citizens will be on the lookout for Elmer Fudd.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't find anything to hang onto. No pay-stubs, no appointment books or calendars. Not even a book of phone numbers. And, you're not going to believe this...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just... we haven't found any fingerprints yet. Not one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you're right. I don't believe it. Keep looking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to put more men on this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset bristles slightly at Mills' abrupt demeanor.</context>
      <utterance>I'm working on it, alright. What have we got.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got about five thousand notebooks in this room. And, as near as I can tell, each notebook contains two hundred and fifty pages.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset looks at the notebook, reads.</context>
      <utterance>Then, he must write about the murders.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills walks. He looks into the adjoining paint room.</context>
      <utterance>"What sick, silly puppets we are, and what a gross stage we dance on. What fun we have, dancing around, not a care in the world. Not knowing that we are nothing. We are not what God intended."  "On the subway today, a man came up to start a conversation. He was making small talk, this lonely man, talking about the weather and other things. I tried to be accommodating, but my head began to hurt from his banality. I almost didn't notice it had happened, but I threw up all over him. And I couldn't stop myself from laughing."  No dates indicated. They're placed on the shelves in no discernible order. He describes a scab on his arm for five pages, then writes about existential philosophy on the next.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Mills leans in the doorway, looking at Doe's strange artworks.</context>
      <utterance>It's just his mind poured out on paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PHONE RINGS in the other room.</context>
      <utterance>You were right. He is preaching.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello... hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>I admire you more and more every day.</context>
      <utterance>I admire you, David. Imagine my surprise on finding you at my doorstep.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, John. Let's...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Long pause. Mills waits.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, no! You listen and don't talk. I suppose you found the painting and the photos. This is just as well. Now we all know we've all seen each other.  I mean what I say. I do admire you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.,CONT</mode>
      <context>John Doe hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, there is one other thing. Fourteen hundred thirty. West Eighty-sixth street. Apartment six-o-four.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset nods. He walks to a dresser. The woman's purse sits open and Somerset extracts her driver's license. He looks at the photo. The woman in the picture is beautiful.</context>
      <utterance>Pride. Just like in the painting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Neill steps up to the woman. He brandishes dull scissors. The captain enters with two uniform cops. He looks around, grim, clenching his jaw.</context>
      <utterance>You can see what he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut her up... dressed the wounds. He put the noose around her neck and stood her on the chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She had the telephone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call for help, and you'll live. But, you'll be mutilated.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Neill's cutting the bandages on the woman's face. He pulls them away in front. Mills looks, disgusted by the sight. Somerset sits in a chair, runs his fingers through his hair.</context>
      <utterance>Or, kick out the chair, and spare yourself a lifetime of hideousness.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'NEILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he did it very recently.</context>
      <utterance>He cut off her nose to spite her face.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, boys, you're running on empty. Go home. Just make sure you sleep with the phone between your knees.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy brightens a bit upon recognizing him.</context>
      <utterance>Tracy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somerset. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy looks up and around.</context>
      <utterance>I'm alright. I'm glad to see you found this place. I almost should have expected to run into you here, knowing that you teach English.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so huge. It's amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is why I moved into this neighborhood.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset notices Tracy noticing his gun.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you love the smell of all the old books. It smells like... like... I guess just old books, but, I love it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me. No matter how often I see guns, I can't get used to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy laughs. She looks at her watch.</context>
      <utterance>Same here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts down the aisle and Somerset walks with her.</context>
      <utterance>If David's going to be back home soon, I should get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you'll come to dinner another night. Before you leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy considers this as they enter an open area.</context>
      <utterance>You can stay and browse a little longer, can't you? I mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Tracy stops. Somerset looks hopeful. Tracy is very tempted.</context>
      <utterance>I... I hardly know anyone I can talk about books with anymore. I'd appreciate the company.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>MOVE TO the aisle marked MYSTERY, where Somerset and Tracy are leaning against shelves. They both hold books they've selected.</context>
      <utterance>The irony is, that after a day of the type of work he did, he'd come home and read me these morbid crime stories. Le Fanu's Green Tea. Murders in the Rue Morgue.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother would give him hell... because I was young, and he was keeping me up till all hours, giving me nightmares.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like a father who wanted his son to follow in his footsteps.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CLERK looks down the aisle, then walks on.</context>
      <utterance>One birthday, he gave me a hardcover book called The Century of the Detective, by Jurgen Thorwald. It traced the history of detection as a science and it sealed my fate. Because it was real, and that a drop of blood or a piece of hair could solve a crime... was incredible to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're closing up, Somerset.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David's going to wonder where I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give you a ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Please, don't bother.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They make their way out of the aisle. Somerset chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>I have to insist. If your husband found out I let you ride the subway at this hour he'd tear my head off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, literally.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've lived here for so long, Somerset. You know this city. I... Tracy can't quite figure how to put it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a hard place, Tracy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy wants to laugh, like it's silly, but can't pull it off.</context>
      <utterance>When David and I lived in Philadelphia, we could afford to live on the outskirts. But now...  I hate it here. I feel scared, and I feel sick and... I hate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to put blinders on sometimes. Most times. But, keep in mind, Tracy, like tonight, there are small pockets of sanity. Some bars and bookstores. Museums. Several last vestiges of civilization.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've visited so many of the schools, looking for work, you know. And, the conditions are... horrible. I can't believe how bad it is.  Children shouldn't have to grow up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset gives her a handkerchief. She wipes her tears.</context>
      <utterance>You can always look into the private schools. You'll find something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>She will not look at him, keeping herself under control.</context>
      <utterance>You're too hard on yourself, Tracy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Tracy is able to muster a small smile.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay to hate this city. It's natural. But, there is a bright side in all this. There is. You want to hear it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, yes. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy leans to give him a kiss on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>I can't think of another place that needs education more than this city. And you're a teacher. You can make a difference in a few people's lives. It's a very good thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They remain close, looking into each other's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Somerset.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset reaches to touch Tracy's face. They kiss. They kiss a long time. Tracy wraps her arms around Somerset's neck. Somerset runs his fingers through Tracy's hair. They share their sorrow. Tracy's tears run down her face. Finally, they part, opening their eyes. They know this is wrong. Somerset's hands are shaking. He grips the wheel, feels helpless.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Tracy's face is flushed. She is confused.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Tracy. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy gets out, neglects to close the door, not looking back. Somerset tries to come to his senses. He doesn't understand either, and his heart is aching. He adjusts the rearview mirror to watch Tracy go.</context>
      <utterance>I... I better go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is just till this is over.</context>
      <utterance>It won't be for long, honey. I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills goes to sit beside her. He puts his hand on her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy nods. She stands, goes to start turning down the covers.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills feels useless, powerless. He goes to the suitcase and starts unpacking the contents. Tracy continues turning down the sheets.</context>
      <utterance>I know. It can't be helped.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills looks at Somerset, who doesn't seem to be listening.</context>
      <utterance>There's two people in that painting. So, maybe he's planning to kill two people this time. Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong this morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset looks up, sips from a cup of coffee, looks at the photo. Mills swings his chair, looks out the window at the morning light on the billboard.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lust is next. Lust is sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apples on the floor. Original sin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset puts the photo down, leans back, takes out a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Adam and Eve.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sex, sex, sex. Fucking sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset looks at the burning tip of his cigarette. He gets up to stretch his legs. Mills picks up the lust photo, puts his feet up on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Lust is everywhere. That's the hard part. I think lust is the most prevalent sin, even more than greed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long pause.</context>
      <utterance>Lust is red.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bright red.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blood red.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red sky at night, sailor's delight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red blooded. Red head. Dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Realization. Somerset and Mills look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Red light district.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would make sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would be fitting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>You're damn right it would.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>WILD BILL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mills and Somerset are across the sales counter from WILD BILL, 37. Wild Bill is shirtless, covered in tattoos. A thick scar runs down his forehead to his bent nose. Leather belts, whips and jackets hang from the walls.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he was here. This morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was definitely him? You're positive?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILD BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. John Doe. Easy name to remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wild Bill pulls a box from behind the counter, digs in it.</context>
      <utterance>What was this job you did for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILD BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wild Bill gives a polaroid to Mills. We don't see the image.</context>
      <utterance>I got a picture of it. That's what he came for this morning. I figured he must be one of those art guys... like those guys who piss in a cup and drink it on stage. Performance art.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, fuck...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILD BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I undercharged him. I was up all night working to finish it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You built this for him? You built this?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILD BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BEEL CHIMES as a POLICEMAN enters the store.</context>
      <utterance>I've built weirder shit than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills and Somerset follow the policeman out.</context>
      <utterance>Somerset... we have a situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILD BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're gone. Wild Bill scratches his scar.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, my picture!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILD BILL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fucking pigs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FAT MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of the fucking booth!</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just wait! I'll come out, just wait!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CRAZED MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He... he... he made me do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An X is scratched into the red paint on the wall. Mills and Somerset move towards the covered body. There are apples on the bed and floor. The ROCK MUSIC from outside SUDDENLY STOPS.</context>
      <utterance>I have to look at you. I have to look at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to want to see this more than once.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZED MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sheet is lifted for the detectives. They grimace at what they see. We do not see. Somerset closes his eyes and walks to face a wall, shaken. The first attendant replaces the sheet. Mills steps back, takes out his handkerchief and sucks on it.</context>
      <utterance>He had a gun! He... he made me do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZED MAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.,CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He made me do it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CRAZED MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And... and... and he said... he asked if I was married. And, I could see he had a gun in his hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where was the girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZED MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where was the prostitute?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZED MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was... she was on the bed. She was just sitting on the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who tied her down? You or him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZED MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man slides off the chair and hides his face in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>He had a gun. He had a gun, and he made it happen. He made me do it! He made me put it on... that thing. Oh, God... he made me wear it. He had the gun in my mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAZED MAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset stands, picks up the Polaroid as two men in white uniforms enter to collect the crazed man from off the floor.</context>
      <utterance>The gun was in my throat. Mills looks at the mirror in the room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's not possible.</context>
      <utterance>There's not going to be a happy ending.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we get him, I'll be happy enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills drinks deep, pours more.</context>
      <utterance>No. Face it now. Stop thinking it's good guys against the bad guys in this city.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you say that? Especially after today?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell me... when you walk into an apartment, and a man has beaten his wife to death, or, a wife murdered her husband in cold blood... and you have to wash the blood off their children. You put the killer in jail. Who won?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I thought like you, I'd have slit my wrists a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the victory?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do your job. Follow the law and do the best you can. It's all there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we caught John Doe tomorrow, and it turned out he was the devil... if it turned out he was literally Satan, then, that might live up to our expectations. No human being could do these horrible things, right?! But, this is not the devil. It's only a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset sits back, looking at Mills.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you shut the fuck up for a while?! Huh? You make these speeches... like you know everything there is to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you're preparing me for the hard times ahead? You think you're toughening me up? Well, you're not!  You're quitting, fine... but I'm staying to fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you fighting for? People don't want a champion. They just want to keep playing the lottery and eating hamburgers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What burnt you out?</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck is wrong with you, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no one thing, if that's what you mean. I just... I can't live anymore where stupidity is embraced and nurtured as if it were a virtue.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're so much better than everyone, right? No one's worthy of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong! I sympathize completely. Because if you can't win... then, if you don't ignore everything and everyone around you, you go insane. It's easier to smoke crack, and not worry that your wife and kids are starving to death. And, it's so much easier to bear a child till that child finally shuts up, because it takes so much work to love. And, if you bothered to think about the abuse, and the damage, you'd be sad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're talking about people who are mentally ill. You're...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I am not! I'm talking about common, everyday life here. Where Ignorance isn't bliss, it's a matter of survival.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to yourself. You say, "the problem with people is they don't care, so I don't care about people." But, if you're not part of the solution...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But, life doesn't conform to analogies.</context>
      <utterance>People who are in arguments over their heads always use meaningless slogans.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're already here, and you've been here a long time. So, there's a part of you that knows, even if everything you say is true, none of it matters.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills stands.</context>
      <utterance>That part of me is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills digs out some money and throws it on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you. You want me to agree with you. "Yeah, you're right, Somerset, this place is fucked. Let's go live in a fucking log cabin!" Well, I don't agree with you. You're quitting, and it makes me sick. Cause, you're the best I've ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Mills leaves. Other patrons watch him go. Somerset takes out a cigarette. He goes to light it. The lighter will not light, and when it does, Somerset's hand is shaking.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the beer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills his face against her, holding tighter still.</context>
      <utterance>David?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy holds his face in her hands, sees that he is crying.</context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills clings to her. She wraps her arms around him as he cries quietly against her, and she kisses him, tries to comfort him. He sobs.</context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Somerset. It's Tracy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is everything alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Everything's fine. Could... could you meet me somewhere. To talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think that's a good idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to talk to someone, Somerset. You're the only friend I have here. I don't know anyone else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy shakes her head. Somerset sighs. Long silence.</context>
      <utterance>David doesn't know about this? You haven't told him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to tell you, Tracy, I'm not the one to talk to about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset takes out his cigarettes, but thinks better of it and puts them away. He watches Tracy stir her coffee.</context>
      <utterance>I just can't think straight. I don't know why I called you, except I can't stand to hold it as a secret anymore. I had to get it out... and I can't tell David yet. Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears come to Somerset's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I... I had a relationship once, very much like a marriage. And, there was a baby. A long time ago. Things were good. And I got up one morning, and I went on a case... a murder, like any other. Except it was my first since hearing about the baby. And, I felt this fear and anxiety coming over me. I looked around and I thought, how can I raise a child here? So, that night, I told her I didn't want us to have children, And, over the next few weeks... I convinced her...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, I wore her down... slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to have children. But...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy reaches to hold Somerset's hand, but he withdraws it, wipes his tears away.</context>
      <utterance>I can tell you, I know... I'm positive I made the right decision. I'm positive it was the right thing to do. But, there's never a day that goes by that I don't wish I had decided differently.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Tracy looks around the cafe, tears in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>If you... if you decide not to have the baby... if that's what you decide, then never tell Mills you were pregnant. I mean that. Never tell.  Your marriage would just wither, and die altogether.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, if you decide to have the baby, then, at that very instant, when you're absolutely sure... tell him. Tell him that exact second. And, spoil that kid every chance you get.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset stands. He forces a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Somerset...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all the wisdom I can share with you, Tracy. I barely know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will I see you again, before you leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset steps away, leaves. Tracy watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>Probably not. But, it's probably better that way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills remains impassive.</context>
      <utterance>I've decided... I want to stay on, till this is over. Till either it's done, or we can see it will never end.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you want to stay now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of two things is going to happen. We're either going to get John Doe... or, he will finish his series of seven, and he'll never be found.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think if you stay you're doing me some big favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm requesting you keep me on as your partner a few more days. You'd be doing me the favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew I'd say yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They enter the precinct house. Down the sidewalk, from a distance, comes John Doe. His brown workboots and clothing are splattered with blood. He walks towards the precinct house, hands in his pockets, like he's merely out for a walk on a Sunday afternoon. People on the sidewalk stop upon seeing him, avoiding him.</context>
      <utterance>No. I wasn't sure at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As soon as this is over, I'll be gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass through a gate and Somerset goes to the staircase leading to the second floor. Mills stops at the duty desk. Other cops are fighting for the DUTY SERGEANT'S attention.</context>
      <utterance>What a great big surprise that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mills and Somerset are on the premises.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills stops, looks. Somerset stops, looks back down the stairs. John Doe stands inside the precinct house doors. He holds out his arms as if to say "presto, here I am." Near silence comes to the room as all eyes go to the figure of John Doe. Mills is riveted, finding this impossible to comprehend. One UNIFORMED COP takes out his gun, points it at John Doe.</context>
      <utterance>Wonder-fucking-ful.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNIFORMED COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several other cops drop what they're doing and draw weapons. Mills, still off-balance, walks back through the gate, takes his gun out and points it at Doe.</context>
      <utterance>It's him!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset comes back down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Get down on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cops move slowly in on Doe from all sides.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John Doe gets on his knees, hands up. Mills moves close, but not too. ONE COP comes from behind, nudges Doe with his foot.</context>
      <utterance>You heard him! Get on the floor!</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spread your legs and get your hands out in front of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John Doe gets on his stomach, obeys. Mills comes right up to Doe, steps on his neck, puts his gun against Doe's head.</context>
      <utterance>Get down! Face down!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Cops frisk and handcuff Doe. Somerset comes beside Mills.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move. Don't move a fucking inch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Lieutenant Somerset.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cop putting the handcuffs on Doe holds up Doe's hands. Doe winces. Every single one of Doe's fingers has a bandage wrapped around it. John Doe looks up, his face pressed against the floor, glasses askew, Mills' gun at his temple.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to speak with my lawyer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He cuts off the skin of his fingertips. That's why we can't find a single usable print in his apartment. For a long time, he's been cutting before the papillary lines can grow back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the trace on his bank account? The guns?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset stands looking in at Doe.</context>
      <utterance>The orphanage is all we have. His bank account is only five years old and it started as cash. There's no credit history, no employment history. We even tried to trace his furniture. All we know for sure is he's wealthy, well educated and totally insane. We may never know how he got that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because he is John Doe, by choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When do we get to question him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't. This goes to court now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This doesn't make sense, captain. He wouldn't just turn himself in!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there he sits. It's not supposed to make sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not finished!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're wound way too tight on this, Mills.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset looks at them. Says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Somerset... help me out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The captain leaves. Mills is furious.</context>
      <utterance>It's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it, Somerset. You know Johnny's fucking with us. He's pissing in our faces again!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wouldn't just stop.</context>
      <utterance>Slow up. You and I are, probably for the first time ever, in total agreement.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... what the fuck, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John Doe's only two murders away from finishing his masterpiece, right? But, can you even conceive of what might happen next? I mean, can you tell me how he's going to go about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can tell you this; I recognize his lawyer. His name is Mark Swarr. He's the one who kept Zero out of prison.  We'll wait for John Doe's plea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>SWARR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swarr wipes his brow with a handkerchief.</context>
      <utterance>My client says there are two more bodies... two more dead, hidden away. He will take Detective Mills to these bodies, but only Detective Mills. Only at six o'clock, today.</utterance>
   <speaker>TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SWARR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says he admires you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is all part of his game plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWARR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Doe claims that if the detective does not accept this offer, the bodies will never be found.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills walks up into Swarr's face.</context>
      <utterance>Frankly, counselor, I'm inclined to let them rot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like what you do for a living?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back off, Mills.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWARR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills eases off. Talbot is agitated, tapping a finger on the gold tooth in his mouth. He looks at Swarr.</context>
      <utterance>I'm required by law to serve my clients to the best of my ability, and to serve their interests.</utterance>
   <speaker>TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't make deals like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to have to pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWARR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My client... he also wishes that I inform you, if you do not accept, he will plead insanity, across the board.</utterance>
   <speaker>TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him try. I'd like to see him try!</utterance>
   <speaker>SWARR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Talbot stands, wringing his hands. Mills and Somerset are looking at each other, thinking it over.</context>
      <utterance>Come now, Martin. Even he knows, with the nature of these crimes, I could get him off with such a plea.</utterance>
   <speaker>TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not letting this conviction slide. I can tell you that, right here and right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>SWARR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Talbot looks at Swarr with hatred.</context>
      <utterance>He says, if you accept, under his specific conditions, he will sign a full confession and plead guilty... right here, and right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset turns to Talbot.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on... just a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he were to plead insanity... this conversation is admissible. The fact that he's blackmailing us with his plea...</utterance>
   <speaker>SWARR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, my client reminds you, two more people are dead. The press would have a field day if they found out the police didn't seem too concerned about finding them... giving them proper burial.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset is thinking it through. He looks at Mills.</context>
      <utterance>I'll do it. I want to finish it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... let's get the fucking lawyer out of the room, and we can talk about how this whole thing's going to go down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If John Doe's head splits open, and a U.F.O. flies out, I want you to have expected it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No emotion. Stay as cold as ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset flicks ash in the sink. Mills finishes shaving. He steps away from the sink and wipes his chest off with a towel.</context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Somerset... we've been through a lot together. And, I uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset walks away. Mills laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I would like to make sweet love to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they leave.</context>
      <utterance>Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a kiss on the lips.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a break.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other. Mills holds out his hand. They shake on it.</context>
      <utterance>Extremely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pilot cranks the helicopter's whining engine and the blades start to spin, churning the air.</context>
      <utterance>Is this wind going to hurt us?</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>California hefts a high-powered automatic rifle as the chopper lifts from the pad and takes off.</context>
      <utterance>Just makes the ride a little more fun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe pushes his glasses back up the bridge of his nose, looks at Mills' eyes in the rearview mirror.</context>
      <utterance>What's your story, Johnny? Who are you, really?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter who I am. Who I am means absolutely nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your deal? You seem pretty fucking nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want this to go well. It's very important to me, obviously.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Downtown and moving west. Looks like you're going to be crossing water.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we're on the bridge, you keep your distance. You hear me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cross the river before us if necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>California taps the pilot's helmet.</context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't be sensational enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John Doe strains to turn, looks out the back window.</context>
      <utterance>Wanting people to pay attention, you can't just tap them on the shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes you have to hit them in the head with a sledgehammer... and then you get their strict attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you looking at, Johnny?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe situates forward, holds his hands in front of his face, looking at his bandaged fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Looking back... at the city proper...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And yet, no pillar of salt.  Lost on you, isn't it? You've never read the Bible, have you, David?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember a lot of people reading it</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You make me sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills slams his fist against the partition. Doe sits back.</context>
      <utterance>Sit back, freak.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ignorant heathen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe looks out the window at other cars, refuses to answer. He's pressing the tips of his forefingers into his thumbs, causing blood to drip from under the bandages.</context>
      <utterance>Right, right. I forgot. You think these murders were for God. Right?  I'm asking you seriously. You really think what you did was God's good work?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Lord works in mysterious ways.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see anything... not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe's in the back seat, trying to bear it, steaming.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, Superstar... who in the world do you think you are? Jesus Christ, Superstar...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can walk from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stay out of this unless I call you in, California. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Somerset takes off the headset/phone, stops the car.</context>
      <utterance>You're in charge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, Somerset. Going for a stroll.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe obliges. Mills moves to unchain Doe's feet, cautious.</context>
      <utterance>Lean on your side. Hands behind your head and lock your fingers together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Doe points with handcuffed hands, at a path through the junk- yard, towards warehouses. Mills motions with his gun.</context>
      <utterance>Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.,CONT</mode>
      <context>Doe starts walking. Mills follows, keeping the gun on Doe. We lose sight of them behind the junk-yard's massive pieces.</context>
      <utterance>Lead the way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills is on edge. His eyes search the towering, twisted junk. Sharp edges reach for the sky. Glass breaks under their feet.</context>
      <utterance>It's right this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SOUNDS of BOATS on the river can be HEARD. Doe's heading for the alleyway created by two warehouses beyond the junk-yard. Doe nears the alleyway. It is pitch dark. Doe stops before entering, turns to Mills.</context>
      <utterance>So far, so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills steps up, keeping his distance from Doe. He can't see a thing in the blackness ahead.</context>
      <utterance>In here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe faces the alley. He starts walking. We MOVE with him as he goes. He's counting silently to himself, moving his lips. Mills walks behind Doe, keeping a sharp eye out in all directions. He's about ten feet behind Doe, keeping his gun trained on the back of Doe's skull.</context>
      <utterance>You go first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Doe continues walking, counting his steps, a bit quicker.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me where we're going.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe stops abruptly. He spins on his heels, facing Mills. Mills is getting closer, pumped, ready to pull the trigger. Doe reaches up with his hands, takes off his glasses. He holds them in one hand. The SOUND of the WATER is LOUDER. Mills is about six feet from Doe, and knows something's wrong. John Doe smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I'll blow your head off right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Doe takes one step backwards and falls, straight down, disappears in the blink of an eye.</context>
      <utterance>What...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>STATIC CRACKLES LOUD in his headset, then it GOES DEAD. California grips his mouthpiece.</context>
      <utterance>I have to go in after him!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somerset, what's going on down there?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mills!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God damn it! Let's do something!</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somerset said wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck that! Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>CALIFORNIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know! Just go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A figure appears in the center of the waterfall behind Mills.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Let's do it! You and me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>John Doe steps out of the waterfall, putting on his glasses. He seems calm, unloads his gun into Mills' back... BLAM, BLAM... Mills twists, blown forward by the bullets slamming into his bullet-proof vest. BLAM, BLAM, BLAM... he stumbles, trying to turn and fire back, but bullets strike him down and he falls to the floor of the catwalk, gun falling from his hand. CLICK. Doe's gun is empty. The gunshots echo. Mills lays there on his stomach, pounded, blacking out, the hot bullets in his vest smoking and sizzling from the water splashing them. Doe moves quickly, starts searching Mills' pockets.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to let you win this!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice reverberates, barely heard against the roaring water. he swims to the edge, climbs out. He walks, looking...</context>
      <utterance>Mills! Pull out!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset looks up, and freezes up on seeing -- -- Doe's handcuffs hang, swinging, on the rail of the catwalk above, with Mills' radio transmitter and wire tied to them.</context>
      <utterance>Pull out now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="43">
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Doe sounds far, his voice echoing from the front of the church.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Somerset.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's David?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's here. With me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset can see through the heat warp. Doe stands facing him from the altar.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me what you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset obeys, bends, slides the gun down the aisle till it hits the bottom altar stair. He keeps walking, slowly.</context>
      <utterance>What do I want? The same you... I want an ending. Stay where you are. Put your gun on the floor and slide it all the way down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the altar, Doe is sweating hard, standing over Mills. Mills is slumped forward on the floor, unconscious. His bullet-proof vest has been removed. Mills' hands are tied tight together in front of him, tied to one end of the thick rope suspended from the ceiling. Doe holds the other end of the rope, has his gun tucked under his belt.</context>
      <utterance>I want to see him. Show me Mills.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe's voice is thick with passion. Somerset is about halfway down the aisle, still moving.</context>
      <utterance>You're an intelligent man, Somerset. You understand what you're a part of, don't you? When this is finished, it will seem surreal, but it will be a whole, crystalline reality. And, no one will be able to deny it, no matter how hard they try.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe walks across the altar.</context>
      <utterance>You're a murderer. That's all. The only way you've distinguished yourself is by your particular brutality.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know that's not true. You know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe picks up a container of gasoline, looks out at Somerset.</context>
      <utterance>You're killing innocent people, and I should admire you? You're doing it because it gives you pleasure. That's the only purpose... your sick pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset stops.</context>
      <utterance>Stay where you are!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Doe begins dousing Mills with gasoline, covering Mills' body and clothing. Mills stirs, coming to. He coughs, choking on the gas and fumes.</context>
      <utterance>I won't deny my personal desires. I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, I don't mourn the victims in this any more than I mourn the</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset is twitching with anger, looking at the gun about fifteen feet in front of him. Mills manages to look up, weak, his eyes barely able to open because of the stinging gasoline.</context>
      <utterance>Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe takes one step down off the altar. Somerset is still edging forward, hands out away from his body.</context>
      <utterance>Somerset?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you really think I'm just going to let this happen?! You think I'm going to let him die?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe fires his gun and the bullet slams into the front of Somerset's bullet-proof vest. Somerset flies back, knocking over a rack of candles on his way to the floor. Doe walks quickly back onto the altar.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills tries to grab at Doe as he passes, but Doe turns and kicks Mills in the ribs. Mills cringes in pain. Somerset lays in the aisle, on his stomach, gasping. He can't catch his breath, his twisted face pressed against the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Motherfucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills tries to rub the gas out of his eyes with his bound hands. His mind works feverishly. He looks around to see where he is, then he searches the floor. We can see, inside his open shirt, the bleeding, upside-down cross Doe has cut into his chest. Doe walks back to shout angrily down at Somerset.</context>
      <utterance>How can you speak of God, Somerset? When was the last time you spoke His name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset holds his chest, blinking, trying not to black out. Mills finds a piece of broken stained glass on the floor. He picks it up, palms it, still choking on gasoline. Doe walks over to the statue of Saint Jerome Emiliani, pulling the rope from above so it goes taut and Mills' arms raise above his head. Doe wraps the rope around Emiliani's arm.</context>
      <utterance>When did you last speak His name? Was it in prayer? Or, did you say the Lord's name after you stubbed your big toe? Or, did you use His name to curse another man?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe begins twisting the loose end of the rope around the statue.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to kill you, Johnny. I'm going to see you dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills clutches the glass piece and starts cutting the rope just above his hands.</context>
      <utterance>The irony, David, is that you policemen and I want the same things. But, you are so short sighted. In this city, where you can see a deadly sin on every street corner... and in every home, we want repentance.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset manages to life his head, struggles to his knees.</context>
      <utterance>We want good over evil. We want values instilled in the children. We want a world where a man or woman can lead a decent life.  Wisdom, understanding, counsel, fortitude, knowledge, piety, and fear of the Lord. Such simple concepts. Why are they non-existent?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe checks to make sure the rope around Saint Emiliani is secure, tightening the knots.</context>
      <utterance>Let him go, God damn you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills watches, gritting his teeth, rubbing the glass against the rope, fingers bleeding.</context>
      <utterance>There were two men once, who had wonderful gardens. Two gardens of flowers that went on as far as the eye could see. Beautiful gardens... the fragrance was inspiration in itself. Doe stands behind Emiliani, heaves against the statue.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Doe finally topples the statue, down the altar stairs, and the other end of the rope pulls Mills upwards, screaming in pain. Mills is held, about eight feet in the air, legs dangling.</context>
      <utterance>But, both gardens were beset by problems. Weeds started to take root, and there were infestations of insects and diseases. The gardens started to turn putrid. And, one man fought to save his garden, because he could never forget how it once was. Everyday he cut the weeds, and killed the insects. Fought the diseases.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That man never had a beautiful garden again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset gets to his feet, steadying himself on a pew. Doe walks across the altar, picks up a long metal pole with a thick wick and candle snuffer on the end. He lights the wick from a near candle. The flame burns long and thin. He looks down at Somerset, takes out his gun.</context>
      <utterance>The other man plowed his garden under.  He plowed it under the soil. He started over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Mills is straining. He nods to Somerset, and Somerset sees Mills cutting at the rope.</context>
      <utterance>Stay there, Somerset. Or, I'll kill him right now. Doe holds the flaming pole up, near Mills. Somerset stops. He looks up at Mills.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright... you don't have to do this, John. You've already made your point.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doe lowers the flame, standing below and beside Mills, with his attention focused on Somerset.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think I chose this? Can you even begin to understand how painful my existence has been? It's like... like having every sense heightened beyond comprehension.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that the stench of the street coats your throat like bile. So, sugar is so sweet it... it makes your bones ache to the marrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're insane. That's why.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mills continues cutting, bleeding, almost through the rope. He begins to swing his feet slightly, his body swaying.</context>
      <utterance>No! You're wrong!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Doe steps towards Mills.</context>
      <utterance>I was chosen. And I've wished a thousand times I could have been a normal man. Like David Mills, a common man... with a common life. But, wishing that is my sin. I can't have it and I shouldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do this!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN DOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I meant what I said. I admire David Mills. I envy David Mills.  Envy is my sin.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as Doe is to put the flame to Mills, the rope is finally cut through. Mills drops, swinging his legs forward, smashing Doe in the face, knocking Doe's glasses off. Mills hits the floor with a thud. Somerset runs forward.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Doe has fallen back, dropping the metal pole. Mills scrambles to his feet and charges at Doe, shouting. Doe squints, screaming, raises his gun. Fires twice! The bullets catch Mills in mid-run, and carry him off his feet, backwards. Somerset grips his own gun, just as Mills' body falls, tumbles off the altar area and down the stairs in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>David, get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Somerset lets out a scream of pain and rage that chokes in his throat. He falls to his knees and halts Mills' body. Somerset's shaking, unable to breathe, turning Mills over and cradling his head in his arms. Tears come to his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>On the altar, Doe throws his gun away. he starts feeling around him, unsteady, looking for his glasses. Mills' eyes are closed. He is still, bloody. He swallows. With one gasp, without a word, he is dead. Somerset looks up at Doe, vision blurred by rage and tears. Doe stands, putting on his glasses, faces Somerset. Somerset lays Mills' body down. Stands, walks up towards the altar, raises his gun.</context>
      <utterance>David... David? Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>Doe stands, quaking, teeth clenched, fists balled up. He waits for the bullets, falls to his knees. The gun trembles in Somerset's hand as Somerset brings the barrel to Doe's face. A millisecond's pause. Somerset changes the angle of fire. BLAM, he blows John Doe's arm to pieces in a splattering explosion. Doe screams, falling back, on the altar floor.</context>
      <utterance>You.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset hasn't acknowledged the captain, still looking away.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I should do this.  We found the motel room Doe must have been staying in after you found his apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT</mode>
      <context>The captain takes out a sealed envelope. Somerset takes it. On the envelope: DETECTIVE SOMERSET, handwritten, in red marker.</context>
      <utterance>Anyway... we found this in his belongings.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I could say something...  Something to... I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset nods.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll keep in touch. I'll come visit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll write to you when we get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy nods. There's nothing left for them to say. They're both empty. It's time for them to give a gesture, a kiss, or a hug, to say goodbye, but neither makes the first move.</context>
      <utterance>Take care of yourself.  Take care of the baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Movers latch up the back of the truck while the driver climbs in and fires up the engine.</context>
      <utterance>That's all, Mrs. Mills. We got everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMERSET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Tracy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerset walks away. Tracy walks away, gets in the passenger side of the moving truck.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Somerset.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
