<movie id="480" title="Semi Pro">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOB COSTAS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>DOCUMENTARY FOOTAGE: This is real ABA footage. A series of great plays are made by ABA stars.</context>
      <utterance>Before the NBA was the NBA, there was another basketball league in America...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB COSTAS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>DOCUMENTARY FOOTAGE: Dr. J launches from the foul line and dunks in the world's first dunk contest. David Thompson finishes an Alley Oop.</context>
      <utterance>.From 1967 to 1976, there was the American Basketball Association. A maverick minor-league that would change the game forever. The ABA made the fast break FAST... Invented the three point shot... And introduced the world to something called the Slam Dunk Contest.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB COSTAS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>DOCUMENTARY FOOTAGE: A young Bob Costas broadcasts from St. Louis, looking pretty sweet in side burns and a tweed jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Singer Pat Boone owned the Oakland Oaks. Wilt Chambelain coached the Conquistadors. I myself was the young voice of the St. Louis Spirits.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB COSTAS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>DOCUMENTARY FOOTAGE: The infamous TV interview where Freddy Lewis wins a 'race horse.' Footage of 'Dime Beer Night.' Footage of the Kentucky Colonials fielding a cheerleader as one of their starting five.</context>
      <utterance>Players like Dr. J, Ice-man George Gervin and Moses Malone were as entertaining as they come. But despite the league's flair, convincing fans to show up for games was often a struggle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOB COSTAS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. </mode>
      <context>DOCUMENTARY FOOTAGE: The Miami Ball Girls dance in bikinis (In truth, some of the girls were still in high school).</context>
      <utterance>For owners, promotional ideas became an art form all to themselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB COSTAS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>DOCUMENTARY FOOTAGE: A guy elbows Connie Hawkins, who turns and punches the guy in the face.</context>
      <utterance>One night, the Nets went as far as to give a free gerbil to it's first fifty fans... There were plenty of punches too, giving the National Hockey League a run for it's money.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB COSTAS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>DOCUMENTARY FOOTAGE: Harry 'The fat Mexican guy' dances.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, the ABA had a style all it's own. The hair was big, the shorts were short and the ball was red, white and blue.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB COSTAS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In 1976, rumors of a merger spread throughout the league. In the end, only four teams would join the NBA and survive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOB COSTAS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Teams like the Kentucky Colonels and the Virginia Squires would disappear forever. But their spirit still lives on to this day.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB COSTAS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Some FUNKY MUSIC plays.</context>
      <utterance>Here, we present the legend of the ABA... Exactly as it happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOB COSTAS</speaker>
      <mode>V_O_</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except, this Flint Michigan team never existed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>MONIX suddenly takes a HUGE HIT, TOTALLY SLAMMED by a big asshole, PETRELLI. He flies into the crowd -- everyone erupts, screaming with glee.</context>
      <utterance>The Amigos are up by one here. They'll need to find a way to stop Monix. He checks the clock, waits... And now drives the lane...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Some tough love from Patrelli.</context>
      <utterance>Ooh, Monix gets taken out hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>WHAT!? Where's the foul on that? That was all ball.  Jesus Christ Leonard! Let them play for once! This ain't fuckin' Greenpeace!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some might say that was a close call, but these referees have done a nice job tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Still stuck in the crowd. Monix struggles to get back on the court. The crowd shoves him around, twisting his ankle, slapping him. The crowd is nuts.</context>
      <utterance>'Oh please. These refs SUCK.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DRUNK LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix is confused, until the woman throws the beer in his face.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Monix, want a sip?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She and her friends laugh. Monix says nothing. Instead, he holds his aching back and limps up to the foul line, annoyed.</context>
      <utterance>Oops.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SUCK, MAN! YOU SUCK DONKEY DICK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again, Monix ignores the drunk lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Monix focuses on his ritual again.</context>
      <utterance>They dodged a bullet there. But Monix still has one last chance to tie it up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>The lady runs on court and attacks Monix, her boyfriend jumps in -- Monix hits her boyfriend with some quick hockey punches. The benches clear, everyone is punching everybody.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! He just pegged a chick! That's the greatest thing I've ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we've got a little bit of pushing and shoving under the basket. What do you make of this, Lou?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Lou Redwood takes his headphones off, climbs over the announcer's table and jumps into the fight.</context>
      <utterance>I'm goin' in.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright then.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More on this Amigo victory, right after this message from Colt 45.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCHNACK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. </mode>
      <context>SCHNACK, the owner, carries a six pack of Schlitz.</context>
      <utterance>Want one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schnack hands them over. Monix might speak, but he drinks instead.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take two.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHNACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Monix. The trade went through.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For who?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCHNACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you're not exactly a spring chicken anymore...</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHNACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: Pieces of an old scoreboard are crammed into the back of the locker room.</context>
      <utterance>That score board.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHNACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a Magnovox.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHNACK</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me: What the Hell did you want to get traded back to Flint for, of all places? Please tell me this isn't about Lynn.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still owe me $400.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CUSTOMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, wasn't that you just now, there on the TV?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, so?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you waiting on us for, if you're a basketball star?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the Hell areyou,the barbecue police? Tell youwhat,I've got the note pad, so I'llaskthe questions: Do youwanta baked potato with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The TV said your name was Sugar Dunkerton. How come your name-tag doesn't say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cause I changed my name, that's why.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Downtown Funky-Stuff Malone?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess it's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't fine.  It's fine...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarence tosses his note pad on the table and his Mother tosses him his duffle bag.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.  It's been a pleasure serving you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MS. QUINCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And don't think I didn't see those cotton briefs of yours in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay outta my stuff!</utterance>
   <speaker>MS. QUINCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you know our ancestors had to pick that cotton? Get yourself some silk underpants. Have some respect.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Panties are silk. Briefs are cotton. I'm out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentleman, please rise...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>PICTURE 2: Jackie Moon in Reno, singing with Pat Boone. He holds up his only hit single. PICTURE 3: Jackie is getting married to LUCY MOON. She's the hottest girl in the world.</context>
      <utterance>Baby, who wants to; love me sexy. baby, are you ready to; lick me sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>PICTURE 4: Jackie hands over a giant check, PURCHASING THE</context>
      <utterance>Take off your shoes and; suck me sexy. Baby, we're naked and we're; humping sexy--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. </mode>
      <context>THE BALL GIRLS: They bounce around in shiny-funky hot pants -- dancing cool, but not in sync. When it comes to ball girls, Flint delivers. THE TROPICAL AISLE: A rowdy bunch is decked out in Hawaiian shirts and packed in behind the visiter's bench, looking for trouble. THE SCOREBOARD: The Magnovox has been sold. The Tropics now do it by hand.</context>
      <utterance>Take off your shoes and; suck me sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON DARREN AND JODY: Two kids in WHEEL CHAIRS are parked next to the hardwood, eating nachos and drinking giant cokes.</context>
      <utterance>Baby, we're naked and we're; humping sexy...</utterance>
   <speaker>OPPOSING PLAYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey there son, what's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELCHAIR DARREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, Mitchstien.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELCHAIR JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Throw any elbows tonight and we'll pound your fuckin' head into the floor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bobby Dee hits the disco ball as TWIGGY trots out.</context>
      <utterance>I'm living a dream, Flint and I know you are too.  AT GUARD, from Peoria Illinois, six foot one -- this guy's single and he can cook lasagna, I've seen him do it -- TWIGGY -- MUNSONNNNNNN!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>FROM SOUTH BEND INDIANA, the man with a heart of gold, his brother's a retard, six foot one, he drives down to visit all the time, at forward, he reads to him, BEE BEE</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YOUR MAN IN THE MIDDLE. Seven foot two, from the People's Republic of Uzbechistan, he's tall, he's sensitive -- loves candle light and long walks on the beach -- VAKIDIS</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now this next guy, where do I start? First of all, that wife of his, she is... Wow.  CANONS, people. If you know what I'm saying. I don't think she's here tonight, but if she was you'd see what I'm talking about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie takes off his blazer, twirls it, then tosses it off screen. It's game time. At center court, PLAYER/OWNER/COACH JACKIE huddles them up.</context>
      <utterance>AND FINALLY: The man you've been waiting for, six foot four, a solid, meaty, two hundred fifteen pounds, your pre-game announcer, your owner, your coach, your pop singing sensation, but most importantly, your POWER FORWARD... Yours truly... JACKIE M00000000N!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A very short Asian man, KONG, nods. The uniform hangs on his tiny body.</context>
      <utterance>Alright you guys, let's huddle up!  Vakidis! Where's he walking to? Kong, get Vakidis.</utterance>
   <speaker>KONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's put on a good show tonight, okay? Let's keep it in the air, keep shooting, look for the baseball pass, launch some early threes to set the tone. Bee Bee, try and do that no-look behind your back thing, I love that, okay? Now let's bring it in. One two three--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you lose weight, Father Pat?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER PAT THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie points up to a leak in the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, fuck off. What's with the cone tonight Jackie?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Vakidis jogs over, SLIPPING HORRIBLY in the puddle, ripping his groin.</context>
      <utterance>For safety.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. </mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scootsie drops it in low to player- owner-coach Jackie Moon. Known best for his aggressive defense, leads the team in rebounds. He's an animal under the boards Lou.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Damn right. He may not be black, but he can play basketball.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, look at this, Jackie waves the rest of his team away, looking for the isolation. These fans are in for a real treat.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks to be setting up his 'Tear Drop from Hades.'</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie is shooting thirty-nine percent from the field, but the crowd always loves to see him go for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a true showman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. </mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Airball.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. </mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep, a Polish swish.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Jackie holds the ball, preparing for another 'Tear Drop from Hades'... But now he suddenly gets distracted by something up in the stands.</context>
      <utterance>Scootsie Double-Day gets the offensive rebound and Jackie calls for it again, trying to establish the low post early.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RAVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHISTLE! Jackie's been walking with the ball. FATHER PAT THE REF wears a holy collar with pin strips over it.</context>
      <utterance>Enough with the cheese already. More chips, less cheese, how many times do I have to tell you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER PAT THE. REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Traveling.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Traveling!?... On who?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER PAT THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie, furious, SLAMS THE BALL down on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>That's bullshit, Father Pat!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOBBY DEE</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Clarence tosses the half eaten candy bar, wipes his hands off on his jersey and jogs right out onto the court during the game, TAGGING HIS TEAMMATE OUT as if it were pick up.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentleman, put your hands together for Downtown Funky- Stuff Malone!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Downtown, wastes no time entering the game -- tagging out Vakidis Roscovenski.</utterance>
   <speaker>.CLAWS COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ref just shrugs. Downtown calls for the ball and gets it.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon Father Pat, he's got to check into the game doesn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>The entire other team leaves their men and guards Clarence five on one, but Clarence never passes. His four teammates watch from under the basket.</context>
      <utterance>Downtown dribbles left, then right a little shake and bake through the legs -- double teamed now, he's got Twiggy Munson open under the basket. Downtown, still with the ball, dribbles behind his back, they triple him, he's got Munson and Ellis wide open under the hoop, but look at these moves!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. </mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Downtown has all five guys on him -- He sprints to the corner and forces up a fade away three... YES! Wow. You think this league's going bankrupt? Well, think again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People call him selfish. I call him the greatest show in shorts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Nice first half guys! That's what I call Flint Tropic's basketball!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Jackie points to the chalkboard. Where one of his catchy slogans is spelled out.</context>
      <utterance>I've been telling you all season, we're about to make a run. Flint Michigan is destined for greatness.  Twiggy, enough with the bounce passes, let's show some zip. Bee Bee, try not to get fouled so much, free throws take too long. Scootsie, what did I tell you about catching with two hands.? God gave you one hand for a reason: To look awesome.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's stay focused on the four</utterance>
   <speaker>'D'S'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dangerous, Dangerous, Dangerous, Dunks. Remember: This isn't just a basketball team. It's a lifestyle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: A few workers are taking out the washing machine.</context>
      <utterance>Yo, Jackie, is the washing machine broken?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone complains. Boo etc. Jackie turns to BOBBY DEE a 'front office' guy.</context>
      <utterance>Listen up guys: I've got some good news and I've got some bad news. The good news is, we're getting rid of that piece of shit washing machine. The bad news is, everyone does their laundry at home from now on. Towels too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Bobby Dee, I need you to clean out your desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY DEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I have kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not fired. I sold your desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY DEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm going to shed a few lockers, so everyone's getting a locker buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarence reveals his 'panty dropper' a brown full-length leather coat.</context>
      <utterance>Forget that. I need my own locker... For the panty dropper.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Now, there's one last thing: I've added some depth to the roster. I think he could deliver some firepower.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Firepower? Who'd you hire?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a TOILET FLUSH. Monix exits the bathroom stall buttoning his pants.</context>
      <utterance>At guard, six one, the hometown kid, from your very own Flint Michigan -- He punches in bunches Ed MONIXXXXXXXX!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix doesn't receive a warm welcome. It's more of a stare- off.</context>
      <utterance>You're out of toilet paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, now, I know everyone in this room has probably been punched in the face by Monix at one time or another.  One of you may have even had your collar bone broken, twice. But that's in the past now and-</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY DEE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. </mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, Jackie, you're on in two.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks Bobby.  I love half time.  Anyways, welcome aboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>LEAVING</mode>
      <context>With that, Jackie leaves. Monix faces his team in silence.</context>
      <utterance>One last thing: If you see a possum try and kill it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. Who wants to be my locker buddy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ladies and Gentleman, this man is about to attempt the impossible. The $10,000 full court shot. So, tell me, what's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dukes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Dukes. You feeling it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah dude.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to spend all of your money on if you win? A shirt?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah man, a shirt. Ha! Whoooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the first time, Dukes looks kind of serious. He sizes up the distant hoop...</context>
      <utterance>Okay people, Dukes is excited. Let's get some clapping going as he prepares himself for the impossible.  This is drama, folks! C'mon now, let's hear it! The $10,000 shot people, let's hear it!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An uncoordinated baseball pass... Sailing off into the distance... And...</context>
      <utterance>He looks ready... And... Here he goes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he step on the line?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER PAT THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it was legal. He made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the Hell has $10,000? I sure he stepped on the line, you know what I'm saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER PAT THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's right. The crowd is too hyped for Jackie to explain that he's broke.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to this crowd. You can't screw a kid over like that. People will kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monix was an All-American at Michigan State, but then went on to a disappointing journeyman career in the NBA. But he did manage to sit on the bench with the world champion Boston Celtics years ago and won a ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. </mode>
      <context>Kyle listens to this and yells to the other room.</context>
      <utterance>I should hire his agent.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey honey, guess who got traded to Flint?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, who?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The word Monix stops her in her tracks.</context>
      <utterance>Monix.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monix?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can you believe it?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! He's already got an NBA ring, but he's still playing... In Flint.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn closes her book, fidgety...</context>
      <utterance>No, I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say he asked to be traded. Who the Hell leaves California to come here? I love this guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up Jackie?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your knees okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. Just icing them down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BALL GIRL MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Jackie!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well look at you! You look beautiful. What's different?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALL GIRL MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dyed my hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's not it... Did your tits get bigger?</utterance>
   <speaker>BALL GIRL MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't lie to me. Those things got bigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>BALL GIRL MAGGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they're the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie keeps walking, bumping into MS. QUINCY, Clarence's mother.</context>
      <utterance>Well, good job.</utterance>
   <speaker>MS. QUINCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gestures to a guy who's lip-locked with Jackie's wife. LUCY MOON unbuttons her fur coat.</context>
      <utterance>Yo Jackie. You know, that wife of yours has been making out with that Mark Spitz lookin' motherfucker all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. It's okay, Lucy and I've got an open relationship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MS. QUINCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that. But he's about to suck on her Damn tits, right here in front of all these people.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucy Moon ignores him, only making out harder.</context>
      <utterance>She's hot right? What can I say, we're freedom lovers.  Hey honey!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right on!  I'm not jealous. It's a sweet deal for both of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MS. QUINCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever slept with another woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No ball and chain here.</context>
      <utterance>I could. That's the beauty of it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>24.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can just go for it. You know, if I ever get invited to some cool orgy, it's definitely not a problem at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MS. QUINCY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever been to an orgy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pshh. Are you kidding? When haven't I been?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard Jackie is going to go to some owner's meeting. What do you think that's about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but it can't be good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIGGY MUNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, let's see that championship ring, Monix.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix takes the ring out. It hangs from his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you promised we could see the ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this piece. It says Celtics right there in diamonds.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you wear it on your finger?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NOW CLARENCE chimes in without looking over...</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I just like to wear it around my neck, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not everyone sits around dreaming of playing in the NBA, you know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe not. But you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIGGY MUNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's all you ever talk about.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not jealous, are you Clarence?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one calls me Clarence.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name's Downtown.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay Downtown. I'll make sure Downtown is only referred to as Downtown, okay Downtown?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't think I don't know what you're doing. You're doing that thing where you pretend to mean what you say, but you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarcasm.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. How'd you like that sarcasm smacked off your face?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring it, funky stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's sarcasm, man. He's doing it again!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix squares off with a smile that says 'hit me.' Clarence takes off his leather full length and folds it nicely.</context>
      <utterance>I got this, alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you like a knuckle sandwich?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knuckle sandwich? Who says that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONIX REARS HIS FIST BACK, about to release a strong Popeye</context>
      <utterance>I do motherfucker. I'm gonna pound you so hard, you're--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie fights his way through the crowd to the DJ booth.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the boogie?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PATROL.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SCREECH -- The music stops.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUSIC CUE: Jackie's song. Everyone goes crazy.</context>
      <utterance>The year was 1973. A young musician named Jackie Moon, finishes years of musical training, only to find he is a slave to the notes on the page. He knows it's time to break free. In a sudden fit of creative mastery, he grabs a pen and a napkin and writes a song that breaks all the rules. Ladies and gentleman... Let's get sweaty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby, who wants to; love me sexy. baby, are you ready to; lick me sexy. Take off your shoes and; suck me sexy. Baby, we're naked and we're; humping sexy--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GAYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad they traded for you, I got myself a cute one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, this is the Daiquiri room?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LUCY MOON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. </mode>
      <context>REVEAL: LUCY MOON, Jackie's wife, is on the couch. She's the hottest girl in the world.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think, Gayle? Does he like it with my boots on, or does he like my boots off?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He seems like a boots on kind of guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it looks like I'm ready. As soon as you slide these shorts off of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you Jackie's wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knows about the Daiquiri room.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a new tradition we're starting, when new players join.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. Well, I'm going to have to pass. I'm good, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, Lucy flicks on the stereo--</context>
      <utterance>Honey, you don't know what good is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(i.e. what's your name?)</context>
      <utterance>Listen um...</utterance>
   <speaker>GAYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is 'no strings attached.'</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gayle and Lucy perform a funky/seductive dance, moving closer and closer to Monix.</context>
      <utterance>You can call me Mrs. Moon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think this is going to happen, Mrs. Moon.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has to.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's bad luck if you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucy has sprayed some WHIP CREAM on her nipples.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'd hate to bring bad luck to Flint Michigan.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you lick these clean for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucy decides that now is a good time to aggressively KISS him. Monix pushes her away.</context>
      <utterance>I can't eat dairy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix walks down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Nice tits, Mrs. Moon. I gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the way out, Monix flicks her off.</context>
      <utterance>I see what this is: You want us to send Eric and Marcus up here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got traded.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Kyle has come out to say hi.</context>
      <utterance>--Yo, Monix, you're wasted! Ha!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sorry man--</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up! That of jump shot of yours ain't broke yet, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Ha.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great back door cut for the lay-up in the third. That's how basketball should be played.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kyle, can you give us a second? We need to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem. Great game tonight man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why does your boyfriend like me so much?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're his favorite player.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, there are still some things I think we need to talk about.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've already said everything I'm ever going to say to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Monix walks away... Then turns back.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess I'll be leaving then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really not going to stop me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix walks more, until Lynn speaks.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to end up walking with a cane the rest of your life. You have to quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... Kill yourself, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill myself?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You act like there's nothing else in the world besides basketball. If that's how you really feel, then go ahead and get it over with. I'm going to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the pep. talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lynn.  Can I ask you for one favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want a favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My knee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn stares at him in disbelief. Monix shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus Christ Monix. It's 4 a.m.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one here can drain it right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix nods, then makes a move toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You're not coming in. We'll do it in the yard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>into the rear view, very</utterance>
   <speaker>CIVILIZED)</speaker>
      <mode> CIVILIZED)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hello Commissioner -- Why sure, I would love one of your Puerto Rican cigars -- Oh, I know I'm a legitimate owner, you don't have to tell me that -- We're merging with the NBA? Oh, that's nice -- Ha Ha Ha! Good one, Commish ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Jackie turns inward, more quietly intense. This is, without question, the greatest moment of his life.</context>
      <utterance>Our league is sold. And the NBA agreed to all of our financial demands!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a real owner. You're in the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four of our teams will be absorbed into the NBA family, the rest of you will terminate operations.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly! You know it!  I'm sorry, wait, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Nuggets, The Nets, The Spurs and the Pacers will play in the NBA next year. The rest of us will dissolve.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The winning owners look at each other, not sure how to handle Jackie.</context>
      <utterance>Dissolve? Dissolve, like, how? How do I dissolve into the NBA?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie pounds the table.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Jackie. We all know how. emotional you get. We waited until the very last second to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kicks over his chair...</context>
      <utterance>No. NO! NO!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know you're upset, Jackie. But you'll be very well compensated.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOSING OWNER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone's agreed to a very large sum.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want a sum! I want my team!  C'mon you guys, you're not going to just sit here and take the money, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do the Spurs have that we don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A huge fan base. A brand new stadium. A solid economic growth package, including strong tax incentives.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, c'mon, that's BULLSHIT!</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie goes quiet, thinking... An epic idea hits him.</context>
      <utterance>The NBA is taking four teams, Jackie, there's nothing I can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The best four teams should go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget the huge fan base, the stadiums, the economic...  Growing... package... inventions...</utterance>
   <speaker>WINNING OWNER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Economic growth pack--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LOSING OWNER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOSING OWNER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's the fairest way.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These four teams DO have the best records. Flint's only won six games all year!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So far. The season isn't over.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOSING OWNER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, maybe we should finish the season first.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This plan sounds like a lot of fun, but it's too late. The commissioner, me, has already decided.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOSING OWNER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, the terms of a merger can only be approved by a league mandate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YES. That's right. What he said.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon you guys, let's try to stay psyched. This is a chance to become a real NBA franchise!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no way we can make it to fourth place. It's mathematically impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ran the numbers. All we have to do is win about eighty-two percent of our remaining games.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighty-two percent? Isn't that a lot?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, c'mon! We just gotta start hitting our threes.  Listen, I know this seems like bad news, but it doesn't have to be. This is a big road trip for us. We've just got to start playing solid Flint basketball.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. We suck, man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes turn on the grumpy one.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think, Monix?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we suck.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVEAL: A SHITTY SCHOOL BUS has the words 'THE JET!' Spray- painted in graffiti letters with a palm tree next to it.</context>
      <utterance>Well... See, now there's some team unity! Now let's load up the jet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we've got a special treat. You know I take care of my family. Today, the Jet is catered. I had Downtown's Mom pack us some hot dish.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ms. Quincy's hot dish? Sweet!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, watch the hot dish, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry Scootsie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIGGY MUNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>POV: Out the window, we can see DUKES, the full court shot winner, holding his GIANT CHECK and looking into the bus. He's still shirtless, with a star-spangled headband.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Jackie, there's some dude out there, wants to talk to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DUKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They said it's 'symbolic.'</context>
      <utterance>I tried Jackie. They won't take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does symbolic mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. But they said I need a real check.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what your bank is talking about. That is a real check. I signed it myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's written in glitter, dude. Can't you just give me, like, a regular sized one?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it. People are usually able to cash these. Maybe you should try another bank.  If you run into any more trouble, let me know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay Jackie, thanks man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie turns away from Dukes and exhales, walking back to the bus.</context>
      <utterance>Any time, congratulations.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Clarence, what's in this 'hot dish' anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Mom cooked your ass a whole Damn meal, why you gotta go asking what's in it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a compliment. It's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEE BEE and SCOOTSIE look over the seat, facing them.</context>
      <utterance>If it's good, then it's good. Why do you gotta know what's in it? What's in hot dish? Hot dish is in hot dish, asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Monix, what were the Celtics like?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fast? No one's faster than me. I should be on the Celtics.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fast up here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smartball. Why'd you get bounced?</context>
      <utterance>You're supposed to be Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you have to be able to jump too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, let us see that ring again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not right now, okay Twiggy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it a little embarrassing wearing that thing everyday?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Embarrassing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call yourself a Celtic? You sat through every single playoff game. You didn't see action once. And now you walk around wearing the ice like you're Bill Russel. Well you ain't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you're just jealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Monix played solid minutes, for lots of teams. He's played in the NBA, that's more than you can say.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That was a pretty heated exchange. Monix looks like he's got something to say, but he doesn't. Clarence has the last word.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever. At least I never sat on the bench and then called myself a champion. You didn't do shit for that Celtic team. If I was Dave Cowens, I'd yank that ring right off your neck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He didn't even play.</context>
      <utterance>He doesn't wear it on his finger because he knows he didn't earn it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>41.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monix looks out the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're just a few minutes away from game one of the Tropic's 6 game road trip. With talk of an NBA merger hitting the league, there's a new electricity surrounding tonight's game...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. Now, a lot of people out there are writing us off. A lot people are saying things like 'Jackie Moon is an offensive liability.' They're saying 'Flint's turnovers led to sixty fast break points per game.'  They're saying 'Bee Bee's retarded brother is so retarded that his eyes look too big,. Like a French Bulldog.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one said that, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes they did. And we're going to use it as motivation, okay? THIS IS</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OH, C'MON!? Where's the charge, Father Pat?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER PAT THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Both feet weren't planted.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FATHER PAT THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it, you're out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie takes a ball and drop kicks it, PUNTING IT high up into the rafters.</context>
      <utterance>What!? What did I say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't guarding my guy anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's too'Damn sweaty, man.  Look at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix notices this discussion.</context>
      <utterance>Gross. Well, I ain't guarding him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sweaty guy backs in on Clarence, posting up top.</context>
      <utterance>Quit talking and play defense!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix delivers a nice two handed bounce pass, but Clarence isn't ready for anything fundamentally sound -- The ball hits him in the nuts.</context>
      <utterance>Right on! I'm open baby! Try a behind-the-back!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Monix is startled. Clarence, his roommate for the night, enters.</context>
      <utterance>I brought us some ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ice? What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarence takes some ice, pops it in his mouth and starts crunching.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, it's free.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want some?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now BEE BEE enters, yet another player in the small room.</context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix ignores this. Laying back, he focuses on the TV: THE CELTICS are playing. Their trapping defense is a thing of beauty. Clarence walks over and flicks the channels, until he stops at 'Love American Style.'</context>
      <utterance>That Root Beer machine took my fucking change, man. White people are assholes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You turned off the Celtics?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, Clarence pulls out a JOINT and lights it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't watch people play basketball. They watch me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the Hell is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you shower in your room?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My wife is using it. I'll be crashing with you guys tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>NOTICING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ice? Awesome.  Love American Style? Turn it up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie, have you ever even slept with your wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>LYING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Are you kidding? Try, like, every weekend. She's so hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like a great arrangement.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys need to wake up. Quit living like it's the 1950's, man. Live it up.  Hey Clarence, let's have some of that smoke, bro.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pretty sure we have a game tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if this is really going to be my life, I might as well be stoned like everyone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix takes the stupid joint. The instant Monix inhales he</context>
      <utterance>Well said.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the Hell is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's harsh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take that back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take what back?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His Mom grows it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, in the yard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Mom grew this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's sweet grass.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm finished, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong, my Mom's weed ain't good enough for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess not.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon man, have some respect for his Mom's weed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it, I ain't sleeping in the same bed as this motherfucker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, just move all those people over to this side.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>DEMONSTRATING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, the TV cameras are going to face this way, right? Well, if we fill the seats on that side, we'll look sold out.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMIGO MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MEANWHILE, ON THE COURT: Both teams are warming up. Clarence now has a new name on his Jersey. There are so many words, there is barely space for a number. It's a mess.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, that's not a bad idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check it out. I sewed it on the bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it say?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The asshole, PETRELLI, wanders over near the Tropics side of the court.</context>
      <utterance>Jumping Johnny Johnson.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETRELLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, Granny Yarn Barn, how's the needle point going?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kiss my ass, Petrelli.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETRELLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey man, I think you spelled 'Flint sucks balls' wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETRELLI</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>The guys laugh. MONIX walks up, defending his teammate.</context>
      <utterance>This guy's the next Betsy Ross! Aren't you Clarence?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one calls him Clarence. His name</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jumping Johnny Johnson.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie hurries over.</context>
      <utterance>His name's Jumping Johnny Johnson.  You got that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OVER HERE. Where is he walking to?</context>
      <utterance>Alright, break it up.  Everyone huddle up!... VAKIDIS!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck it. Listen up, we're on National TV tonight. And you all know what that means: The league needs a good clean game.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's a bunch of dog shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! You guys want to merge or not? Because the fastest way to screw this up is to start punching people in the face while the commissioner is at home, watching the game with his kids... Children are very impressionable. Their minds are not yet soiled by the cruel realities of this world.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind the huddle, FANS BEGIN WALKING RIGHT ACROSS THE COURT. Both teams turn to watch this strange thing. The Amigos manager leads the herd, Jackie helps out, directing them across to the other side.</context>
      <utterance>No punching.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Monix drains a nice jumper, but out of nowhere, Petrelli, the guy we hate, throws a hard shoulder, knocking Monix to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>This sold out crowd is loving this one, the Amigos up by twenty-six here in the second.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>C'mon!</context>
      <utterance>That's a moving pick Father Pat!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER PAT THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix can't believe it. Petrelli taunts Monix.</context>
      <utterance>Play on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETRELLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix faces off.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong Monix, cat got your 'nads?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about commercials?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie thinks about this, then nods 'good idea.'</context>
      <utterance>Commercials, what about commercials?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it. Time out Ref!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. </mode>
      <context>The camera's on air' red light turns off.</context>
      <utterance>A time out on the floor, 5:20 left before the half, the Amigos 45, the Tropics 19, we'll be right back after this message from Shasta.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAMERA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And... You're clear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Players hold their heads in pain. Others limp back to the bench.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome back to the ABA game of the week...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Off camera, Monix delivers a secret punch to Patrelli's spleen.</context>
      <utterance>.The camaraderie and spirit of this league is on full display here tonight...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--This is bullshit guys. They're kicking our ass in basketball and they're kicking our ass during the commercials, too. Does anybody here understand the concept of the pick and roll? Because they're going to keep double teaming at the top of the key until somebody rotates the Damn ball...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix looks at this group and gets even madder.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! C'mon guys! Rotate the ball.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Twiggy Munson and Scootsie Double-Day hang their heads.</context>
      <utterance>Does anyone in this room have any pride? Don't you realize, this is thelast four weeks of basketball anyus are ever going to play?Is thishow we're really going togo out?You'd think we'd want toend ourcareers battling, hustling after every loose ball. Boxing out under the boards. Setting picks for our teammates. But we haven't done shit out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix paces in front of the guys, a man possessed.</context>
      <utterance>We're a bunch of selfish assholes -- And I've got news for you, we aren't going to finish in fourth, we're going to finish dead last.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix is staring right at Clarence. And Clarence is actually listening...</context>
      <utterance>One day, you're going to look back on your life... And you're going to look back on this time... And you're going to realize...</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment of silence after the intensity. Monix waddles to the door.</context>
      <utterance>.You're going to realize you never even played basketball.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix limps off, everyone's head is hanging low.</context>
      <utterance>Now, you guys have fun out there in the second half. If anyone needs me, I'll be in the training room, draining my knee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dukes! I don't make the rules. If they can't cash it, maybe you'll have to go out of state.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would if I could, but if I give you another check, that would be two checks. That would be $20,000, not ten. What are you trying to pull here?  I've got to take this other call Dukes. Bye!--  Flint Tropics hot line... Oh hey Commish ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do we have to put the court together?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess the Ice Capades sold out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, kids love that stuff. Although, I find the wild-life masks realistic and frightening.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monix should be here helping us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. </mode>
      <context>The guys look up to find Jackie. He does not look happy.</context>
      <utterance>Guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The commissioner just called.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I looks like we've got ourselves a situation. We've got some new 'terms and conditions' for this merger deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Basically, we've got to average at least 2,000 fans per home game for the rest of the year.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIGGY MUNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>2,000 people? Every home game?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said the NBA will only take a franchise that has fans.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. Winning is going to be hard. But getting 2,000 people to watch is going to be impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's try and stay positive. My Mother always believed Flint was a town of destiny. And I believe that. Now, I've already started work on a huge idea to promote us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of huge idea?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two more Johnny Walkers. And another pack of Kools.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could use some fresh air, Monix. You want to take a nap in the back of my truck?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode>ANGRY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just the drinks and the smokes, alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She asked me to tell you to quit going to her house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, tell her that's just fine with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Sorry man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. </mode>
      <context>REVEAL: Clarence.</context>
      <utterance>Monix.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, well, well, look who it is.  Brian, I'd like you to meet Jumping Johnny Downtown Funky stuff Boner- time finger-blast Fag-erton.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny for short.  Two coffees.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what brings you to the The Kremlin?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I know you and I haven't always been the best of buddies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>57.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I've been thinking about what you said the other night. This is gonna be our last chance. If I'm ever going to get into the NBA, it's going to be with the Tropics.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate to break it to you, Clarence, but the Tropics will never play in the NBA.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So maybe we won't. But like you said, I don't want to look back on this with any regrets. I know what you think of me. But I'm willing to put our differences aside. I'm telling you right now, I'll do whatever it takes to win.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean, like, pass?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would consider passing, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry kid. Even if I wanted to play harder, this knee won't let me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix could not be less interested.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not just talking about you playing point guard... I'm talking about you teaching us...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix drinks, not into it...</context>
      <utterance>Monix, you know more about basketball than any man who's ever set foot in Flint.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I'm saying is, instead of getting so pissed off at us all the time, why not just show us what the Hell you're talking about? Coach us a little. I mean, we can't get any worse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why should I give a shit about the Tropics?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you. You've got all that basketball shit stored up in your head. I know you're dying to pass it down to somebody. Why not us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Jackie? He's the coach.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(looking up, re: TV)</context>
      <utterance>Jackie's got his hands full, trying to sell tickets. He's obsessed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALL THE TROPICS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>This is the worst video ever made. All the guys boogie around until Clarence steps forward, taking focus...</context>
      <utterance>We are the Tropics hooping crew, running and gunning and dunking on you -- But we're not here to talk no trash, we're just here to do the Tropical Mash --</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Johnny Johnson and I got the moves -- If you try and stop me, I'll just get smooth --</utterance>
   <speaker>KONG</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Kong and I ain't five feet -- But I get more ass than a toilet seat --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my team, so get to know them -- If you get near the lane I'll yank your scrotum --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALL THE TROPICS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. </mode>
      <context>The ball girls trot out and boogie with them.</context>
      <utterance>-- We are the Tropics hooping crew, running and gunning and dunking too -- We're not here to talk no trash, we're just here to do the Tropical Mash --</utterance>
   <speaker>BALL GIRLS</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- They're not here to talk no trash -- they're just here to do the Tropical Mash --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two more Johnny Walkers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix doesn't answer, he just drinks. Clarence gets the hint and walks out.</context>
      <utterance>So that's the way it's going to be?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking good Monix.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. You too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ms. Quincy told me the Tropics asked you to coach them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ECU: A SHARP NEEDLE PIERCES FLESH.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lynn is draining Monix's knee. It looks painful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what it takes to be a real team, Lynn.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay still.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's the reason you won't coach them?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter. The truth is, I hate basketball right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you really hate basketball? Or do you hate yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would I hate myself?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, for one, you cheated on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn just stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>You hate me for that. Not me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, maybe I hate myself a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't wear the ring around your neck anymore.  Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I rode the bench through the playoffs, Lynn.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monix, that was greatest moment of your career. And you look back on it like some kind of embarrassment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Riding the bench was the greatest moment of my career?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did more than ride the bench, Monix.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else did I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynn continues the business of disposing fluid into the toilet and preparing another syringe.</context>
      <utterance>Every practice, you took your team to the limit. I know you did. I was the one draining this stupid knee of yours every night. The Celtics were practicing against you, Monix. And when you ran that scout team, you were running Milwaukee's offense better than their first stringers ever could.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By game time, your team knew where Milwaukee was going to be before their own players did. The Celtics made the right adjustments to win that series. And those adjustments came from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, I should be proud of running the scout team?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dave Cowens put that ring in the palm of your hand. And he told you to wear it with pride, because you were a champion. And he meant it too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was being a nice guy. The bench is the bench.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your whole life, you've bitched about people playing selfish. It takes a team to win, right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But when you're on the team, your effort doesn't count? Is that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you weren't on the Celtics that year, would they have won it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch that needle.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answer me. Would they have won?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix looks away for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Yes you do. You know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing this? What does any of this matter, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it matter? You're drinking yourself to death!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Lynn throws the needle. Monix dodges it.</context>
      <utterance>God, I wish I hated you as much as you hate yourself!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're a champion, you asshole!</context>
      <utterance>I made sacrifices! How many years did I support you? And finally, after all of our blood and sweat and bullshit together, you got there, Monix! You made it, you won an NBA championship ring. It wasn't just about you, okay? And I'm sick of you acting like you're some kind of joke. You didn't blow it. You're not a fraud. You're not a fake champion. And all the time we spent together, fighting for you to get to that moment, was not a waste!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>CHOREOGRAPHING</mode>
      <context>One by one, each dips down like a waterfall. And now a leg kick.</context>
      <utterance>1 and 2 and 3 and 4 and turn like you mean it -- Bee Bee, Arch that back. Yes. Now, the waterfall...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice leg kick Kong. Those flexible hips are a coach's dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now big finish -- and freeze. And then we start the game after that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we going to practice or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins pacing around, more passionate than ever...</context>
      <utterance>This is practice, okay Clarence? We need to get two thousand people in here! Our intro dance has to blow people's minds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The team seems to be looking off screen.</context>
      <utterance>From now on, I want our afros bigger... And shinier ... . I want our shorts shorter... And tighter... We're going to pull our tube socks up higher than we ever have before.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you're back! Listen, you should probably chalk your hands up for this number.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie, I asked Monix to coach us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie is totally thrown by this. He looks around at the team. Clearly, a decision has been made.</context>
      <utterance>Coach?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, coach?  What is this? What's going on?  It's a Mutiny.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie. Don't be like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on a second. Last time I checked, we didn't live in Flint, Russia. We live in Flint, America. I'm coach until a new one is elected.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone feels bad, but they all raise their hands.</context>
      <utterance>Don't make us elect Monix, man.  Alright, show of hands. Who wants Monix to step in as player-coach?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please God No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIGGY MUNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry Jackie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cool. I get it. I'm a big boy, I can handle it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>65.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie cries harder.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't take it so hard, Jackie. You're a great owner. We all know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woah. Hold on. Did you just say 'great owner?'</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Everyone thinks so.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, when you said great owner, were you just saying that? Because it's not cool to mess with me about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie is emotional. It's a bittersweet moment. He takes off his whistle, then walks over and hands Monix his whistle.</context>
      <utterance>We mean it. For real. Monix is just more of an X's and O's kind of guy, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now he pulls out a bunch of crazy notes on loose paper written in ball point pen. The pages look insane.</context>
      <utterance>Here. You may need this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And here are some ideas for plays I've jotted down. Just thoughts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks Jackie.  The way I see it, any team in this league can put together a run. Most of our opponents are all flash. If we play unselfish, fundamental basketball, we can win games.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it. Unselfish, guys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Unselfish. Unselfish meaning tough team defense, full and half court traps, boxing your man out to help the team rebound.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unselfish means sprinting up the floor on every fast break NOT because you can get a DUNK -- and get your DICK SUCKED after the game -- but because if you sprint up the floor you might pull the defense out of position and free a teammate up for a high percentage shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, so, what's going on with the blow jobs?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I vote we keep the blow jobs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone raises their hands in favor of blow jobs.</context>
      <utterance>All in favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would everyone let the man talk please? Clarence is serious. This shuts everyone up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix FLIPS OPEN A SWITCH BLADE KNIFE AND STABS THE BALL, deflating it. This gets everyone's attention.</context>
      <utterance>The most important work we do on the court is away from the basketball.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until you start moving like a real team, you practice without a ball.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, Clarence, run the offense.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarence jogs over and stands next a scout team opponent.</context>
      <utterance>Set a pick for somebody.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix corrects Clarence, moving his body the way he wants him to stand.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, that's kind of a pick, I guess. Try standing on the other side of Scootsie's man, so you free him up to cut into the lane.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scootsie cuts across the lane. The team slowly gets i rotating faster.</context>
      <utterance>Widen your stance. Plant your feet. Hands back. Like this. Now Scootsie GO. Set a pick for Jackie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've completed the play. Monix stands there, smiling. The players look at each other, what's the big deal?</context>
      <utterance>Now Jackie pick Bee Bee's man, and rotate to the rim like this... Everyone move to the open space. And Clarence you swing back out up top.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what that was?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A flash to the high side post with an outside screen and a back door cut. Let's do it again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, how come you don't have to run with us? You're a player, just like the rest of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarence sets a screen for Scootsie and they perform the same basic rotation.</context>
      <utterance>I'm saving my knee for the games. Coach's decision. NOW RUN.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not just rotating, we're clearing out, making space. A pass and cut can change defensive match- ups. Creating seams can give us back door looks. Down screens can make a team vulnerable to penetration.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on. I'm lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit. What's up with all of these fucked up words, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIGGY MUNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, what are we, building some kind of basketball space. ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to understand it yet. Just run it again. You heard me -- AGAIN.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, maybe we could try, like, play number two.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. We're running this play. We're running this play until we puke.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Basically, we have.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm pretty beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Until we puke' is not a figure of speech. We are literally going to puke.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does he mean by 'literally?'</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he's talking about vomit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monix, can I talk to you for .a second?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarence tries to gag himself with his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to be brain dead. Because someday you're going to be too tired, or too nervous to think - - AGAIN! And when you are, this is the play I'm going to call. The play that your lungs and legs will have memorized. We will be able to run this in our sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>HEY! No sticking your fingers down your throat, Clarence, I saw that. You're going to puke. And it's going to be all natural -- AGAIN!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're fired!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get up and run. You're going to puke like everybody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monix, I need to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll. talk after you puke. GO!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>71.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie can't get up, but he crawls, dying...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't puke Monix!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie crawls harder along the hardwood.</context>
      <utterance>Yes you can. Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monix! You don't understand. I've never thrown up in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never puked. Ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That makes no sense. Everyone has thrown up before.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't. I swear to God. I can eat anything. I can drink anything. I've been sick, but I've never puked. I swear to God.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's bullshit. Keep moving, you're going to puke.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this point, Monix can't help but be intrigued.</context>
      <utterance>I don't puke. I can't do it! It's the truth! I swear on my Mother's grave.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Babies throw up all the time.</context>
      <utterance>What about when you were a baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She said I was fascinating.</context>
      <utterance>My Mom said I never did. I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Jackie looks up at Monix, it's clear he is not lying.</context>
      <utterance>You can call my Dad! I've never puked.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that kind of dangerous?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens if you swallow poison?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I ate bad sausage before. But nothing happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie manages to stand up.</context>
      <utterance>Stand up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever been punched in the Jejunum?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. What's a Jejunum?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's part of your small intestine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I doubt--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHRUB. JACKIE WAILS IN DESPAIR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MONIX stands in the doorway, watching this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie is about to speak, but then takes stock of his feelings. There is now an air of tranquility about him. Reborn. He's almost Euphoric...</context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm beautiful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Instead of celebrating, Clarence hustles back on Defense. The Tropics execute a half court trap. As we watch Monix play, we continue to the voice over from practice...</context>
      <utterance>. If a guy's more open than you are, he gets the ball...</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>On the in bounds, Monix and Jackie Moon trap an opponent. Monix slaps the ball free. He flips to Clarence who fakes; the fast break dunk and dishes to Scootsie.</context>
      <utterance>.On defense, we're going to learn to play together. We're going to use team traps to pressure people into turnovers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you believe that? Jumping Johnny Johnson actually passed the ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>The other team calls time out.</context>
      <utterance>It was a great pass, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Jackie Moon has made several great defensive plays down the stretch. I tell you, Jackie's not afraid to knock people around in the lane. He's a monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>A twenty-second time out on the floor, Monix huddles them up.</context>
      <utterance>Like a retard in a China shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen up. I'll in-bound. Clarence, protect the ball and penetrate if you can. Kick it out to Scootsie or me and everyone crash the boards hard. Looking good, we're thirty seconds away from taking this one home. Let's bring it in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right guys. But remember, we want to win, but not by too much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TWIGGY MUNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't want to win by too much?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the Hell is he talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's worried about the corn dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are signs everywhere.</context>
      <utterance>If we score a hundred points, everyone gets a free corn dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Monix, but we don't even have corn dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't give a shit. We're taking it to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're up by seven, Monix. Can't we just take it easy? We're talking about a lot of corn dogs here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There could be a riot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone nods. WHISTLE!</context>
      <utterance>I don't give a shit about the corn dogs, okay? We play hard every second. We're running the offense. Everyone got that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Monix has the ball in his hands. He in bounds to Clarence. Clarence penetrates and kicks it to Scootsie. Scootsie has an open look. He sizes up a jumper...</context>
      <utterance>The Tropics are just one bucket away from the magic number. Listen to this crowd. They know what's at stake: A free corn dog.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooh. He gets taken out hard by the coach.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>The ball bounces into the air, rolls around the rim... And</context>
      <utterance>Nice!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>77.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was the first time in my life. And, well, it's made me feel... I guess you could say I've got a new clarity in life.  Since vomiting on Wednesday, I've been facing my demons. I'm not going to be an imposter any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>77.</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I want you to know, I just mailed out 562 corn dog coupons.</utterance>
   <speaker>77.</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Dukes walks in. He is still shirtless. Jackie hands him a duffel bag.</context>
      <utterance>And I'd like to bring somebody special in... DUKES!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In this bag, is ten thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, it's twenty three hundred. But I'm going to pay you the rest. The Tropics will not let you down. From now on, I want my conscience clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Thanks Jackie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I confess something to everyone? It's something I've never told anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know my song 'Love Me Sexy?'</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone knows that song.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stole it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIGGY MUNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even Monix is fascinated by this.</context>
      <utterance>It's true.  My Mom wrote it. Three weeks before she died. And I stole it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, your Mom wrote that? Was she a singer?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, she wrote it on a napkin. I duped the whole world. I'm nothing but a fraud.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's true, I'm a famous singer. And I've landed the hottest wife in the world. But, to be honest, we usually only sleep together once a year. On VJ day.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn. VJ day? That's cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And even on that day, I don't feel like it's me who's sleeping with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She married me because of my song, but I didn't write it. So sometimes I feel like it's not even me who's with her.  Deep down, I feel like it's really my Mom who is making love to her. When I hold Lucy's supple breasts in my hands, they are my Mom's hands. When I eat a pair of edible panties off of her, they are my Mom's teeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's pretty weird.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm living in a prison, Dukes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you write a song yourself? Then you wouldn't feel like a fake any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUSIC CUE: HOT CHOCOLATE 'EVERY 1's A WINNER.' MEGA-MONTAGE: THE TROPICAL FEVER SEQUENCE. (Note: The music fades in and out throughout as needed). -PRE GAME: The Tropics do their 'intro dance.' They perform the waterfall down into.a cool pose. The crowd loves it. -TROPIC HIGHLIGHTS: They run a fast break weave, Monix makes the layup. Clarence penetrates and dishes to Jackie for a pull up jumper. -THE TROPICAL AISLE: Fat people in Hawaiian shirts go crazy. A lady chucks her nachos at the other team. -RESULTS: The scoreboard shows a Tropics win. -ATTENDANCE: A clicker counts up to 182 fans. -MORE INTRO EXCITEMENT: Jackie introduces his starting five.</context>
      <utterance>Oh please! I could never write anything as brilliant as 'Love Me Sexy!'  Listen to me, Tropics. Today is a new day. I am going to be the greatest basketball owner you've ever seen. And we're going to make it to fourth place.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarence jogs out with Coffee Black sewn into his jersey...</context>
      <utterance>And at guard, six foot two. Formerly known as Clarence Withers, and Sugar Dunkerton, and Downtown Funky Stuff Malone, and Jumping Johnny Johnson -- He's launching his new name tonight -- Put your hands together for: COFFEE BLACK.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OPPOSING PLAYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, are you okay little girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHEELCHAIR JODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-RESULTS: Three successive winning scores are flashed in a row. A newspaper shows the Tropics moving up further in the standings. -CLARENCE'S MOM: Quincy is throwing. a party for the team at their BBQ place. She dances happy. -NEW PROMO PHOTOS: QUICK CUTS of the team's new glossy calendar: Mr. January: Jackie wears only a tool belt. February: Clarence lies on a lamb wool rug. March: Bee Bee Ellis, by a waterfall, wears a cardigan. April: Monix, annoyed, holds a rose in his teeth. -ATTENDANCE: A clicker counts up to 711. -MONIX THE MASTERMIND: In the meeting room, Monix and the team study film. Monix draws up a defensive scheme on the board. On the court, he gives Clarence an advanced lesson.</context>
      <utterance>Eat my crippled ass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLINT RALLIES AROUND THEIR TEAM: The guys in Hawaiin shirts are out flyering.</context>
      <utterance>Rotate further out from the key, so when you get the ball you can face the basket. You've actually got some moves, so you can penetrate...</utterance>
   <speaker>TROPICAL AISLE GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come see the Tropics tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>TROPICAL AISLE GUY #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-MONIX THE PLAYER: Despite his knees and back killing him, Monix plays like a champion. He's still got some jump left too. He knows this is his last run, there's nothing left to save it for. -TRAINING ROOM: Clarence drains Monix's knee. -JACKIE THE PROMOTER: Jackie's wife, Lucy Moon, rides a mechanical bull topless. The crowd goes nuts.</context>
      <utterance>See the biggest half time stunt ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-ATTENDANCE: A clicker counts up to 890. -TROPIC HIGHLIGHTS: Scootsie Double Day Scores. Twiggy Munson Scores. Bee Bee Ellis scores. Jackie Moon hits a ill advised three pointer. Monix rejoices, he's actually having fun.</context>
      <utterance>Good job honey! Looking good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>-FLINT RALLIES AROUND THE TROPICS: People are buying Tropic's jerseys. -RESULTS: The standings show the Tropics all the way up to sixth place. -FLINT RALLIES AROUND THEIR TEAM: The ball girls are doing a kick line, wearing cute cheerleader skirts. Clarence watches from the bench.</context>
      <utterance>.Jackie Moon with a three. He's the fourth player in double figures. They're really sharing the ball tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold up. Are these girls wearing underwear?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's true, the ball girls are flashing the crowd with every kick.</context>
      <utterance>Which girls?  Oh. It doesn't look like it. Wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode>MESMERIZED</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice work, Jackie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Melinda winks at Jackie, as her skirt flips up. The crowd is going goes crazy. -ATTENDANCE: The clicker raises to 906. -MORE PRACTICE: Clarence slams a dunk and does a jig.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't do it. They did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clarence, do me a favor, if you dunk the ball, don't dance afterwords. Act like you've been there before.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, Monix, I need him to dance. A lot. The fans need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's either that, or we play with a monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, you can dance a little bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-GAME TIME. CLARENCE DUNKS THE BALL: He immediately launches into a preposterous celebration: Back flip, 360 spin down to the splits, back up, he and Jackie give each other ten and then do an extended hand jive routine. Now Jackie blows Clarence a kiss, which 'knocks him out flat.' Clarence then poses, elbow on the floor, hand under his head, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>If you dunk it, go fuckin' ape shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>83.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-JACKIE THE PROMOTER: Halftime, at center court, a ramp is set up. Behind the ramp, all the ball girls lay head-to-toe.</context>
      <utterance>JACKIE'S WIFE: LUCY MOON sleeps with LOU REDWOOD.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY DEE</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Jackie comes ROLLER-SKATING at high speed. He hits the jump -- It's going to be close --</context>
      <utterance>These beautiful girls reach a combined total of 47 feet... And here he comes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OW.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, keep doing'it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBBY DEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure boss?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the COMMISH (the league official) steps over.</context>
      <utterance>Just keep taping it up. I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Jackie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(a little worried)</context>
      <utterance>Oh, hey Commish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>84.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know you were in town this weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, my office has been getting your numbers. You claim you've had over two thousand people at every home game this month.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The commissioner looks around, skeptical. As we scan the stands, it's clear the crowd is still not big enough.</context>
      <utterance>That's correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we've counted only nine hundred and eighty three here tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you don't think people go to the bathroom?  Saturdays can be a little slow. You should have been here the other night, it was SO PACKED.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The commish waves over a little bald man in a suit. PEEKSKILL carries a brief case and never talks.</context>
      <utterance>Don't bullshit me, Jackie.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From now on, Peekskill here will be attending every Tropics home game. You're going to have to get a real crowd here if you want to qualify for the merger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow, at half time, I, Jackie Moon, will wrestle a bear.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, well there's something. But, defensively, as a team, do you</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--That's tomorrow! One night only! See Dewie the wrestling bear attack me. He's killed people in public before.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, well, that's some half time show.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix doesn't speak... He stares into her eyes for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if it isn't the toast of Flint Michigan. Shouldn't you be out signing autographs?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you marry me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Technically, we're still married right now, Monix.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you love me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then let's do it. For real this time. I need you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The question is, do I need you?</context>
      <utterance>Shit. I know you need me, Monix.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's loyal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dogs are loyal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monix?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Still undetected, Kyle settles in to watch the show, still wearing his Monix jersey. Lynn finally looks over and spots Kyle. We can't be sure, but his hand might be in his pants. Lynn can't believe her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix finally notices his sex partner is having a conversation. He turns to see Kyle.</context>
      <utterance>Ixne-on-the-erking off-je.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woah. What the fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monix, you of dog!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the Hell are you doing!?</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm the victim here. I'm allowed to do as I please. This was an honor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix stands up, wrapping a sheet around him.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's all cool.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, c'mon man. Don't be like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix grabs his shit and walks out of the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Believe me, this is not all cool.'</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not you, asshole. He was talking to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OFFICER MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey is that Coffee Black? I'm officer Miller, State Correctional, I'm a big fan, you can call me Jimmy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie Moon ordered up a bus full of prisoners. Any idea where we all should sit?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We sold out, man. You did good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm scared of bears, Clarence.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate these things. I'm freaking out right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're scared of bears, why the Hell are you wrestling one then?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It was a good idea.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this place. We're packed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, don't worry, you'll pin him easy. It'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie is seriously petrified. Clarence adjusts the collar of his ref jersey and looks around, worried about his friend.</context>
      <utterance>You don't understand. I don't like bears. I'm feeling dizzy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should call it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NO. Look into my eyes.  You're the ref tonight. No matter what happens in there, do not stop the fight, okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>91</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These people came to see a show. I've got to make it through at least one round.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, until you finish the first round, I won't call it. Hey, how bad can three minutes be, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAR HANDLER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The bear handler is a large frizzy haired woman.</context>
      <utterance>Are you guys ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, are we ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, let's do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAR HANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys want to give me a safe word?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a safe word?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAR HANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a word for you to yell to the Ref, so he can stop the match.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need a safe word.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAR HANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what, if you get injured or you really feel like you're in danger, yell, um, I don't know... Spumoni. Once I get a signal from the ref, I'll come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's Spumoni?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's an Italian Gelato, sort of like Almond flavored ice cream.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it good?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I've never had it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BEAR HANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really good.  Okay, so Spumoni is the safe word then?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DING DING DING! The bell has rung. The crowd goes crazy. Clarence assumes his position as ref. Jackie walks slowly toward the bear, frightened. They bear scratches his belly, cute. Jackie immediately quits.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't need a safe word, okay? Let's just do this. One round.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, fuck this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? You can't quit already.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SPUMONI. I'm out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't SPUMONI, all he did was scratch his nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PEOPLE START TO BOO. Jackie looks around at the angry crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Well, too bad, I'm SPUMONI-ING.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's true, the bear is pretty docile. The bear's indifference gives Jackie a glimmer of confidence.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta give 'em a show. C'mon, the bear seems pretty tired, look at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie nods, then hops around with his dukes in the air. Now he does a shuffle for the crowd. After dancing a bit, the bear is still motionless.</context>
      <utterance>Just test him out a little. Maybe it won't be so bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARENCE THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAR HANDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woah-ho. I've never seen that before.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taking it strong to the rim is Coffee Black. Yes! This sold out crowd is going nuts. You've been a little quiet Lou, how are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Mexican stole my bike.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>As Jackie does a victory dance, the commissioner approaches.</context>
      <utterance>And, believe it or not, the Flint Tropics are in perfect position to qualify for the NBA merger. If they win their final game, they'll clinch fourth place. But nothing is ever easy against the first place San Antonio Spurs.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hey Commish. Good game huh? And a packed house too.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to talk to you... And the rest of your team. Alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but even if you beat the Spurs on Friday, we just can't have an NBA franchise in Flint.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just not good business. Flint isn't a big enough media market, okay? This stadium is small and, frankly, it needs to be torn down before someone gets hurt. I'm sorry but nobody ever thought you guys could ever get this far.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well tough shit. This team did make it this far. Rules are rules.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks at each other. Jackie's brain has slipped into a deep trance. He is no longer inside his body.</context>
      <utterance>Rules are rules... Until the expansion committee makes new rules. Then those rules are the rules.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The devastation of what is happening is palpable. Nothing has ever hurt this bad before.</context>
      <utterance>Don't take this personally, Jackie. These other teams have strong markets, new stadiums. It's just not going to happen for you Flint boys. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The commissioner stands brave, eyes closed, chin out. Jackie is too confused and devastated to hit anything. He stumbles out of the room like a zombie. The team follows. The commissioner opens his eyes. A long silent beat...</context>
      <utterance>I know you're going to punch me, Jackie. So let's just get it over with.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly KONG darts in and squeezes the commissioner's balls with a kung fu grip.</context>
      <utterance>How did I get out of that one?</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TWIGGY MUNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This can't be happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They can't just do this, can they?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix just looks to the ground, as in 'it's over.'</context>
      <utterance>We can get a lawyer, dude. We can fight this!... Can't we?... Monix?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie opens his mouth... He tries to speak, but he can't.</context>
      <utterance>Jackie... Please... Say something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you crying?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Monix is leaving. He turns and walks off, alone down the dark street... The others walk away too...</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.  I'm trying to.  I wish I could just puke this away.  Do it to my Jejunum, Monix. Help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! Monix! Where is everyone going?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>-BEE BEE ELLIS stands in the middle of the Tropics court, upset. -JACKIE walks, sad, along the streets of Flint -- Now he suddenly picks up a pipe and SMASHES THE WINDSHEILD of an innocent truck. He turns and TACKLES A GARBAGE CAN.</context>
      <utterance>In an American Basketball Association policy shift, it seems the Flint Tropics will not be playing for an NBA birth after all...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>-SCOOTSIE DOUBLE DAY finishes spray-painting the words 'BULLSHIT' on a wall. REVEAL: He is in his own child's nursery room. The baby starts crying. -The TROPICAL AISLE guys are fat and shirtless, burning their Hawaiian shirts outside the stadium.</context>
      <utterance>Friday's match-up against the first- place San Antonio Spurs will be the Tropics final basketball game...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if that news wasn't bad enough for the Tropics, we've just been informed that Coffee Black, the team's top scorer, has been traded to the Spurs.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least someone from Flint is on his way to the NBA next year.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought I might find you here.  I got traded.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess the San Antonio Spurs are picking up the players they want, before we're eligible for the expansion draft.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee Black, going to the NBA...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They won't let me finish out with the Tropics. So, we'll be playing against each other in the last game. That's pretty weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't be weird. The game doesn't count.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen I'm sorry about--</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, I just want to say that, this year, you really--</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarence stares at him. Then eventually stands up to leave. There are a million things he wants to say, but he says this:</context>
      <utterance>--DON'T. Alright? Just don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We worked so hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it was all for nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, that's just it then?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Hey Lynn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought the deal was, you were going to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pshh. Relax.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you're just going to sit here in my house and drink for the entire day?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a problem with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I do. Maybe you could put some pants on and go piss off somebody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, maybe I will!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode>STANDING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are my pants?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me something, Monix-</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix doesn't say anything.</context>
      <utterance>Whatwereyou trying to accomplish thisyear?You never really gave a shitaboutthat NBA merger, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix still stays quiet.</context>
      <utterance>The merger, Monix, did you ever care about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, if you didn't care about the merger, what the Hell were you playing for!?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted fourth place! Okay? That was the whole fucking thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix doesn't look at her.</context>
      <utterance>Well, guess what! Fourth place is still sitting there, waiting for you to win it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a big faker and I stole this; Song-ly sexy. I'm the biggest failure in the; world-ly sexy. I'm going to kill my; self-y sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Bee Bee Ellis hears Jackie voice and discovers him in laying the garbage. Jackie ignores his teammate.</context>
      <utterance>Jackie?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to hang myself with an extension; cord-y sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie! What the Hell are you doing in a dumpster?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am urinating in my pants right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix called a team meeting.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta get it together, man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen up. We all know that Clarence has been traded. And we all know that this game doesn't matter anymore, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guys nod, solemn.</context>
      <utterance>Well I've got news for you. This game does matter. It matters because this is the last real basketball game any of us is ever going to play. Ever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie is moved. The guys look at each other and nod.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow night, I say we leave it all out there on the floor. Because there's nothing else for us to save it for. Clarence or no Clarence. NBA or no NBA. Merger or no merger. We decided we are going to win fourth place. And that's what we're going to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over the past five weeks, we've become a team. And that is no small thing. Jackie, have you ever been on a real team before?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does it feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It feels pretty good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All your lives, you've dreamed of playing in the NBA. Well, guess what? Tomorrow night, you are. You're playing an NBA team. And for one night, the world is going to know that you belong.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>Monix turns inward, speaking with an emotion that is pure.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I tried to pretend like it didn't matter to me if we made it to fourth or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the truth is, I want this more than anything I've ever wanted in my whole fucked-up life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I think you do too. I think you can taste it. Because we earned this. We made this happen. And we're four quarters away from making our dreams come true.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Spurs may be the 1 team in the league, but they're going to have to prove it on Friday night.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since this game doesn't count, Jackie. What exactly is your motivation?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie and the announcer look at each other for a long moment of silence...</context>
      <utterance>We.'re going to win this game, because we want it. It's as simple as that. That alone should make people want to show up and root for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plus, this is the FLINT MICHIGAN</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TV ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Save your ticket stubs, the mega- bowl is an historic event.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a Mega-Bowl. What's not to understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This game has no effect on--</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--The Mega Bowl trophy is twelve feet high. AND IT IS GLORIOUS.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but this sounds like something you just made up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're just words.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it doesn't make any sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(directly at camera)</context>
      <utterance>Oh please. You're just words.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>if the commissioner is listening, I recommend he stay out of the city of Flint tonight. He's not too popular in this town.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>i will stab him in the stomach with an eight inch hunting knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There were many wild protests in Flint this week. But it seems like the whole city is now focused on beating the San Antonio Spurs. This team seems to have captured every heart in this town of underdogs. People have poured in from around the state to support this drive toward their first mega-bowl championship.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Now Petrelli enters frame. The guy we hate has been traded to the Spurs too.</context>
      <utterance>The Flint Tropics will be playing without their number one scorer, Coffee Black tonight. The Spurs have signed several new players from around the ABA, locking them in before they hit the free market in next year's expansion draft. The .big man, Pete Petrelli has been sent over from the dismantled Anaheim Amigos.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETRELLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We may be teammates, but I still think you're a dick.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks Petrelli.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to know what I love? This. The eleven of us right here, right now, waiting for the biggest game of our lives to begin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context>This is what I love.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to remember something. I want you to remember what this feels like, to be here in this locker room together, one last time, shoulder to shoulder with these men. Because we are not ourselves tonight. We are one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's play basketball.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SPURS COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee Black, you're going in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The coach stares him down, then picks another player.</context>
      <utterance>I can't. I've got back spasms.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is easily the worst half of basketball the Tropics have ever played. And that's saying something.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. It's a shit fucking sandwich.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's watch the F-bomb, Lou. We're live.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please, this is our last game. I can say whatever I want. Watch this: I hope Gerald Ford gets ass raped.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE TROPICS RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay then. We've got just fifteen seconds left in the first half... Here's Monix with a no-look to Jackie... He goes up strong--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LYNN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone in the stadium watches as Jackie lays out cold.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never seen anyone take a hit quite like that before. This looks serious. CLARENCE looks worried from the Spurs bench.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SPURS COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEE BEE leans over Jackie, worried.</context>
      <utterance>Do not leave this bench, Coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie? You awake?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER PAT THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring in the stretcher!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>MONIX gets in Petrelli's face.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to speculate, but I'm pretty sure he's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you trying to prove Petrelli? You afraid to play basketball?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETRELLI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix attacks Petrelli.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, check the scoreboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Monix is after Petrelli. This is total chaos.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER PAT THE REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let those fifteen seconds run out!  It's half time! Everyone off the court!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>The guys carry Jackie off the court and into the locker room. ON CLARENCE: He's had enough. He stands up and begins walking across the court, to join the Tropics.</context>
      <utterance>And at half time. It's the Spurs 60, the Tropics 29.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SPURS COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the Hell are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to my team.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPURS COACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the front row, the COMMISSIONER hears all of this and stands up, surrounded by security guards.</context>
      <utterance>This is your team. You are not leaving this bench.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMISH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sit down! You're not playing with those idiots ever again. If you walk away from this bench now, you're never coming back. I'll see to it you never play in the NBA! Ever! Do you understand what I'm saying to you, Coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, Clarence walks across the floor. The crowd erupts.</context>
      <utterance>My name ain't Coffee. It's Clarence.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Clarence takes off his Spurs jersey and throws it into the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this. Coffee Black is walking over to the Tropics. This crowd is going crazy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TWIGGY MUNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clarence!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the Hell are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm with you guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you out of your mind? You want to lose your NBA contract? Get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix cracks a smelling salt and waves it over Jackie's face.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to give up the NBA for this?  Well, you're a fucking asshole.  Jackie. Are you okay buddy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACKIE'S DREAM MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, I want you to go forward, and tell the others what I have told you here today. Do you understand me, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes Mother. You are so kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I stole your song.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE'S DREAM MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgave you for that a long time ago. I'd say it's about time you forgave yourself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's so fluffy. I miss you, Mom.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to leave this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE'S DREAM MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss you too, Jackie. Now, you gotta wake up. You're missing the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. I am? That's bad isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you make time go backwards?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE'S DREAM MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie walks into the clouds, then turns back.</context>
      <utterance>Not really. Now hurry up. And don't forget what I said.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Mom, I threw up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE'S DREAM MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you did, sweetie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's awake.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This just in. It sounds like Jackie Moon is up and around the locker room. That's good news for the Tropics.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I don't care how quick their defense is, we need to move the ball and--</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--Hold on you guys. I have something to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie seems very serious...</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a dream. I had a dream, I was in heaven and my Mother spoke to me... She was wearing a flowing white gown... And she showed me a whole new way to score a basket. She spoke to me and said with this gift, you will win fourth place.'</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's lost his mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIGGY MUNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to figure out what we're going to do in the second half.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we don't have time for any ghost baskets.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Jackie dribbles at the top of the key, doing a lot of pointing along with multiple hand signals.</context>
      <utterance>We're back in action here at the Mega Bowl. Coffee Black is playing for the Tropics... And Jackie Moon makes the start... In fact, it looks like he's trying to run the offense here...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Clarence cuts to the basket and Jackie throws him a lob. SLO MO: As Clarence leaps, we hear Jackie's voice over from the locker room...</context>
      <utterance>This is a new offense for the Tropics. Jackie dribbles to the top of the key... And... Jackie makes eye contact with Clarence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>SLO MO: Clarence catches it and slams it hard.</context>
      <utterance>I had a dream. And in my dream, my mother jumped... Her gown flowing in the wind... And she caught a pass in the air and dunked it, without ever touching the ground...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Everyone stands there, astonished. The other team is frozen. The fans are confused. The ref has no idea what to do.</context>
      <utterance>.She lifted her veil and said 'I call this the Alley Oop.'</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>The other players are starting to appreciate what they've just seen.</context>
      <utterance>.And she said it would change the game forever...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SPUR #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, bro.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woah. I'm sorry, I don't know what just happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPUR #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't he have to dribble first?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOU REDWOOD</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the Hell is going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Jackie, isn't that against the rules?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The whole arena is waiting for Father Pat the Ref to process this information.</context>
      <utterance>No. My Mom said it was fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>-Another Alley Oop! Dukes, shirtless, pumps his fist.</context>
      <utterance>There it is again, Clarence leaping, and forcing the ball in a downward direction through the goal net off of a high arching pass -- Hold on, I'm being told this is called an Alley Oop. Yes, That's easier to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>-Monix double teams and forces a turn over. In the back of the stadium, LYNN can't help but scream.</context>
      <utterance>Jackie lobs to Clarence again. YES! Another Alley Oop! The Spurs don't know what's hit them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monix with a steal-- A long bounce pass to Scootsie Double-Day for a lay-up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>117.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-Monix cuts off a Bee Bee Ellis pick toward the basket..</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you, Monix is playing on one leg here in the second half.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0. </mode>
      <context>SCOREBOARD: SPURS 100, TROPICS 99 -- : 15 left.</context>
      <utterance>Monix penetrates-- and-- Wow! He flipped it up behind his back and Clarence slammed it home with one hand!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>IT'S THE FINAL PLAY: The fans pray. Monix takes a deep breath, then in bounds the ball-- SLO MO: Jackie dribbles, looks up and lofts a perfect pass to Clarence... SLO MO: Clarence flies up for the alley oop slam dunk... SLO MO: At the last second, Petrelli flies into frame and swats it away!</context>
      <utterance>In all my years of radio, I've never seen anything like this. The Tropics have fought their way back from a twenty nine point deficit. With twelve seconds left to play, they're down by one point. A basket here could win it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>IN THE HUDDLE: Monix is yelling above the noise.</context>
      <utterance>Petrelli with the rejection! It's out of bounds -- The Tropics keep the ball, with seven seconds on the clock. I'll tell you Lou, the Spurs were looking for that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks at each other, worried.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, listen up: They've made adjustments out there. We can't just keep running the Alley Oop, okay? They're keying on Clarence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCOOTSIE DOUBLE-DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not going to run the alley oop?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we going to run?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to run The Puke.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Puke?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me you've forgotten it. Everyone smiles at each other. They haven't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Puke.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to pick away from the ball. We're going to move to the open space. I won't in bound the ball until someone has a good look. .</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring it in! One two three--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>SLO MO: Clarence sets a pick for Scootsie- Everyone rotates. Jackie picks and rolls to the basket, open... Monix zips Jackie a no-look pass...</context>
      <utterance>Monix, looking to inbound...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie goes up strong...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>The ref hands Jackie the ball. The players take their places along the lane. Jackie steps to the line. The whole arena is on pins and needles.</context>
      <utterance>Jackie Moon will shoot two free throws here, his team down by one, with two seconds on the clock. One will tie it. He needs both to win it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry you guys, I got this...  I am awesome at free throws.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you, I don't remember the last time I've ever seen Jackie attempt a free throw...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the Hell are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you've never seen me shoot free throws before?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He shoots them Granny style.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEE BEE ELLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always has.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie's ritual is insane. He breathes, spins the ball, turns around 360, deep knee bends, touches his left shoulder four times, then SUDDENLY WINGS THE BALL HIGH IN THE AIR.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first attempt is... GOOD!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Jackie does the same ritual. But this time a bead of sweat rolls over his forehead. He is nervous. But he tosses anyway... SLO MO: The Ball floats toward the basket. Flash bulbs pop. SLO MO: The ball bounces off the rim, away from the basket. SLO MO: Monix elbows his way into position for a rebound.</context>
      <utterance>The game is tied. One more and the Tropics win.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVE ABA RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>SLO MO: Monix catches the ball in the air and re-shoots a fade-away jumper. Swish!</context>
      <utterance>No Good -- Monix with the put back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCY MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kiss me, you hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Mom says you're a bad lady. She says your vagina is for sad people.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, there really is a trophy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's the Mega Bowl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEGIN END CREDITS.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As Credits roll, we hear a voice...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With their first pick in the 1977 NBA draft, the New Jersey Nets select...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DRAFT ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarence stands up, happy, and walks on stage. He holds up a uniform with words: SHITBITCH U.B. PHYNE on it. REVEAL: In the crowd, Monix claps, cheering Clarence on... He is with wife, LYNN. But now Monix stands up and walks on stage too. He puts a NEW YORK NETS hat on.</context>
      <utterance>.Shit, bitch, you be fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRAFT ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monix and Clarence shake hands for the cameras.</context>
      <utterance>Here to welcome him is rookie Nets coach, Ed Monix.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for bringing me on board, coach.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the good players were gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we really have to live in New Jersey?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just smile for the cameras, Shitbitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RECORDING ENGINEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounded pretty nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that was a great take. Play that back for me, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RECORDING ENGINEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, can you take that ring off for a little while? I'm getting some feedback from your microphone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="166" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PLACE DIAMOND RING.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie studies his ring with a smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE MOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry Robert, the ring stays on.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
