<movie id="482" title="Serenity">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that the war's over, our soldiers get to come home, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of them. Some will be stationed on the rim planets as Peace Enforcers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand. Why were the Independents even fighting us? Why wouldn't they look to be more civilized?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a good question. Does anybody want to open on that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear they're cannibals.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's only Reavers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reavers aren't real.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Full well they are. They attack settlers from space, they kill them and wear their skins and rape them for hours and hours --</utterance>
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode>CALMER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's true that there are... dangers on the outer planets. So let's follow up on Borodin's question. With all the social and medical advancements we can bring to the Independents, why would they fight so hard against us?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We meddle.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RIVER is a dark, intense little girl, writing with one hand and "typing" with the other. (Typing consists of holding a long wooden stylus and tapping either end down different columns of chinese characters on her desktop screen.) She is a good two years younger than the other kids.</context>
      <utterance>River?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People don't like to be meddled with. We tell them what to do, what to think, don't run don't walk we're in their homes and in their heads and we haven't the right. We're meddlesome.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>gently taking her</utterance>
   <speaker>STYLUS)</speaker>
      <mode> STYLUS)</mode>
      <context>She violently PLUNGES the stylus into the girl's forehead</context>
      <utterance>River, we're not telling people what to think. We're just trying to show them how.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>2ND TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's dreaming.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nightmare?</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Off the charts. Scary monsters.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DOCTOR MATHIAS is not instantly likable -- nor gradually, for that matter. A cold man, and more than a little satisfied with himself.</context>
      <utterance>Let's amp it up. Delcium, eight- drop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>River starts convulsing, mewing in misery. The Inspector starts forward, slowly.</context>
      <utterance>See, most of our best work is done when they're asleep. We can monitor and direct their subconscious, implant suggestions...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>The Inspector steps into the light. He is rigid, cold, staring at the girl with no emotion at all. His name, as we will very soon learn, is SIMON.</context>
      <utterance>It's a little startling to see, but the results are spectacular. Especially in this case. River Tam is our star pupil.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've heard that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a genius. Her mental capacity is extraordinary, even with the side-effects.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, obviously, she's unstable... the neural stripping gives them heightened cognitive reception, but it also destabilizes their own reality matrix. It manifests as borderline schizophrenia... which at this point is the price for being truly psychic.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What use do we have for a psychic if she's insane?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to tell you the security potential of someone who can read minds. And she has lucid periods -- we hope to improve upon the... I'm sorry, Sir, I have to ask if there's some reason for this inspection.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode>TURNING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I making you nervous?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Key members of Parliament have personally observed this subject. I was told their support for the project was unanimous. The demonstration of her power --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is she physically?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like nothing we've seen. All our subjects are conditioned for combat, but River... she's a creature of extraordinary grace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>6.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>River is suddenly next to him. He jumps a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat, as they face each other, Simon fighting emotion.</context>
      <utterance>Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They know you've come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon turns suddenly as he hears footsteps, people heading at them from the other side of the doors. 4wo SIMON</context>
      <utterance>We can't make it to the surface from inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>But River has, impossibly, scampered up over some lab equipment to the dark top of the corridor, where she holds herself in a perfect split, feet against the walls and outstretched hand holding the sprinkler for support. The doors burst open and two doctors pass by, hardly noticing the lone orderly. Passing right under River.</context>
      <utterance>Find a --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is standing by the window -- and the Security Agent is right behind him, PUNCHING the window with all his might. Simon helps River onto the gurney, then jumps on himself as the Security Agent cracks the glass. The two are whisked up in the gurney, River on her knees, Simon standing beside her holding one of the cables --</context>
      <utterance>Get on!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The action freezes.</context>
      <utterance>Stop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>Doctor Mathias storms in, two security men (not the ones from the opening) and a nervous young female intern following. Mathias looks greyer and more gaunt than when we saw him last.</context>
      <utterance>Remarkable children.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me! No one is allowed in the records room without my express permission.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mathias looks at the hologram -- realizes which one it is.</context>
      <utterance>Enter the doctor.  Forgive me. I prefer to see the event alone, without bias.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to see your clearance.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He places his hand on a screen as he says it. Mathias looks at the readout, and drops the bluster.</context>
      <utterance>You're right to insist. I know you've had security issues here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apologies. An Operative of the Parliament will of course have full cooperation.  I'm not sure what... I see no listing of rank, or name.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have neither. Like this facility, I don't exist. The Parliament calls me in when... when they wish they didn't have to. Let's talk about the Tams.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I assume you've scanned the status logs...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>River was your greatest success. A prodigy -- A phenomenon. Until her brother walked in eight months ago and took her from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not quite so simple.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm very aware of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There was no way I could --</context>
      <utterance>He came in with full creds. He beat the ap-scan, the retinal...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. Of course. The boy spent his fortune developing the contacts to infiltrate this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gave up a brilliant future in. medicine as well, you've probably read. Turned his back on his whole life. Madness.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mathias looks uncertain.</context>
      <utterance>Madness, no. Something a good deal more dangerous. Have you looked at this scan carefully? At his face?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's love, in point of fact. He loved his sister and he knew she was in pain. So he took her somewhere safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here because the situation is even less simple than you think.  Do you know what your sin is, Doctor?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I. I would be very careful about what you --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>SADLY</mode>
      <context>He touches the computer screen and the hologramic image jumps to the Doctor and Simon in the lab, Mathias repeating:</context>
      <utterance>It's pride.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I was told their support --</context>
      <utterance>Key members of Parliament have personally observed this subject.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Key members of Parliament. Key. The minds behind every diplomatic, military and covert operation in the galaxy, and you put them in a room with a psychic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was... she read cards, nothing more.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's come to our attention that River became much more unstable, more... disturbed, after you showed her off to Parliament. Did she see something very terrible in those cards?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever... secrets she might have accidentally gleaned... it's probable she doesn't even know she knows them. That they're buried beneath --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they are in her. Her mind is unquiet. It's the will of the Parliament that I kill her. And the brother. Because of your sin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, in certain older civilized cultures, when men failed as entirely as you have, they would throw themselves on their swords.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The air rings crisply as the Operative pulls out his sword.</context>
      <utterance>Well, unfortunately I forgot to bring a sword to --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Parliament has no further interest in psychics. They represent a threat to the harmony and stability of our Alliance.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR MATHIAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would put that down right now if I were you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The agents move. He slices the throat of the one behind him with true grace, thrusting at the second as he's pulling out his gun and pinning his hand. A moment, and the dying agent reflexively squeezes the trigger, shooting his own arm. The Operative pulls out the sword and the agent falls as quietly as the first. Mathias bolts but the Operative pins him to the wall. He bunches his fingers and jabs the side of the Doctor's spine. Mathias stiffens, suddenly, agonizingly immobile. The Operative steps back, observes the Doctor's rigid grimace for a moment. Almost ceremoniously, he drops to one knee and holds the blade out to one side, hilt to the floor and point tilted toward the doctor. The Doctor stares at it in horror as his paralyzed body begins to tip over toward it. The Operative turns toward the terrified intern at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Would you be killed in your sleep, like an ailing pet? Whatever your failings, I believe you deserve better than that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>He's almost startled when the Doctor's body drops into frame, slowed suddenly by the sword. It squeaks down the blade, the Doctor unable to cry out, as the Operative whispers to him:</context>
      <utterance>Young miss, I'll need all the logs- on behavioral modification triggers. We'll have to reach out to River Tam, and help her to come back to us. No matter how far out Simon has taken her, we can --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>Mathias is dead. The Operative pulls the sword out as the body rolls over. As he wipes the sword down:</context>
      <utterance>This is a good death. There's no shame in this, in a man's death. A man who's done fine works. We're making a better world. All of them, better worlds.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Young miss, I need you to get to work now. I think I may have a long way to travel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's addressing the pilot, WASH. Flight gear and a hawaiian shirt, toy dinosaurs populating his station -- no old soldier, but just as startled.</context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoah! Did you see that -- The ship bucks --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was that the primary buffer panel?</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It did seem to resemble --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another buck --</context>
      <utterance>Did the Primary Buffer Panel just fall off my gorramn ship for no apparent reason?</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought Kaylee checked our entry couplings! I have a very clear memory of it --</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah well if she doesn't give us some extra flow from the engine room to offset the burnthrough this landing is gonna get pretty interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Define "Interesting".</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Oh god, oh god, we're all gonna die?"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the Captain. There's a little problem with our entry sequence; we may experience slight turbulence and then explode.  Can you shave the vector --</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm doing it! It's not enough.  Kaylee!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just get us on the ground!</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That part'll happen, pretty definitely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>we're gonna explode? I don't wanna explode.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jayne, how many weapons you plan on bringing? You only got the two arms...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just get excitable as to choice, like to have my options open.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't plan on any shooting taking place during this job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what you plan and what takes place ain't ever exactly been similar.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>First Mate ZOE enters from the lower level. Her mode of dress and military deference mark her as a war buddy of Mal's.</context>
      <utterance>No grenades.  No grenades.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we crashing again?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk to your husband. Is the mule prepped?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good to go, sir. Just loading her up.  Are those grenades?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cap'n doesn't want 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got the Primary Buffer</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's shiny, Cap'n. Not to fret.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>JOLT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me the entry couplings would hold for another week!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode>WORKING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was six months ago, cap'n.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My ship don't crash. If she crashes, you crashed her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>Simon nods, the ship jolting again.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor. Guess I need to get innocked 'fore we hit planetside.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bit of a rockety ride. Nothing to worry about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not worried.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fear is nothing to be ashamed of, Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't fear. This is anger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's kinda hard to tell the one from t'other, face like yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I imagine if it were fear, my eyes would be wider.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll look for that next time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not taking her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No no, that's not a thing I'm interested in talking over with --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not going with you. That's final.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guests? I earn my passage, Captain --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's time your little sister learned from your fine example.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've earned my passage treating bullet holes, knife wounds, laser burns...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of our jobs are trickier than others --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you want to put my sister in the middle of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The passenger dorm has a time-worn warmth that most of the ship shares. Except, of course, for the sterile blue of:</context>
      <utterance>Didn't say 'want'. Said 'will'. It's one job, Doc. She'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A mentally traumatized sevente--</context>
      <utterance>She's a seventeen year old girl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a reader. Sees into the truth of things; might see trouble before it's coming. Which is of use to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's your guiding star, isn't it? What's of use.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context>Simon jabs the inoculation needle into Mal's arm.</context>
      <utterance>Honestly, doctor, I think we may really crash this time anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you understand what I've gone through to keep River away from the Alliance?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do, and it's a fact me and mine have been courteous enough to keep to our own selves.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you threatening to --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts away, Simon still keeping pace.</context>
      <utterance>I got one purpose here: keep this boat in the air. I take the jobs I get -- which is less and less, case you ain't been keeping track.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every year since the war the Alliance pushes just a little further out towards the rim. Makes it a chore for naughty men like us to slip about -- and keeping you two on board means working twice as hard to avoid the law. Means turning down a score of honest jobs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon starts up the stairs as Mal calls to him:</context>
      <utterance>So here is us, on the raggedy edge. Don't push me and I won't push you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>As Mal walks on, we tilt up to see the Mule, a four-man hovercraft hanging from chains near the ceiling. Jayne and Zoe are tossing duffle bags into it.</context>
      <utterance>Things get gritty I will keep her from the fray, but she's coming. Best you get her ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zoe, is Wash gonna straighten this boat out before we get flattened?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera picks up Simon's feet as they enter foreground on the catwalk, and track with them to find:</context>
      <utterance>Like a downy feather, sir. Nobody flies like my mister.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's lying on her side, looking straight at us. A loose summer dress draped over her small frame.</context>
      <utterance>River...</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. We're going for a ride.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>River puts on a huge pair of goggles, looks at her brother.</context>
      <utterance>Now, River, you stay behind the others. If there's fighting you drop to the floor or run away. It's okay to leave them to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the brains of the operation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should hit town right during Sunday worship. Won't be any crowds.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Fanty and Mingo are right about the payroll, this could look to be a sunny day for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode>APPROACHING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, I'll ask you one last time...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He peels out, leaves Simon fuming. Kaylee sidles up to him...</context>
      <utterance>Doctor, I'm taking your sister under my protection here. If anything happens to her, anything at all, I swear to you I will get very choked up. Honestly. There could be tears.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mind the Captain none, Simon. I know he'll look out for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's amazing. I bring River all the way out to the raggedy edge of the 'verse so she can hide from the Alliance by robbing banks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just a little Trading Station. They'll be back 'fore you can spit.  Not that you spit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we hoping to find here that equals the worth of a turd?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Which once a month rests here.</context>
      <utterance>Alliance payroll. There's peace enforcing squads stationed all about this quadrant. Can't use credits out here -- they got to pay their boys in cashy money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something about stealing from the Alliance just warms a body like whiskey in winter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal turns back to River.</context>
      <utterance>Shiny. Let's be badguys.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ready to go to work, darlin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no pattern to the pebbles here, they're completely random. I tried to count them but you drove too fast. Hummingbird.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Great. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two men who appear to be farm folk rush Mal and the others. Mal draws on the elder one and he stops dead in his tracks. Mal's gun is long, not unlike Civil War era issue, but very much new in design. The other tries to tackle Jayne, which is not necessarily a great idea. Jayne clotheslines him so hard he spins right upside-down -- and Jayne grabs him by the legs and CRACK! -- bounces his head right off the floor, knocking him out cold.</context>
      <utterance>Hands and knees and heads bowed down! Everybody, now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>The guy who rushed Mal complies along with everyone else. Jayne dumps his catch on the floor and rips open his dirty shirt to reveal the purple of an Alliance uniform.</context>
      <utterance>Y'all wanna be looking very intently at your own belly buttons. I see a head start to rise, violence is gonna ensue.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at Mal, who motions for Zoe to open the front door. She does, and River steps in. ANGLE: RIVER'S BARE FEET -- walking slowly among the hunched- over customers as Mal addresses them.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like this is the place.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he is speaking, Jayne is scrambling to the back office, finding the small vault locked.</context>
      <utterance>You've probably guessed we mean to be thieving here, but what we are after is not yours. So let's have no undue fussing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>River suddenly looks around, perturbed. CLOSE ON: a young tough. River looks up at Zoe, alarmed, and silently points to the young man. He is slowly reaching for the weapon in his belt. He finds Zoe's sawed-off nuzzling his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>She's locked up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops his weapon, slides it across the floor. Mal moves to the Trade Agent. Hauls him up, tosses him toward the vault. Zoe and Jayne follow.</context>
      <utterance>You know what the definition of a hero is? It's someone who gets other people killed. You can look it up later.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRADE AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is just a crop moon, don't think you'll find what you --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal reaches in, pulls a lever and the floor opens, a six foot hole appearing, stairs leading to a corridor, all gleaming metal and blue light. Zoe smiles. Jayne peers down as Mal addresses the Trade Agent.</context>
      <utterance>At last. We can retire and give up this life of crime.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a fed down there? Be truthful.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRADE AGENT</speaker>
      <mode>NODDING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'all are Browncoats, hey? Fought for independence?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voice of a young Alliance GUARD comes up from below.</context>
      <utterance>War's long done. We're all just folk now.  Listen up! We are coming down to empty that vault!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jayne impatiently fires a burst of machine-gun fire down into the hole. A beat...</context>
      <utterance>You have to give me your authorization password!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Repeater.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and right by her, in the shadows, is a man. Mostly. He is hideously disfigured, a combination of self- mutilation and the bubbling red of radiation poisoning. His clothes are rags, his eyes pinpoints of glazed madness. A blade blurs through frame...</context>
      <utterance>Did sound summat like gunblast... Maybe you aught run tell Lawman...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds her, as she whispers, wide-eyed...</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is up? You all right? What's goin' on?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reavers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leg's good, it'll bleed plenty and we avoid any necessary organs...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking more of a graze..</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you don't want it to look like you just gave up...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every heist, he's gotta start yelling my name --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is already loading up with bags as Mal thinks quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Mal! Reavers! The girl's pitchin' a fit. They're here or they're comin' soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>(to the guard, pointing to the VAULT)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that open from the inside?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whah -ah- yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get everyone upstairs in there and you seal it. Long as you got air you don't open up, you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I -- Buh I -- Mal is in his face, dark and huge:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zoe take the wheel --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>1J -- and jump on themselves, Mal scanning the area as he hands River up to Jayne's care. As the craft powers up, slowly moving, the young man Zoe kept from trying to pull his weapon bursts out of the station, grabbing the back of the mule.</context>
      <utterance>You see 'em? Anybody see 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take me with you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get in the vault with the others --</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stay here! Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Reaver craft ROARS over their heads. It's nearly the size of Serenity. Torn apart, belching smoke -- a welded conglomeration of ruined ships, painted for war. Predator, pure. It disappears over the rooftops.</context>
      <utterance>It's too many. Drive, Zoe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come they ain't blowing us out of the air?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>River is squashed down on her back, being very small.</context>
      <utterance>They wanna run us down. The up- close kill.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They want us alive when they eat us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal says nothing, keeps firing.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, sure would be nice if we had some grenades, don'tchya think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wash, baby can you hear me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not gonna reach you in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just keep moving, honey. We're coming to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jayne grabs the Mule, legs dangling, pulled out between the two vessels as Mal slams a new cartridge into his pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Grab on!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal steadies himself and takes aim, seemingly at Jayne --</context>
      <utterance>I won't get et! You shoot me if they take me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well don't shoot me first!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get some distance on 'em. You come to the flats, I want you to swing round. Gonna try a Barn Swallow.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>J Simon! Open the loading dock!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, baby, we've talked this through...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She throws the wheel and the mule comes hard about, fishtailing slightly as it faces the oncoming skiff.</context>
      <utterance>Talkin' ain't doin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't slow down!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>River?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaylee runs in to see how everyone is. She goes to Simon.</context>
      <utterance>I swallowed a bug.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bloodied Reaver POPS into frame from under the skiff-top. He lunges for Mal, baring sharpened teeth -- Mal spins and draws, fires into his belly as Jayne and Zoe both fire at the same time. The freak takes too long to go down, but down he goes. Dies sitting against the s i op. 4 Everybody takes a moment to look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Is he okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stupid, selfish, son of a whore ---</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a hair's breadth from riddling you with holes, Doctor --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"One simple job! She'll be fine!"</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She IS fine! Except for bein' still crazy, she's the picture of health!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wasn't for River, we'd probably be left there. She felt 'em coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never again. You understand me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems I remember a talk about you giving orders on my boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well sleep easy 'cause we're off your boat. Just as soon as River gets her share of the "bounty".</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well let's not do anything hasty...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>No, shiny! I'm sick a' carrying tourists anyhow. We'll be on Beaumonde in ten hours time, you can pick up your earnings and be on your merry. Meantime you do your job. Patch up my crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is looking at the Reaver. Everyone does, for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>He didn't lie down. They never lie down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I think things'll glide a deal smoother for us without River and Simon on board... but how long do you think they'll last?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc made his call. They's as babes in a basket when we took 'em in; we sheltered 'em plenty. Man has to cut loose, learn to stand on his own.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop by Mal Is room.</context>
      <utterance>Like that man back in town?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to shoot him. What the Reavers woulda done to him before they killed him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>vo,</context>
      <utterance>I know. That was a piece a' mercy. But before that, him begging us to bring him along...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woulda slowed us down.</context>
      <utterance>We couldn't take the weight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know that for certain</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Or Jayne?</context>
      <utterance>Mule won't run with five. I shoulda dumped the girl? Or you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONSIDERING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Jayne...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coulda tossed the payload.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Washenters from the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>And go to Fanty and Mingo with air in our mitts, tell 'em "here's your share"? They'd set the dogs on us in the space of a twitch, and there we are back in mortal peril. We get a job, we gotta vo make good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I don't disagree on any particular point, it's just... in the time of war, we woulda never left a man stranded.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's not happy with the reply. Mal climbs down to his room as Wash reaches Zoe, slides his arms around her.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe that's why we lost.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kaylee, are you ever gonna put that capture down?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode>0.5.</mode>
      <context>The picture pans over to the bed -- which River is bending over and sniffing curiously. Inara is packing things up.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta have records of everything. A bona fide Companion entertained clients on this very ship! In this very bed!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For one sweet second, we was almost classy.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4 You promised to help me pack.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Inara shoots an uncertain look at the camera -- and the picture freezes, goes back to the beginning. During all this, Mal has picked it up. He looks at it a moment, tosses it aside. Looks around at nothing much.</context>
      <utterance>Honest, Inara, why do you have to leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not get it. How's a guy get so wrong?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dumps the body in, she starts the doors closing.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't logical. Cuttin' on his own face, rapin' and murdering -- I mean, I'll kill a man in a fair fight... or if I think he's gonna start a fair fight, or if he bothers me, or if there's a woman, or I'm gettin' paid -- mostly only when I'm gettin' paid. But these Reavers... last ten years they just show up like the boageyman from stories. Eating people alive? Where does that get fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shepherd Book said they was men that reached the edge of space., saw a vasty nothingness and just went bibbledy over it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, I been to the edge. Just looked like more space.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. People get awful lonely in the black. Like to get addlepated ourselves, we stay on this boat much longer. Captain'll drive us all off, one by one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just in a whinge cuz that prissy doc is finally disembarking. Me I says good riddance. He never belonged here, and his sister's no saner than one of them Reavers.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't even so! River's a dear heart and a boon to this crew! You just don't like her 'cause she can read your mind and everything you think is mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there is that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up toward one of the shuttles.</context>
      <utterance>Her and Simon could have a place here. Now they're leaving us. Just like Shepherd Book.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like Inara...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHEYDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The girls. They've learned more from you these last months than the rest of us could show them in two years.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're very sweet. But they're not Companions.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEYDRA</speaker>
      <mode>WRYLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've no hope for them? Junk the lot, start anew?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On Sihnon we started training at twelve. Years of discipline and preparation before the physical act of pleasure was even mentioned. Most of these girls --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEYDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're all of good family, the highest academic standards --</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Control. Was the first lesson. And the last and these worlds are not like the Central Planets. There is barbarism dressed up in the most civil weeds. Men of the highest rank who don't know the difference between a Companion and a common whore. It's unsafe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEYDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You should know better.</context>
      <utterance>All the more reason the girls look to you. You came out here alone, before the Alliance ever thought to establish a House this remote. You've seen so much. You're a figure of great romance to them. 4d INARA Great romance has nothing to do with being a Companion, Sheydra.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEYDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inara nearly spills her drink.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not the one who had a torrid affair with a pirate.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A who? With a what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEYDRA</speaker>
      <mode>SMILING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the talk of the House. The girls all trade stories in the dorms at night.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't... have a pirate...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHEYDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In one of the stories you make love in a burning temple. I think that's my favorite.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode>SITTING</mode>
      <context>(mutters in Chinese)</context>
      <utterance>This is unbearable. Captain Reynolds is no pirate; he's a petty thief. And he never laid a finger on me. All he ever did was rent me a shuttle and be very annoying.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHEYDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A year on his shuttle and he never laid a finger on you. No wonder you left.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode>BRIDLING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I left because -- go away. We're no longer friends. You're a stranger to me now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEYDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>104 I do love to watch you boil. Don't worry. The stories will fade. And your Captain Reynolds has probably gotten himself blown up by this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. That would be just like him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>40.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>KAYLEE  You look the captain in the eye, know who you're dealing with.</utterance>
   <speaker>40 SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Since he doesn't know what to say, she rattles on:</context>
      <utterance> I wish there was...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't aughta be so clean. It's a dead giveaway you don't belong, you always gotta be tidy. Don't pay anybody in advance. And don't ride in anything with a Capissen 38 engine, they fall right out of the sky.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and heads off. Simon starts in the other direction, but River looks after her and the others.</context>
      <utterance>Kaylee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>River... do you want to stay with them?</utterance>
   <speaker>4 RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's heading off and doesn't hear:</context>
      <utterance>No, I fear it's not safe anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not my fault the Doc's got no stomach for Rim living --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is entirely and for all your fault! If you'd given Simon a moment, just a moment where he didn't think you were gonna throw them off or turn them in, he might've --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have reached the guncheck, where Jayne and Wash have already checked their guns. It works like a lunch automat: Mal sticks his gun in a drawer, pulls out a chit -- the q0 drawer closes and rotates, revealing another empty one. A large bouncer with a shockrod watches impassively.</context>
      <utterance>What? Swept you into his cleanly arms? Made tidy love to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as they continue</utterance>
   <speaker>DOWN)</speaker>
      <mode> DOWN)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you dare joke! You know how much I pined on Simon. And him fair sweet on me, I well believe, but he's so worried about being found out --</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain didn't make 'em fugitives.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he coulda made 'em family! Steada driving them off. Steada keeping Simon from seein' I was there, when I carried such a torch and we coulda -- goin' on a year now I ain't had nothin' twixt my nethers weren't run on batteries!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh god! I can't know that!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>40 I could stand to hear a little more...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you had a care for anybody's heart you woulda --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>ENOUGH</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew he was gonna leave. We never been but a way station to those two. And how do you know what he feels? He's got River to worry on but he still coulda shown you... if I truly wanted someone bad enough, wouldn't be a thing in the 'verse could stop me from going to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment, Mal is too shocked to react. Kaylee storms out.</context>
      <utterance>Tell that to Inara.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MINGO is young, tough -- somewhere between a gangster and a fur-trader. Sounds lower-class British, or something like it.</context>
      <utterance>4 Domestic troubles?</utterance>
   <speaker>FANTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FANTY moves out from behind Mingo to reveal that he is Mingo's identical twin. Apart from slight differences in dress, they are indistinguishable.</context>
      <utterance>Domestic troubles?</utterance>
   <speaker>MINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cause we don't wanna interrupt.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man should keep his house in order.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mingo. Fanty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pointing at his</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER)</speaker>
      <mode> BROTHER)</mode>
      <context>,do</context>
      <utterance>He's Mingo.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's Fanty. You're Mingo.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ghahh! How is it you always know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fanty's prettier.  Feel to do some business?</utterance>
   <speaker>MINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bit crowded, isn't it? As you see, we come unencumbered by thugs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which means at least four of the guys already in here are yours. All's one. I'll just keep Jayne with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, are you sure you don't --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go. Go get yourselves a nice romantic meal.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are my two favorite words!  Honey... "Meal..."</utterance>
   <speaker>MINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite a crew you've got.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, they're a fine bunch of ruebens.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you keep them on that crap boat is the subject of much musing tween me and Fanty.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We go on and on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'm noticing. Is there a problem I don't know of? You got 25% of a sweet take kissing your foot, how come we're not dispersing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FANTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our end is forty, precious.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My muscular buttocks it's forty --</utterance>
   <speaker>MINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is as of now. Find anyone around going cheaper.</utterance>
   <speaker>J FANTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jayne sees her, nudges Mal, who looks and turns back to business. We stay on her as she wanders around the perimeter of the bar, vaguely listening in on Mal's deal.</context>
      <utterance>Find anyone around going near a sorry lot like you in the first instance. ANGLE: RIVER has entered, is looking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>FANTY</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're unlikable, Mal. You got no respect for us above you, you got enemies in every quadrant, and your ship's older than the starting point of time. You's charity cases to such as us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well here's a foul thought. I conjured you two were incompetent; sent us out not knowing there were V0 Reavers about. Now I'm thinking you picked us out because you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That were a sign of faith, boy. And it doesn't affect our forty per. Danger is, after all, your business.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is all background noise to River, who has moved to the CV screen, on which is a commercial. It's animated, goofy, cartoon animals and anime-style Asian girls all transforming to insane fantasy figures as they sing about:</context>
      <utterance>Reavers ain't business, double dickless.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>River...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's taking out a group of four, high kicks and perfect precision -- Two men come from either side, one whipping out a knife -- she does a perfect split, grabs his wrist above her head, using his momentum to stab the other one -- Mal fights to get back to the gunrack. The bouncer reaches her and she wrests his shockrod from him, uses it on him, on Fanty and Mingo -- the fan-dancer is bolting and River hurls the rod at her head, knocks her cold... She's everywhere. On tables, chairs, under your legs, using the room itself to take out every single person there. One man hides behind a wall -- impossibly, she swings her leg around the corner and nails his face. Jayne grabs her from behind --</context>
      <utterance>V0 Whuhuh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>She grabs his crotch and squeezes -- his grip loosens and she spins, facing him, and flat-heels his nose with her palm, V0 twirling into a gut kick that doubles him over, dispatching of another while she cracks Jayne's head with a small table -- Somebody pulls a gun and she snaps his elbow, causing him to scream out even before he shoots himself in the gut -- Mal frantically wrests a gun from the vending locker as River knocks the other guy's gun in the air, kicks someone else and then catches it, whips it around just as Mal comes up with his, they are pointed right at each other --</context>
      <utterance>Gorrammit, girl, it's me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And River drops to the ground, fast asleep. There is a beat. Mal looks around the bar. He and Simon, who has run up to the entrance, are the only ones standing. He looks down at River. She lies unconscious, helpless.</context>
      <utterance>Eta Kooram Nah Smech!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think maybe we ought to leave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>CAPTIVATED</mode>
      <context>An Ensign is revealed looking at a separate monitor:</context>
      <utterance>Hello again. Yes, it's me. I'm glad you've finally asked for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENSIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing here that would --</context>
      <utterance>We got a pos on a retinal -- man carrying her out is Malcolm Reynolds, captains a Firefly-class transport ship, "Serenity". Bound by law five times, smuggling, tariff dodge... not convicted.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ship. The name of the ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>10</speaker>
      <mode>SOFTLY</mode>
      <context>He looks over at the Ensign with a small, strange smile on his lips -- as his glasses are covered by text.</context>
      <utterance>Crossref. Malcolm Reynolds. Serenity.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENSIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Serenity Valley. Bloodiest battle of the entire war. The Independents held the valley for seven weeks, two of them after their high command had surrendered. 68% casualty rate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENSIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, Sir, I just didn't --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the feds ever bothered to crossref justice files with war records... Yes. Our Mr. Reynolds was a sergeant, 57th Overlanders. Volunteer. Fought at Serenity till the very last. This man is an issue. This man hates us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENSIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First Mate Zoe Washburn, formerly Corporal Zoe Alleyne, also in the 57th. Career army, looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON: THE LENS of his glasses. On it is a slowly moving picture of INARA.</context>
      <utterance>She's followed him far... Give me the crew, registered passengers -- Our Captain is a passionate man, no room there for subtlety. He's bound to have some very obvious...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-40  .weakness...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I see her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's still napping just now. And I believe you've got some storytelling to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode>ENTERING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're out of atmo, plotted for Haven. No one following as of yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven? We're gonna see Shepherd Book?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>NODDING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got to lay low. And I could fair use some spiritual guidance right about now.  I am a lost lamb; what in hell happened back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Start with the part where Jayne gets knocked out by a ninety pound girl. 'Cause I don't think that's ever getting old.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we know if anyone was killed?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's likely. I know she meant to Ad kill me 'fore the Doc put her to sleep, which how exactly does that work anyhow?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Safeword.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The people who helped me break River out -- they had intel that River and the other subjects were being embedded with behavioral conditioning. They taught me a safeword, in case... something happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not sure I get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If I speak the words, "Eta --</context>
      <utterance>A phrase that's encoded in her brain, that makes her fall asleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well don't say it! moo ZOE It only works on her, Jayne.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well, now I know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"In case something happened."</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feel to elaborate on what that something might be? I mean they taught you that fancy safeword, they must've figured she was gonna, what -- start uncontrollably crocheting?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They never said what --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal grabs him and throws him against the wall, in his face.</context>
      <utterance>And you never did ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight months. Eight months you had her on my boat knowing full well she might go monkeyshit at the wrong word and you never said a thing --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I brought her out here so they couldn't get to her, I don't even know how they --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My ship. My crewi You had a gorramn timebomb living with us!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks at Kaylee, the truth of Mal's words hitting him.</context>
      <utterance>What if she went off in the middle woo of dinner, or in bunk with Kaylee, did that give you a moment's pause?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought she was getting better.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I thought they was gettin' off!  Didn't we have a intricate plan how they was gonna be not here anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We couldn't leave them now...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, now that she's a... killer woman we ought be bringin' 'em tea and dumplings!  In earnest, Mal: why'd you bring her back on?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal steps aside. Simon enters the locker.</context>
      <utterance>May I see her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She goes woolly again, we're gonna have to put a bullet to her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's crossed my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I make a suggestion that doesn't involve violence, or is this the wrong crowd?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>V0 Fanty and Mingo might be coming hard down on us, or the laws... or maybe nobody could be bunged about a little social brawl. We need to get our bearings. I think we need to talk to Mr. Universe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR UNIVERSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is good. This is...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR UNIVERSE</speaker>
      <mode>GIGGLES</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.she's beating up all the burly men and I'm having a catharsis, it's happening right now, you guys always bring me the very best violence. You think you're in a hot place?</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what we're looking to learn. Is there any follow up, a newswave...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MR UNIVERSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no "news", there's the truth of the signal, what I see, and there's the puppet theatre the V0 Parliament's jesters foist on the somnambulant public. Monkey taught to say the word "monkey" -- lead story on 32 planets. But the slum riots on Hera, not a --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about this? Did this make the... puppet theatre?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR UNIVERSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir. And no lawforce flags, either -- I hadda go into the security feed direct...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR UNIVERSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't stop the signal, Mal. Everything goes somewhere and I go everywhere. Security feeds are a traipse to access -- and I wasn't the first one in, this has prints on it -- oh! Look at her go! A0 Everyone is getting bruises and contusions. Contoooosions.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So somebody else has been fed this. That doesn't like me too well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR UNIVERSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zoe, you sultry minx, stop falling in love with me. You're just gonna embarrass yourself. I have a commitment to my Lovebot, it was a very beautiful ceremony, Lenore wrote her own vows, I cried like a baby, a hungry, angry baby.  And she falls asleep. Which, she would be sleepy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr Universe works the screen. The image rewinds and stops on River coming up to it, looking at it. She whispers the word, "Miranda", and starts to move away.</context>
      <utterance>Can you go back? See if anybody spoke with her 'fore she acted up, -40 made any kind of contact with her...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miranda...? Go back further.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR UNIVERSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls another screen close, starts working that one. Matching timecodes, he pulls up the commercial.</context>
      <utterance>No..</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr Universe has a third screen showing the commercial as</context>
      <utterance>Um... please?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR UNIVERSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friends and potential lovers, I</utterance>
   <speaker>4DO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>have good news and I have the other kind. Good is you're very smart. Someone is talking to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The oaty bar?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Subliminal. It's a subliminal message broadwaved to trigger her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR UNIVERSE</speaker>
      <mode>NODDING</mode>
      <context>Mal, Zoe and Wash look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>I been seeing this code pop up all over, last few weeks. And I cannot crack it. It's Alliance and it's high military, so here then is the bad. Someone has gone to enormous trouble to find your little friend. And found her they have.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're afraid of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts tearing up, breathing faster... Simon runs his hands through her hair.</context>
      <utterance>They should be. What I will show them... Oh God...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay, it's okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show me off like a dog, old men covered in blood, it never touched them but they're drowning in it... so much loss... I don't know what I'm saying. I never know what I'm saying...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said something. When you were triggered, do you remember? The Captain saw you say something on the feed...</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miranda.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miranda.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask her. She'll show you all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show us what? Who is Miranda?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode>BEAT</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I... talking to Miranda now? Nw She shoots him a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a multiple, dumbo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Right. But I think somehow when they triggered you it brought this up, this memory --</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't mine. The memory. I didn't bring it and I shouldn't have to carry it, it isn't mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode>URGENTLY:</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't make me sleep again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put a bullet to me. Bullet in the brain pan, squish.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches out and touches his face, affectionately.</context>
      <utterance>Don't say that. Not ever. We'll get through this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things are going to get much much worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the Captain hasn't tossed us in the airlock, so I'd say we're --</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has to see. More than anyone... he has to see what he doesn't want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks.</context>
      <utterance>River. What will Miranda show us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Death.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she starts laughing. Quietly at first, then louder, then almost uncontrollably, screaming in his face:</context>
      <utterance>Whose death?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive what you can, and send me on my path. I will walk on, until you bid me rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hope that ain't for me, Shepherd.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's prayer for the dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I really hope it ain't for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's for the men River might have killed in that bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weren't River that did it, you know that. Somebody decided her brain was just another piece of property to take, fenced it right Vd up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a plan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiding ain't a plan?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll do you for a spell, and the folks here'll be glad of the extra coin...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.but they'll be coming. Alliance is after this girl with a powerful will. I look to hear the tromp of their boots any moment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't.  This isn't a palms-up military MW run, Mal. No reports broadwaved, no warrants... much as they want her, they want her hid. That means Closed File. Means an Operative, which is trouble you've not known.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I coulda left her there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not your way, Mal.</utterance>
   <speaker>V0 MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a way?</utterance>
   <speaker>V0 MAL</speaker>
      <mode>THINKS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that better than a plan?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can play the thug all you want, but there's more to you than you're ever like to 'fess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just think that 'cause my eyes is all sorrowful and pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only one thing is gonna walk you through this, Mal. Belief.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sermons make me sleepy, Shepherd. I ain't looking for help from on high. That's a long wait for a train don't come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorta man they're like to send believes hard. Kills and never asks why.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's of interest to me how much you seem to know about that world.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't born a Shepherd, Mal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have to tell me about that some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks away, offering this:</context>
      <utterance>No I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>Mal watches him go, thinking.</context>
      <utterance>Sideways.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eight-year-old River is working away, not paying attention.</context>
      <utterance>River?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>River looks up, scared. All the other children wordlessly get up from their seats and lie on the floor next to them.</context>
      <utterance>River, you look tired. I think everybody's a little tired by now; why don't we all lie down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>She starts to lie down herself, right on the grass.</context>
      <utterance>A little peace and quiet will make everything better.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... Vao TEACHER River. Do as you're told. It's going to be fine. Lie down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whuh huh nuhwhat?</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>He pops up, turns to the screen as the white noise becomes:</context>
      <utterance>Mal! You up? Got a wave. I'm a bounce it down to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mal. I uh, is this a bad time</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good as any.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please tell me you're wearing pants.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How's your world?</context>
      <utterance>Naked as the day I come cryin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cold. It's autumn here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still at the Training House?</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right where you left me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>picturesque.</context>
      <utterance>I remember it as nice enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is that. What about you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With the locals, I thought maybe...</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Thank you, I... I guess we have something of a problem here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could use a gun hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hoping not. But if you were close at all, you -- the crew -- could take your ease here a while... and there'd be payment...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Payment is never not a factor. I could sound out the crew... This pot like to boil over soon?</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon. Not right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it would be, I mean I would like to... Kaylee's been missing you something fierce --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss her too. I even miss my shuttle, occasionally.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you left a... got some of your stuff in a trunk, never did get a chance to drop it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>stuff... just sundries I expect.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't look through the...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>64</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inara smiles blandly, nods. An awkward beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's kind of late where I'm at. I'll send a wave as soon as I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She disappears. Mal thinks a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inara. Nice to see her again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, trap?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trap.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We goin' in? moo MAL It ain't but a few hours out...</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but, remember the part where it's a trap?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's the case, then Inara's already caught in it. She wouldn't set us up willing. Might be we got a shot at seeing who's turning these wheels. We go in.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you be sure Inara don't just wanna see you? Sometimes people have feelings -- I'm referring here to people...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guilty glances.</context>
      <utterance>Y'all were watching, I take it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>140 You see us fight?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trap.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're about seventy miles from the Training house. And nobody on radar... if the Alliance is about, they're laying low.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>4dO He starts out, turns back to Zoe.</context>
      <utterance>They're about. Find us a home. I'll take the shuttle in closer. Zoe, ship is yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember: if anything happens to me, or you don't hear from me within the hour... you take this ship and you come and rescue me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? And risk my ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>EXITING</mode>
      <context>I don't wanna get left.</context>
      <utterance>I mean it. It's cold out there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear Buddha, please send me a pony, and a plastic rocket, and --</utterance>
   <speaker>I NAR.A</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mal! What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You invited me.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never thought for a second you'd be stupid enough to come!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that makes you kind of a tease, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew my invitation wasn't on the level --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which led me to the conclusion that you must be in some trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine! I'm. giddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a woman schooled in telling men what they wanna hear, you ain't much of a liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mal, you cannot handle this man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>ENTERING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to say, I'm impressed that you would come for her yourself. lw And that you would make it this far in that outfit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>STANDING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can be very graceful when I need to.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal sheds his shawl and robe. Inara kneels at the alter, picks out another incense stick.</context>
      <utterance>I've no doubt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm praying for you, Mal.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's very thoughtful. But I mean it when I say you're not in any danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speak your piece.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're beginning to understand how dangerous River Tam is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is a mite unpredictable. Mood swings, of a sort.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's worse than you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It usually is.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That girl will rain destruction down on you and your ship. She's an albatross, Captain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Operative moves further into the room. Whenever he moves, Mal counters.</context>
      <utterance>Way I remember it, albatross was a ship's good luck... til some idiot killed it.  Yes, I've read a poem. Try not to faint.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen your war record. I know how you must feel about the Alliance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fair to say. But I have to hope you understand you can't beat us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got no need to beat you. I just wanna go my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you can do that, once you let me take the girl back home. Give me the opportunity to help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I gotta do is let you take one more thing away from me. I've had a lot of things taken in my time. And it may just be that this is one too many.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This psychotic, potentially murderous girl who can't have the slightest awareness of your protection. This is where you "draw the line".</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'm a whimsical soul.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a number of lives that hang in the balance here. Lives under your care. Are they as whimsical as yourself?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Operative is stopped by this. Unhappily, he continues:</context>
      <utterance>I got no notion that I'm being heroical at all. Any more than I think you're really just a harmless bureaucrat come to help me out. You move like a killer.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal pulls a small device, clipped wires sticking out all around it, and tosses it to the Operative.</context>
      <utterance>I have a warship in deep orbit, Captain. We locked on to Serenity's pulse beacon the moment you hit atmo. I can speak a word and send a missile to that exact location inside of three minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do that, best make peace with your dear and fluffy lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pulse beacon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Advice from an old tracker: you J wanna find someone, use your eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long do you think you can really run from us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, a jack-rabbit, me. 'Sides, I never credited the Alliance with an over-abundance of brains. And if you're the best they got...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Reynolds, I should tell you so that you don't waste your time: You can't make me angry.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal smiles -- then glares at Inara, mouthing "Hey!"</context>
      <utterance>Oh please. Spend an hour with him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need her, Captain. River is... my purpose and I will gather her to me. The brother as well. Whatever else happens is incidental. In the greater scheme.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is it that the greater scheme always makes everything not that great?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to resolve this like civilized men. I'm not threatening you. I'm unarmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws and shoots the Operative in the chest. The Operative goes down as Mal grabs Inara, moves for the-doorway. The Operative is on him in a second, choke-hold from behind.</context>
      <utterance>Great!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses Mal hard against a wall, spinning and blocking a blow from Inara -- she is clearly trained in martial arts, but he flat-heels her to the ground within seconds. Mal is going for his gun again, turning, and the Operative kicks him in the face, sends him back, gun flying. Mal gets to his feet and they square off. Mal breathing hard, nose dripping blood. The Operative perfectly poised, waiting.</context>
      <utterance>I am of course wearing full body armor. I'm not a moron.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No back up? We're making an awful ruckus...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll come when they're needed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd start whistling.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come at each other. The Operative is the much better trained -- he's fluid, his blows sparse and deadly.</context>
      <utterance>Captain, what do you think is going to happen here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing here is what it seems.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This isn't the grand arena.</context>
      <utterance>He's not the plucky hero. The Alliance isn't some evil empire.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to look: the incense stick burns away -- rather like a fuse -- and FLASHES in an explosion of light and sound.</context>
      <utterance>And that's not incense.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>.I had him...</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that I was winning!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALLIANCE SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody dives for cover. The moment they do, Mal and Inara race into the shuttle, Mal sweeping up the grenade just as the last light goes out and nothing happens. One soldier turns to look and Mal shoots him back down as the door shuts on him and Inara.</context>
      <utterance>Grenade!</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang on to something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4 You sure you remember how it -- He nearly falls over as:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you to hang on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. </mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget the pulse beacon, there has to be another way to track the ship -- get a read on the nav sat. It's a registered transport, you must be able to locate --</utterance>
   <speaker>ENSIGN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you found a nav sat trajectory?</utterance>
   <speaker>ENSIGN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir... we've found seven. The Operative looks more unhappy than angry.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does he think this is a game?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That ain't so hard --</context>
      <utterance>Why, 'cause this guy beat up Mal?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't beat me up --</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because he's a believer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I honestly think the only reason we haven't been blown out of the air is that he needs to see her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Needs to see her why?</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm uncertain. I would say to be sure of the kill, but... I just know he'll kill us all to get to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So no hope of a reward, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he mention a deal of any kind?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give the two of them up. Go my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which you was all ready to do not a day ago. What went sour?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cutting them loose ain't the same as handing them over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That so? 'Cause the corpse I'm about to become is having trouble telling the difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he say anything about a "Miranda"?</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know who or what, but it's on River's mind. Conjure it might be the reason he's after her.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think maybe it poses some kind of threat to the Alliance?</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we care? Are we caring about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You dumbass hogs, the only people she's a threat to is us on this boat!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, we get back to Haven in a 'r/ few hours time --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiding under the Shepherd's skirts, that's a manful scheme --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna run this ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you can't!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do a damn sight better job'n you. Getting us lashed over a couple of strays...  No offense, Doc, I think it's noble as a grape the way you look to River, but she ain't my sister  and she ain't your crew. Oh, and neither is she exactly helpless! So where's it writ we gotta lay down our lives for her, which is what you've steered us toward.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't start this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>No, the Alliance starts the war -- and then you volunteer. Battle of Serenity, Mal: besides Zoe here, how many --  -- I'm talkin' at you -- how many men in your platoon came out of there alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna leave this room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stalks upstairs. There's a quiet moment.</context>
      <utterance>You're damn right I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal turns, eyeing her.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't the war, Mal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you telling me that because you think I don't know --</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You came to the training house looking for a fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to know who I'm dealing with. I've seen too many versions of you to be sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I start fighting a war I guarantee you'll see something new.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll get off. River and I'll get off at Haven and find some --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's saying that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody besides Jayne is saying that.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you fog things up. You always have -- you spin me about. I wish like hell you was elsewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No trouble now, little crazy person... we're going for a nice</utterance>
   <speaker>I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door and she is on him in an instant, whip blow to the throat, the nose -- he fires wildly as she jumps on him, wraps her arms around his neck and topples him back --</context>
      <utterance>shuttle ride --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's sealed off the bridge. I do not like her there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tosses him a bolt remover. He starts pulling a bolt out of a panel on the wall, tells Zoe:</context>
      <utterance>Cap'n!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pops the panel off and starts wriggling in among the wires.</context>
      <utterance>Check the shuttles. She coulda 40 snuck in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can it be there's a whole planet called Miranda and none of us knowed that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because there isn't one. It's a blackrock. Uninhabitable. Terraforming didn't hold, or somesuch. Few settlers died.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to show them. I didn't know if you were going to make me sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could've asked...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a tick, yeah! Some ten years back, before the war. There was call for workers to settle on Miranda, my daddy talked about going. I should've recalled...</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there's nothing about it on the Cortex -- History, Astronomy... it's not in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half of writing history is hiding the truth. There's something on this rock the Alliance doesn't want known.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right at the edge of the Burnham Quadrant, right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoah, no, no --</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a bad notion --</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hits some commands on the screen, pulls back to reveal a couple of other planets near Miranda.</context>
      <utterance>Show them the bad...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is us, see? And here's Miranda. All along here, this dead space in between, that's Reaver territory.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They just float out there, sending out raiding parties --</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe a hundred ships. And more every year. You go through that you're signing up to be a banquet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at his monitors, looks ahead...</context>
      <utterance>I'm on board with the run and hide scenario -- and we are just about...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops, looking at the ground by the steeple. There is the body on the ground, face down. The child she played with at dinner. Kaylee stares, at first uncomprehending. ANGLE: MAL, moving in the other direction, approaches the cannon, Jayne behind him. He stops and sees: Book, lying by the cannon, torn up badly from the waist down.</context>
      <utterance>Shepherd? Shepherd Book!</utterance>
   <speaker>4 MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to the Shepherd, grabs his searching hand.</context>
      <utterance>Get the Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shepherd... Don't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't go far...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't've been you. I'm so sorry, it was... they should've hit us. They should've hit me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That crossed my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode>ROUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shot him down --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I killed the ship... that killed us. Not... very Christian of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did what's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming from you, that means... almost nothing... HNAAH! Ah, I'm long gone...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doc'll bring you round. I look to be bored by many more sermons 'fore you slip -- don't move --</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm not one of your crew.</context>
      <utterance>Can't... order me around, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Book coughs up blood, grabbing Mal. Urgent, almost angry.</context>
      <utterance>Yes you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... it's on you now... all this death, this shit... you have to find a course. This can't mean nothing. River... you have to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Book grabs Mal's face, talks as though replying to something:</context>
      <utterance>Come on, keep it up --</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stopped. His hand slips away, his blood leaving a distinct print on Mal's face. Jayne and Simon run up,Simon slowing down -- going to the e he's-dead.----Zne -a r.7-1, ;,,,r them as Jayne looks around him, Mal still fixed on Book.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care what you believe! Just... believe it. Whatever you have to... His breathing becomes laboured. Hitched.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come they ain't waiting? They know'd we was coming, how come they only sent one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zoe realizes the answer, turns to Wash.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get on the Cortex. Wave the Sanchez brothers, Li Shen -- anyone whose ever sheltered us after a heist. Tell them to get out. Get out now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>V0 I'm sorry. But I cannot let you hide and I cannot let you run. Things become... extreme. And we wish for another way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk at me like a righteous man. You are a killer of children.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When God wanted Pharaoh to release His people from bondage -- you know the story? He didn't ask. He sent his plagues down upon Egypt. That's me, Captain. The path to peace is paved with corpses. It's always been so.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So me and mine got to lie down and</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to live there. How could you think -- there's no place for me there, any more than 40 there is for you. Malcolm, I'm a monster. What I do is evil, I've no illusions about it. But it must be done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Do you know why?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not my place to ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will never see River Tam. I'm telling you this.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe not. But you'll keep her close now, and when I blow Serenity out of the air, this will be ended. You're so terribly out of your depth, Captain. Your old boat can't take the pressure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She ain't buckled yet. And the 40 only reason you're talking such a lot is you can't get a fix on us.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, your scrambler's code is too old for our seekers. You love that, yes? The small triumph over modernity. You really are the noble savage.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody -- ever -- calls me noble.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's what's going to kill you, Malcolm. Nobility. It confuses your text, which is self-interest. And sin.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only- many-I-know-who still --bel i-eved- in sin just died by your hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you believe in?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a solitary thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something changes in Mal's expression.</context>
      <utterance>If that were true, you'd be nothing more than a Reaver.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>Mal flicks a switch and every screen goes dark.</context>
      <utterance>But then, maybe you're not that far from --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get these bodies together.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got time for gravedigging?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zoe, you and Simon are gonna rope V0 'em together. Five or six of 'em. I want them laid out on the nose of our ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you insane?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, the bodies...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kaylee, I need you to muck the reactor core, just enough to leave a trail and make it read like we're flying without containment, not enough to fry us.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These people are our friends --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kaylee, you got a day's work to do and two hours to do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>87.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MAL   Jayne, you and Wash hoist up that cannon mount. Goes right on top.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Piece or two of the other ship, stick it on. Any place you can tear hull without inner breach, do that too.  And we're gonna need paint. We're gonna need red paint.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir. Do you really mean to turn our home into an abomination so we can make a suicidal attempt at passing through Reaver space?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean to live. I mean for us to live. The Alliance won't have that, so we go where they won't follow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And everybody (save River) is talking at once:</context>
      <utterance>V0 God's balls, there's no way we're going out there!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the point of living if you sink to the level of a savage --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, we should talk this over --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't takin' orders from a man has lost his brainstem -- , -Mal pule-s-his- in his face, steps back, hand on his.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks through the group, toward the smashed cockpit of the Alliance fighter. Struggling to get out is the badly wounded pilot. He sees Mal coming and raises his hands in surrender. Mal shoots him in the head, turns back.</context>
      <utterance>This is how it works. Anybody doesn't wanna fly with me anymore, this is your port of harbour. There's a lot of fine ways to die. I'm not waiting for the Alliance to choose mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>He grabs a body -- drops it at Zoe's feet as he heads toward the ship.</context>
      <utterance>I mean to confound those killers, and take my shot at getting to Miranda, maybe finding out what all I'm dying for. That's my theme now. So I hear a word out of any of you that ain't helping me out or taking your leave I will fucking shoot you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get to work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up: she's in the corner looking through that trunk of hers, hands on a long oilcloth wrapped around something.</context>
      <utterance>Mal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>I NARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figured that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything of use in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts it down and crosses to the bed. He sits by her.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to stay in the shuttle, you know. There's empty rooms, if you wanna sleep awhile.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think anyone's set to sleep? Simon's portioning out overdoses of morphine, just in case.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheerful fellow.  Did you really miss this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. He doesn't look at her when he asks:</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes... Not so much right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Site does lo9}E-at-- t -m-</context>
      <utterance>Why did you leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you ask me not to?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>90.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dissatisfied, Mal rises.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both want to say more. They don't. He goes.</context>
      <utterance>I, uh, I'd better go check on the VW crew. See how the inevitable mutiny is coming along.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every reading I'm getting says normal. Oceans, land masses... no tectonic instability or radiation.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but no power, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. Something. Might be a beacon, but it's awful weak.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>V0 MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gravity's Earthnorm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal pulls off his helmet. Breathes, looking around him.</context>
      <utterance>02 levels check, pressure... if there's anything wrong the scanner isn't reading it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIDER ANGLE: They're in a CITY. Gleaming metal, spread out for miles in every direction. Portions decimated by fires long since cold, others overgrown with weeds, but mostly intact. But silent, as if trapped in amber.</context>
      <utterance>Well something sure as hell ain't right...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--ai-n-lt the settlement-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No entry wound, fractures...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poison?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>O . S . </mode>
      <context>ANGLE: JAYNE is by a downed hovercraft. Inside are three skeletons: two grown-ups and a small child. Clothes in better condition, and again no sign of violence.</context>
      <utterance>Got another one!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE: RIVER is quietly becoming more and more upset. CLOSE ON: KAYLEE walks in front of an office building, staying away from the cars as she hears:</context>
      <utterance>They's all just sittin'. Didn't crash...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>pressed up against the glass wall right behind her. Mouth open, skin dead blue, terribly skinny... a thing to haunt.</context>
      <utterance>Couple more here... 0 0 orpse _of_aman is</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kaylee... Come this way. Come here. Don't -- But she looks --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- and steps back, horrified, as the others approach. It's an office. About half the employees are there, in chairs or on the ground, all in the same state as the first fellow. We see ANGLES of the corpses as the gang evaluates...</context>
      <utterance>GAAAAaaoh God --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come they're preserved?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Place must've gone hermetic when the power blew. Sealed 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're they doing? What's everybody doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no discoloration, nobody's doubled over or showing signs of pain...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's gasses that kill painless, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they didn't fall down. None of them. They just lay down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More than anything, it looks like starvation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody want to bet there's plenty of food around?</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They notice River now, in the middle of the street, keening. She drops to her knees, clutching her head.</context>
      <utterance>They just lay down...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>, make them stop, they're everywhere, every city every house every room, they're all inside me, I can hear them all and they're saying nothing! GET UP! PLEASE, GET THEM UP! , please God make me a stone...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>UPSET</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's starting to damage my calm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jayne --</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's right! Everybody's dead! This whole world is dead for no reason!</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get to the beacon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a loud bang somewhere behind her -- she starts, gathers herself.</context>
      <utterance>-- just a few of the images we've recorded, and you can see it isn't.. it isn't what we thought. There's been no war here, and no terraforming event. The environment is stable. It's the Pax, the G-32 Paxilon Hydroclorate that we added to the air processors. It's...  .well it works... it was supposed to calm the population, weed out aggression. Make a peaceful... it worked. The people here stopped fighting. And then they stopped everything else. They stopped going to work, stopped breeding... talking... eating...  There's thirty million people here and they all just let themselves die. They didn't even kill themselves. They just... most starved. When they stopped working the power grids, there were overloads, fires -- people burned to death sitting in their V0 chairs. Just sitting.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARON</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>The bang again.</context>
      <utterance>I have to be quick. There was no one working the receptors when we landed, so we hit pretty hard. We can't leave. We can't take any of the local transports because...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARON</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>They've become...</context>
      <utterance>There are people... they're not people... about a tenth of a percent of the population had the opposite reaction to the Pax. Their aggressor response increased... beyond madness.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode>QUIETLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reavers... they made them...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She whirls, grabs a gun and fires -- then aims the gun at her own head - but a Reaver is on her, knocks the gun away and bites her face -- She screams continuously as the Reaver tops her, biting at her and tearing at her clothes, at her skin.</context>
      <utterance>I won't live to report this, and we haven't got power to... people have to know...  We meant it for the best... to make people safer... to... God!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>QUIETLY</mode>
      <context>Wash does, nobody saying anything.</context>
      <utterance>Turn it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>10</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mal walks outside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seen so much death... I been on fields carpeted with bodies, friends and enemies -- I seen men and women blown to messes no further from me than you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mal...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fighting.</context>
      <utterance>But every single one of those people died on their feet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>River...</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, wet eyes full of clarity.</context>
      <utterance>I'm all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>There is a beat as he eyes them all.</context>
      <utterance>You all got on this boat for different reasons, but you all V0 come to the same place. So now I'm asking more of you than I have before. Maybe all. 'Cause as sure as I know anything I know this: They will try again. Maybe on another world, maybe on this very ground, swept clean. A year from now, ten, they'll swing back to the belief that they can make people... better. And I do not hold to that. So no more running. I aim to misbehave.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By way of emphasis he loudly cocks his big-ass rifle. Mal takes in the fact that Jayne has spoken for them all.</context>
      <utterance>My grandma always told me: if you can't do something smart, do something right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That the same grandma told you 4 there was an evil dwarf spirit living in your well?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>NODDING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was a fun grandma.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we have a plan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr Universe. We haven't the equipment to broadwave this code, but he can put it on every screen for thirty worlds. He's pretty damn close, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Based on our orbital trajectories, he reached optimum proximity just before our sunset. If we make a direct run within the hour we're only 67,332 miles out. At full burn we'd reach him inside of three- hours .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still got the Reavers, and probably the Alliance between us and him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a fair bet the Alliance knows about Mr Universe. They're gonna see this coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a long moment, his jaw tightening imperceptibly.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON: One of Serenity's jet engines, as it FIRES up.</context>
      <utterance>They're not gonna see this coming.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MR UNIVERSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's no problem! Bring it on bring it on bring it on! From here to the eyes and ears of the 'verse, that's my motto, or it might be if I start having a motto.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We won't be long.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR UNIVERSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna get caught in the ion cloud, it'll play merry hob with your radar, but pretty pretty lights and a few miles after you'll be right in my orbit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>ON SCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll let us know if anyone else comes at you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HELMSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm reading activity in the cloud.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not with fire...</context>
      <utterance>Lock and fire on my command.  You should have let me see her. We should have done this as men.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELMSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>,Wd</context>
      <utterance>Sir!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vessel in range, lock on...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>ADMIRINGLY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bastard's not even changing course...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not good...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELMSMAN</speaker>
      <mode>FREAKING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Target the Reavers!  Target the Reavers! Target everyone! Somebody FIRE!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're too close for them to arm --</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is gonna be very tight --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode>ENTERING</mode>
      <context>V0 Zoe and Mal shoot a look at Jayne.</context>
      <utterance>Hey look, we're upside down.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am a leaf on the wind, watch how I soar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>J INT. BRIDGE - CONTINUING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mal looks out at the chaos...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are suddenly JOLTED by a glancing blow from another ship -- Wash struggles to control her --</context>
      <utterance>Chickens come home to roost...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell --</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode>PANICKY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay! I am a leaf on the wind!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Wash are frantically flipping buttons -- the ship whirs to a semblance of life - -</context>
      <utterance>Where's the back up? Where's the back up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back up reads at 20%.. - Can you get us down?</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna have to glide her in!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will that work?</utterance>
   <speaker>WASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>140 Long as that landing strip is made of fluffy pillows...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Strap yourselves to something!</context>
      <utterance>Everybody to the upper decks!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The entire crew piles out, all heavily bedecked with weapons.</context>
      <utterance>Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Head inside!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zoe slows, looking around her.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. Jayne, rearguard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir.  This is a good hold point_</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all stay together --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. They have to come through here; they'll bottleneck and we can thin 'em out. We get pushed ,oO back there's the blast doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can rig 'em so they won't re- open once they close.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then shut 'em and hide til --</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to draw them til it's done. This is the place. We'll buy you the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move those crates back there for cover -- and make sure they ain't filled with anything goes boom.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nobody (but River) realized he wasn't there. Zoe is dead calm. ,No ZOE He ain't comin'. Everybody takes that in, Kaylee's eyes welling up.</context>
      <utterance>Wait, Wash -- where's Wash?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear savage SCREAMS from the hanger -- they're approaching. Mal moves to the door, Jayne beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Move the gorram crates! Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE: HIS POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to Jayne.</context>
      <utterance>Reavers rush toward them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jayne smiles grimly, tosses Mal a grenade as he pops his own and fastballs it at the Reavers.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me you brought 'em this time...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up at him.</context>
      <utterance>Zoe... are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do the job, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off -- passes Inara, the two of them holding a look for as long as they can. Then he's in the elevator and gone. Jayne moves over to Zoe.</context>
      <utterance>You hold. Hold till I'm back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain's right. Can't be thinking on revenge if we're gonna get through this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks back at their army: A companion, a doctor, a mechanic and a more-than-usually out of it River. A beat, and he looks back at Zoe with forlorn hope:</context>
      <utterance>You really think any of us are gonna get through this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOVEBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal stops.</context>
      <utterance>Mal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOVEBOT</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guy killed me, Mal. He killed me with a sword. How weird is that? I got... a short span here... they destroyed my equipment but I have a back-up unit... bottom of the complex, right over the generator. Hard to get to. I know they missed it. They can't stop the signal, Mal. They can never stop the signal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't shut them up...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay... -</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BANG as a body slams against the door.</context>
      <utterance>They're all made up of rage. I can't...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just stay low. I'm right here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She picked a sweet bung of a time to go helpless on us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jayne and I take the first wave. Nobody shoots less they get past our fire. Simon moves to Kaylee, who is shaky as hell. The bangs on the door continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I didn't plan on going out like this. I think we did right, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him with soft surprise.</context>
      <utterance>I never planned... anything. I just wanted to keep River safe. Spent so much time on Serenity trying to find us a home I never realized I already had.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My one true regret in all this is never being with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With me? You mean to say, as, sex?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode>SMILES</mode>
      <context>Kaylee snaps her cartridge home with way more precision than we might expect from her, takes steady aim at the door.</context>
      <utterance>I mean to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks at her a moment, then turns his attention to the door. Inara come up into frame with the contents of the oilcloth: a bow and arrow, which she pulls back with focused grace. ANGLE: THE DOOR starts to come off its hinges.</context>
      <utterance>Hell with this. I'm gonna live.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guy killed me, Mal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard to get to. That's a fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she is in a trance, and we see beneath the calm, to the bubbling magma of rage that keeps her firing, single shots, each one a kill, till five men down and she's out of ammo. The sixth comes at her swinging a blade and she blocks, the precision of military training still in her as she flips him, wresting the blade free and swinging it down out of frame, bringing it up bloody, swinging again as the door bursts open and she's rushed from behind --- But Jayne totes an automatic, sprays killing fire on the lot, moving forward himself --</context>
      <utterance>Zoe... Gorramnit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I s</context>
      <utterance>Shot me in the back. I haven't... made you angry, have I?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a lot of innocent people in the air being killed right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's no wise-ass attitude in him now. They stand, facing off at ten paces.</context>
      <utterance>You have no idea how true that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know the secret now. The truth that burned up River Tam's brain and set you after her. And the rest of the 'verse is gonna know it too. 'Cause they need to.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really believe that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>V0</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Operative raises his gun -- but Mal is the quickdraw master, shoots the gun out of the Operative's hand and gets two hits to the chest (armored) before he makes it to cover.</context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, that ain't exactly plan</utterance>
   <speaker>A..</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Operative hides behind some machinery. Tries to peek out at Mal -- and more shots send him scrambling back to cover. Mal holsters his gun and jumps for the rung above him, starts going hand over hand to the island, moving as fast as he can. The Operative sees his moment, dives for his gun -- but it's been ruined by Mal's shot. He looks over at Mal with death in his eyes. He runs at the railing, vaults off it, and grabs a chain -- it snaps and he swings, grabbing another. He reaches Mal and double kicks him from behind -- Mal flies 4 off the rung but grabs a chain -- he tries to kick at the Operative, but the guy is frikkin' Tarzan, he climbs up and pulls a lever releasing one end of Mal's chain -- Mal goes swinging, smacks into the wall six feet below the platform. He scrambles up just as the Operative swings himself toward the platform from above.</context>
      <utterance>He drops out his cartridge and slams another in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spine's intact --</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon pulls a spraycan from his bag, sprays the wound with a foam that hardens instantly into an elastic covering.</context>
      <utterance>Just gimme a bandage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a hit in the shoulder, grimaces and keeps firing. River watches, the gun limp in her hand. Kaylee grabs it and starts another round -- but she's peppered with dart-like projectiles. She screams and drops the weapon, pulling the projectiles from her -- Inara helps her up, pulls her back as Zoe shouts:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, now you're likin' guns, huh? Cheaters!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone stumbles or is dragged into the inner corridor. Inara hits the controls and the doors start to close, from each side and above and below. Then, when the hole is maybe four by four, they stop.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody fall back! Fall back!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jayne! Grenade!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses it through the hole. Zoe doesn't even flinch from the blast as she thinks.</context>
      <utterance>Very last one...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna get in --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can close it... from outside...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to stand, fails.</context>
      <utterance>No one's coming back from that...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much ammo do we have?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inara is by the elevator, pounding for it to come.---</context>
      <utterance>We got three full cartridges and my swingin' cod. That's all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lift isn't moving...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kaylee cries out and Simon moves to her.</context>
      <utterance>When they come, try to plug the hole with 'em...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm starting to lose some feeling here... I think there's something in them darts they throwed at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands, looking around him. His bag is over by Zoe.</context>
      <utterance>Lie still. I'm gonna give you something to counteract the --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>and SHKOWW!, the bullet takes him in the belly -- everything suddenly moving very slowly as he spins slightly, one foot lifted, a confused expression on his face -- then speeding right back up as he slams down on his back, gasping for air. River's mouth opens in a scream she doesn't make. Blood spreads from Simon's belly. Inara rushes to him, grabs cloth and puts pressure on the wound, puts Simon's hand on it.</context>
      <utterance>My bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep pressure here...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is by his side, takes his hand. She has a kind of serenity to her, like she understands something now.</context>
      <utterance>My bag. Need... adrenaline... and a shot of calaphar for Kaylee... I can't... River...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>River... I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights go out. Everyone looks about them. Jayne fires again, but all the sound has bled out save these two.</context>
      <utterance>No. No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate to... leave...</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands as the emergency lights come on, giving her face an unearthly glow as she looks down at him.</context>
      <utterance>You won't. You take care of me, Simon. You've always taken care of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>She's running so fast, nobody has time to react til she DIVES through the hole in the doors, then Simon SCREAMS her name, the scream following us back into the Black Room where River lands in a perfect roll, comes up in a room full of Reavers. Without a moment's hesitation she makes it to the panel, gets the doors closing. She dodges a blade, but a blow to,the back of the head shakes her. She weaves around a couple of Reavers to get to the closing doors, but at the last second her ankle is grabbed and pulled out from under her. The last thing we see is her being dragged back as they swarm over her. ANGLE: THE BLAST DOORS, as they shut with a shuddering RLUNG.</context>
      <utterance>My turn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what your sin is, Malcolm?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>He pulls the sword out, grimacing. Holds it over the Operative. The smile gone.</context>
      <utterance>But right now...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>He stabs down at his foe's face -- but the Operative rolls out of the way, kicks Mal from the ground and is up in a second, grabbing Mal's sword hand -- the sword drops -- and punching him repeatedly in his stomach wound.</context>
      <utterance>vao I'm gonna have to go with Wrath.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAYNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You suppose he got through? Think Mal got the word out?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He got through. I know he got through.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Operative spins him and DIGS his bunched fingers right into the same nerve cluster that he paralyzed Doctor Mathias with. Mal goes rigid, his face a rictus of pain. The Operative goes near the railing and retrieves his sword. Mal trembles, trying to move -- but nothing happens.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>He lunges -- and Mal twists gracefully out of the way, grabbing the Operative's swordhand and pulling it forward -- while driving his elbow into the Operative's neck with staggering force.</context>
      <utterance>You should know there's no shame in this. You've done remarkable things. But you're fighting a war you've already lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Operative drops the blade, mouth open, stumbling back, unable to make a sound. Mal spins him, grabbing both his arms and working his own through them in a twisted full nelson -- then bringing his arms up suddenly, the Operative's mouth going wider as we hear his arms crack. Mal drops him sitting against the railing, picks up his sword, saying:</context>
      <utterance>Iwo Well, I'm known for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>He squats down, looks the Operative in the face.</context>
      <utterance>Piece a shrapnel tore up that nerve cluster my first tour. Had it moved.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>He reaches over the railing, pulls the back of the Operative's jacket through and shoves the sword through the fabric, pinning the Operative in his sitting position.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry 'bout the throat. Expect you'd wanna say your famous last MW words now. Just one trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't gonna kill you. He moves to the console, starts prepping it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>He inserts the cylinder, turns it slightly. It hums to life.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, I'm gonna grant your greatest wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>He hits "send all". The cylinder lights up and the broadcast V0 begins. Here it is projected as a two-dimensional image on the clear plastic partition, right in front of the Operative. There are images first of the city -- of bodies, on the street, in homes and offices... image after image, jus.t as we saw on the research vessel -- and in River's mind.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna show you a world without sin.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARON</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>Mal hits the controls and a ramp extends towards the other side. He begins to cross. Never even looks back. On the Operative, trapped, watching in growing horror...</context>
      <utterance>These are some of the first sites we scouted on Miranda. There is no one living on this planet. There is no one...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>140 MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zoe looks at the badly wounded Simon, is about to give a report -- and the doors start to open behind her. Everyone turns to look, those who can feebly raising weapons, as the square iris of the opening blast doors widens to reveal River, standing alone. She is holding two Reaver blades, is bloody but unbowed. And the only one alive. We hold on her a moment, then the wall behind her is ripped completely away. Behind it, grappling hooks chained to a huge tractor pull the wall away as through the smoke come some fifteen Alliance soldiers, who line up, rifles trained on our gang...</context>
      <utterance>It's done. Report?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drop your weapons! Drop 'em now!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we engage? Do we engage?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Operative stands just under the canopy of the nose of the ship, framed by the rain behind.</context>
      <utterance>If you're here to tell me we ain't finished... then we will be real quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what an uproar you've caused? Protests, riots -- cries for a recall of the entire Parliament.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode>TURNING</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've seen the broadwaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be pleased.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Verse wakes up a spell. Won't be long 'fore she rolls right over and falls back asleep. Taint my worry.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't guarantee they won't come after you. The Parliament. They have a hundred men like me and they are not forgiving.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That don't bode especially well for you... giving the order to let us go, patching up our hurt...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told them the Tams were no longer a threat -- damage done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>123.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>THE OPERATIVE  They might listen, but... I think they know I'm no longer their man.</utterance>
   <speaker>W MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They take you down, I don't expect to grieve overmuch. Like to kill you myself, I see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mal looks at him a moment, then picks up his gear to head inside. The Operative starts away into the rain, then stops to look up at the nose of the ship. ANGLE: the newly painted Serenity, standing tall in the rain.</context>
      <utterance>You won't. There is...  .nothing left to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE OPERATIVE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTINUING</mode>
      <context>Mal hits the button to close the inner doors, steps inside as they slide together. Glances at the Operative, unimpressed.</context>
      <utterance>"Serenity". You lost everything in that battle. Everything you had, everything you were... how did you go on?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="166" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Operative watches the door shut. A moment, and he goes.</context>
      <utterance>You still standing there when the engine starts, you never will figure it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a whiner...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, we have a green light. Inspection's pos and we're clear for upthrust.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think she'll hold together?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="167" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's tore up plenty. But she'll fly true.</utterance>
   <speaker>VW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A beat between them before:</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Could be bumpy.</context>
      <utterance>Make sure everything's secure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes off and Mal heads up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Always is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="168" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're taking her out. Should be about a day's ride to get you back to your girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="169" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ready to get off this heap and back to a civilized life?</utterance>
   <speaker>INARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, a smile in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I, uh...  I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and heads into the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>Good answer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="170" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>V0 River is in the copilot's seat, looking intently at the screens and buttons.</context>
      <utterance>You gonna ride shotgun, help me fly?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is flipping switches without even looking, as the ship hums to life.</context>
      <utterance>Think you can work out how to get her in the --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="171" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, clearly some aptitude for the... but it ain't all buttons A0 and charts, . You know what the first rule of flying is? Well, I suppose you do, since you already know what I'm about to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks out at the rain on his windows, at his screens, taking her up as he says:</context>
      <utterance>I do. But I like to hear you say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>River also looks out at the sky.</context>
      <utterance>Love. You can learn all the math in the 'verse, but you take a boat in the air you don't love, she'll shake you off just as sure as the turning of worlds. Love keeps her in the air when she oughta fall down, tells you she's hurting 'fore she keens. Makes her a home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="172" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Storm's getting worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll pass through it soon enough.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
