<movie id="493" title="Signs">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham looks around -- panic growing in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Where are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham and Merrill in unison turn in the direction of the YELLING. They look away from the house, across the yard and into THE THICK WALL OF CROPS.</context>
      <utterance>Daaaad!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BO stands peacefully lost in her thoughts. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Bo where's Morgan?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo finally looks at her father. Beat. She smiles softly.</context>
      <utterance>Bo?</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Are you in my dreams too?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't a --</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Graham looks in the direction of THE BOY'S VOICE. He's close. Graham picks up Bo and rushes through the crops. He finds MORGAN standing with his hands in the pockets of his pajama bottoms. DOGS ARE BARKING NEARBY.</context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham puts Bo on the ground and moves right in front of Morgan. The ten-year old boy looks deep in thought. Graham takes hold of Morgan's chin and turns his face so he's looking straight at him.</context>
      <utterance>Morgan what's happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Morgan's eyes reveal he's come to some answer.</context>
      <utterance>Are... you... hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. THE DOGS KEEP BARKING.</context>
      <utterance>I think God did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan takes hold of his father's unshaven chin and turns his face. Graham is forced to look to his right. Beat. Graham sees something. Graham Hess slowly rises to his feet. He starts moving forward towards something. He walks through a thin layer of crops and emerges in a clearing. Two German Shepherds are running back and forth. They are clearly agitated. Graham looks around at the THOUSANDS OF CORN STALKS LYING</context>
      <utterance>Did what Morgan?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham stokes the coals with a LONG BARBECUE FORK.</context>
      <utterance>... Lee actually the reason I'm calling is about Lionel.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was he at home last night with you or was he out and about with the Wolfington brothers? Graham moves around from behind the barbecue and heads towards the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there was a little mischief done to our crops last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham steps through the back screen door into his</context>
      <utterance>I know he's a fine boy... No one's saying otherwise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen Lee, I don't even mind if it was him. You could just talk to him and that would be enough for me... See it was kind of strange finding the crops like that. The kids were... confused by it. It would take the strangeness away if we knew it was Lionel and the Wolfington brothers just messing around...  The movies...  Are you sure?  Okay, then... Thank you for your patience Lee. Graham turns off the phone. He turns to put it on the counter and realizes his children are seated on the kitchen floor with one of their two German Shepherds. There is a LARGE PUDDLE on the kitchen tiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham looks at the majestic dog. It's shivering.</context>
      <utterance>Houdini peed. I think he's sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan and Bo lead their dog out with worried expressions on their faces. Graham grabs a handful of paper towels and places it on the puddle of urine. The DOORBELL rings with Graham still on his knees on the kitchen floor. He leans back so he can see down the hall. A balding police officer stands on the other side of the screen door.</context>
      <utterance>Take him outside. I'll call Dr. Reynolds.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OFFICER EDGAR PASKI nods that he knows.</context>
      <utterance>That was quick Edgar. I only called you boys about two hours ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Graham stares at Officer Paski.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Kindleman twisted her ankle as she put it, "diving for her life" when a bunch of school kids rode down the sidewalk on skateboards. She went down to Thorton's store this morning and started spitting on the new skateboards. Spitting! By the time I got there, Mrs. Kindleman had sprayed the whole damn place... She must have had a cold or something. It was enough to turn a grown man's stomach.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what happened to your crops?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's contaminated.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drinks.</context>
      <utterance>You don't even know what that word means.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not contaminated. It's just tap water. Pour it in his bowl.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It tastes funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Houdini just sits staring at them. He is not shivering. He doesn't drink. He is unnaturally still. Bo pushes the bowl closer.</context>
      <utterance>He licks his butt everyday. He's not going to mind. Bo shrugs and pours it into the bowl. Beat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOUDINI BEGINS TO GROWL. Bo stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Houdini?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Houdini crouches down.</context>
      <utterance>Bo don't run.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong boy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The German Shepherd trembles. His body tightens. He's about to leap. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it Houdini!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bo, run.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the strangest thing Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't call me Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't call me Father. It's just Graham now.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stands in awkward silence fifty feet away from each other. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said something was strange. What's strange?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The footprints.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about them?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are none.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not broken.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham looks around at the hundreds of thousands of corn stalks bent over each other in a perfect wave.</context>
      <utterance>What kind of machine can bend a stalk of corn over without cracking it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Can't be by hand... It's too perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham, nods in agreement. Officer Paski stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Doesn't sound much like Lionel Prichard and the Wolfington brothers. They can't take a piss without wetting the front of their pants.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Second thing this week I can't explain.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was the first thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some animals around the county exhibiting uncharacteristic behavior. Sometimes violent behavior. Theo Henry had two of his fingers bit off by his cow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like a virus.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a thought catch in Graham's eyes. He turns back and stares in the direction of the house. You can barely see the roof over the crops. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>No Father, they're edgy. On alert. Like they act when they smell a predator around... Peeing on themselves and everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't hear my children.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FORK DEEP IN ITS NECK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at Morgan as he slowly pulls an inhaler from his pocket and brings it to his mouth. He inhales the asthma spray. Beat. He lowers the inhaler so he can speak.</context>
      <utterance>Beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Graham stares at his ten-year old son.</context>
      <utterance>He wanted to kill Bo.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Morgan nods, "No." His tough exterior breaks as his face starts to tremble. He starts crying. Graham picks him up in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Did he hurt you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham reaches up for Bo. She has dirt and tears on her face. Beat. She slowly climbs down. Graham carries both his children as they cry in his arms. He starts towards the house. Merrill walks out from the back holding a bowl of food.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry Morgan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill sees Houdini lying under the jungle gym.</context>
      <utterance>I used a little Tabasco in the potato salad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Houdini's sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill stands still with potato salad in his hands. He nods. The children watch over their father's shoulder as Merrill runs to their other German Shepherd sitting quietly near the house and leads her by her collar across the yard to the shed. Graham reaches the porch of his house and opens the screen door. The last thing the children see as they enter the house, is the image of Officer Paski pulling the barbecue fork out of their dead dog's neck.</context>
      <utterance>Please tie up Isabelle to the back of the shed. Make sure the knot's tight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham stares off. Beat. He smiles a little.</context>
      <utterance>They're tough cookies, those two. They think Houdini's playing with you up there.  At least it got them to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay Miss Puzzle Master. I got one for you... What can make geometric shapes the size of a football field... and what would scare every animal in this county?  Have you figured it out yet?  You probably have...  Give me a hint Colleen... Is it bigger than a bread box?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>I saw a monster. Can I have a glass of water?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with the water next to your bed?</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham slowly gets up from the bed. He takes his daughter's hand and starts out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>It tastes old.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the rule about getting up in the middle of the night?</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only for pee or poop.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham leads his four-year old daughter down the darkened hall.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you thinking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you talk to mom when you're by yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It makes me feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does she ever answer back?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham's eyes drift to the bedroom window. A LARGE</context>
      <utterance>She doesn't answer me either. Beat. They both sit quietly for a moment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, this guy is trying to scare us. He's messed with our property, he's coming around the house. It's time for an ass whoopin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill opens the front door. It's pitch black outside. Merrill turn to Graham and gestures with his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>This is not an intelligent way to approach this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill brings his fingers together at the end of a circle.</context>
      <utterance>We both go outside and move around the house in opposite directions. We act crazy, insane with anger. Make him crap in his pants and force him around till we meet up on the other side.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Explain, act crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Curse and stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to curse.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't mean it. It's just for show.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't sound natural when I curse.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just make noises then.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Explain noises.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to do this or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They HEAR MOVEMENT OUTSIDE. Merrill and Graham look out into the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>You want him coming in the house next time? Beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill and Graham go out the front door in opposite directions.</context>
      <utterance>On the count of three.  One... two... three.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham spots a LARGE FIGURE darting around the corner ahead of him.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhhh... I'm insane with anger.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've lost my mind! It's time for an ass whoopin'!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cursed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham's eyes drift above them.</context>
      <utterance>I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They follow the roof around the corner. They find themselves in the backyard. Their eyes catch movement away from the house. They just catch A GLIMPSE OF THE LARGE FIGURE as he disappears into the crops. The swing on the swing set is still moving from being hit. They stare across the yard silently. ALL WE HEAR IS THEIR</context>
      <utterance>He's on the roof.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was very dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it was.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't describe him at all? Don't you think that's find of odd?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It does seem kind of odd doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know whether to look for a midget or a --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He definitely wasn't a midget.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.  So he was tall?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would say so.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Over six feet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was very dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it was.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham and Merrill stare at Edgar Paski.</context>
      <utterance>We've established that.  Just tell me about his clothing then.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They keep staring. Edgar closes his pad.</context>
      <utterance>Was he wearing a Scottish kilt or jeans?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you two something. Don't be embarrassed by the answer. It is possible... Just possible now, you might have been chasing each other around? You said you went in opposite directions.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three men stand in the doorway. Edgar opens his pad.</context>
      <utterance>Edgar, it sounds as strange to me saying it, as it is to you hearing it. But we couldn't see him. He stayed mostly in the shadows. All we could make out was movement.  But I'll tell you something with absolute certainty. There was someone watching our house last night. He was looking in my children's windows and I want you to find him Edgar.  I need you to take this seriously, just incase, it is something serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan walks up to the front door. He holds up a baby monitor.</context>
      <utterance>I apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I use Bo's old baby monitor as a walkie-talkie?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It needs batteries.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three men follow Morgan into the house. They pass through the family room where Bo stands at the television. She is staring at the screen. ON THE SCREEN IS AERIAL</context>
      <utterance>Edgar, come inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How certain are you, that this was a male?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham opens one of the cabinets and pulls down some batteries. He hands them to Morgan.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know any girls can run like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are D's; I need double A's.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham starts out of the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>I have some upstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all move into the</context>
      <utterance>I don't know Merrill. I've seen some of those women on the Olympics. They could out run me easy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy got on the roof in like a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo nods and moves to the television. The pack of men follow Graham up the</context>
      <utterance>Bo, can you turn down the volume until Officer Paski leaves?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That roof is over ten feet high.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They arrive on the landing and follow Graham into his bedroom. He moves into his</context>
      <utterance>He's telling you the truth, Edgar. Whoever it was, is very strong and can jump pretty high.</utterance>
   <speaker>BATHROOM.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They all move in with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham takes the clock radio from the sink. Tries to open the back.</context>
      <utterance>They got women's high jumping in the Olympics. They got these Scandinavian women who could jump clean over me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham waves the radio. The men and Morgan move out of the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot, it needs a screw driver. I have double A's in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They moves down the STAIRS.</context>
      <utterance>I know you're making a point Edgar. I just don't know what it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo's cartoon is replaced by a special report news icon.</context>
      <utterance>Yesterday afternoon, an out of town woman stopped by the diner and started yelling and cussing cause they didn't have her favorite cigarettes at the vending machine. Scared a couple of customers. No one's seen her since... My point is, we don't know anything about the person you saw. We should just keep all possibilities available. They move through the FAMILY ROOM.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo starts looking around the couch. Graham stops before entering the kitchen. The group stops with him. He looks at Bo searching the couch. He walks over to the television. There are three glasses of water on the TV set. He stands next to the set. Doesn't see what's on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Dad, where's the remote?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo stops looking through the sofa cushions and looks to her father. Looks at the glass.</context>
      <utterance>Bo, you're too old to still be doing this. The rule is, you take a glass of water, you finish it.  Now what's wrong with this one?</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's dust in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This one?</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This one?</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Bo turns back to her search. Graham tucks the clock radio under his arm and collects the three glasses. He heads towards the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Morgan took a sip. It has his amoebas in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excluding the possibility that a female Scandinavian Olympian was running around outside our house last night, what else is a possibility?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They follow Graham and Morgan through the swinging door into the KITCHEN. Graham puts the glasses in the sink with a group of other half-filled water glasses and opens the drawer to pull out a screwdriver. He starts opening the clock radio.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not done asking questions and I don't appreciate the sarcasm.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham looks at Edgar.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have anyone who might have a grudge or something against you? Maybe a church member, who might not have liked the fact, that you left the church?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you owe anybody money? You can tell me off the record if you need too.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan hands Graham the baby monitor and Graham starts replacing the batteries.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is anything missing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham hands Morgan the monitor. He turns it ON. THERE IS A</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's still making the noises. It's broken.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan heads out of the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>It's old Morgan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar nods.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, I was out of line with that whole female Scandinavian Olympian thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Merrill walks out of the kitchen. Graham watches Edgar think it over.</context>
      <utterance>It's just that, I'm pretty strong and pretty fast. And I was running as fast as I could. And this guy...  He was just toying with us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan sits with his monitor next to Bo, who quietly watches the TV. Merrill and Graham squeeze in next to Morgan.</context>
      <utterance>Could everyone just take a seat on the couch. I have some preliminary thoughts.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Officer Paski walks towards the windows. Graham, Merrill and Morgan follow him with their eyes. Officer Paski walks next to the television.</context>
      <utterance>There are three possibilities here. We'll call them one, two and three. The level one scenario is that there is a sane individual, who for real reasons wants to do you harm. I really don't believe that's what we're looking at here. In my opinion, whoever this is, they don't want to do harm to you all. That's kind of clear.  The level two scenario is, this is a mentally unstable person who's fixated on you and your family. This is a possibility, but a very slim one.  I assure you I will treat all three possibilities carefully, but in all likely hood we are looking at what we'll call a level three scenario. He's a watcher. Someone who this is a game for. He's laying low. Doesn't want to be seen. But he wants to watch you. Study you folks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be damned.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo gets up.</context>
      <utterance>Turn up the volume Bo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't find the remote. She presses the up arrows on the TV controls.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The television report cuts to Columbia University PROFESSOR.</context>
      <utterance>-- images were shot yesterday afternoon by a thirty-four year old local camera man in Kerala, a southern city of India. It is the eighteenth reported crop circle found in that country in the last seventy-two hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode>TV</mode>
      <context>Morgan takes the asthma inhaler from his pocket and breathes in deeply.</context>
      <utterance>Crop circles first emerged in the late seventies with the renewed interest in extraterrestrial life. They died out by the early eighties; dismissed as hoaxes. This new resurgence is wholly different. Elements of it are unexplainable. The speed and the quantity in which it has appeared implies the coordination of hundreds of individuals over many countries...  There is only a limited amount of explanations. Either this is one of the most elaborate hoaxes ever created, or basically...  It's for real.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Extraterrestrials.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE ROOM GOES SILENT as everyone watches the images on the television screen.</context>
      <utterance>What in God's name is going on? Beat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar turns back to Graham.</context>
      <utterance>Don't ask me what I think. Cause I can't think straight right now. I'm going back to the station. Have a cup of Marcia's coffee and try to think clear. After that I might make some calls.  Hoaxes... People got way too much time on their hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'll tell you something, what I said in their, still goes. You and your family have been through a lot in the last two days... Not to mention what happened to you all seven months ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edgar stares at Graham.</context>
      <utterance>Six months.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And three weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's left its mark still. The last thing these children need to do, is worry about some crazy things happening in the world. Take them into town. Get their minds -- your mind, on everyday things. It's good medicine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good advice...  Say hi to Marcia for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take care of yourself...  Graham.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... signs intended to be seen from the sky -- CLICK. Graham TURNS IT OFF.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan nods and then plops back into the backseat.</context>
      <utterance>No radio either... Just for a while.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan holds out his hand. Graham gives his son a look as he reaches into his back pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Book money.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan takes the money Graham gives him, then takes Bo's hand and walks down the sidewalk. Graham watches them turn into a store. Merrill steps onto the sidewalk. Hands in his pockets as he walks away. Graham turns and calls after him.</context>
      <utterance>Only one.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham starts across the street to the pharmacy.</context>
      <utterance>Meet back in fifteen minutes. Merrill waves over his shoulder. He keeps walking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SURROUND A CIRCLE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morgan steps up to the counter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Extraterrestrials?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what they keep alluding to. It's just a bunch of crock. They're trying to sell sodas, plain and simple. I've been watching these reports since morning. I've seen twelve soda commercials so far. Twelve!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have book on extraterrestrials?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan shrugs. Mrs. Nathan pushes her husband aside.</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me you believe this horse manure?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Nathan points over to the far corner.</context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact, I think we have one. Came by mistake in a shipment. Decided to keep it for city people.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last row. Third book from the left honey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RADIO HOST</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is no one saying the obvious? This is just a rash case of copycats. Someone, somewhere, does the first one. It's on TV, it's on the internet. In less than an hour a couple hundred people get the same brilliant idea and here we are... on the verge of mass hysteria.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHARMACIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was asthma medicine right Father?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Pharmacist looks back at Graham and then reaches up and TURNS OFF THE RADIO. She quietly finds the prescription on the shelf and moves to the counter across from Graham. She doesn't ring it up. She just stands there fiddling with the bag holding Morgan's medicine. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>For Morgan Hess. And it's not Father anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHARMACIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham stares at the girl. Beat. He nods "yes."</context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you a favor Father?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHARMACIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Graham leans forward on the counter and takes the girl's hands in his. He talks very slowly.</context>
      <utterance>Can I take confession with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. When Tracey speaks her VOICE IS A BIT SHAKY.</context>
      <utterance>Tracey, I -- am -- not -- a -- reverend -- anymore. I haven't been for six months. You know this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham looks at the young girl's teary eyes. He exhales slowly.</context>
      <utterance>All this stuff on TV...  Joe Gills was in here talking about the end of the world... I'm just a little scared.  Please. I need to take confession with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>CREWCUT GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill realizes the crewcut guy is talking to him.</context>
      <utterance>I got it figured.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CREWCUT GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've had two separate folks tell me they think there are strangers around these parts the last couple of nights. Can't tell what they look like, cause they're staying in the shadows -- covert like. No one's got hurt mind you... And that's the give away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREWCUT GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's called probing. It's a military procedure. You send a reconnaissance group, very small, to check out things. Not to engage, but to evaluate the situation. Evaluate the level of danger. Make sure things are all clear...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crewcut guy savors the beat of silence.</context>
      <utterance>Clear for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CREWCUT GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes a second, but Merrill smiles. The crewcut guy smiles back. Merrill points at a poster.</context>
      <utterance>... For the rest of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crewcut guy reaches to a stack of brochures. Picks the top brochure and hands it to Merrill. The crewcut guy begins to stare at Merrill closely.</context>
      <utterance>You have a pamphlet or something I can read?</utterance>
   <speaker>CREWCUT GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill looks up from the brochure. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Hey you didn't used to play baseball did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CREWCUT GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill not, "yes."</context>
      <utterance>Shit. I know you. You're Merrill Hess. I was there that day you hit that five hundred and eighty seven footer over the left field wall and set the record. That thing had a motor on it... It's still the record right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got the bat at home... On the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREWCUT GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>You got two minor league home run records don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five. The five longest.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREWCUT GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, why aren't you in the pros making stacks of cash and getting handfuls of T and A?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Merrill turns to the young man, about his age, who sits at the folding table.</context>
      <utterance>Cause he also has the minor league strike out record.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIONEL smirks.</context>
      <utterance>Hello Lionel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIONEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>He'd just swing as hard as he could every time. It didn't matter what the coach said, didn't matter who was on base, he'd whip that bat through the air as hard as he could... Looked like a lumber jack chopping down a tree.  Merrill here, struck out more times than any two players.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREWCUT GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Merrill tucks the pamphlet in his jacket. Looks like he's not going to say anything. When he does, the words are soft and worn; they've been said a hundred times.</context>
      <utterance>You really hold the strike out record?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. The crewcut guy shakes his head. Merrill turns and starts walking. As he passes Lionel, Merrill makes a small, quick move in Lionel's direction, like he might hit him. Lionel flinches and covers his face. Merrill walks out the door of the army recruiting office.</context>
      <utterance>Felt wrong not to swing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PHARMACIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham glances at the girl as she sits sideways to him at the counter.</context>
      <utterance>I cursed thirty-seven times last week... I said the f-word a couple times, but mostly "shits" and "bastards."  Is "Douche bag" a curse?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose it's in its usage.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHARMACIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about "John you're a douche bag for kissing Barbara?"</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a curse.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHARMACIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham's eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>Then it's not thirty-seven. It's seventy-one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHARMACIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stole a bottle of Ruby red lip stick from K-mart... I punched my brother in the back three times... Graham looks around the empty store for help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MRS. NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan doesn't look up from the extraterrestrial book.</context>
      <utterance>Carl, there's something wrong with our water!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your water is fine. Bo has a thing about her drinking water. She's had it her whole life. Like a tick people have. Except it's not a tick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo shrugs. She places the glass she sipped on the table with the other glass. Mrs. Nathan stares at the four-year old.</context>
      <utterance>Is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Everyone turns to the front of the store where Mr. Nathan points to the TV screen. A Coke Cola commercial is on. Beat. Mrs. Nathan turns back to find Morgan holding out the extraterrestrial book to her.</context>
      <utterance>Thirteen!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pharmacy crowded?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>spending time with Tracey Abernathy alone. Is that understood? Beat. Everyone nods, "yes." Graham puts the key in the ignition and turns the car on. Merrill watches as Graham's hand goes to put the car in reverse -- and then stops. Graham is staring out the windshield. Merrill follows his stare to a thin, thirty-year old man in a LEATHER JACKET coming out of a store. Merrill's face changes expression too. They both stare as the man passes in front of the car.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want any one of you</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone in the car watches the man in the leather jacket as he steps off the sidewalk towards the truck. It's here that he notices the stares. He glances up to see the faces watching him from the station wagon. The leather jacketed man keeps moving to his truck. He gets in, turns it on, and without looking over to the station wagon, backs out of the parking lot. Beat. The Hess family sits quietly.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nobody says anything for the longest time.</context>
      <utterance>Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham puts the station wagon in reverse and backs out into the street.</context>
      <utterance>He's the man who killed mom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>What if Bo's baby monitor is picking up signals from the extraterrestrials?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All this crop stuff. They did it twenty-five years ago. It was a joke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a code.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan hands Graham the monitor in the front seat. THE BEEPS</context>
      <utterance>Let me see that please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's noise.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's broken Morgan. It'll just keep doing this.  Let's get out of the car okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We might lose the signal.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't just sit in the car in our own driveway like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Nobody gets out of the station wagon.</context>
      <utterance>We'll look like mental patients.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting out now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham pulls the handle. His door opens. He waits before getting out. The other three station wagon doors open right after.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OUTSIDE CAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Graham stands and closes his driver side door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone stares at the baby monitor in Graham's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Voices. Did you hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not English though. You heard the voices right Uncle Merrill?</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham doesn't move his arm. He keeps it out in the air where he had it as he closed his door. Graham looks to Merrill over the roof of the station wagon.</context>
      <utterance>I heard them Morgan.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's probably picking up another baby monitor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill concentrates on THE SWIRLING MOVING TEXTURE COMING</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't sound like words.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROM THE BABY MONITOR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Graham looks around at his rapt family.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See this is why we're not watching those news reports. People get obsessed.  I'm letting go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham looks at Merrill, who's now one of them. Beat. Morgan is the first one to move.</context>
      <utterance>You'll lose the signal!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves from the back passenger door to the back bumper where he begins to climb onto the station wagon.</context>
      <utterance>Don't let go.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morgan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan crawls on the roof and takes the monitor ever-so gently out of Graham and Merrill's outstretched hands.</context>
      <utterance>It gets clearer, the higher you hold it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morgan, be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill climbs up over the side and joins Morgan on the roof. Merrill keeps a hand on his nephew. Morgan raises the monitor above his head.</context>
      <utterance>I got him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham cuts her off by taking a seat on the hood. He takes hold of Bo. All four are on the car now. Morgan stands up on the roof of the station wagon. Merrill holds him by the waist. Bo tries to get up onto the roof by climbing over Graham and the windshield. Graham boosts her up over his head with both hands.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill reaches out his free hand. Bo reaches out to him.</context>
      <utterance>Merrill you got her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SPEAKER.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham brings Bo down into his lap. Morgan takes a seat next to Merrill on the roof. The Hess family sits like mental patients on the top of their station wagon.</context>
      <utterance>They hung up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Graham starts to move.</context>
      <utterance>You know something? Even entertaining the possibility of this for a minute has been exciting.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham reaches the barbecue area. There's a flashlight on the picnic table. Graham TURNS THE FLASHLIGHT ON. A NARROW</context>
      <utterance>I can see how people can get carried away with this type of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a kind of faith. It's an intoxicating thing to believe in something you can't see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE BEAM OF HIS FLASHLIGHT FINDS A NARROW PATH. Graham starts following it. His shoulders brush crops on either side.</context>
      <utterance>You were always good at that...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believing in things you couldn't see.  You would have been the first person on that station wagon wouldn't you? You and Morgan would have been wrestling for that baby monitor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan, Merrill and Graham stand silently before the television set.</context>
      <utterance>Fourteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Mexico City officials as well as U.S. officials have confirmed that these are not air crafts from either government's airforce. The first sighting was made by an Air Mexico 747 en route from Mazatlan to New York as the unidentified crafts entered Mexico City air space. They were not detected by radar by either country.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Everyone just watches the fourteen lights hovering on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>The crazies were right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan reaches into the pile of video tapes under the television stand. He grabs one. Bo snatches the video as Morgan tries to put it into the VCR.</context>
      <utterance>We have to tape this...</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan stares at his sister.</context>
      <utterance>My ballet recital.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen Bo. This is very important. Everything people have written about in science books is going to change. The history of the world's future is on the TV right now. We need to record this so you can show your children this tape and say you were there...  For your children Bo.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My ballet recital.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham doesn't take his eyes off the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham and Merrill sit down at the same time on the sofa. They both have the same dazed, slow movements. Morgan rummages through the pile of videos frantically. He finds one and reaches for the VCR.</context>
      <utterance>Find another tape.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan slams the tape marked "Bay Watch" into the VCR and presses record. He's breathing heavy now. Wheezing actually. Morgan moves to the sofa and takes a seat in between his father and his uncle. Bo walks over and squeezes in also. The four of them stare at the television.</context>
      <utterance>Uncle Merrill, I'm using your tape.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>... You're seeing a live feed from our NBC affiliate down in Mexico City. The time there is 7:17pm. This image has not been adjusted or enhanced in any way. What you're seeing is real.  Everything they wrote in science books is about to change.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan brings his asthma spray to his mouth and inhales.</context>
      <utterance>Told you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham turns his sleepy eyes away from the screen to Merrill.</context>
      <utterance>Some people are probably thinking this is the end of the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill looks his brother in the eyes. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>That's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think it's a possibility?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That wasn't the answer you wanted?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Graham thinks it over.</context>
      <utterance>Can you at least pretend to be like you used to be? Give me some comfort?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Merrill is deep in thought.</context>
      <utterance>... There are all different ways you can tell that there's someone really there watching out for us. You see signs. Sometimes they're little ones. You think of someone. The phone rings. They're on the phone... Sometimes they're big, like fourteen lights hovering over Mexico City.  Sure, there are a lot of people watching this who think this could be a bad thing. But there are a lot of people watching this, who think it's a miracle. A sign of God's existence. It's all in how you look at things Merrill.  What you have to decide is what kind of person you are? Are you the type who believes in miracles and looks for signs or are you the kind who believes, things just happen by chance?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill looks at the TV screen. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>I was at this party once. I'm on a couch with Sara Mckinney. She was just sitting there, looking beautiful and staring at me. I go to lean in and kiss her and I realize I have gum in my mouth. I turn and take out the gum. Stuff it in my paper cup next to the sofa and turn around. Sara Mckinney throws up all over herself.  I knew the second it happened. It was a miracle. I could have been kissing her when she threw up. That would have scarred me for life. I may never have recovered.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a miracle man. Those lights are a miracle.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>There you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>So which type are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you feel comforted?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two of them turn back to the silent screen of the television. It's a long beat before Graham speaks.</context>
      <utterance>What does it matter then?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Merrill turns and stares quietly at his brother.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know what Colleen's last words were before they killed her?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said, "See", and then her eyes glazed a bit and she said... "Tell Merrill to swing away." Merrill's mouth opens a bit. Graham turns and chuckles at his expression.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill nods, "No."</context>
      <utterance>Do you know why she said that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham turns back to the television. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Because the nerve endings in her brain were firing as she died, and some random memory of us at one of your baseball games popped into her head.  There is no one watching out for us Merrill. We're all on our own.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the kids protection. All they were doing was watching TV from five a.m. I felt like they were getting obsessed like you said. They should be playing furry, furry rabbit or tea party or something right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's furry, furry rabbit?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a game isn't it?  Anyway...  There's been some interesting developments.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Graham looks at the TV screen. There's a daylight shot of Mexico City. The skies are empty above it.</context>
      <utterance>Eleven a.m. They're gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill puts a finger in the sky on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>But they're not really gone. We just can't see them. Early this morning a bird flew right at the area where the lights were hovering last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill's finger trails to the bottom of the screen.</context>
      <utterance>It stopped dead in the air and fell straight down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They caught it on tape and they've been playing it all morning. They found the bird. His head crushed in. When you see the footage it looks like the bird flew into a wall in the sky.  They think they have some invisible shield thing going, like an optical illusion.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bird could have had a heart attack and crushed his head when he fell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham looks at the empty sky on the screen with different eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Already thought of. Two other birds did the same thing an hour later. Not as dramatic. They lived. But you could see they hit something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're still there hovering. In fact, some people think there's more of them now. All over the place. Over us even.  And there's a theory about the crop circles now. They think it could be some kind of landmark, visual mapping system -- so they can navigate. Coordinate. Makes sense doesn't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the aliens can't read our minds.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan holds up the book he bought from Nathan's bookstore. Graham enters the room. The children make space for him on the bed. He takes a seat between them. Morgan puts the book on his father's lap.</context>
      <utterance>They tell you everything in this book.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says they're probably very small -- like my height -- because, as their brains developed, there was no use for physical development. It says they're probably vegetarians, because they would have realized the benefits of such a diet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham looks on the back cover for a picture. There's none there.</context>
      <utterance>Who wrote this book?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scientists who have been persecuted for their beliefs.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan closes the book.</context>
      <utterance>That means they're unemployed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo points at the book.</context>
      <utterance>Dad, are you going to be serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham looks at his two children with foil on their heads.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Morgan puts the book on his father's lap.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what got into me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Morgan opens the tome.</context>
      <utterance>There are pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Bimboo, one of the authors of the book --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bimboo?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just asked his name.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Graham acknowledges with a nod that he did have a tone.</context>
      <utterance>You had a tone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan turns the page.</context>
      <utterance>He says there are two reasons why Extraterrestrials would visit us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham looks at an illustration of a small, bulbous headed figure shaking hands with a bearded human.</context>
      <utterance>To make contact in the spirit of exploration and furthering the knowledge of the universe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan turns the page. There is a picture of a house. A space ship is hovering over the home shooting laser beams at it. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Or the other reason... They're hostile. They've used up the resources on their planet and are looking to harvest our planet next.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan and Bo lean in closer to look at the picture. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Looks a little like our house doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The same windows.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three of them study the picture of the house. It's on fire. Their eyes move to the front yard. There are three bodies lying dead on the front lawn. Two are children.</context>
      <utterance>That's weird.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham steps out into the hallway. He tucks the book under his arm and picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>That's enough from Dr. Bimboo for now. Everybody in this house needs to calm down and eat some fruit or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NOTHING BUT DEAD AIR. Graham looks at the receiver and then slowly hangs it up. Graham walks down the hall to a small window. The window looks down the driveway and out onto the road. Graham stares into the distance. About a half-mile away we see the TIP OF A HOUSE. Graham gazes at it for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill nods.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going out for a few minutes. No one leaves this house. No one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham starts down the hall. Merrill steps out of the closet for the first time. He looks down the hall shocked.</context>
      <utterance>Ray Reddy's house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham unlocks the front door.</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he just called here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Morgan pulls his eye away from the telescope that is set up on the window seat in his room.</context>
      <utterance>You don't think something bad will happen do you Morgan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo nods, "Yes."</context>
      <utterance>Why, you got one of your feeling again?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo nods, "Yes" slowly.</context>
      <utterance>Is it bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo hugs Morgan tight.</context>
      <utterance>If it does, I won't let anything bad happen to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo keeps hugging Morgan.</context>
      <utterance>Who said I was going to die?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Morgan peels Bo's arms off of him.</context>
      <utterance>Who said I was going to die?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo lets go. Morgan puts his eye to the eyepiece of the telescope.</context>
      <utterance>Come on Bo. I need to keep a look out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAY REDDY doesn't look over. Doesn't react. Keeps staring. Ray clutches the steering wheel tightly, turning his knuckles a yellow white. Graham glances to the backseat of the truck. There are two large bags over flowing with clothes. Graham's eyes gently move back to Ray and drift down to the TWO BLOOD STAINED AREA ON HIS SHIRT. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Hello Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Ray doesn't look over when he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>What happened Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wrote your number down to call you. It's been sitting next to the phone for six months. When I knew it was inside the house, I couldn't think of any other number to call. I panicked.  Thank you for coming Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears start falling down Ray's face.</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray finally turns. His red face quivers as he talks.</context>
      <utterance>I worked so long that night. I ain't never fallen asleep driving before. And never since. Most of the ride home, there wasn't a car insight in either direction. If I'd fallen asleep then, I'd a ended up in a ditch with a head ache. It had to happen at that right moment. That certain ten-fifteen seconds when I passed her walking. It was like it was meant to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray starts the car.</context>
      <utterance>I guess if this is the end of the world, I'm screwed right? People who kill Reverends' wives aren't exactly ushered to the front of the line in heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>To the lake. The way I see it, all the places marked in the crops and such -- none of them are really near water. I figure they don't like water.  Can't be any worse than here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks at Graham.</context>
      <utterance>Ray, did you see one of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men stare at each other for a beat. Ray looks away. He puts the car in drive.</context>
      <utterance>I'm truly sorry for what I've done to you and yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham steps away as the truck moves forward and pulls down the driveway.</context>
      <utterance>And don't open my pantry Father. I locked one of them in there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill's eyes open.</context>
      <utterance>... The startling footage we're about to show you was photographed by a forty-two year old Romero Valadares.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This video was taken yesterday afternoon at his son's seventh birthday, in the city of Passo Fundo, Brazil. It was sent to the local news bureau there and satellited to us a few minutes ago. All initial opinions are; this is genuine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SHADOW STOPS MOVING.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SILENCE. There is no movement from the pantry. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>The police are here... I am with them... I am a police officer.  I just want to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know all about the hoax. We already took some of your friends downtown in the paddy wagon.  Paddy wagon?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham stares at his family huddled on the couch. Beat. Graham takes in the news as he moves to the stairs. He takes a seat on the second to last step. He sits obscured by the balusters. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>They're skin changes color. That's why we couldn't see him that night.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me something Morgan. In that book of your, did they happen to detail what would happen if they were hostile?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. They would invade us using only ground tactics. Hand to hand combat. They wouldn't use their technology or fight an airborne battle, because they would know we would eventually use nuclear weapons and the planet would be useless to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, what book is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they say what our chances would be if they did invade?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They said one of two things could happen. One, they fight and are defeated and leave to return again with full forces hundreds or even thousands of years later.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's two?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words hang in the air. Graham sits quietly on the second step of the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>They win.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think about the idea that they don't like places near water, and we might be safe from them near a lake or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds made up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one raises their hand.</context>
      <utterance>We can choose to believe it and pack up and leave.  Or we can stay here. Board up this house. Hide inside our home and wait it out. Either way, at least we'll be together.  All those in favor of the lake, raise your hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All four put their hands in the air. Beat. They lower them and sit in silence.</context>
      <utterance>All those in favor of home, raise your hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>How do we know boards will do anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because, they seem to have trouble with pantry doors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>They decided to show themselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They think these look like stages immediately proceeding an attack maneuver.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like War of the Worlds.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The image goes back to a quiet TV anchor. He takes a second before starting up again.</context>
      <utterance>They think it might happen all at once. The words silence everyone. Beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The television shows hundreds of Israelis in a temple and in the streets praying. Graham watches quietly as the masses pray side by side.</context>
      <utterance>Hundreds of thousands have flocked to synagogues, churches and temples.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ground forces are being assembled in countries throughout the globe...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo watches as Graham leaves the doorway of the closet. She turns back to the television. Beat. Merrill leans down between his niece and nephew.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to get back to the windows.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They don't answer. They watch the soldiers loading up onto trucks on the television.</context>
      <utterance>You guys okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some guy had a sign that said it was the end of the world.  Nothing really bad is going to happen, is it Uncle Merrill?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan glances at Bo and then back to his uncle.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Merrill gazes at the two questioning faces. He looks back at the empty closet doorway where Graham stood. He turns back to the children.</context>
      <utterance>You sure right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children think it over. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>You know about signs Morgan? Not like the ones people write on. It's like if you poured a glass of milk and you dropped the glass by mistake and broke it before you could drink it. Then you looked at the milk carton and saw that the milk was spoiled. They're things that happen by chance or luck, but make you feel that someone's watching out for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>I once had a bad dream and I couldn't wake up. I kicked at the table next to my bed and something fell on me and I woke up. It was a picture of mom. She was smiling. It made me feel safe... You mean like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, like that.  I believe in signs Morgan. I think there's someone watching out for us. I got to believe he's going to make sure we're all right in the end.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill stands and leans against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Too many windows in the bedrooms. We don't have enough boards.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll have to board up the bedroom doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we going to sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone sits quietly for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>The family room.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Isabelle?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>We'll keep her in the garage, after dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make sandwiches.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want spaghetti?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should eat fast Bo.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill glances at Graham.</context>
      <utterance>Spaghetti sounds great.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want, Morgan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham nods "yes."</context>
      <utterance>Anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>French toast... and mashed potatoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham turns and looks at Merrill. They stare at each other quietly. They have a conversation without words. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Now we're talking.  How about you Merrill?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chicken Teriyaki.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good choice... I'm going to have a cheeseburger with bacon.  Extra bacon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with everyone? Eat. No one says anything. No one eats.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo sits next to her three glasses of water and begins to cry.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to hear anymore talk like that. And I don't want to see anymore faces like the ones I'm looking at.  We are going to enjoy this meal. Nothing can stop us from enjoying this meal! Enjoy!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop crying!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan's face is hard, but tears start to fall anyway. Graham watches as both his children cry at the table.</context>
      <utterance>Don't yell at her!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham takes big scoops of every dish and piles it on his plate. He digs his fork into the pile and starts to shove it in his mouth. He swallows.</context>
      <utterance>Fine, if you all don't want to eat, then I'm going to have some of everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo, Morgan and Merrill watch in stunned silence as Graham stuffs more in his mouth. He chews and chews and swallows hard. He digs his fork into the pile again. Graham starts crying as he eats. He keeps taking more bites. More tears fall. Morgan gets up from his seat. He goes to Graham's chair. He leans against his dad's arm and cries with him. Graham's fork stops moving. He watches as Bo moves from her seat to his other side. She holds her dad's arm and cries. Beat. Graham pulls them both up onto the chair with him and hugs them tight. Merrill leans forward and comes to the pile on Graham's chair. Merrill buries his head in Graham's shoulder. The Hess family huddles together at one end of the table. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>This tastes so great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo nods "no" lightly.</context>
      <utterance>Did I ever tell you what everyone said when you were born, Bo?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham stops hammering. Merrill keeps going.</context>
      <utterance>You came out of your momma and you didn't even cry. You just opened your eyes and looked around at everybody. Your eyes were so big and gorgeous, the ladies in the room gasped.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham smiles to himself as he remembers the moment. Merrill finishes hammering. Graham goes over and picks up Bo.</context>
      <utterance>They literally gasped.  Then they go, "She's like an angel." They said, "We've never seen a baby so beautiful."</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo nods, "no."</context>
      <utterance>And you know what else happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go down now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we turn off the lights?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They already know we're here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan looks at his father, unable to speak.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know what happened when you were born Morgan?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You came out and your momma kept bleeding. The doctors rushed you out of the room before I could even see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THERE ARE THUDS ABOVE THEM.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All four look up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're on the roof.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While they were trying to fix her up, all she kept asking about was you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham takes Morgan's hand.</context>
      <utterance>They're in the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham smiles down at his son who smiles gently back.</context>
      <utterance>I wanted your momma to see you first. She had dreamed about you her whole life.  They waited till she felt better, then they brought you in. They placed you right in her arms. And she looked at you. And you looked at her. You just stared at each other for the longest time and then she said real soft, "Hello Morgan, I'm you momma, you look just like I dreamed."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham brings his arms down. He sees his children watching from the bottom of the stairs. Graham looks around where he is. There is a very small table with photos against a wall. A laundry closet and three boarded up bedroom doors... nothing else. Graham turns to Merrill.</context>
      <utterance>This is a very temporary solution.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill's face is a deep crimson.</context>
      <utterance>How temporary?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham looks around again... the same things... the same table... the same closet... Graham stops and stares at the closet. It has a wooden folding door that opens and closed on a guide rail. The wooden folding door is very tall. Its top is one foot from the ceiling. Graham goes to the closet and grabs the door. He starts rocking it hard. Pulling it out... It starts to come out of its guide rail... Graham leans back with all his weight... The thin wooden door rips out of place. One end is still attached at the hinge. Graham pulls it straight. It reaches into the middle of the landing. It stands right next to Merrill. Right under the attic trapdoor. Its top is only a few inches lower than Merrill's reach.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-two seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill hesitates and then lowers the attic trapdoor. It connects with the top of the closet door and stops. The trapdoor is now open almost a foot... We can now see part of the bottom step of the wooden pull out stairs that lead to the attic. Merrill and Graham step away as the closet folding door holds the weight of the attic door. After a moment, the spring on the attic trapdoor recoils as the pressure is let up. The trapdoor closes. Beat. It opens with force, slamming the top of the standing closet door with a THUD. The attic trapdoor closes again. Opens again with force.</context>
      <utterance>Let go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is going to do nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham points to a set of narrow stairs that lead to a darkened door at the bottom.</context>
      <utterance>We have to go in the basement.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Graham looks at the faces of his frightened children.</context>
      <utterance>There's no way out of there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I ever tell you, I dislocated Uncle Merrill's arm?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we make a run for it out the back?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill looks at the boarded up back door. Graham turns to Bo and Morgan who stand against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>They're right behind the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was only a year and half old.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THUD WITH A CRACK OF WOOD FROM UPSTAIRS. Merrill turns and stares at the barricaded entrance to the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>He was trying to eat a second chocolate bar. Your grandma said, "No." He tried to take a bite, so I grabbed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must have pulled his arm at an awkward angle. His elbow popped right out of the socket.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't scream or anything. His arm just flopped to his side and he got real still.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham moves towards the basement stairs.</context>
      <utterance>They're coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham gestures for the kids to come to the stairs. Morgan and Bo move to their father slowly.</context>
      <utterance>I held him in my lap in the back seat as we drove to the hospital. I couldn't stop crying... We need to go into the basement now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham ushers the two children down the stairs. He waits for Merrill. Merrill turns from the kitchen door and walks toward him. Merrill stops and looks down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>You know what your Uncle Merrill did right after the doctor put his arm back in place? He jumped off the table and gave me a hug. He had already forgotten that I was the one who hurt him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We won't be able to get out of there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Merrill's eyes fill with water. He doesn't look up at his older brother.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I hurt your arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill walks down the stairs. Graham waits at the top. He watches the kitchen door with the table and chairs against it. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham closes the door behind him. It has no lock.</context>
      <utterance>We forgot our foil helmets!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The basement is lined with metal shelves. The shelves are cluttered with all sorts of canned goods, extension cords, cleaning supplies, decorations, outdoor tools. Merrill rummages through the shelves frantically.</context>
      <utterance>We need something to wedge against the doorknob.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll read our minds!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're scaring your sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham puts his ear to the door and listens.</context>
      <utterance>I'm already scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merrill --</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill moves to another set of shelves. He starts knocking things to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merrill!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill reaches between two stacks of shelves and pulls out a pick for digging in the ground. He holds it up in the air. It has a three-foot wooden handle. Merrill turns and rushes in Graham's direction. A single light bulb hangs from a wire in the ceiling. It is the only light in the room. Merrill CLIPS THE LIGHT BULB with the end of the wooden handle as he crosses the room.</context>
      <utterance>Got it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>What's happening out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't even imagine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham looks at Merrill's corner of the darkness. Morgan moves his BEAM ONTO MERRILL.</context>
      <utterance>They're just making noises. They're not trying to get in.  Why are they doing that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BANG. A beat of silence.</context>
      <utterance>They want our attention on the door?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're distracting us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The book says they're probably very good problem solvers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What book!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll find a way in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can feel air.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's getting stronger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm close.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill looks at his nephew turning gray. Graham pulls Morgan closer to his body and talks into the child's ear.</context>
      <utterance>We don't have his medicine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan's throat is closing -- his face is filled with strain and panic.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be scared Morgan. We'll slow it down together. Feel my chest. Feel it going in and out. Breathe like me. Breathe like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo moves to Merrill and curls up with him as they watch. Graham closes his eyes. Beat. He opens his eyes and talks into Morgan's ear.</context>
      <utterance>He can't breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham closes his eyes -- talks to the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Stay with me. Stay with me. I know it hurts. Be strong baby... It'll pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill stares at his brother's desperate face. Graham's eyes open as Morgan's tiny fingers press down on Graham's hand. The fingers squeeze with all the strength they have. Graham looks to Merrill helplessly. Merrill's eyes fill up with water. Graham's eyes close.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do this to me again. Not again.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham's eyes open as he leans in close to Morgan's ear.</context>
      <utterance>I hate you. I hate you...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Here comes the air...</context>
      <utterance>The fear is feeding it... Don't be afraid of what's happening... Believe it's going to pass... Believe it... Just wait... Don't be afraid... The air is coming... Believe... We don't have to be afraid... It's about to pass... Here it comes... Don't be afraid...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham opens his eyes from sleep. HE SQUINTS FROM THE LIGHT</context>
      <utterance>... Jordan, Saudi Arabia and Bahrain have also confirmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill walks back to the radio on the metal shelf. THE</context>
      <utterance>I found a pack of light bulbs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Parts of China and Northern Korea are among the few remaining to verify withdrawals.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're broadcasting...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill waits for his brother to say something. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>It came on about two hours ago. Woke me up.  We won Graham.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>It went on all night. Everywhere. It was completely a ground battle. Mostly hand to hand. You can't see them unless you're up close. A lot of people died. Some from combat. But most from poison gas inhalation. They secrete it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many died?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They think over a hundred thousand. They're just estimates.  But we held strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do they know it's over?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>A mass evacuation by them started about eight o'clock this morning. It's eleven now.  They're leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't think we'd make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, there's things I can take and a couple things I can't and one of them I can't take, is when my older brother --  -- who is everything I want to be, starts losing faith in things. I saw your eyes last night.  I don't want to ever see your eyes like that again, okay? I'm serious. Merrill's face is hard. He looks shaken. Graham stares at the conviction in his younger brother's expression.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THERE'S A WHEEZING SOUND FROM THE CORNER OF THE ROOM. Graham and Merrill turn to look at Morgan -- laying down on Merrill's folded sweater. Morgan's breathing is strained. He still looks grey.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's been like that for awhile. We need to get him some medicine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have they said anything about our area?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham looks at Morgan lying limp on the ground. Graham turns to Merrill.</context>
      <utterance>Philadelphia and its outlying counties are cleared, but who knows for sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not strong enough to fight off another attack.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We need to be sure, before we open that door Graham. The two men stand under the single dangling light bulb. Graham quietly turns and looks at Morgan. He moves across the room towards him. Merrill watches as Graham kneels down and reaches to Morgan's side. Graham unclips the baby monitor from his son's belt. Graham walks back to Merrill. He holds it out between them. Beat. He turns it ON.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good enough for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan strains to look in her direction. Graham looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>People are dancing. She points at the closet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan nods, "yes" as he struggles to breathe.</context>
      <utterance>You want to see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bring the TV in here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham stands motionless with his hands at his sides. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>What do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was an accident. Drunk driving. They weren't sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Officer Paski gestures in the direction of one of the ambulances. Ray Reddy sits to the side on the grass. His arms rest on his bent knees.</context>
      <utterance>He wasn't drinking. Ray fell asleep at the wheel.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham smiles a little smile.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... That's the first thing Colleen asked too.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>She's talking... Which ambulance is she in?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not in an ambulance Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See Father, Ray's truck swerved off the road and ah... Hit Colleen and then a tree. She was pinned between the two.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Pinned? What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The truck... the truck has severed most of her lower half.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>She won't be saved. At this point she's alive, because the truck is holding her together. She doesn't feel much, and she's talking almost like normal. We didn't pull the truck out, cause we wanted you to come down here to be with her, as long as she's awake. That won't be very long.  Father, you understand what I've told you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Edgar.  Is this the last time I'm going to talk to my wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER PASKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi sweetie.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham glances down. There are bundles of blood soaked blankets in the area below her. They peek out under the twisted front of the truck. Graham looks up quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Hi baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just taking a walk before dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>You love walks.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>I guess it was meant to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't feel much.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham touches her cheek. She starts crying. Graham starts crying with her.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Tell Morgan to play games -- it's okay to be silly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Tell Bo to listen to her brother. He'll always take care of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Tell Graham --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLLEEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And tell Merrill to swing away.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?  Colleen?... Colleen?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morgan's face is obscured by gas.</context>
      <utterance>Swing away, Merrill.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill turns and looks to Graham.</context>
      <utterance>Merrill.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Graham's eyes are not on Merrill. Merrill follows his eye line to the baseball bat mounted above him. Beat. Merrill reaches up and takes the bat off its resting place. The creature starts to move. Merrill's hands tighten around the handle as he walks forward. He stops. His weight shifts to his right leg. The creature begins to turn and becomes more visible as its lines and colors don't match in position in the room. Merrill's left leg goes out. His torso and shoulders turn with staggering speed and strength. The bat slices through the air of the family room... Contact. The creature gets HAMMERED across the back with the baseball bat. Morgan is dropped. He falls to the carpet of the family room in an unnatural crumpled pile. His arms and legs flop lifelessly to the carpet. The creature turns to face Merrill. All the creature sees is the BLUR OF WOOD as Merrill swings like a lumberjack. SLAM. The creature falls to the ground. Graham takes Bo by the hand and moves to Morgan. Graham picks up his son's limp body in his arms. The creature moves to its feet. Merrill's hands choke up on the bat. Merrill's eyes are on fire. Graham leans down and picks up the full syringe of medicine on the ground. Merrill SCREAMS as he swings again. His powerful muscles pull his shoulders whipping around. The bat connects with the creature across its chest. The creature is thrown back into the wall. Two glass of water fall off a shelf and CRASH ONTO THE CREATURE'S SHOULDER. The water connects with it's skin. The creature makes a HIGH PITCHED INHALE SOUND. Bo and Graham look up.</context>
      <utterance>Swing away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill stares at Morgan. His body is utterly still.</context>
      <utterance>His lungs were closed.  His lungs were closed. No poison got in... No poison got in.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Merrill reaches for Morgan's still hand.</context>
      <utterance>His lungs were closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Morgan lies lifeless.</context>
      <utterance>Graham.</utterance>
   <speaker>BO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bo is crying.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERRILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Graham.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HIS SON'S VOICE MAKES HIM STOP. Graham starts crying. Every bit of sadness trapped in his body is released. He looks down through tears and tears at Morgan.</context>
      <utterance>Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did someone save me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah baby. I think someone did.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
