<movie id="495" title="Sister Act">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SISTER IMMACULATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christine?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sister, may I be excused?</utterance>
   <speaker>SISTER IMMACULATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christine...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sister Immaculata nods, pursing her lips. Christine stands and heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>It's an emergency. Real bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>CHRISTY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Vince -- hold me a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd love to. babe -- but I've got to go. It was great. Like usual.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 3.</context>
      <utterance>It was twenty minutes. Like usual.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VINCE LAROCCA stands at the mirror, adjusting his clothing and checking his hair. Vince is a powerful, charismatic man who rules an organized crime empire with personal magnetism and threat. Vince's hold over Christy is obvious, if unfortunate; he can seem expansive and generous one minute, ruthless and dangerous the next.</context>
      <utterance>The best.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy turns on a lamp and lights a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>You are something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on -- stay. Just a little. We can talk, I'll get a pizza. Pizza in bed, we'll have fun. And you still haven't told me what happened. What did she say?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did who say?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince turns to face Christy, turning on the charm.</context>
      <utterance>Who? The other woman. Your wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are so damn sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vince...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did I get so lucky? What is it now, five years we've been together? Who do I thank?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today was the deadline, Vince. Vince sits on the bed. He takes Christy's hand, and kisses it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want us to be together. Like people. Honest, decent people. In the eyes of God. Babe, today... I went to confession.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 4.</context>
      <utterance>You did what?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the first time in I don't know how long. I wanted everything done right. Open and above board. I told Father Antonelli I was in love. I told him it was a special love, for all the ages.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said that? And what did he say? Did he say you could leave her? Did he say we'd be happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(outraged)</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to go against a priest? Get excommunicated? You think I'm nuts?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can still see each other. Just like always. It's a different kind of sin. Smaller.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince backs off, and starts searching for his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>You pig!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Babe, it's not me! I love you! It's God!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince ducks as Christy throws an ashtray at him, and it smashes against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>You lying sleazeball! The best years of my life! What am I, garbage? Am I lint?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CLOCK-RADIO hits the wall beside Vince's head.</context>
      <utterance>You're upset. I understand. I should go. I hate to. Page 5.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A LAMP hits the wall, as Vince dodges it. He makes a phone gesture with his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Get out of here! And never come back!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince kisses two fingers, and blows the kiss to Christy. He leaves. Christy is left standing on the bed, holding a particularly garish stuffed animal she was about to hurl. With Vince gone she slumps to the bed, cradling the stuffed animal. She is caught between tears and rage.</context>
      <utterance>I'll call.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ELVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Backstage, there's still a look of resolve in Christy's eye as she waits to go on with MICHELLE and TINA, her back- up singers.</context>
      <utterance>Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. Are you lonesome tonight? Welcome to the Moonlight Hotel and Casino's incredible Platinum Oldies Spectacular.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you can't quit. What'll happen to us?  Tell her she can't quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Onstage, Elvis glances into the wings to be sure the Ronelles are ready. Page 6.</context>
      <utterance>I told her. She stuck pantyhose in my mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elvis disappears. The spotlight hits Christy, who wears a high beehive wig and a sequinned, early Supremes-style gown. Michelle and Tina wear matching gowns and wigs. The band begins a doo-wop vamp.</context>
      <utterance>Please welcome our own girl group extraordinaire, our beehives of beauty -- the fabulous Ronelles!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONELLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Betty?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This prom is a real drag.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONELLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(gasping)</context>
      <utterance>Oh my!</utterance>
   <speaker>RONELLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Betty?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that. Get a gander.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONELLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(sighing)</context>
      <utterance>Oh my!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's so dreamy. He's like... a Greek god. He's the cutest guy here. He's boss. He's fab. He's...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONELLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Betty?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screw this dump. It's a roach motel with sequins. Every guy I meet is either married, a cop, or a lush from Des Moines.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about us?</utterance>
   <speaker>TINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You taught us the act. The songs, all the moves.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pock-faced weasel of a man named JOEY opens the door and leans into the room.</context>
      <utterance>And where did it get me? I'm stuck in this rathole! You're holding me back, just like Vince! I should be headlining!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want? This is a private area! Get lost!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't got nothin' I ain't seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey takes a step into the room and sets a box on the chair near Christy.</context>
      <utterance>Then stop trying to memorize it. Hit the road.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 8.</context>
      <utterance>From Vince.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His ashes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey leaves. Michelle and Tina hover around the box, very excited. They pick it up, trying to tempt Christy.</context>
      <utterance>With love.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Vince! With love!</utterance>
   <speaker>TINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michelle and Tina can't restrain themselves: they open the box. Inside is a rather gaudy fur coat. Michelle and Tina are impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a fur!</utterance>
   <speaker>TINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's new!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a bribe. Five years of my goddamned life!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you earned it!</utterance>
   <speaker>TINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vince owns the casino! Cash in</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a KNOCK on the door, and Tina opens it. Lieutenant Eddie Mulcahy enters. Christy is not pleased.</context>
      <utterance>I should throw this in his facet</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus. What is going on here?  Why me? Whose dog did I kill?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>TINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie picks up the coat.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Eddie.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Vince? What a guy. Doo-lang, doo- lang.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least he's not a cop. At least he can afford a decent gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to buy.you,..stuff. On your birthday . When we were seeing each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, like what? Quilted coat hangers, that your mother picked out? Lottery tickets? A travel iron?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I don't shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cause you're always out, arresting people. Making trouble. I don't know why I went out with you in the first place, it was embarrassing! I couldn't hold my head up, I used to tell people you were a security guard!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah? Well, how do you think I felt? You were singing in bowling alleys back then. I told people you were a hooker!</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down, you two. It's always like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, now, she goes out with a' better class of people. Vince Laflocca.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a businessman.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A what? When are you qonna wake up?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When are you gonna get off my case? Have you got a search warrant? What do you want -- cheap thrills?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Information, baby. I thought maybe somebody around here might have a conscience.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 10.</context>
      <utterance>Think again! And get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy hurls a jar of cold cream at Eddie's head. He ducks, and the jar hits the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going. My regards to Vince, And the Mrs.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie leaves. Christy is standing, absolutely furious.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it! I'm not taking it from him, and I'm not taking it from Vince! From now on, it's all about me! And if I can't spend it, drink it, or sleep with it -- it's gone. Like Sister Immaculata used to say, "Life is short, and then you fry." So long, girls -- see you in church! Christy grabs the mink and heads out the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ernie Schmidt. How long you been with us, Ernie Schmidt?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince gestures to the lush office and its furnishings.</context>
      <utterance>Three years, Mr. LaRocca. One behind the bar, two as croupier.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince gestures to Joey, who takes out a revolver and points it at Ernie's head.</context>
      <utterance>Ernie, you know what's important to me? What counts? It's not all this. This is '-- what? Frosting. Loyalty. That's me, Ernie. That's home.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ernie's eyes open wide with denial as the gun comes closer to his temple. Page 11.</context>
      <utterance>You ain't been loyal, Ernie. What did you tell the cops?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't tell the cops anything. I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey slams Ernie on the side of the head with the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Joey?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who else, Ernie? Who else was in on it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why am I wasting my time?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on the door to the office, which opens. Christy appears, with the mink coat in her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GUNSHOT is heard, 0.S. Christy's eyes widen, and her jaw drops, at what she has just witnessed. ANGLE on the office. Ernie is slumped in the chair, dead. Joey stands over him, holding the revolver. Joey, Willy and Vince stare at Christy.</context>
      <utterance>Stuff this up your...</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Babe.  Christy tries to speak; she can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy glances around the room; she doesn't move. She quickly sizes up the situation. She tries to appear matter-of-fact. unaffected by what she's just seen.</context>
      <utterance>Christy. Is there a problem? With the coat?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... it's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. A lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that why you came up here, Christy? To thank me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And to say you're sorry. About this afternoon. And the things you said. Forgotten. Completely. Do you understand? Forgotten.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince crosses the room, to Christy. He takes her hands in his, and kisses them.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Yeah. Forgotten. Page 13.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy kisses Vince, quickly.</context>
      <utterance>That's my girl. My girl in mink. Will you be home? Soon?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy reaches for the doorknob, without looking at the door. She fumbles a bit. She finds the door.</context>
      <utterance>Right. I'll be... at the apartment. Call me. Thanks. Again.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy walks backwards, out the door. She turns; she is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Mink. Wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vince -- is she... okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(considering this)</context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, won't she talk? She seemed kind of upset.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She did.  Bring her back. Now. For a talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if she runs?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With guns drawn, Willy and Joey run after Christy.</context>
      <utterance>Take care of it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Christy, crouched behind a half-wall. She is clutching the coat.</context>
      <utterance>Christy? He only wants to talk to you! Page 14.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a stuffed toy, a "Garfield the Cat," attached to the wall near Christy, with suction cups. Christy tries to pull the cat's feet off the wall, very quietly.</context>
      <utterance>Christy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy finally just yanks the cat off the wall. She hurls it as high and as far as she can, to the opposite end of the room. ANGLE on the flying stuffed cat. Joey sees the blur of the cat; he SHOOTS it, and the cat explodes.</context>
      <utterance>Christy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy steadies herself against a Xerox machine. She accidentally activates the machine, which lights up and starts HUMMING. ANGLE on Willy, as he hears the Xerox machine. He quickly moves toward the SOUND. Willy reaches the Xerox machine; the area is deserted. He starts moving quickly down the aisle A chair, the kind on casters, comes rolling out of one of the cubicle doorways; the chair hits Willy and he falls. Christy runs out of the cubicle; Willy is on the floor, struggling to get up. As Christy sprints away, Willy SHOOTS at her. He misses, but a glass partition SHATTERS. Christy runs for an open elevator, but it has been summoned from another floor and the doors are beginning to close. She runs even faster. A BULLET whistles past her ear and hits the back wall of the elevator. She reaches for the doors a moment too late, and the elevator is gone. Christy scrambles to the door beside the elevator and runs into a stairwell as two more BULLETS bite pieces out of the door.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Christy! There's no place to go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right between the eyes! Down and out! The guy was gone! I... I couldn't believe it!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You couldn't believe it? Vince the Prince?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never said he was an altar boy, okay? But he sent his goons after me! They tried to kill me! I'm not kidding!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tough break. Whoa.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you expect? Vince is as dirty as they come. We've been finding bodies around here for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know anything about bodies! I mean, he didn't bring it home. He was good to me... sometimes. He was sweet. He took care of me. Who am I supposed to go out with? He owns a casino. He let me sing.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't do you a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screw you!</utterance>
   <speaker>TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, she'll sing great. When she sings for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sing -- like testify? Are you nuts? I just want you to protect me! You're cops!</utterance>
   <speaker>TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Busy cops. We don't have time to be bodyguards for anyone who comes in here with some cockamamie story. Mink coats and laundry chutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 17.</context>
      <utterance>Unless, of course, you're willing to testify.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three detectives move in closer now and really apply the pressure.</context>
      <utterance>What is this, some squeeze play? Can't you just protect me without any strings?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could put you into our witness protection program.</utterance>
   <speaker>TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hiding place.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A new identity.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you'd have to agree to testify. The whole nine yards.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then-you run.</utterance>
   <speaker>TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You listen for the footsteps.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then one day they find you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They open a window.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's ten flights up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten flights down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten flights?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd lose. You'd die. All over the sidewalk. And into the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right! I get the picture! I'll do it! I'll testify!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tate leaves. Christy looks to Eddie for a bargain now.</context>
      <utterance>Get a stenographer. Page 18.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, here's what I want. I know about this stuff. A five-star hotel. With room service.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe Hawaii.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Diamond Head.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. And I'll need a new look. Like a disguise.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe Armani.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- Calvin Klein.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For sportswear. And a limo. And my hair -- up?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could work.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, what do you think this is -- Wheel of Fortune? Let me spell it out for you. You have to hide like you don't even exist. You have to get so far hidden away that you never see sunlight.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay -- no limo.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you gonna do, put me in a bag and bury me?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie smiles. Christy doesn't like the sound of this at all a Page 19.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna put you in the last place on Earth that Vince would ever look for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate you. I totally hate you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Christy looks around the lobby, various religious artifacts loom at her; we see them from her terrified P0V. ANGLE on a crucifix, casting an ominous shadow, a stack of hymnals, and a large, framed Sunday School-style portrait of St. Katherine. Christy shudders.</context>
      <utterance>Safest place in the world. You think Vince would look for you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nuns, Eddie. There are nuns here. Everywhere. It's crawling with 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a convent. All you have to do is shut up, behave yourself, and get along.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy turns to head back to the entrance, but Eddie catches her arm.</context>
      <utterance>With nuns? With rulers? No way. I'm gonna go back, work things out with Vince.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy searches his eyes for a lie, but realizes he's telling the truth.</context>
      <utterance>Vince has put out a contract on you. A hundred grand. You've seen him in action.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 20.</context>
      <utterance>But... but Vince loves me. How could he... I mean, five years...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And one bullet. That's all it's gonna take.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Vince has contacts all over the place! This is San Francisco! They'll be looking for me!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everywhere but this little hole-in-the- wall convent. Nobody knows you're here but me. We're trying to get a quick court date. A month, maybe two, tops. I'll spring you as soon as I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stay here! I'll crack up! Eddie, what am I gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From inside the chapel, the CHOIR begins to sing a hymn -- horribly. The voices don't blend, and individual notes are real migraine material. Christy looks aghast. Eddie urges her into a corridor, and she follows.</context>
      <utterance>Pray.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not. I am very sorry, but no.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can save this young woman's life, and imprison a parasite -- all in one gesture. Page 21.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she's been exposed to the underside of life. She is the underside of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And therefore an ideal prospect for rehabilitation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're a small convent, Bishop. Surely there are... more appropriate shelters.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your small convent is in danger of closing, Reverend Mother. The Las Vegas Police Department has offered to make a generous financial donation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Bishop...</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>St. Katherine's is a Benedictine Order. You have taken a Vow of Hospitality. To all in need.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lied.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior's jaw locks. She realizes she is stuck with the situation and will have to control it as best she can. There is a KNOCK at the door, and Eddie and Christy enter.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome, Lieutenant. Everything is in order.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The thought of being left alone with Mother Superior panics Christy, like a child left in the principal's office.</context>
      <utterance>Aces. Bishop -- maybe a cup of coffee, down at the corner?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you're not leaving me alone...</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 22.</context>
      <utterance>You're never alone in this house, my child. Eddie touches her gently on the arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One month, two tops. Behave yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(a last-ditch attempt)</context>
      <utterance>Bishop...</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A convent? They put me in a convent? What's the problem? Wasn't there any more room in Hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your full name? Your Christian name?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother Theresa. Gandhi. Don't you understand? This is all a mistake. I'm the good guy. I'm the witness. And I'm being punished!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christy. Christy Van Cartier.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough joking.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my real name! Currently I'm a singer. Sort of.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 23.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. This isn't happening, tell me this isn't happening. It's a nightmare, I'm back at St. Anne's!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>St. Anne's?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parochial school. Akron. St. Android's.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were unhappy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was expelled! When I was fifteen?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The reason?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beats me! What do you think? Smoking! Heavy petting, without a chaperone. Heavy petting, with the chaperone. And wearing a black bra, under my uniform. The demon bra.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see? You see? I have to get out of here I have to make a phone call. Don't you get it? I'm in a convent! You're a nun!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior rises. She is an extremely imposing woman.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy sits in a wooden chair across from Mother Superior.</context>
      <utterance>Sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Van Cartier.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(belligerent)</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 24.</context>
      <utterance>Your cigarette -- out. Christy inspects her cigarette.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has come to pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I joined this convent some thirty years ago. At that time, the world knew some measure of peace. And hope. Our order was a beacon of hospitality, to families, to children, to a neighborhood filled with promise. And, as the years have passed, I have watched that promise destroyed. Drugs. Gangs.  Spandex. And. so I have made this convent an oasis, a retreat from horror. And now that horror has invaded these sacred walls.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you talking about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And all those like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean black people?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not. I mean the wicked. The heedless. And their Las Vegas concubines.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a concubine?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy stands, facing off with Mother Superior.</context>
      <utterance>Check your driver's license.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Got it. Look, the way I see it, I'm stuck here, right? I mean, I'm here or I'm target practice. So here's the deal -- I don't bug you, you don't bug me. I'll catch up on some sleep, watch some tube, lay back and lay low. So just get me a key and show me to my room, and do not disturb. Capisce?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 25.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. But it's almost lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool. Is there a menu? Or buffet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before we do, you might like to freshen up. And you'll certainly want to change</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about a robe? One of those big terry cloth jobs, with like embroidery on the pocket. "Guest of St. Katherine's"</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior takes Christy's skirt and blouse, and tosses them down a chute marked "INCINERATOR."</context>
      <utterance>Would you like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mother Superior carries Christy's lacy bra at the end of a ruler; it goes down the incinerator.</context>
      <utterance>You should hand-wash that blouse, and send somebody out for some things. I look good in reds, purples, hot pink -- and shoes. Five-inch heels. Fuck-me pumps. Oh, man -- sorry. 'Scuse my mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excused. Open the cabinet to your left. You will find appropriate attire.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! No! I can't do this!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Normally dressed, you are a sore thumb, and you endanger us all. While you are here, you will conduct yourself as a nun. Only I shall know who, and what, you truly are. You will not disrupt the convent. You will not influence the Sisters with your colorful street talk. You will draw no attention to yourself in any way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But look at rites Look at this! I'm a nun! I'm invisible! I'm a penguin!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As of now, and until you leave, you are Sister Mary Clarence.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence? Like a guy? Like a dumb guy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Mary is in deference to the Holy Mother, the Clarence in honor of Saint Clarence Loyola. There are three vows that every nun must accept. The vow of poverty...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The vow of obedience.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 27.</context>
      <utterance>Like to who?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the vow of chastity.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy starts to leave; Mother Superior grabs her by the wimple</context>
      <utterance>I'm outta here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on SISTER MARY ROBERT, the nun standing beside Christy. Sister Mary Robert is naive and mouse- like, but very sweet. She has only been at the convent a few years; she wears the simpler habit of a novice. She sneaks a look at Christy. Her eyes widen, and then she resumes staring at her hands.</context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon, Sisters. I apologize for my tardiness. I would like you to welcome a new member of our order, Sister Mary Clarence.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone sits, including Christy. SISTER MARY PATRICK, a nun seated at the middle of the table, waves her hand. Mary Patrick is extremely cheerful, a truly upbeat person.</context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence comes to us from a somewhat more progressive convent. She is eager for a more disciplined life, and will make every effort to conform to our ways.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mary Patrick?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Christy, looking thoroughly disgusted. Page 28.</context>
      <utterance>Reverend Mother, on behalf of the sisters, I'd like to welcome Mary Clarence to St. Katherine's.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on the nuns, watching Christy.</context>
      <utterance>As part of our welcome, I've had a little thought, just for fun. Could we have our new friend offer today's blessing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy stands up slowly, aghast.</context>
      <utterance>Very well. Mary Clarence, rise please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Mary Patrick, beaming. She and the other nuns bow their heads.</context>
      <utterance>A blessing? Like, for lunch?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So far, so good. Mother Superior has one eye open.</context>
      <utterance>For what we are about to receive...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on the nuns, staring at Christy. Mother Superior rises, very quickly.</context>
      <utterance>may the Lord... prepare us and... watch us and... walk through the valley and be our shepherd and... to the republic for which it stands... God bless us every one, hallowed be thy name. Hallelujah. Ave Maria. Boyardee. Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sisters, for the rest of the day we shall declare a Vow of Silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surely you are familiar with this practice, Mary Clarence. Only when our lips are silent, can our prayers truly be heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silence? No talking? All day?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 29.</context>
      <utterance>Until sundown.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy reaches for a piece of bread.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy looks up.</context>
      <utterance>And Mary Clarence?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a new member of our order, I think you might also enjoy a ritual fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A fast. To remind us of the poor, of those who must endure without enough to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No food?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Christy, clutching her fork, hungrily watching the other nuns eat.</context>
      <utterance>No food. Not until sundown.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They grilled me for six hours in there. And my hotshot lawyer -- where the hell were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince reaches his car. As Joey opens the door for him, another car drives by, and stops. Eddie is driving; he leans out the window.</context>
      <utterance>It takes time, Vince. Slow and steady. We've been through this before.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince lurches toward Eddie; Larry restrains him. Eddie drives off, chuckling.</context>
      <utterance>So long, Vince. See you soon. Page 30.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's so damn cocky. This is different.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a bluff, Vince.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry covers his ears with both hands.</context>
      <utterance>You know so much. They've got Christy, and we've got to find her. Get her 8x10, from in front of the lounge. Fax it to every contact we got.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't hear this. I'm an attorney, Vince, and you're just an honest casino owner. Object of a witch hunt. Innocent victim.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince looks grim and vindictive, as he gets into the car.</context>
      <utterance>Keep the message vague, but let 'em know. The price has gone up. Christy Van Cartier -- a quarter of a million. Dead or nearby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this all the food I get?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Until breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stop by a door.</context>
      <utterance>That's tomorrow! Don't you have any snacks? Machines?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This shall be your cell, Mary Clarence.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your cell. Your room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were right the first time. Is this like, solitary? The cooler? Where's the furniture?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our lives are simple. We have little need for material possessions.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, sure thing. But what about, like, appliances? Like a little color portable? Boom box?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Useless distractions.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like the Stone Age. The room time forgot. What about a phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And whom would you call?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know... Satan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your cell is more than adequate.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. So what do we do now? Ping- Pong? Row over to the monastery?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is nine p.m. Pleasant dreams.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. No. You're kidding. Lights out? At nine? My day's just starting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure. If I were you, I would use this time, to think about my life. And its direction. Or lack thereof.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with my life?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From all I've heard, just about everything. Your singing career seems all but nonexistent, and your married lover wants you dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode>MORE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Page 33</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>After the door shuts, Christy stands and looks out the one small window in her cell. She leans her head against the wall. She is trying not to think about what Mother Superior has said. Still, the mess her life has become overwhelms her. She fights back tears.</context>
      <utterance>If you're fooling anyone, it's only yourself. God has brought you here. Take the hint. Mother Superior leaves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Robert, in her nightshirt, stands outside.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, we're late.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's after five. We have to bathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five a.m.?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it a glorious morning? Good morning, Mary Clarence. sleep well?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this like your old convent?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which convent was that, Sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which convent? It was, um, the Little Sisters... of the Moonlight. In Vegas. Everybody used to come to Mass. Frank. Dean. Sammy. Right at ringside.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARY LAZARUS is a much older nun; she is very no-nonsense, a hard-liner.</context>
      <utterance>Enough jabber.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Progressive convents. Vanity. It sounds awful. It sounds just like this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like my old convent, in Vancouver. Out in the woods. It wasn't all modern, like here. No electricity. Cold water. Bare feet. Those were nuns. It was Hell on earth, but I loved it. This place is a Hilton.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MY BOYFRIEND'S BACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The nuns giggle.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did that come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't heard that song in ages. The Ronettes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shirelles.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know that song?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1961? '62? Mary Clarence, that's when many of us took final vows. It's the last secular music we recall.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HEY-LA, HEY LA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Page 36.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Lazarus leaves the bathing room, and the other nuns resume scrubbing themselves. Christy looks around.</context>
      <utterance>That's enough. We've got to get to chapel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody got conditioner?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLARKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarkson gives Eddie a fax sheet, showing a publicity photograph of Christy.</context>
      <utterance>There was a raid on a pawnshop in L.A. this morning. The place was fencing stolen property. They found this.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Data-base hoods. It's a wonderful world.  Beloved daughter missing. Reward of two hundred and fifty thousand dollars. Please find our adored angel, we miss her so. Dead or alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vince is getting desperate. Where is she, Eddie? Where'd you stash her?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's who?</utterance>
   <speaker>TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't even tell us?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't even tell the Pope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Girls make grunting noises.</context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon, young ladies. And welcome to our Christian Youth Group.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on the Girls, exchanging glances and rolling their eyes. Page 38</context>
      <utterance>Hi. I hope we'll have some fun, and maybe learn a little something, too. Now, today's topic is something very up-to- date -- "Teenage Promiscuity." My. Now, can anyone tell me -- just what is promiscuity?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Patrick points to a Girl in bicycle pants. a bustier and a leather baseball cap. Her name is Lawanda.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone? Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, it's like, you know, doin' it. A whole lot. Till your head falls off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sister Mary Patrick?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to see you, at once. Girls, please excuse Sister Mary Patrick for a few moments. Mary Clarence?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girls, this is Sister Mary Clarence. She'll be minding you until Sister Mary Patrick's return. Mary Clarence, please assign a biblical passage. Do not attempt discussion. Am I understood?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior and Mary Patrick leave the classroom. Christy now stands at the front of the room. She is visibly uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>Come, Sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, hi there. I'm... Sister Mary Clarence. And you're... young Christians. I guess I should assign you this passage. What's good? What were you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 39</context>
      <utterance>We were talking about the wild thing. Teen promiscuity.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sister Mary Pat was discussing it. You know she thinks it's a sin.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... yes. Yes it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come? Sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Girls all laugh and make jeering noises.</context>
      <utterance>Well... because it's in the Bible. "Thou shalt not..." Thou shalt not.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me -- just what are you all doing here? At Sunday School?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cause we love it so damn much. And cause we gotta come here. Probation.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probation?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We all got caught. Shoplifting. Cuttin' school. Cuttin' up some bitch with a blade. So we gotta come here. So we'll be good, in the future. So we'll learn valuable lessons. And I learned mine. I will be incredibly good, I will never rip out nobody's nose-ring by accident ever again. Can I go now?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you learned a whole lot, I can tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what would you know about it, anyway? What do any of you nunheads know about anything? About doin' the nasty, or gettin' high?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCHITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 40.</context>
      <utterance>Leave her alone, Lawanda, she's just some ol' nun! Don't pick on no nun, it's bad luck!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the Girls look up, stunned by Christy's language.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, so maybe I'm a nun -- so, you want to ask me something? You want to listen, for once in your little lives? You want to pay some attention?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about crack? You a user?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the girls jeer at Charlene.</context>
      <utterance>I said I was a nun, not an asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>KESHIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got you, Charlene!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCHITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunked by the nun!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what about the sex stuff? What if some dude is after you, and he's always saying stuff, commin' on sweet and mellow. Like, oh, baby, you know you'll love it. Oh, baby, if you loved me, you'd stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you listen to that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but... I don't know... sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I know, it's hard. But do what I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls all laugh; they are really beginning to like Christy. Page 41.</context>
      <utterance>Just tell him, I do love you, but I can't -- I'm a nun.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, like what if you are doin' it? What about protection? Who's responsible?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCHITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about them things, you know, for the guy? Aren't they like, a mess to put on? Don't they kinda mess up the mood?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deal with it, sweet thing. It's important, nowadays. You just practice at home, with a balloon and a banana.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>Mother Superior has returned, with Mary Patrick. Everyone has been so wrapped up in the discussion, that no one has noticed their entrance.</context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because a banana is part of a balanced breakfast. And don't forget fiber.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A balloon and a banana! Tell me, Mary Clarence, what were you thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those girls were asking questions. They've got it rough. I wish somebody had talked to me about that stuff when was their age. I wish somebody would talk to me about it now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a convent, not a clinic. We offer moral guidance, not hardware.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been out in those streets? Do you know what those kids are up against? You should help them!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 42.</context>
      <utterance>We are nuns. We seek solutions through prayer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes it's not enough!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are correct. Sometimes prayer alone cannot help a situation. Such as your own, for example. How do you feel about physical labor?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It never solves anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do your recall the words of Saint Peter, in Ecciesiastes 1:27? He spoke unto a wastrel youth. He said, "Take up thy task, and know ye the path of contentment."</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In English?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior smiles in a rather evil manner.</context>
      <utterance>How to put it... ah, Of course, Mary Clarence. "No pain, no gain."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon, you gorgeous thing... tell me... how lonely?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's that call you were expecting, Vince.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you hold? Can you try? Willy passes the phone to Vince. t Page 43</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you found out where Christy is yet? Hey, bozo, you re on my payroll! You want to try making it on a cop's salary? Find her, and find her now! Vince passes the phone back to Willy.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willy heads for the fax machine. Vince regains his composure, and picks up his own phone; he pushes a button.</context>
      <utterance>Raise the ante to three hundred grand.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, baby... you are? Totally? Not a stitch?... Yeah, I'm naked too... inside...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The minute I saw you. I said to myself, she's a weaver. Have you ever used a loom?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not in years.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it all comes back, in just a jiffy. I'm working on a wall-hanging, of the convent.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To sell, of course. I hate to say it, but we're in terrible trouble here at St. Katherine's. We need a new roof, the furnace is going, and there's no money.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 44.</context>
      <utterance>But don't you get money? From the Vatican?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence. Goose. We're completely self-supporting. Like all convents. Like yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, right. At my old place, we used to... wash cars. Groom dogs. So... nice loom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it lovely? Now I'll demonstrate, and then you can hop right in.  You just draw your beater in, keep it pressed against the pick, and open the shed. Then pass your shuttle, beat, and open the next shed. Shuttle. beat, beat, shuttle, beat, shed. Keep tension on the warp. Is that clear?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just about. Show me again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You betcha.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shuttle, beat, shed. And watch your heddles.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior appears.</context>
      <utterance>I love my heddles. Show me again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence -- how is your weaving progressing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, she's doing just fine, Reverend Mother - Page 45.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really catching on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior gestures to the loom. Christy sits at the loom, and waves as Mother Superior and Mary Patrick exit. Christy stares at the loom; a look of horror crosses her face. She has not been paying attention to Mary Patrick's instructions. She cracks her knuckles, as if she were about to play the piano. She grabs two parts of the loom, at random. She moves these parts. ANGLE on the loom. As a result of Christy's movements, the loom collapses, piece by piece. The tapestry unravels, the many skeins of wool snap, and the mechanical apparatus disintegrates, until finally the entire loom shudders and falls to the floor, as Christy watches, aghast.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Mary Patrick, I need you in the office. Mary Clarence, carry on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I'm not a weaver!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Months of work, and the loom, absolutely ruined!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior stops dead in her tracks; she turns and stares at Christy. Then she smiles, in a rather frightening manner.</context>
      <utterance>Look, this isn't my kind of thing! I wasn't cut out to make little tapestries, or knit little sweaters! I don't do that! I'm a star!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me talk to Detective Eddie Mulcahy. It's an emergency. Real bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy cups her hand around the phone and speaks quietly and frantically. INTERCUT between Christy and Eddie.</context>
      <utterance>Mulcahy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eddie, you've got to get me out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not again. You can't keep calling. Somebody's going to catch on to where you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm going insane! All these people do is pray and work, work and pray! I don't get it -- when's the weekend? They have gruel, Eddie, that's what they call food! Gruel -- it's like Alpo for nuns! I sleep in a cell, on a board, and I pray five times a days Do you know what I pray for, Eddie, do you have any idea? Check your crotch, Eddie --anything fall off yet? Get me outta her!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down. Look, I didn't want to tell you this, but we've had some problems with our protection program lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keeping our witnesses alive. We hide them, but there's a leak in the department, and they end up dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 47</context>
      <utterance>You son-of-a-bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just need a few more weeks,</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the distance, Christy hears the CHOIR practicing; they sound even worse than usual.</context>
      <utterance>But it's a nightmare! Mother Superior is out to get me! She hates my guts! She keeps thinking up new kinds of torture!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you hear that? That choir? Eddie, in here, that's what they call music!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the line goes dead, Mother Superior enters. Christy takes her dust rag and pretends to polish the receiver. She sings as she works.</context>
      <utterance>Don't call again. It's not safe. I'll be in touch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sister Mary Robert enters, very shyly. She barely looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What does she want now? I did the dishes. I oiled the pews. I dusted the hymnals. Two hundred hymnals. Why can't people share?</utterance>
   <speaker>I... I...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Page 48.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I brought you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Robert holds out a rather rugged crust of brown bread. Christy takes it..</context>
      <utterance>An extra heel of bread. Please take it, you need your strength. You've been working so hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. So which one are you? Sister Bruce? Sister Doug?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Robert. I'm... Mary Robert.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Robert nods, and resumes looking at her hands. She doesn't 1eave, but she's still tongue-tied. Christy is at a loss.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Okay. Bob. Nice to know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Bob, how long have you been in? St. K's?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three years. Sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three years. A rookie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A novice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Robert bursts into tears.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, like a learner's permit, right? When do you hit the big time? You know, when do you take the final vows?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 49.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Bob! What's going on here? What'd I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to help me</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, sure, but what's the problem? Are they keeping you a prisoner here? Do they drug you? Did Reverend Mother like, kidnap your parents? We can call the Enquirer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you don't understand -- I don't want to get out! I want to get in?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Mary Clarence, I'm so unworthy. I want to take my final vows, I would do it tomorrow, but Reverend Mother won't let me!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She won't? Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She says I should wait. She says that no one should become a nun as an escape from life. She says that I'm not experienced enough to make the decision yet. In a mature manner.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Robert nods, solemnly. Suddenly, from the streets outside the convent, we hear a BLAST OF hot dance MUSIC, and the SOUND of laughter and carefree conversation.</context>
      <utterance>She said that? Reverend Mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then there's only one thing to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy stands, and goes to the crucifix hanging on the wall. She speaks to the crucifix, and listens, as if Jesus is advising her. Page 50.</context>
      <utterance>Reverend Mother says you need experience, right, in life. In order to make a responsible decision. This is going to be very painful for me. You know how much I love this little room. This whole convent. Wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must I do this thing, 0 Lord? Please help me.,. yes, I know... I must put my selfish cares aside... I must think of others... yes, she's here...  He says hi... yes, I understand... let thy will be done. Amen. You too. Christy turns to Mary Robert, having received a holy message.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must do this sacred thing, Mary Robert.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course! We must do it! It's the will of God! What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must... get you some experience. We must... leave this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another BLAST OF MUSIC from the street. Christy turns to the crucifix. She gets confirmation.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We hear you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 51.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure this is what Reverend Mother had in mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy breathes deep, and then lets out a whoop. She spins, letting her habit billow around her.</context>
      <utterance>I know it is. It's life. Experience. Take a deep breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Robert's eyes widen. She points to herself -- "Me?" Christy nods. Mary Robert lets out a tiny little whoop, and does a little, timid hop.</context>
      <utterance>Now you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a start.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Sisters. Are you going in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy hands over the beer. Christy and Mary Robert enter the club.</context>
      <utterance>And you, with the devil's brew passing through your lips.  A mind is a terrible thing to waste.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bobs</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Experience! Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The club is alive with activity; the bar is crowded, couples are making out at small tables, and the dance floor is packed. The atmosphere is a combination of hazy darkness and colored lights; the club should have the feeling of a hot neighborhood party, with people of all ages and races. The MUSIC percolates, and Christy starts to move to it. She and Mary Robert find a table in the corner, and signal a nearby waitress.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress looks at the two women strangely; the club has never hosted nuns before.</context>
      <utterance>A couple of bowls of chili.  And another round of these.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to do this. So I can become a nun.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Initiation. You understand. Later on, we make her wear her underwear on her head.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 53</context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress leaves, shaking her head. Christy and Mary Robert watch the action at the club. Across the room, MIKE the bartender stares at the nuns, especially Christy; he tries to place her.</context>
      <utterance>And she wants to be a nun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are all these people?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From across the room, Mike the bartender continues to study Christy's face. He takes out a copy of Vince's fax photo and stares at it. He covers Christy's hair in the photo with his hands, creating a wimple. There is no question in his mind; the two are the same. Mike has a dangerous look in his eyes as he takes a gun from the drawer and slips it into his pocket beneath his apron. There is a LIVE BAND on a small stage at one end of the club. They start playing a hot dance number, and the club really begins to cook, as the dance floor fills. Christy and Mary Robert, both still seated, start to move with the music. A very good-looking LOCAL DUDE comes over to the nuns table. He is clearly amused at their presence.</context>
      <utterance>This is your neighborhood. Your turf. You should get to know 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Sisters -- how you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come they let you out? Out of that convent place?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time off. For bad behavior.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oww! A nun havin' fun! I don't believe it! It's good to have you ladies in this fine establishment. So... anybody on the move?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 54.</context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Robert leads the Dude out onto the dance floor.</context>
      <utterance>Bob! What're you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy decides she'd better keep an eye on Mary Robert; she grabs another DUDE, and heads for the dance floor. As the music percolates, Christy and Mary Robert dance; Christy is very hot, and Mary Robert picks up on her moves. The CLUB PATRONS are delighted, and cheer as the nuns start to get down.</context>
      <utterance>You watch yourself!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLUB PATRON #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do it, Sisters!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLUB PATRON #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the song, and the nuns' exuberant dancing, peak, the Club Patrons cheer, shouting "Hallelujah!" and "Amen!"</context>
      <utterance>Sway and pray!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those people are wonderful! Why don't we ever see them in church?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good point. Especially that dude you were with. I'd like to see him down front.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence! You're so... different from the other sisters. Sometimes, well... sometimes you sound more like a layperson.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the two women laugh together, they don't notice the car that begins to follow them, creeping slowly forward with its headlights out. Page 55.</context>
      <utterance>Honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't wait to tell Reverend Mother about all my experiences. I've learned so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car's bright lights suddenly switch on, and the nuns turn, startled. The car hurtles toward them. They scream, and Christy grabs Mary Robert and throws her out of the car's path; the two women land on a pile of garbage bags. Struggling to her feet, Christy sees the car go into reverse, and then pull forward again. She sees a glint of light reflect off a gun as the car's driver (Mike the bartender) leans out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you know, you don't have to tell her everything. I mean, nothing really happened. We just... took a walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy shoves Mary Robert towards an alley. As she does so, the gun GOES OFF with a red flash. The shot misses the two women and SHATTERS a plate glass window of the store behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy grabs the ladder of a fire escape, and shoves Mary Robert up the ladder ahead of her.</context>
      <utterance>Keep moving!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Christy and Mary Robert climb the fire escape, another GUNSHOT ECHOES in the alley, ricocheting off the fire escape. The nuns climb higher up the building. Mike pursues, looking for a shot between the steps and the landings, but not finding any openings. He takes the steps two at a time and begins to gain ground. At the fourth floor landing, Christy's heel gets stuck in the grating. She pulls frantically at the laces. Page 56.</context>
      <utterance>Climb! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mike arrives at the landing just as Christy twists her toot out of the shoe, and surprises him with a lunge for the gun. Mike's hand is knocked back against the metal frame of the fire escape, and the gun flies loose, RATTLING down the metal steps to the landing below. Christy shoves Mary Robert into the open window of an apartment, and follows her in.</context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my Lord!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The couple continues to look stunned as the nuns race out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Experience!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was all that? Who was that man? Why would he shoot at us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, some people just don't like nuns. I wish I had a ruler.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door to the convent swings open. Mother Superior is waiting.</context>
      <utterance>We could have been killed! But you saved me!  Thank you, Mary Clarence!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 57</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- thank you so much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd she say?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You blew it -- big time. She doesn't want you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does she know people are trying to kill me out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's counting on it. She's concerned for your safety, but she wants me to try and find another convent that will take you. Or a carnival.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what am I supposed to do in the meantime?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, Christy rises and approaches the door. She looks at Eddie, who motions her to go in. She finally does.</context>
      <utterance>Go in and talk to her. It can't hurt.  Go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... hi there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe we have anything to say to each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior glances up from her work. She is justifiably outraged.</context>
      <utterance>Look... I know I shouldn't have, I'm incredibly sorry about Mary Robert, I wasn't thinking, I didn't know that would happen! Page 58.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Robert's life was in danger! Your behavior was inexcusable!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know! I'm sorry I didn't mean for it to happen! And I was the one they were shooting at!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence, I have given you every opportunity. To change. To make a decent life for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A decent life? Excuse me? As what? A janitor?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clearly, you have learned nothing. And you present an ongoing threat, both to this convent and to yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you can't kick me out! Guys want to kill me! You're a nun! A big nun! Aren't you supposed to have compassion? For the wayward sheep? I mean, I'm a major sinner! All-time great! Hall of Fame! Aren't I, like, your dream come true? Your Olympic event? Mother Superior stares at Christy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence, perhaps you are correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may stay. But I shall restrict your activities to but a single task.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have, I believe, some minimal background in music. Therefore, you are to join our choir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode>MORE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Page 59</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will sing, and you will sleep,' that is your schedule until you depart. As almost no one attends Mass, you will be unable to cause further damage.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're my Olympic event.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the choir, please, anything but that. The choir -- I mean, have you heard them? I'll do anything, scrub floors, toilets, you name it, but not that I</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The choir, Mary Clarence. Go for the gold.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this... choir practice?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy spots Mary Robert.</context>
      <utterance>Sure is! Come on in, and sing a spell.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Robert, I am so sorry about last night...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Lazarus cuts off this chitchat, thrusting a hymnal at Christy.</context>
      <utterance>Now stop that. You didn't shoot at me. You were only trying to help, to give me experience. I tried to explain that to Reverend Mother, but -- I don't know if she understood.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soprano or alto?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Lazarus hands Christy a hymnal, and raps her baton. The choir begins to sing; Christy doesn't even bother trying. She is horrified; the choir is the worst-sounding group in history. They seem to be singing in several random keys, and they even have trouble with the words. No one looks up from their hymnals. Sister Alma, the organist with the hearing aid, is plodding along.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever. Page 60.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're looking for Mike.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willy grabs Mike's arms and bends them behind his back.</context>
      <utterance>You found him -- but we're not open yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willy slams Mike's face into the wall, stunning him. Joey lifts Mike's groggy face and offers sympathy.</context>
      <utterance>Hey -- the till's empty!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry -- I don't know what gets into him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willy hammers Mike's face into the wall again.</context>
      <utterance>We're the guys from Vegas. You had Christy last night, but you let her get away. It's upsetting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you didn't tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't tell you what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That she's a nun! That chick you're looking for -- she's a nun!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 61.</context>
      <utterance>What? Christy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A nun?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willy and Joey look at each other, and consider this. Then they burst out laughing. They refuse to believe Mike's story.</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willy and Joey pick Mike up, and hurl him over the bar. Then they exit, still laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme a hand here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A nun!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence, are you with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, I don't really know this one...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence has a background in music. That's what Reverend Mother said.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really, Mary Clarence? Were you a choirmistress?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Kind of... free-lance.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Free-lance? Oh really? You think I don't see? You think I took vows yesterday? I know what you're up to. You and Reverend Mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 62.</context>
      <utterance>You're a ringer. She brought you in to replace me. Out with the old.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence, could you? Mary Lazarus, you're terrific, but...  Could you help us?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've heard us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone falls silent. Mary Lazarus walks across the room, eyeballing each member of the choir.</context>
      <utterance>Well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone watches Christy.</context>
      <utterance>There's a word for this -- mutiny.  So, Mary Clarence, you think you can do better. I believe I'd like to see that.  I'm out to pasture. Dry dock. The glue factory. Go ahead, Sister -- make 'em sing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(to Nary Lazarus) With all due respect... let's have a look at this. Christy goes over to the piano. She examines the sheet music for "Let They Thoughts He Guided." She sits at the piano, beside Sister Alma. Christy picks out the hymn on the piano, accompanying herself.</context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 63.</context>
      <utterance>Man. I sound like you guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very nice. Sisters, have we learned our lesson? I won't hold this little episode against anyone. I'll try not to.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Robert. Mary Robert jumps, startled by the attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Robert, I've watched you. You never really sing. You whisper. Nothing comes out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to mess anyone up...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a C.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Robert sings a little louder.</context>
      <utterance>Louder! Like you're onstage.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Robert sings louder still.</context>
      <utterance>Like people are eating, and there's silverware, and you want them to hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Robert finally lets out her full voice, which is huge and glorious. After singing a single perfect note, she stops abruptly; she has scared herself.</context>
      <utterance>Think about that guy you were dancing with!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 64.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see? We've got the voices. They're just allover the place. I've heard all of you, in the shower --you're decent. Better than me. We just need charts -- harmony -- chops.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chops?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two nuns trade places.</context>
      <utterance>The goods. The sound. The sale. Let's rearrange a few things. Mary Patrick, you re not a natural soprano, you're an alto. Get over here. Mary Robert --with the sopranos.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sister Alma plays the note, and the nuns try to duplicate it, but the results aren't much better than before. Christy uses her pitchpipe; she circulates among the nuns, giving each her note, urging them closer to pitch.</context>
      <utterance>Sister Alma -- a C.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sister Alma hits the note. Christy shuffles a couple of more nuns to other sections, then gets a third note going with the altos, using her pitchpipe. For one moment, the nuns all realize they are singing a perfect chord. They are elated.</context>
      <utterance>Middle section, hold that note, for dear life. Sopranos, an A. Sister Alma?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did it! We actually sang a chord!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was exciting!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, for one second. That was the blend -- you've got to listen to each other. Be a group.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Lazarus, I get the feeling that you like discipline. Hard work. Page 65.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. I'm a nun. Four Popes now. The Lord hates a loafer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear you. How many days a week do you rehearse?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two days. An hour or so.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. We're a choir, right? Headliners. The big room. Two days a week won't cut it. Every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you really think we could do it? Get better?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Mary Lazarus, what do you think? They're pretty raw.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wet behind the ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bunch of real mama's girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy and Mary Lazarus look at each other, as real comrades. Christy leans on Mary Lazarus' shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, please? Can't we try?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll be hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy and Mary Lazarus shake hands, firmly. Christy turns to the choir, very businesslike.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten-hut!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. It's ancient.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy starts clapping her hands to the sound of the washer-dryer; gradually, the other nuns join her.</context>
      <utterance>It's a rhythm section. The beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Patrick -- do you remember the Dixie Cups?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(singing)</context>
      <utterance>The Dixie Cups? Oh my. I was just a girl. Of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold it. Mary Patrick, you're a pretty cheerful person, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a murmur from all the other nuns -- "Oh, yes.</context>
      <utterance>Am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, I am, I know it! All my life, I've just been... upbeat. Optimistic. Perky. I can't help it. Even when I was little, I remember my mother used to say, "That child is pure sunshine. She'll either be a nun -- or a stewardess."</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 67.</context>
      <utterance>So use it. When we sing hymns, they're usually about rejoicing, right? Celebration. Most music is. So don't hold back. Let all that joy go right into your voice. Make me happy. Let me hear it. Perk out. Perk down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NUNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Reverend Mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior takes one more glance around, then leaves. Now that the coast is clear, the singing begins again, quietly, to the rhythm of the machine.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Sisters.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BISHOP O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As usual, the chapel is almost empty, except for the nuns. The choir is in place behind the pulpit.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome this Sunday morning, 0 ye few and faithful. Page 68.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy nods to the Bishop, and signals to Sister Alma, who begins the accompaniment.</context>
      <utterance>The choir, I am told, has elected a new director -- Sister Mary Clarence, who will lead them in Hymn 127.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LET THY SOUL BE HEALED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Page 69.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sister Alma, inspired by Christy and the choir, burns up the organ with a solo. More people from the street begin to enter; tentative, curious, drawn by the music. At the end of the solo, Christy makes a gesture to the choir, and each member produces a tambourine. The chapel is full of energy, music and life.</context>
      <utterance>Sister Alma!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Robert sings, really letting the power of her voice ring out. She is astonishingly good.</context>
      <utterance>Mary Robert! Page 70.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 71.</context>
      <utterance>Gospel. A jazz solo on the organ. What next? Jesus goes to Rio? Good Friday-a- go-go? What were you thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking Las Vegas. Get some butts in those seats.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what next? Popcorn? Curtain calls? This is not a theater. or a casino.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. People like going to theaters and casinos. But they think church is for Grandma -- we could change that. Pack the joint.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Through blasphemy? You have corrupted the entire choir!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on. That's not fair. I worked hard with them. They gave up their free time, and they loved it. Those women are happy. And we can get even better. We can wake this place up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of the question.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please let me try. I'm begging you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy is crestfallen. There is a KNOCK on the door, and O'Hara enters. The other members of the choir are in behind him like sardines.</context>
      <utterance>And I am refusing. As of tomorrow, Mary Lazarus will resume her leadership of the choir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reverend Mother, I just wanted to congratulate you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't enjoyed Mass this much in years. What a marvelous program. Innovative. Inspiring. You are to be commended.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 72.</context>
      <utterance>Well... thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't wait until next Sunday, when the choir performs again. Did you see the people walk right in from the street? That music, that heavenly music -- it called to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must tell the Cardinal. I.11 send him a personal letter, describing your efforts, your bold new fight to keep your little convent alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy has just been eating this up with a spoon.</context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Patrick jumps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Bishop. Reverend Mother has some other ideas too. She's too modest to talk about it, but she thinks we should get out of the convent and into the neighborhood more.  This woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless her! There are so many problems in this neighborhood that we could help solve. That's why many of us became nuns. It's marvelous, Reverend Mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know Reverend Mother. Hides her light under a bushel. She has plans for us to move right onto the streets. Get to know people. Work with 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 73.</context>
      <utterance>You're a pioneer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Bishop, surely you realize -- this is a most dangerous neighborhood.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you'll face that danger head-on. As if I could stop you. And you have my complete support in this matter. Anything you can do to revitalize this neighborhood would be a blessing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you love her?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look at your feet, and I don't want to see anybody counting. Make it look easy. Again!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, right, cross with the left, spin and turn!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hopeless I</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amateurs 2</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Babies</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're here to pray for you, brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Get the hell out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know you don't want to sell drugs. You just had an unhappy childhood, and maybe a learning disability. You just need someone to pray for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know you don't want to bring pain and misery to your friends and neighbors. We'll pray to find you some honest work.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we know that, even though most people would call you a leech and a parasite, the lowest slug of humanity! We know that deep down inside, you're probably even worse. And so you truly need our prayers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nuns give him room, and the Driver zips off down the street. A small crowd has begun to gather, and it is growing by the moment, murmuring encouragement for the nuns. Christy turns to the Dealer, as other cars drive slowly past.</context>
      <utterance>What is this? Outta my way!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, prayer is the answer, and prayers free We're going to give free prayers to everyone who drives up to this house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're nuns!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Free prayers right over here! Drive up and get your prayers!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're hassling my customers! That's not legal! I know my rights. This is restriction of trade.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dealer's eyes turn ugly as he takes a gun from his pocket. Mary Patrick steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna call a cop? Page 76.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to shoot us all, tough guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it worth it? A lot of witnesses here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dealer glances at the surly crowd, then gives the nuns a disgusted look. He puts the gun away.</context>
      <utterance>Can I get a witness?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'll find another neighborhood to do my business. You can' t stop me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dealer turns and walks back to his house with anger. The crowd APPLAUDS and CHEERS. The picture suddenly becomes GRAINY, and we hear the voice of a NEWS REPORTER.</context>
      <utterance>If we can stop you here, they can stop you there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEWS REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.0.</mode>
      <context>CAMERA PULLS BACK and we see a TV screen with an image of the nuns and neighbors still celebrating. On top of the TV are several framed photographs of Vince Laflocca, his wife and children. INT. VINCE LaROCCA'S LIVING ROOM - NIGHT CONNIE LaROCCA, Vince's wife, watches the TV NEWS STORY and calls to Vince in the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>It was a truly remarkable scene, as the nuns from St. Katherine's literally drove the crack dealers from the neighborhood, led by the feisty Sister Mary Clarence.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrying a roast beef sandwich and a can of beer, Vince appears from the kitchen and glances at the TV screen to see a shot of the convent. He looks at Connie and makes a sour face. Page 77.</context>
      <utterance>Vinnie, get in here. You gotta see this!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince turns away from the TV just as a closeup of Christy appears on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>What? Nuns? You got me in here to see nuns? Isn't there a ball game on or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince leaves the room, and we see Christy again as she leads the choir.</context>
      <utterance>Look -- she's adorable!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NEWS REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This tiny convent has experienced an amazing turnaround. The sisters have revitalized and taken back their neighborhood, all due to the energy and talent of the convent choir, a group led by this gifted young nun. Tell us, Mary Clarence1 what makes you so special?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie all but spits out his wine. His eyes are wide as he watches Christy being interviewed. In one stride, he grabs his hat and coat and is out the door on the run.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm not special, Bob. It's just hard work... and prayer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eddie! You scared the hell out of me!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if I was Vince? You'd be dead right now. What are you doing giving interviews on TV?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't my fault! They just showed up. It's helping the convent.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're supposed to be hiding out!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really can't talk about it now. The place is packed. SRO. I've got a show to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to yourself. This isn't a career opportunity.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that. This isn't about me. It's about the choir. You should hear them. They're good. Really good. And I taught them.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, look at you You're glowing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. You look... great. I mean it..</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Lieutenant?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie sits on the bed beside Christy.</context>
      <utterance>I've been worried about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean -- worried about my testimony?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 79.</context>
      <utterance>No -- worried about you. Personally.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well.. thanks. I've been thinking about you.. - sometimes. I mean, there aren't a lot of guys around here. I mean, sometimes I feel like... a nun.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not... seeing anybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Most of the time I'm thinking about you. And now... you've really changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie and Christy are gazing into each other's eyes; they are just about to kiss. Their lips are less than an inch apart.</context>
      <utterance>You re sort of... radiant. your eyes are shining. You're rea1ly different...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie and Christy jump apart, their intimacy has frightened them both, particularly given Christy's outfit, and their location.</context>
      <utterance>You're... you're a nun.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy goes to the door.</context>
      <utterance>We're in a convent!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just remember - you're a target. Don't you think Vince has a T.V.?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy hurries toward the chapel, leaving Eddie to shake his head and wonder.</context>
      <utterance>Magic time! Page 80.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sister Alma starts playing a doo-wop vamp. Mary Patrick and Mary Robert step forward from the choir, standing beside Christy the way the Ronelles used to do.</context>
      <utterance>This Sunday's hymn is inspired by the lesson of Mary Magdalene. You know the one. Mary Magdalene was a young lady with a past. She was no stranger to sin. She was no stranger to practically everybody. Many condemned her. The whole neighborhood. But one man refused to do so. One man said, hey now, wait a minute. Listen to the story.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK AND ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hail, Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jerusalem is a real drag. Everybody hates me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK AND ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People throw stones. They call me names. I mean, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK AND ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -- wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Mary?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That man -- who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 81</context>
      <utterance>He's a carpenter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not like other guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's decent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's... dreamy. He's...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHOIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mary?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackpot! Two buckets</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is so exhilarating! All week long, I can't wait till Sunday, when we sing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd rather sing than do anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's better than ice cream.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's better than springtime.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks at Christy with astonishment.</context>
      <utterance>It's better than sex!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone's attention suddenly turns to Bishop O'Hara as he approaches.</context>
      <utterance>I imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The choir gathers around O'Hara with curiosity.</context>
      <utterance>Better and better, Sisters, you are truly an inspiration. And I bear gladsome tidings.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The choir reacts with an excited buzz: "The Council of Cardinals!", "What shall we sing?", etc. Mother Superior appears, from the center aisle.</context>
      <utterance>I've kept the Cardinal informed of your progress in the neighborhood. He has been most impressed. And he has invited you to attend a special evening Mass at St. Matthew's Cathedral on Sunday night1 to sing for the Council of Cardinals.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is indeed glorious news, Bishop. We will be honored to appear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode>MORE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Page 83.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And on such an occasion, I feel a completely traditional program will be best.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The council of Cardinals is perhaps the most esteemed body in the entire Catholic church. They command the utmost respect. Your more... secular entertainment would be wholly out of place.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Reverend Mother -- everyone loves our new style.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's brought people back to the church.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that why we were asked to sing for those Cardinals?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe this can be settled by a simple vote.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A vote?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the nuns look at one another. Then, slowly, one by one, they all raise their hands. Mother Superior is pure steel at this moment; her expression betrays no emotion. Christy, on the other hand, is quite confused.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. Mary Clarence, a convent is not a totalitarian state. Most major decisions are made by the membership as a whole. A membership that, I am certain, will vote in a rational and pious manner. All those in favor of allowing Mary Clarence to select a program?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... wait a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 84.</context>
      <utterance>The majority has spoken.</utterance>
   <speaker>BISHOP O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reverend Mother, as always, you are a true leader. Gracious and understanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will be wonderful, Reverend Mother. You'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a pro.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nuns cheer, and cluster around Christy, chattering about the upcoming concert, as Mother Superior strides off.</context>
      <utterance>I am certain the presentation will be a great success. Congratulations, Mary Clarence. And congratulations to you all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sent for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior continues with her paperwork as Christy picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>You have a phone call.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With mixed emotions, Christy speaks softly.</context>
      <utterance>Good news, kid. I pulled a few strings the judge has agreed to move the trial up. We'll be in court in a couple of days.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior is a very interested eavesdropper.</context>
      <utterance>That soon?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 85.</context>
      <utterance>Forty-eight hours -- and you'll be a free woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. That's good to hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, don't thank me or anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy hangs up the phone. She looks at Mother Superior.</context>
      <utterance>Right, right -- thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey -- your prayers have been answered. I'm leaving. In just a couple of days.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really. Well, that makes two of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have submitted my resignation to Bishop O'Hara. Privately. I have asked to be relocated as soon as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -- why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must go where I can be of use.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -- there's so much more to do right here. And look, if it's about me, I mean, I'm gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indeed. After how long? A few weeks? I have been here thirty years. And yet, it would seem, I know nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But everything that's happening is good! You can be a part of it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A part of what? Mary Clarence, it is one thing to rabble rouse, to sweep into town and declare a holiday. You have raised the Sisters' expectations, you have excited and confused them. They imagine this neighborhood to be some sort of delightful ongoing block party.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode>MORE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Page 86.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and I know that life is not so simple. There will be disappointments. Rude shocks. And you will have vanished. How... fortunate.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, so I just got things started. But you could build on that. You could keep it going.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sorry, Mary Clarence. I seem to have misplaced my tambourine. Good day, Mary Clarence.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy, frustrated, leaves the room. Mother Superior looks up, she is truly torn, a proud woman unsure of her choices.</context>
      <utterance>Good day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ice cream!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence -- you shouldn't have. Where did you get this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy and the nuns sit on stools, enjoying their ice cream by candlelight.</context>
      <utterance>It's a sin. It's a wicked indulgence. Is this butter almond? Page 87.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's contraband. Don't ask. But I wanted to give you a treat. A sort of... thank-you gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A thank-you? For what? You're the one we should be thanking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there any syrup?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... see, at my old convent, I wasn't always... real popular. I was sort of selfish and... not real helpful. Okay, I'll say it -- I wasn't much of a nun. But now, thanks to all of you... maybe I'm shaping up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence, don't be silly. You're an example to us all. You've taught us so much. We're singing for the Cardinals, and then -- who knows? Maybe the choir can travel -- to schools, and nursing homes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we can get some of the local kids to sing with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could cut a demo. Look for a label.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's true, wouldn't that be great. Of course, we never know when things are going to change. Any one of us could be transferred to another convent, tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you leaving us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no. We'll always be together.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy and the nuns qiggle, and continue eating their ice cream, in a spirit of true friendship. Mother Superior watches this scene, hidden in the shadows by the door to the kitchen. She has begun to see Christy in a new light. She looks thoughtful, and walks off.</context>
      <utterance>That's what Diana Ross said. Page 88.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're too late. Mulcahy just left.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need his signature on some things. They can't be processed without it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Parker looks annoyed -- he doesn't like deviations from procedure -- but after a moment of indecision, he sets the file folder on Tate's desk and walks away. Tate finishes the newspaper and shoves it aside. Bored, looks at his watch, then flips the file folder open and glances at its contents; routine money vouchers for equipment, supplies, etc. Tate is about to close the folder and shove it aside when something catches his eye.</context>
      <utterance>Leave 'em. He'll sign 'em later.</utterance>
   <speaker>TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He examines a money voucher for a generous donation to St. Katherine's Convent in San Francisco. It only takes a moment to put two and two together, and Tate scrambles for his phone and dials a number.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is this...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tate said you were gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 89.</context>
      <utterance>I get all the way down to my car, and, of course -- where are the keys?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie nods and moves on as Parker enters the elevator. After a few steps, Eddie suddenly looks disturbed. He picks up his pace. A little panicky, he begins to jog toward the squad room.</context>
      <utterance>I left the money vouchers with him. He said you'd sign them in the morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tate hangs up the phone and BOOM! Eddie hits him from behind like a linebacker, drilling him to the floor. Other detectives look up from their desks with confusion and alarm. Eddie pins Tate to the wall and snatches the voucher from his hand.</context>
      <utterance>St. Katherine's Convent on East Barton. It's gotta be the place.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarkson and another detective restrain Eddie before he can hit Tate.</context>
      <utterance>You're the leak, you son-of-a-bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nobody dares even question Eddie at this moment, and two detectives drag Tate away. Eddie grabs Tate's phone and dials long distance.</context>
      <utterance>Get him out of here! Downstairs, in the cell! I want his ass locked up now!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarkson dials quickly. Eddie listens to Tate's telephone as it RINGS and RINGS and RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Clarkson, get on the other line. Call Frisco Central. Tell 'em to get two squad cars outside St. Katherine's convent, and stop anybody with an out-of- state license plate from getting near the place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Council of Cardinals! I'm so nervous! What if I forget the words?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right to Hell. Just kidding. Where is that bus?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It should be here any minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy looks out the window, but sees no bus.</context>
      <utterance>Dress rehearsal at four, performance at 8:30. Sharp.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reverend Mother! Quick! Where's Christy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior points up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>They know she's here! They're on their way!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior looks alarmed as Eddie takes the stairs two at a time.</context>
      <utterance>The rehearsal room!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone makes a final check of their appearance, and then the group leaves the room to head for the bus. Mary Robert and Mary Patrick are the last to leave, except for Christy.</context>
      <utterance>It's here! Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry, Sister!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy primps in the mirror one last time, then leaves the room. She is puzzled to suddenly see Eddie running toward her from a side staircase. Page 92.</context>
      <utterance>Get moving. I'm right behind you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie grabs her hand and pulls her toward the side staircase.</context>
      <utterance>Eddie...?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vince knows you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy and Eddie hurry down the steps to the side entrance, and she almost trips on her choral robes. Eddie opens the door and starts outside, but Christy stops in her tracks.</context>
      <utterance>Long story. His goons will be here any minute. We've got to get you out of here '- now!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't go with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a show -- at St. Matthew's Cathedral. We're singing for the Cardinals.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie jerks her hand, and Christy follows him reluctantly to the car.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna be singing for St. Peter if you don't get your ass out of here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence! Sister!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 93.</context>
      <utterance>It's no use. She just isn't here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The HORN on the school bus blows loudly down in the street.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't make any sense. She was right behind me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't sing without her! What should we do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eddie -- I've got to go back. They won't sing without me. I'm deserting them.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think they'd understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie glances at her, impressed by the influence the convent has had.</context>
      <utterance>That's not the point! They need me!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They need you? A bunch of nuns? For what? Moral guidance? Make-up tips?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't get it! It's a big thing for them, it's like... Caesar's Palace. Prime-time. They're singing for the Cardinals. It's like... "Star Search." If first prize was a trip to the Vatican. They've worked really hard, they deserve this.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 94.</context>
      <utterance>Nuns?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're not nuns. They're like.. people. With one outfit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that guy in the bar was right? She's like... some kind of nun?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lawanda and her friends watch Joey and Willy pounding on the convent door.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right -- when I see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You dudes looking for nuns? They all went to St. Matthew's.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>St, Matthew's? Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWANDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey and Willy run past the girls, get into their car and take off.</context>
      <utterance>Praise the Lord.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets her go, then gets out to pump gas.</context>
      <utterance>Even nuns have to pee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy runs up to the Biker..</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy swings onto the back seat; the Biker puts his Harley in gear and flies down the street. Eddie is shocked as he drops some money on the ground and jumps into his car to follow.</context>
      <utterance>I'm late for church. Can I get a lift? Page 96.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARDINAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this the choir you've been speaking so highly of, Bishop?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The choir seems very demoralized as they finish the hymn. Mary Patrick is close to tears.</context>
      <utterance>They're just a bit nervous. They'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We sound terrible We need Mary Clarence.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're losing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand. Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clapping his hands briskly, the FLOOR DIRECTOR suddenly steps forward from behind the TV cameras and hustles the choir away from the altar.</context>
      <utterance>Her whereabouts are unknown, and we must proceed without her. Pull yourselves together.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOOR DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dispirited, the choir leaves the altar and walks toward the back of the church. Page 97.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Sisters, we have to move on now. That was great, just great. Charlie, throw a spot on the pulpit. Let's get a balance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two Technicians turn toward her, and she is horrified to see they are. Joey and Willy. Christy gasps as Willy sticks a gun in her ribs. Joey smiles at her.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me -- where's the rehearsal room?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey opens a door that leads to an alley behind the cathedral. Mary Robert looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>The rehearsal room is right this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, this isn't the way. Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy suddenly lifts her knee into Willy's groin, and he buckles over. She scrambles for the gun, but Joey beats her to it. Christy looks frantically at Mary Robert.</context>
      <utterance>They're from my old convent.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run! Take off!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Revived Willy lunges for Mary Robert and grabs her. The two men hustle the two struggling nuns out the door to the alley. Page 98.</context>
      <utterance>Again?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey starts the car, and it takes off with SQUEALING tires. Willy has his gun pointed at Christy, who sits beside Mary Robert.</context>
      <utterance>Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what do they want? Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's got nothing to do with this. Let her go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right to the cops. No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Robert, don't panic. Remember what we talked about? Experience?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car comes to a stop at an intersection. Christy reaches across Mary Robert and opens the car door. She shoves Mary Robert into the street.</context>
      <utterance>You can handle this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Robert executes a perfect somersault onto the sidewalk. She looks to heaven, crosses herself and runs back to the cathedral. Willy grabs Christy before she can escape.</context>
      <utterance>Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's gettin' away!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 99.</context>
      <utterance>Forget her! We got the one we need! Step on it! Joey takes off again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean -- they kidnapped her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes -- two men -- and they had guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She shouldn't have come back. She knew she was in danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -- why would anyone kidnap a nun?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior suddenly steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Were they Catholics?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nuns all react with shock and emotion.</context>
      <utterance>She isn't a nun. Her real name is Christy Van Cartier, and she is a professional entertainer. She witnessed a vicious crime, and has been hiding in our convent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An... entertainer?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wasn't a nun?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER NUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She lied to us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... but... she was such a wonderful nun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look what she did with the choir. She made us sing beautifully.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 100.</context>
      <utterance>That should have tipped us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't care who she is. We can't sing without her!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's our inspiration!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's the act!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reverend Mother, I know that you and Mary Clarence didn't always agree, but -- we've got to help her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to save her!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nuns all look to Mother Superior for an answer.</context>
      <utterance>We can't leave it up to the Feds!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down. Think clearly. Mary Robert, do you have any idea who those men were?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said they were from her old convent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... she was a showgirl. She didn't have an old convent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She told us about one. The Little Sisters of the Moonlight. In Las Vegas.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the nuns hurriedly cross themselves.</context>
      <utterance>All right. It's a beginning. Las Vegas, Nevada.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior leads the way out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Mary Lazarus, find the Bishop and tell him the situation. Everyone else -- follow me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Driver opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>Emergency! Open up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nuns are all zooming past the Driver, onto the bus.</context>
      <utterance>The San Francisco airport! Immediately!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Lazarus grabs the Driver's sleazy novel, confiscating it. The Driver starts the engine. As the bus drives off, Eddie's car streaks INTO THE SCENE and parks in front of the cathedral.</context>
      <utterance>Step on it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'HARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie turns and races back toward the car.</context>
      <utterance>There was a kidnapping. We think Las Vegas.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifteen hundred for the run to Vegas. Rock-bottom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we don't have fifteen hundred!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Manager starts back toward his office.</context>
      <utterance>We're nuns!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't help you. No exceptions.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voice has a powerful ring of authority to it, and the Manager looks around.</context>
      <utterance>Young man! Page 102.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are nuns. We pray.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We pray for good things. Food for the hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peace on Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>However, we can also pray for other things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Measles.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lawsuits.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a pause, as the Manager stares at the nuns in horror.</context>
      <utterance>Tax audits.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nuns begin to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Come, Sisters. Let's go to chapel. Bring your beads.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy does not reply.</context>
      <utterance>Babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Babe, what happened here? Look at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening, Vincent.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, Vincent? This is me, doll. I know you. What did you think you were doing? Running to the cops. Hiding out. No, no. You're sorry now, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince, Willy and Joey all look at each other, perplexed.</context>
      <utterance>I am sorry for all my sins. And yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a nun, Vince.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Chris. I always will. I gave you so much. My time. My affection. A big-time career. And how do you repay me? What's the thanks I get? Where's the loyalty, huh? Where's the love?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince stands; the charm hasn't worked. He's getting angry.</context>
      <utterance>You will be judged, Vincent. We all will.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean -- judged? I don't get judged, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode>MORE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Page 104.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who are you to talk? You were nothing. You couldn't even sing. I must have been out of my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's acting weird, Vince. Ever since we picked her up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince grabs the front of Christy's habit and squeezes it tightly around her throat.</context>
      <utterance>It's spooky. It's like she ain't even afraid or nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's afraid. Come on, tell the boys you're afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey and Willy look a little unsure as Vince storms out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Who gives a damn? Waste her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so beautiful...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what a lovely name. Las Vegas...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The plane sets down at the Vegas airport. Mother Superior and the nuns climb out.</context>
      <utterance>And Gommorah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's done?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not... totally.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's... she's a nun.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you nuts? She's not a nun. It's Christy. She's a babe!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, Vince, how do you know she didn't like, join up and become a nun when she was in that convent?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It didn't happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was real quiet and peaceful all the way back in the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No smart-ass remarks or nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe this. Okay, I want both you guys to go back there, and both of you shoot her at the same time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look happy with this solution as Joey and Willy leave.</context>
      <utterance>Right. That way we'd never know which bullet got to her brain and killed her first. It could always be the other guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, we got one-two-three, and on three we both shoot. Got it? Page 106.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey points his gun at Christy's left temple, and Willy points his gun at her right temple.</context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy closes her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>One... two...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neither man shoots. They look at each other with anger. Christy opens her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Three!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't shoot!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither did you!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figured if you were gonna, then I wouldn't have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I figured, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Las Vegas -- she's here somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Patrick is pointing to a group of billboards that feature huge ads for the local hotels and casinos. The center billboard has a splashy picture of a roulette wheel, the Elvis impersonator, and Christy and the Ronelles. The bottom part of the billboard shows the name of the Moonlight Casino and Lounge.</context>
      <utterance>Look! There she is!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Little Sisters of the Moonlight!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 107.</context>
      <utterance>But how do we get there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stand back.  Taxi!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It didn't work, Vince.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were both supposed to put your guns to her head and shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We both missed.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, so the problem is still the nun outfit, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, take it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strip down a nun? You want us to fry?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For like, twelve zillion eternities?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, she's not a nun! Get her out of the nun outfit, and put her in some clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe pants.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A sweater.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey and Willy are very confident about this solution. They strut off, pleased with themselves. Page 108.</context>
      <utterance>And then we can ice her. No nun, no evil eye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He works the ropes free, and Christy rubs her wrists to get circulation back again.</context>
      <utterance>We got it all worked out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Christy -- strip.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy suddenly drops to her knees and begins to pray.</context>
      <utterance>That... thing. That nun thing. Take it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's she doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's praying.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Joey and Willy bend down to help her up, Christy suddenly grabs their neckties in each hand. With a fierce jerk, she pulls the neckties with all her might, smashing Joey's head against Willy's. Page 109. Stunned, Joey and Willy stagger backward, holding their heads. Christy scrambles out the door while the two men groan in pain.</context>
      <utterance>And God bless Joey and Willy, who are only trying to do their jobs.  Pox fibula tibia vobiscum. Et marcus domino's pizza. Have mercy. Amen.  I'm finished now. Help me up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There she goes! she's taking the stairs</utterance>
   <speaker>I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They run quickly after her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In unison, the nuns all cross themselves.</context>
      <utterance>Brace yourselves, Sisters.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nuns spread to every part of the room, looking for Christy. Page 110.</context>
      <utterance>Spread out and look for Mary Clarence. Try to blend in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me -- has anyone seen a nun?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CROUPIER and the players stare at the two nuns.</context>
      <utterance>A Benedictine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CROUPIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Place your bets.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red 21.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy looks up to heaven.</context>
      <utterance>You sure? How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Joey stands at the opposite side of the roulette table, glaring at Christy. The crowd around the table watches Christy for a moment, then they all put their chips down on Red 21. Joey starts working his way around the table toward Christy as the Croupier spins the wheel. The ball falls into a slot.</context>
      <utterance>Red 21.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROUPIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone at the table turns toward Christy, outraged. She gives them a reprimanding look.</context>
      <utterance>Black 14.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy suddenly realizes that Joey is almost at her side. She shoves the Salesman against him and runs away. Page 111.</context>
      <utterance>Did you learn something?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nuns surround Christy and head through the crowd in a cluster. Joey and Vince pursue them from different directions. Just before they catch them, Mother Superior barks an order.</context>
      <utterance>Saving you. Move!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nuns split up, each taking a different direction. Vince and Joey look bewildered.</context>
      <utterance>Break!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get her!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 112.</context>
      <utterance>Which one!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince, Joey and Willy each pick a nun and follow her. Vince catches up to a nun, whom we only see from the rear. He grabs her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>The nun!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nun spins around; it is Mother Superior.</context>
      <utterance>Babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince releases her and frantically searches the crowd again. Joey catches up with his nun, only to find it is Mary Patrick. The shell game has worked; Christy has escaped for the moment.</context>
      <utterance>Sweetheart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the nuns suddenly come together, and see that the exits are blocked by Vince and his hoods. Vince spots Christy in the center of the group.</context>
      <utterance>There's nuns everywhere! Hundreds of 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There she is!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy sees Vince pointing at her.</context>
      <utterance>Which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy runs toward a set of glass doors set off to one side. The other nuns follow her.</context>
      <utterance>Quick, there's another way out of here. Follow me. Page 113.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince, Joey and Willy head for the lounge. Across the room, Eddie sees Christy and the cluster of nuns head through the glass doors. He barks into his walkie-talkie.</context>
      <utterance>She's heading for the lounge! Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move in -- now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't see anything in here!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Willy -- hit the lights.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willy moves off to find the light switch. There is a flash of black and white fabric behind some chairs.</context>
      <utterance>Find 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There! Before he can shoot, there is another flash of fabric on the opposite side of the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And a third flash of fabric near the stage.</context>
      <utterance>No -- there!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Willy has found the lights, and the lounge is suddenly brightly lit. The mobsters blink for a moment, then find all the nuns bunched together in a corner, trying to find an exit.</context>
      <utterance>Over there!</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nuns turn and face the mobsters, shielding Christy.</context>
      <utterance>Freeze! Everybody! Page 114.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joey?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy steps forward, to the front of the stage.</context>
      <utterance>Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right here. Let the others go -- they have nothing to do with this.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joey -- do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, boss -- she's still, you know, a nun.</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Superior steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>She's a broad! Got it! Just some broad!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guarantee you, she is no broad. She is Sister Mary Clarence, of St. Katherine's Convent. She is a model of generosity, virtue and love. You have my word, gentlemen. She is a nun.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vince has had enough. Facing Christy, he raises the gun and points it right between Christy's eyes, only inches away. The nuns all recoil with horror. BLAM! The gun goes off, but Christy isn't hit. She blinks her eyes open, shocked to be alive. Instead, it's Vince who falls, crumpling to the floor, and clutching his shoulder. Across the room, Eddie holds a smoking police revolver. The nuns all swarm around Christy joyously.</context>
      <utterance>Hear that? Now aren't you glad we didn't shoot her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence -- you're alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Page 115.</context>
      <utterance>Christy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Van Cartier.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy breaks away from the jubilant nuns. She faces Mother Superior.</context>
      <utterance>You know? About me? About everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reverend Mother -- Thank-you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saved my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Police pour into the room and gather up Joey, Willy and Vince. Eddie walks over to Christy and Mother Superior.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a Christian.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you have a concert to go to?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That depends. Sisters, you don't know this, but Reverend Mother's been making all sorts of noises about resigning. That's bad news. I don't know if we could sing, if we thought that was true.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a note.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary Lazarus coughs, and points to her throat, as if she has laryngitis. All the other nuns imitate her.</context>
      <utterance>Impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I guess you're stuck. Life sentence. No parole.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Christy, watching this. She grins.</context>
      <utterance>Very well.  I hold you responsible for all of this, For introducing a lounge act into my convent. For utterly disrupting our way of life. And for placing all of us in mortal danger.  Thank-you. Page 116.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Eddie, thanks a whole bunch. Thanks for sticking me in a convent. So you think, after all this, maybe I really am a nun?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. There's only one way to be absolutely sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eddie takes Christy in his arms, and they begin a kiss. As they do so, Vince struggles toward Christy, as two cops hold him back. He is furious.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>VINCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was good to you! You re nothing but no-talent garbage! You're a two-bit Tramp!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That used to be true, Vince. I was with you. But something happened. And I'm different now. Real--different. I've had, well, you might call it -- a religious experience. And I've got just two words for you. And those two words are...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Clarence!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MARY PATRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just realized -- this is the last time we'll all be together. We're going to miss you so much. Page 117. Christy and Mary Patrick embrace. Mary Patrick is tearful.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey -- you re supposed to be the cheerful one. Why do I suddenly feel like Snow White?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY LAZARUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy and Mary Lazarus embrace.</context>
      <utterance>You re okay -- for a civilian.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reverend Mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since Mary Clarence came to St. Katherine's, I've been shot at, kidnapped by Mafia hit men, and I've tasted beer. Is that enough experience yet? For final vows?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. What about skydiving? A crank call to Billy Graham?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have evidenced great maturity, Mary Robert. We shall have a serious discussion.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about me, Reverend Mother? I think you were right. I'm just a bad influence. Sister show biz.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps not. Perhaps we can all use... a little Spandex.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? And maybe shorter habits, and women priests, and sleeping late?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER SUPERIOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christy and Mother Superior embrace.</context>
      <utterance>Don't push it.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
