<movie id="504" title="Soldier">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>2010</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RILEY, panning for the next target, holds fire, passes over two MOTHERS HOLDING CHILDREN, pans for a nearby SOLDIER TARGET. But the SOLDIER TARGET zips behind the MOTHERS HOLDING CHILDREN, taking cover, weapon pointed at RILEY. For half a second RILEY hesitates! BUDDA BUDDA BUDDA! TODD blazes away, mercilessly blowing away the MOTHERS HOLDING CHILDREN TARGET and the SOLDIER TARGET.</context>
      <utterance>Suddenly multiple TARGETS appear, charging. BUDDA BUDDA BUDDA! First TARGET down!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAIN TITLE APPEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as the ROAR OF GUNS gives way to MUSIC...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel Mekum has his "boys" unpacked. I think he wants to show them off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmmmph.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They look...impressive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they're...pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so hot about them?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very much improved. In every way.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Colonel Mekum from Q. He's their commanding officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Improved...how?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As I said, in every way. Physically and psychologically. More endurance, quicker responses, better hand-eye, improved technical training. Where the First Psychology gave you ninety-eight percent obedience, this bunch gives you 99.4.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...He used to say, "If it ain't broke, don't fix it."</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I...see. I'm not sure I quite get your...point...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the soldiers we've got now, they've been through all kinds of heavy shit...and they've always got the job done. Now these new ones, these "hot shots" of yours...what kind of action have they seen? They are battle-tested, aren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's up to you field guys. H.Q. wants you to break 'em in when you do the annual security sweep in January.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sweep is just routine, not even police action. I'd like to see some sort of...meaningful evidence...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Such as?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RUBRICK and SLOAN exchange a startled glance, but MEKUM doesn't seem fazed as we...</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we could run some tests. Kind of a comparison, the old and the new...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very nice, Riley. Fall away.</utterance>
   <speaker>RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As RILEY joins the VETERANS squatting motionlessly, RUBRICK glances at the shredded electronic target, glances at his stopwatch, then looks at Mekum.</context>
      <utterance>Sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MEKUM smirks, picks up the weapon, disassembles it rapidly.</context>
      <utterance>Thirty seconds, 90 percent hits.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RUBRICK, CHURCH and SLOAN exchange glances of disbelief as MEKUM scatters the disassembled parts onto the concrete floor with a loud clatter. TODD watches, unblinking, as MEKUM looks to the NEW SOLDIERS.</context>
      <utterance>Let's make it more difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A blond Nordic giant is suddenly on his feet among the NEW SOLDIERS. There is real dignity in his salute; he's like a pro.</context>
      <utterance>Caine Six-Oh-Seven!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAINE 607</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OFFICERS look at each other again in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Assemble the weapon, load, fire on the target from various evasive positions in a thirty-second period.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MEKUM punches his watch as CAINE 607 gracefully begins to pick up pieces of weapon, doing it rapidly, yet without apparent haste. TODD is watching, revealing nothing. CLACK! KA SHACK! CLICK! CAINE 607 slaps the weapon together, loading a magazine with a final KA SHUCK, then he dives to the floor, firing a rapid burst at the electronic target which blinks wildly... OFFICERS watch, impressed. CAINE 607 is firing from another position. The target goes crazy. CAINE 607 is rolling and firing at the same time. The target goes wild. MEKUM's watch clicks off 27 seconds...28...29... The firing stops. TODD stares impassively as CAINE 607 salutes. Beside him, RILEY watches also.</context>
      <utterance>Starting...now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RUBRICK is looking at the electronic target, grudgingly impressed.</context>
      <utterance>As you were, soldier.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ninety-nine percent...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While taking evasive action...</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's...very good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See? Much stronger.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about endurance?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our man has been out there fifteen minutes now. Shouldn't you send one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a minute.  Now, see this test? This shows what they do under sleep deprivation conditions. Forty-eight hours awake and they can...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MELTON, one of the husky new soldiers, climbs to his feet and steps toward MEKUM, saluting.</context>
      <utterance>Melton, Eight Five. Forward.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight Five, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MELTON's face shows no expression as MEKUM continues.</context>
      <utterance>Ten miles, Melton, on the run.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got sixty minutes. Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MELTON heads out into the rain running smoothly and easily as we...</context>
      <utterance>Sir!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My man left exactly twenty minutes after yours. Make a note of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we supposed to do with the old soldiers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old soldiers never die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shape appears in the rain a hundred yards off, moves closer, takes the form of a runner running. It's TODD, still moving at the same pace, his face like stone. TODD lopes into the big warehouse and, breathing hard but evenly, comes to a halt in front of RUBRICK and salutes.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, age is a factor, but the real factor is the training program, especially the psychological. The mind controls the body after all, and we're doing wonderful things with the mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHURCH has been thinking and now he speaks to MEKUM.</context>
      <utterance>At ease, soldier.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is he tired?</context>
      <utterance>What's the price of all that speed?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tired?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Send him up the chain, Rube.</context>
      <utterance>Todd here ran the pace he's been taught to run. He's still strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soldier! Up the chain!</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD salutes and lopes toward ten chains that dangle from the rafters sixty feet above, grabs one, and starts up it, hand over hand. MEKUM watches TODD climb, then looks at CHURCH who is looking at him expectantly. MEKUM grins at CHURCH. Then MEKUM looks back at TODD, not hurrying. TODD is thirty feet up and climbing, passing the eight inch circular "platforms" or footholds in the chain every ten feet.</context>
      <utterance>Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Melton, on the double! Up a chain!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MELTON takes a few easy strides, gracefully catches a chain mid- stride, and smarts up, climbing easily and twice as fast as TODD. CHURCH, SLOAN, and RUBRICK crane their necks as the two men struggle upward toward the rafters. Three quarters of the way up, MELTON comes even with TODD, then passes him. MEKUM, watching, smirks. CHURCH is watching too, and he's still not satisfied. His brow is knit, something's bothering him.</context>
      <utterance>Sir!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about...spirit?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spirit?  Oh! You mean "AQ"..."aggressive qualities"?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever the latest jargon is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Much better, much higher. For example, where your old ones expressed ninety percent of their sexual energy in aggressive physicality, these new ones are ninety-nine percent without sexual inclination. It's all aggression.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real men!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLOAN raises her eyebrows, gives RUBRICK a look. Frowning thoughtfully, MEKUM looks up.</context>
      <utterance>At ease, Lieutenant.  What if they fought? A sudden silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, Rube. Tell Todd to take him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look at MEKUM. Is this the chink in the armor? The new soldiers can't fight?</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"No"?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now CHURCH, RUBRICK, and SLOAN are stunned. They exchange a glance.</context>
      <utterance>Not fair. No contest. Send two more of your old ones up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RUBRICK shrugs, turns to the VETERANS still sitting stoically in a group on the cement floor.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two of the veterans, ROMERO and GOINES, leap immediately to their feet and climb rapidly. SLOAN, CHURCH, and RUBRICK exchange a look as MEKUM smirks confidently. ANGLE ON TODD AND MELTON ABOVE. They're still facing each other across the sixty foot drop. MELTON glances down...without losing sight of TODD. ROMERO and GOINES are coming up the chains fast, hand over hand. They're within ten feet, their impassive faces look dangerous. Nothing shows on MELTON's machine-face, but he starts a slight motion in his chain so that he spins slowly. That way, as the veterans surround him, he keeps a continual eye an all three. TODD, his face impassive, eyes MELTON vigilantly.</context>
      <utterance>Romero, A. -- Goines, D.L. -- up the chains.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're...fantastic!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmmmmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could have a problem here, couldn't we? I mean, we just lost three men...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Training accident." Paperwork.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I wouldn't worry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the bodies?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Turning his back on SLOAN and RUBRICK, CHURCH approaches MEKUM who's still raging, indicating MELTON to the blank-faced NEW</context>
      <utterance>Incinerator.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're very...impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was our best man who got his eye... Todd, a real tough one. Survived police action in Montana, fought in the Argentine Sector, and in the Saudi Campaign to say nothing of --</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The NEW SOLDIERS sit impassively, the bleeding MELTON among them, staring right at the VETERANS. Not far away three dead bodies lie motionless as we...</context>
      <utterance>Old news! They're nothing at all! Wait until you get these new fellas into some real action. I guarantee you'll be awed. I guarantee it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HAWKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as the hubbub finally dies down, a grizzled pioneer named SLADE bellows loudly at her.</context>
      <utterance>Please! Quiet, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HAWKINS stares SLADE down, refusing to speak until she has real silence. When she finally speaks, her voice is calm and controlled.</context>
      <utterance>Just tell me one thing! How many of them are there and are they armed?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sudden murmur dies away quickly under HAWKINS' hard stare.</context>
      <utterance>There in a man...one man. He was found in the trench by several children...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A murmur goes through the crowded room, then a woman named ELISE speaks over the hum of voices...</context>
      <utterance>This man was not armed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HAWKINS glances toward MACE, a muscular, bearded man, about thirty.</context>
      <utterance>How could there only be one? How could he get here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A commotion in the back room causes MACE to break off as JIMMY PIG, a clean-shaven burly-looking pioneer in his thirties, pushes his way in, followed by four more PIONEERS. All five of then are wearing their huge hooded parkas, strange Eskimo-type wind goggles, and carrying weapons.</context>
      <utterance>He was unconscious. We couldn't ask him anything. He --</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An excited hubbub. HAWKINS is trying to restore order when SLADE shouts over the commotion.</context>
      <utterance>Nothin' out there. We couldn't see nobody, couldn't see no ship, no vehicles, nothin'...plus the wind's up again real strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HAWKINS ignores him as she speaks with firm authority.</context>
      <utterance>They're hiding, I bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The way she says it, you know she's used to getting her way, and, in fact, PIONEERS are exchanging glances and nodding when SLADE shouts again.</context>
      <utterance>Let's everybody calm down right now!  We have an injured man among us. One man. A traveler. Unarmed.  We all want to do the decent thing. The decent thing is to help him. Mace's wife, Sandra, is looking after him now. Now, I'd like a vote of support on this course of action from all of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You keep an eye on him, Mace! You watch him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANDRA smiles, stands up, moves toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Want to try some more of this? TODD swallows weakly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hears her VOICE in the next room...a low murmur. He's looking around again when a NOISE makes him look back toward the door. A two-year-old is crawling into the room on hands and knees. The baby boy, NATHAN, stops just inside, seeing TODD in the bed. NATHAN looks into TODD's eyes with childlike interest and wonder. TODD meets the look with those blank soldier's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You rest now. I'll give you more later. TODD watches her exit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean he's survived worse? Did he say something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but he's covered with old wounds, all sorts of scars. Knife scars, bullet scars, burns.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A soldier!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are words on his shoulder. Tannhauser Gate, the Argentine Sector, Montana, Bolivia, Shanghai</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MACE and SANDRA look into each other's eyes, very worried. Then...</context>
      <utterance>The Tannhauser Gate was a battle...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll have to sleep on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MACE is looking around. He spots the open door to the bedroom, hurries to it, and disappears. SANDRA starts after him, looking worried...but before she gets to the door, MACE reappears with NATHAN safely in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Nathan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's any danger to Nathan --</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MACE and SANDRA lock eyes in firm understanding as we...</context>
      <utterance>I won't permit danger to Nathan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MACE is watching TODD sharply.</context>
      <utterance>You must be...you must be feeling better. TODD says nothing. His eyes flick to NATHAN.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're teaching the boy to walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD says nothing. His eyes follow MACE who's gone to the corner where he's seizing a heavy metal rod that might be a weapon. TODD tenses. Ready. Dangerous. As MACE turns toward him, MACE doesn't notice the danger in TODD'S eyes.</context>
      <utterance>He's late learning. He was sick for a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He innocently approaches with the metal rod. Super alert, TODD watches MACE hold the rod out to him.</context>
      <utterance>I got something for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD looks mistrustful.</context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like this. MACE demonstrates, using the rod like a cane.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Expressionless, watches MACE use the cane.</context>
      <utterance>See?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MACE never even realizes how much danger he was in.</context>
      <utterance>Practice with it. In a day or two maybe you'll be strong enough to go out to the garden with Sandra.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But ELLEN's eyes are on TODD and so are the others crowding behind her to peep over her shoulder. They all want to get a look at TODD, but when he looks in their direction, they retreat shyly. SANDRA is wearing a parka too. She picks up NATHAN from where he's sitting near TODD's feet and carries him to the door, giving him a kiss, then handing him to ELLEN. NATHAN starts to cry and holds his arms out to his mother as ELLEN hugs him and comforts him. TODD watches the drama as ELLEN and SANDRA comfort the child and soothe his fears at being separated from his mother. Nothing shows in TODD's eyes...but affection seems to fascinate him. As ELLEN and her cohorts hurry off with NATHAN, they sneak over- the-shoulder glances at the strange monster, TODD. Just then MACE, dressed in a heavy parka also, comes out of the bedroom and heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>I came for Nathan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MACE is heading out the door as we...</context>
      <utterance>Let's go. Come on, Sergeant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her meaning clear, SANDRA continues to demonstrate to TODD how to plant the seedling in the earth.</context>
      <utterance>You have to watch out for them. They probably wouldn't kill someone your size, not if you were healthy anyway. But they'd make you pretty sick. Someone smaller...like me, or a child...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD follows her look to the other side of the trench where the plants are already eighteen inches high. Other PIONEERS, working on their hands and knees also, are sneaking glances as TODD, among them, a middle-aged woman named JUDITH and an older woman, EMMA. SANDRA frowns one of their looks away protectively as she selects another seedling from a tray and hands it to TODD.</context>
      <utterance>In a month this one will be as big as those.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD looks at it. He doesn't exactly look scared, but he handles it gingerly, seemingly intimidated by the delicate seedling. He starts to plant it carefully as we...</context>
      <utterance>Here. You try one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't talk to a soldier no more than you can talk to a...a...bomb! Or a bullet! They're trained, they're killing machines. They got an objective and they go after that objective and nothing stops them but killing them.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The conversation gets the attention of JOHNNY and WILL who stop food-fighting to listen to the adults talk.</context>
      <utterance>Just one? To kill us all?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First off, if there's one, there's more. That's how it is, soldiers travel in bunches. Second, they don't waste soldiers on folks like us, that's for police! Training soldiers to kill weaklings like us is not what they call "cost effective."</utterance>
   <speaker>CHESTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then who do they fight?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON ILONA noticing WILL and TOMMY listening.</context>
      <utterance>Other soldiers! There's a saying, "Soldiers deserve soldiers."</utterance>
   <speaker>ILONA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON TOMMY and WILL glancing toward the next table. ANGLE ON THE NEXT TABLE where TODD, wedged between SANDRA and MACE, is eating like a machine, looking neither right nor left as people jabber all around him. ANGLE ON JUDITH whispering to EMMA at a nearby table as she watches TODD eat.</context>
      <utterance>Slade, hush up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON SLADE who turns now and boldly addresses TODD across the gap between the tables...</context>
      <utterance>You see how much he's eating?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a sudden hush in the noisy room, broken only by a few urgent whispers and a cough. TODD looks up from his food and meets SLADE'S look. SANDRA scowls at SLADE as SLADE persists...</context>
      <utterance>I don't see how you can not remember how you got here, Sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The silence is even more charged than before. SANDRA looks alarmed. Someone coughs. The tension is unbearable.</context>
      <utterance>You're not a deserter, are you... Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sigh of relief from everybody! But SLADE presses on.</context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how come you're not with your unit?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on, Slade, let the man eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON TODD, actually struggling with the question... remembering. Suddenly he blurts...</context>
      <utterance>It's not an unreasonable question.  How about it, Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was...replaced.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD hesitates for half a second before answering.</context>
      <utterance>Replaced?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are looks exchanged among the PIONEERS as we...</context>
      <utterance>By a better soldier, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Across the room, TODD, wearing a T-shirt and baggy pants is sitting on a stool, his face impassive as ever. As SANDRA talks, her back to him, TODD's eyes are on the contours of her body against the shift she's wearing. It's very...erotic.</context>
      <utterance>...And it got worse and worse. My father hadn't had any work in three months and...also...there were other things...violence... political feelings. My father said he'd heard it was better in the Trinity moons. A lot of other people must have had the same idea because the ship was jammed with people...mostly families. That's probably why it broke down... overloaded.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD'S face is as impassive as ever while his eyes caress the shape of her body...and she, unaware, continues to reminisce.</context>
      <utterance>Even after they made the repairs, it barely got off the ground, it was an old converted mining transport, a piece of junk to start with. It just...dropped. Maybe you saw what's left of it...out there in the wind. A lot of people died. And we couldn't make any radio contact... So we were stuck here. Nobody was happy about it. A few years later, when the dumpers started coming over and dropping stuff, people tried to get their attention with explosions and fires. But it didn't work. They must be unmanned...or they just don't care. Maybe they think we're garbage too!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As SANDRA maneuvers NATHAN, TODD catches glimpses of her breasts pushing against the material of the shift. She continues, still not noticing where his attention is.</context>
      <utterance>So there really wasn't any choice. People had to pull together and make the best of it. We became a... community.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wry laugh. She turns to put NATHAN down on the floor and catches TODD's eyes just as he shifts them quickly from her breasts. For a moment it's awkward...she looks at him...then she recovers.</context>
      <utterance>One good thing...nobody bothers us. Who'd want to fight over a godforsaken place like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD doesn't answer as we...</context>
      <utterance>I guess that's what you like! The fighting, I mean. The wars.  You must...you're a soldier...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HAWKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CHILDREN barely acknowledge her as she comes even with them. She looks at what they're looking at. What they're seeing through the doorway is TODD, shirtless, doing an eerie sequence of tai chi exercises. His muscular body ripples, revealing an incredible map of scar tissue that speaks eloquently of the life he's led...gash marks, long zippers of stitches, the puckered patches of burns. HAWKINS watches for a long moment, her eyes worried. In the midst of a slow graceful movement, TODD suddenly whirls and delivers a lightning blow to an unseen enemy with amazing speed and fury, the terrible force contained in the movement all too obvious. Even as HAWKINS and the CHILDREN gasp silently, TODD returns to the graceful, almost balletic movement, even spookier now, that preceded the deadly thrust. The CHILDREN's eyes are like saucers, their jaws agape. HAWKINS shudders...and breaks the hypnotic spell, speaking aloud to the children.</context>
      <utterance>You children are supposed to be doing lessons.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lessons.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, we're not going to shoot anything. That's not what we mean by "hunting."  Jimmy Pig, you're not going to shoot anything, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What could I hit?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's how we call for help. Two shots. There'll be someone on duty, listening in case we get off the wire and get lost or something. We have flares too. Come on. Other are already climbing the ladder out of the trench to the surface above as MACE urges TODD to follow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD follows his look to a long open trench leading, apparently, nowhere.</context>
      <utterance>Sandra said she told you how we wound up here. Our parents and so on.  Over here, we call these "catcher trenches."</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sudden SHOUT, "HEYYUP! YO!" distracts them. TODD looks forward, sees RED pointing to a chunk of steel a hundred yards off the wire. ANGLE ON JIMMY PIG, already fastening his safety rope and a second rope to the wire, then heading off toward the piece of steel, trailing the two ropes. ANGLE ON MACE, explaining the procedure to TODD.</context>
      <utterance>We try to work 'em when they're dry. It's lousy going in there when they're flooded. You can see...</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD is watching JIMMY PIG as he approaches the piece of steel and starts to attach his rope to it.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever looks useful, if we can get a rope to it, we'll go for it. But you can't ever go further than your safety line because it'll come up on you with sometimes maybe ten seconds or even less.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing at first...then a very faint WHISTLING. The sound he heard that first night when he was on the settlement "roof."</context>
      <utterance>Like right now. You hear that? TODD listens.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD can see JIMMY PIG. He's attached the rope to the steel and he gives a signal. As PIONEERS start to haul on the line, pulling the steel toward them, MACE shouts at JIMMY PIG.</context>
      <utterance>It's close when you hear that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But MACE breaks off, realizing that TODD'S attention is elsewhere. TODD is beyond MACE toward the landscape. MACE (and the other PIONEERS) turn to see what TODD'S looking at. ANGLE ON THE "JUNK MOUNTAINS" in the distance, several miles off, where, hovering high above the junk mountains, an ancient DUMPER SHIP issues a steady stream of metal and concrete debris onto the junk heaps far below. The faint THUNDER of the refuse tumbling onto the steep slopes is just audible over the SOUND of the wind. CLOSE ON TODD, as realizes how he got here. ANGLE ON MACE, reacting to TODD'S intense interest.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, thanks, Sergeant. Thanks a lot...</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As TODD turns and looks at MACE, MACE puts out his hand again for the gun. TODD seems to notice the weapon in his hand for the first time. Unhesitatingly, he hands the rifle to MACE... As MACE casually takes the weapon, the PIONEERS breathe a sigh of relief, grinning again as the tension eases. TODD has turned his gaze back to the DUMPER SHIP, fascinated. So that's what they did to him! Just then, JIMMY PIG claps TODD heartily on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Dumpers. They come every twenty or thirty days.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD, reacting to the smack on his shoulder, looks at JIMMY PIG like what was that? Are you hitting me? But all the PIONEERS are gathering around TODD in such a jovial manner that the puzzled soldier sort of understands this isn't an attack.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, partner. These no-goods woulda just let me blow away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Glowering at the monitor where MEKUM's badly transmitted VIDEO IMAGE is quivering and distorting, CHURCH waves the print-out map he's holding in his hand, a map showing hundreds of little dots against a vast field, stars and moons in the vast sea of space. RUBRICK and SLOAN watch as CHURCH addresses MEKUM's image indignantly.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry to disturb the tranquillity of outer space on Christmas Eve, but I'm off to the Caribbean in a few hours, and I wanted to make sure you'd got the transmission on the security sweep.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got it all right. This is an outpost here, not the Third Army! You've got us securing thirty-four locations and erecting monitor units in one month and --</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Piece of cake, guys! These are totally remote, totally uninhabited territories. All you do is set down, send out a patrol purely as a formality, then have those veterans of yours put up an A-Type unmanned monitoring unit. You should be on about number twenty-five by the time I get back from my vacation...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>say squatters or refugees?</context>
      <utterance>What if we do run into people...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you sure as hell don't want to get involved in evacuating people and that sort of thing.  My advice would be to..."avoid paperwork."</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eliminate them, you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHURCH hesitates. SLOAN and RUBRICK look at him. Then CHURCH blurts a question, his voice breaking...</context>
      <utterance>Well, no one's out there, but officially these are "hostile zones." Therefore you'd be within your rights to classify anyone as "hostile," I think. But I repeat, you should be worried about boredom, not action. Any other questions before I go?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down there...is it snowing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RUBRICK is pouring another glass from a bottle of Scotch as the little tree winks on and off, and we...</context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas, Captain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, fellas. At ease!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eyes riveted on the THREE OFFICERS, the NEW SOLDIERS are unresponsive to Christmas cheer. In fact, they look almost angry, like big dangerous animals, as the three OFFICERS stagger stupidly down the row of bunks, every eye following them.</context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas, everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHURCH almost falls over as he places the tree on the floor As stone faces watch him without expression, RUBRICK waves a couple of bottles.</context>
      <utterance>We brought you a little Christmas tree.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLOAN, giggling, does a provocative bump and grind.</context>
      <utterance>And some good cheer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The NEW SOLDIERS don't react. Stone faces.</context>
      <utterance>How about some Christmas pussy, guys? Anybody for a quick piece?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's "conduct unbecoming," Sloan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Christmas! Haven't you heard of piece on earth? "Piece on earth," get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RUBRICK sets three bottles down and indicates them to the NEW</context>
      <utterance>Christ, I wish we were on Earth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whump! NATHAN falls on his ass.</context>
      <utterance>It seemed like he was never going to walk. Then all of a sudden...he's an expert.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's it like...? TODD stares at her, trying to process the question. Seeing his difficulty SANDRA tries to help...</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant Todd...what's it like...what's it like being a soldier?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer, a stare.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD gulps. His blank stare could pass for stupidity.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think about food? Or women? You must think about something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD wets his lips. He seems about to answer...and yet it's difficult for him. He could kill a person easier. On the floor NATHAN GOOS happily, oblivious.</context>
      <utterance>What about feelings then? You must have feelings. You must feel something.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fear.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fear! You mean...you feel afraid?  That's when you're in battle... What about other times? Now, for example?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fear.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A stunned silence. Finally SANDRA speaks...</context>
      <utterance>Always.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD looks at her. This is incredibly difficult for him, like physical labor. He wets his lips and take a breath.</context>
      <utterance>You don't...look afraid. You look fearless.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fear and...discipline.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God. But there's nothing to be afraid of here. I can't hurt you. I wouldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANDRA is overwhelmed. She reaches for him, hugs him to her breast like a little baby, holding him. But TODD is as tense in her arms as steel. He can't relax. He's even trembling. NATHAN, on the floor, looks up, smiles innocently. SANDRA lets go of TODD and steps back, looking at him, her face troubled, as we...</context>
      <utterance>Always. It makes us...alert.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's speaking to JOHNNY who is doing martial exercises.</context>
      <utterance>You're not supposed to do that anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what? I'm a soldier.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELLEN looks up from the blocks.</context>
      <utterance>They're gonna kick him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They can't kick him out...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gonna. My father --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother says when someone's sick or hurt, you have to help them. You don't have a choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but what if the hurt person is...evil?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>because if you don't, you're evil!</context>
      <utterance>You still have to help them...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father says...uh...he says, "Soldiers deserve soldiers."</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That's what my father said too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father's making Sergeant Todd a scarf because he saved his life one time. He's knitting it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WILL is smirking with satisfaction at having settled that when out of nowhere ELLEN's little fist hits him hard on the nose. WILL looks stunned. Blood oozes from his nose. He starts to cry. ELLEN looks horrified at what she's done as we...</context>
      <utterance>That's dumb. Your father's dumb.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG'S WIFE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>SANDRA is examining the knitted scarf as JIMMY PIG and his WIFE stand in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Jimmy knitted it himself. He worked on it for two months.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIMMY PIG looks very embarrassed. He shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>It's beautiful, Jimmy. He'll love it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He saved my life out there. I guess Mace told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIMMY PIG nods, takes the knitted scarf back from SANDRA as we...</context>
      <utterance>You should give it to him yourself. I think he's in the meeting room... doing...exercises.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHESTER, Johnny's father, rushes in to see what the commotion's about. ANGLE ON JOHNNY in the tin cauldron that serves as a bath tub. JOHNNY'S bare chest and shoulders are covered with crude imitations of TODD's tattoos.</context>
      <utterance>What....? What... are...those? Chester! CHESTER!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHESTER and EVA exchange a look.</context>
      <utterance>Those are my war marks. From the battles I fought.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People are upset about him.</context>
      <utterance>There's going to be a meeting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not fully recovered.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're both silent for a long moment. MACE has something weighing on his mind that he hesitates to say...but finally he says it.</context>
      <utterance>That's what scares people. He gets stronger every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've caught him..sneaking looks at you. At your body.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A heavy silence, then...</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MACE stares at the ceiling and speaks with difficult honesty.</context>
      <utterance>Are you afraid of him, Mace?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another pause before...</context>
      <utterance>Yes.  God knows where he's been...or what he's done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never been afraid of anyone before...not this way. I feel he could break me in half...with no real effort and no real...feeling.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told me he's afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MACE is staring grimly at the ceiling as we...</context>
      <utterance>Maybe he is. It doesn't matter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HAWKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD is standing in front of the room full of grim-faced PIONEERS, all looking at him. It's like a court. HAWKINS is flanked by MACE and SANDRA...</context>
      <utterance>No one here has any animosity toward you, Sergeant. None of us here is your enemy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she speaks, TODD's blank stare considers the weathered faces of the PIONEERS facing him. He sees CHESTER, EVA, RED with his WIFE, JIMMY PIG and his WIFE, SLADE and MRS. SLADE, JUDITH, EMMA, SALLY. As HAWKINS continues, TODD's sharp eyes pick out details. He sees JIMMY PIG opening and closing his hands nervously, he sees SLADE fingering a barely noticeable rifle barrel. CHESTER has a weapon too.</context>
      <utterance>Moreover, we respect your qualities. We have no doubt that you are a very, very good soldier.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWKINS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The PIONEERS are nervous, ready for trouble, afraid TODD might take this badly and fly off the handle. As TODD's huge hand opens...and closes, their eyes are on it. He could pick up the table and hurl it at them, break men in half with his bare hands. His face is like stone, his eyes like diamond chips as he glances toward SANDRA. TODD sees SANDRA is moved, trying to suppress her emotions, biting her lip, as HAWKINS goes on...</context>
      <utterance>But, because of your training, I don't think you'll ever be able to function in a group like this, a community of vulnerable people, of families, of children, where the ability to fight is not the sole purpose of existence.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAWKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're different from us, Sergeant. We don't hate you for that, but we have agreed that to try to include you would pose an intolerable risk to the community itself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll give you any tools you need, warm clothing, a good knife, boots.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if you're ever sick...or you get hurt...</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MACE doesn't finish. TODD's eyes glance again at the PIONEERS. They too seem moved, not so ready to shoot. TODD blinks. Once. And we...</context>
      <utterance>You're a friend, Sergeant. It's just...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD glances at the knot of PIONEERS gathered in the trench, all eyes on him. SANDRA is among then with NATHAN in her arms. For just a second TODD's eyes go to the cheerful face of NATHAN; then he turns to MACE. MACE is startled to see TODD pull the scarf from his mouth to speak. He's never spoken before unless spoken to.</context>
      <utterance>If you need us...you can ask us for help.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then TODD replaces the scarf over his mouth and starts to climb out of the trench into the wind as we...</context>
      <utterance>It's not true.  I'm not a good soldier.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RUBRICK turns to CHURCH who's standing in the cramped cockpit, staring out a window at the gloomy planet outside, watching the CRAWLER creep over the terrain.</context>
      <utterance>All right, Crawler, Crawler, we got you. This is Daddy. Continue per, over.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're clear. We can send a crew out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sloan's already on it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As VETERANS start to pull space suits from under the bunks, SLOAN turns her back on them...but hesitates before exiting as though expecting something. Sure enough, veteran RILEY speaks up.</context>
      <utterance>Suit up, fellas. Time to go build another play house.</utterance>
   <speaker>RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLOAN says it even before she's turned. She knew who it would be.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Riley, what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We haven't been issued weapons, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're not soldiers anymore.</context>
      <utterance>You won't need weapons, Riley.</utterance>
   <speaker>RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RILEY swallows hard and with effort keeps his hand from saluting as he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>You don't even have to salute anymore. A simple "Yes, sir" will do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the door closes, RILEY, unable to restrain himself any longer, salutes hastily as we...</context>
      <utterance>Y-yes...sir. SLOAN turns her back and exits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every time it's time to send them out, Riley asks about weapons. And every time I tell him they don't need weapons anymore, they're not soldiers anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next one's going to be a real pain in the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? What flavor pain in the ass? Gravity pain in the ass? Atmosphere pain in the ass?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about a "gaseous currents" and "urgent convections" pain in the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're trying to say a "wind pain in the ass."</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wind!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mace glares at her for a moment, knowing she's right. Then he turns away and starts out defiantly.</context>
      <utterance>Mace! What about the vote? Everybody voted.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANDRA looks relieved and worried at the same time and we...</context>
      <utterance>We voted wrong!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLOAN and RUBRICK are looking over CHURCH's shoulder while a NEW SOLDIER sits stonefaced at the control console flying the ship.</context>
      <utterance>It's a dump. Literally.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit! We're gonna set up a monitor on a garbage dump! So we can monitor garbage rusting?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will the wind affect the patrol?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RUBRICK shakes his head, snorts disgustedly.</context>
      <utterance>The Crawlers are low enough and heavy enough, they won't blow. The men should wear armored vests and carry double weapons and ammo for the weight. They may have to use lines too, like mountain climbers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MACE breaks off. Todd isn't listening; he's looking off toward the horizon. MACE follows his look. Five miles away he can see an ugly insect-shaped spacecraft descending from about ten thousand feet.</context>
      <utterance>Damn! Thank you, Todd. God damn! I almost took a... a...swim there!</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD doesn't answer. He's staring at the descending ship with soldier eyes and a stone face as we...</context>
      <utterance>My...God! Someone's landing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANDRA stands there stunned as excited PIONEERS mill past her, jamming the corridor, and we...</context>
      <utterance>Someone's landing! Jimmy Pig spotted a ship!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD meets his look but doesn't answer. He finishes the tourniquet and turns his back on MACE to peer out through a gap in the engine at the CRAWLER. TODD sees the CRAWLER approach the cable, watches it veer left and start to travel along the cable...straight toward the colony! TODD turns and looks into MACE's face. MACE's eyes are clouded with horror.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit, Todd...I'm...dead... aren't I? I'm not going to make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD shakes his head no. MACE's eyes fill with new horror.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not..a soldier.  A...mistake? Was it...a mistake?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD turns away from MACE and peers through the machinery. He can see the CRAWLER is a hundred yards away now, traveling along the cable toward the colony. He can see the faces of the NEW SOLDIERS hanging on the outside of the CRAWLER, hard faces, goggled and ominous. When TODD turns back to MACE, he finds MACE eyeing him with pure hatred. MACE sneers weakly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God. They won't...they won't...? Not Sandra! Not... not...Nathan!</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD peers out again at the NEW SOLDIERS. They look invincible as we..</context>
      <utterance>Soldiers! Soldiers...  ...deserve...soldiers! His eyes roll back. He's dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both CHURCH and SLOAN look up in astonishment from the card game they're playing on a tiny fold-out table.</context>
      <utterance>People. They've spotted people!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"People"! "People"? What do you mean "people"?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two civilians. Unarmed. They've killed both of them. They've spotted smoke from some kind of camp and they're going to check it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A camp! Jesus Christ!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn!  Did they ask for assistance?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHURCH frowns, considers, then frets...</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like my daddy used to say, "Nothing's ever as simple as it's supposed to be...except shit."</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, "Daddy."</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you think they are?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The civilians?  Squatters...refugees. I don't think we want to know, do we?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good point.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Report from Crawler One. Everything under control. No need for assistance.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's resistance?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ineffectual. About fifty disorganized people with almost no fire power. Three men are going in to clean them out; one man's staying with the Crawler.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again RUBRICK and SLOAN exchange a glance and an eye-roll at the fretting old fuddy-duddy. Then SLOAN changes the subject brightly.</context>
      <utterance>Humph. Sounds reckless, three against fifty. The old ones, the veterans, they would have called for support...just in case.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speaking of Riley and his old soldiers...why don't we let them start putting up the unit? It's gonna take forever in this wind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will we be issued weapons, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Riley...no weapons. You're not a soldier, Riley.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got armored vests. You got to aim for exposed parts like the face...</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RED and SALLY watch SINGH step out directly in front of the advancing THIRD SOLDIER and FIRE five shots rapidly...PING!</context>
      <utterance>Here goes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>RUBRICK, looking uneasy, is facing CHURCH who's looking up at him from a game of solitaire at the little table. SLOAN is biting her fingernails in the b.g.</context>
      <utterance>A "growl"! He heard a growl?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he didn't say the word "growl." He said a "throat-noise," but I asked him to imitate it and it sounded like a growl to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God! Who are we fighting here!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think...I think we have to assume the missing men are...down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew Mekum's hotshots were green. No reinforcements, then they walk right into an enemy stronghold.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could send reinforcements now...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not. Those bastards are just waiting in there for us. No more of this fancy super-soldier shit. We do it with the hammer... RUBRICK and SLOAN exchange a nervous glance as CHURCH paces agitatedly.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, what does that mean, "the hammer"?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daddy always said, "When you want to insert a nail in a piece of wood, you don't do nothing fancy or glamorous, you don't finesse or play the hero, you just pick up your damn hammer and hit that sumbitch till it's in."</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ! Now Daddy's a carpenter!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I...don't...quite...follow...sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take the whole unit, both Crawlers, and tell 'em to pound that place with rockets, cannons, mortars, everything we got...from a safe distance.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raw firepower!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It may not be heroic, and we may waste some ammo, but by God we'll get the job done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly seeing TODD she breaks off, stares at him. Squatting on the floor, surrounded by weapons, TODD'S eyes meet hers for a long moment...then he looks away, goes back to assembling the weapons with quick sure movements, almost as if he wanted to avoid her eyes. SANDRA wets her lips to speak, hesitates, then finally blurts out what she can hardly bear to ask...</context>
      <utterance>Nathan, thank God, there you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. TODD finishes with the weapon, starts checking the next one.</context>
      <utterance>Did he find you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD looks up at her and nods. Their eyes lock.</context>
      <utterance>My husband...Mace...he went out to look for you. He...found you, didn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD nods, turns back to his arsenal. SANDRA stands there, hugging NATHAN to her chest, holding her tears in, her lids quivering, fighting to conquer her emotion. After a long, difficult moment, she wins the battle with herself. She looks numb, stunned, but she's not crying. TODD has begun to dress. He straps a sheath knife to one ankle, pulls on boots. Then he pulls a jersey over his muscular torso, covering all the old scars, the tattooed names of battles, and the tourniquet on his arm. Staring at him with glazed eyes, SANDRA notices a blotch of blood form on the jersey, leaking through the tourniquet. She speaks numbly.</context>
      <utterance>They...killed him...didn't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stuffing his pockets with ammo and other items, TODD glances at her with eyes that glitter dangerously.</context>
      <utterance>Your wound...it's still bleeding.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANDRA stares at him stupidly as he continues to dress, pulling on a heavy armored vest.</context>
      <utterance>I like to bleed, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD pulls on a second armored vast, one that already has a ragged hole in it from a rocket.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't...hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANDRA watches him go to the heap of charred furniture in the corner and take a blackened stick from it, watches him smear charcoal under his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Not enough, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD looks at her, a savage with blackened eyes.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know they'll come back?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're soldiers, sir. Like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...what do they want?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment SANDRA is silent, then...</context>
      <utterance>They are obeying orders, sir. It's their duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD crosses two utility belts across his armored chest like bandoliers.</context>
      <utterance>You know who they are, don't you? Do you know how many there'll be?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seventeen more, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seventeen! My God!  You can't fight seventeen yourself! You have to organize the rest of us, show us what to do. We don't have your...your skills...but we're not cowards. We'll do what you tell us, we'll --</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice is soft as silk but hard as steel. She looks into his eyes. Does she detect a hint of approval, of respect, in those flat expressionless snake eyes?</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD turns to go, laden with weapons, a flamethrower on his back, a rocket rifle on his shoulder, another in one hand.</context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soldiers deserve soldiers, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks back at her, right into her eyes this time.</context>
      <utterance>But...one soldier against seventeen!</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am going to kill them all, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue dressing obediently, their eyes the sullen eyes of robots. But CAINE 607 speaks up, at once respectful and dignified...</context>
      <utterance>Double belts, double ammo, double everything! You've got to be heavy there or you'll blow away, fellas...and we wouldn't want that, would we?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAINE 607</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's dark now, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're afraid of the dark, Sergeant Caine?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAINE 607</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir. But the manual says --</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what nightscopes are for, soldier. For the dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAINE 607</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. But the sixth rule is "never give the enemy an advantage unnecessarily." If they're expecting us --</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Sergeant, this may come as news to you, but you're not a real hot thinker! Your pitiful efforts at tactics have cost us three men already. So turn it off, that little pea brain of yours!  That goes for all the rest of you mental giants too. All you have to do is go boom-boom. Understand? Boom-boom! Kill kill! Say it... Kill...kill...kill... Draped in battle gear the seventeen NEW SOLDIERS obediently repeat the words after her, their eyes blank and sullen... "Kill kill kill..." They look like somber death machines as we...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>TODD turns back, looking down into the trench, and sees SANDRA looking up at him.</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant! Sergeant Todd!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD looks at her for a long moment, his face a mask, before he nods almost imperceptibly. Her eyes are full of tears.</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant...these soldiers...the ones you're going to fight... Are these the "better ones"...the ones who replaced you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD looks into her eyes. It is impossible to tell if he knows that she cares about him and that she is blessing him. After a moment he turns away and lumbers off into the darkness, the CLANKING of his equipment the only sound in the spooky stillness.</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant Todd...I think they...I think...someone made a serious... mistake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE GUNNER and the DRIVER exchange a glance. The GUNNER takes the mike and speaks into it.</context>
      <utterance>Crawler Two to Crawler One. Do you have a sitrep?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crawler Two, we are one down, responding to sniper activity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAINE 607</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crawler One, do you require assistance?</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is negative. We will eliminate the sniper and rendezvous at target.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAINE 607</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAINE 607 accelerates the CRAWLER.</context>
      <utterance>Roger, One. We are proceeding to target.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUNNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DRIVER angles right, aiming for one o'clock.</context>
      <utterance>Tentative at One.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DRIVER swings the wheel back and they continue slowly through the darkness. In the back seat, two NEW SOLDIERS peer into the night with blank faces. One of them is watching a huge plastic sign cartwheel past in the wind when -- -- he reacts! -- as TODD'S face appears is only inches from his, right against the plexi! BAM! Before the NEW SOLDIER can do more than look startled, TODD shoots out the window with a pistol and shoves a live grenade through the hole.</context>
      <utterance>That's negative, no target.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANDRA is bandaging TOMMY'S arm while ELLEN, NATHAN, and WILL are huddling under a table in the most protected corner of the room. JIMMY PIG and JUDITH exchange a pained look as JIMMY PIG pushes JOHNNY toward SANDRA and the table.</context>
      <utterance>Where's my father? Where's my father? JOHNNY looks around urgently.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny, get over under that table with Miss Sandra and Ellen and the others. Miss Judith, you better go on down the root cellar with Emma and help with the ones down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BAH-DOOOM! Another fierce CONCUSSION twenty yards away shakes dirt from the ceiling. ELLEN beckons from under the table...</context>
      <utterance>Where's my mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Johnny.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CAINE 607</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crawler Two to Crawler One. Come in, One.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAINE 607</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two to one, take your port to our nine o'clock and commence firing.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FOOOMP! The GUNNER fires again, rocking the vehicle. CAINE 607 looks at the SCOPE. The blip continues on directly on its course. CAINE 607 picks up the mike again.</context>
      <utterance>Copy, Two. Port to your nine and commence firing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAINE 607</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crawler Two to Crawler One. Again; proceed to port nine...</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FOOOMP! The GUNNER fires again as CAINE 607 looks at the screen. The blip on the screen keeps on straight, doesn't alter course!</context>
      <utterance>Affirmative, Two.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAINE 607</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two to One. You are still on twelve o'clock. Correct to nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the blip continues straight, directly at them. And suddenly CAINE realizes! Dropping the mike he snaps at his GUNNER urgently.</context>
      <utterance>Roger.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAINE 607</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the startled GUNNER starts to obey both of them are bathed in sudden, blinding white light as CRAWLER ONE suddenly switches on all lights and... KA-BLAM! KA-BLAM! MUZZLES FLASHES from CRAWLER ONE. WHUMP! WHUMP! CRAWLER TWO shudders, taking two direct hits. The GUNNER SCREAMS in pain.</context>
      <utterance>Gunner, hard to port, target hard to port!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They stopped shooting!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As RED joins the effort. SLADE snaps at him sarcastically as he strains against the heavy beam.</context>
      <utterance>Give us a hand, dammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's good news, you think?</context>
      <utterance>You think  that's good they stopped? It means  they're comin' for us! To  kill us!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant Todd  said...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The smoke is getting thicker. EMMA and JUDITH are coughing, looking scared.</context>
      <utterance>That he's gonna  stomp a whole army? Couldn't if he wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He  knew them! He said --</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANDRA pushes at the beam with all her strength, fighting back tears of despair.</context>
      <utterance>He's dead! If he isn't  dead, he joined 'em. He don't  care about us, he's a soldier. Besides, we threw him out, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The massive beam won't budge! Eyes wide with terror, EMMA and RUTH peer out of their trap.</context>
      <utterance>He's not dead!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daddy calling Number Two...</context>
      <utterance>This is Daddy, come in, Number Two.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Number One? Try Number...</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLOAN is pacing, looks sick to her stomach with fear.</context>
      <utterance>I tried One. I can't get either one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>guerilla action...</context>
      <utterance>There was...some kind of...</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now CHURCH is pacing back and forth, panicky, ranting...</context>
      <utterance>Then we lost them...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should have waked me sooner! This is bad, very bad. I never should have let that clown Mekum test his wonder boy army on me. "If it ain't broke, don't fix it." Shit! We don't even know what we're up against. How many...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We couldn't get any figures on enemy troop strength.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not even estimates...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're sitting ducks here! There could be a couple of divisions! More! We don't even have the weapons to arm the old soldiers.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello... Hello, One. This is Daddy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELLEN and the CHILDREN look alarmed as SANDRA gathers them and ushers them toward the exit, glancing back toward the trap door as she's leaving. EMMA and RUTH meet her look with frightened eyes. Noticing SANDRA'S hesitation, JIMMY PIG reassures her...</context>
      <utterance>Get them kids  hid somewhere! There's soldiers coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And suddenly!!! The beam slips back five inches, almost closing the opening. EMMA and JUDITH SCREAM! JIMMY PIG, RED and SLADE look alarmed, defeated.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. Couple more inches and they're out. SANDRA and the CHILDREN exit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RED takes off at a run.</context>
      <utterance>You know where Thomas keeps those two axes? Go get the axes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't  chop 'em out. We don't have time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just as good  to die chopping as fighting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This  ain't gonna work. Where's them axes? He musta run into soldiers and got killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know there's soldiers coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(shouts to Emma)</context>
      <utterance>'Cause soldiers  finish what they start -- unless you stop 'em. And we're what  they started, and we didn't stop 'em!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only one axe?</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They took the other one!</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toldja.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I couldn't... I couldn't... count 'em. Four, I think. Maybe five.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More! Trust me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLADE picks up a rifle, hands it to RED.</context>
      <utterance>Turns. JIMMY PIG starts chopping furiously.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As RED looks at the rifle, alarmed, SLADE "comforts" him.</context>
      <utterance>Do what you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIMMY PIG gasps for air as SLADE takes over chopping again. RED exits, worried.</context>
      <utterance>They're gonna kill us anyhow. No point in surrendering.  Turn!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"-- sailed an a river of crystal light into a sea of dew. Where are you going and what do you wish the old moon asked the three. 'We've come to fish for herring fish...'"</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a "moon?"</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what a moon is! It's...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD maneuvers the flashlight beam, sees the frightened CHILDREN.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God! It's... it's you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you...all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should go, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clutching TODD's combat pants fiercely, SARAH looks up timidly at the big stonefaced man as SANDRA turns to ELLEN.</context>
      <utterance>Sarah, you hang on to Sergeant Todd. No matter what happens!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ellen, go to the Commons. Tell Jimmy Pig and Mr. Slade that Sergeant Todd says we have to leave as soon as they get everybody out of the root-cellar. Can you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, yes, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right. The soldiers are gone for now. But be careful where you walk. And if it's too smoky, just come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell them to bring all the food and clothing they can carry.  Do you all understand that Sergeant Todd here is going to help us, and whatever he says to do you must do immediately, as if he was your father or your mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON TODD'S stone face. Unfamiliar territory.</context>
      <utterance>He's not my father!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frightened faces look to the awkward "killing machine." TODD looks like a statue decorated with CHILDREN. JOHNNY is sobbing as he hangs onto TODD's giant hand obediently.</context>
      <utterance>No... but he's our friend. Our good friend. Do you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want my father and my mother! Can he find where my father is? I want him to find my father!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SANDRA freezes. TODD is alert, tense...and covered with</context>
      <utterance>No. No, he can't do that, but -- A SCREAM! From the corridor!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MEKUM/VIDEO SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As SLOAN and RUBRICK look on uneasily, an indignant CHURCH addresses the image on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>You can't be serious! This is some kind of a joke...in poor taste.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not only are we apparently out twenty of your fancy new soldiers, your supermen, we're out both crawlers and all the weapons...so we can't arm the old soldiers, the ones you "improved" on, to defend ourselves...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHURCH flashes a scowl at SLOAN as, on the screen, MEKUM erupts excitedly.</context>
      <utterance>We've got to get out of here, Colonel Mekum!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM/VIDEO IMAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Abort? You want to lose twenty top soldiers to a phantom army and then abort the mission? Do you know what that would look like on my record? Or yours? We'd be explaining it for the next fifty years from some goddam assignment in God knows where, we'd --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, how's it gonna look when we lose the ship too? How's that gonna look on the old record? 'Cause that's what's gonna happen if we don't get our ass outta here. We can't defend ourselves with no weapons and --</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM/VIDEO IMAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on, hold on there, Captain! At ease! Let's calm down and remember...remember we're soldiers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good plan, Colonel.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM/VIDEO IMAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we can't just get the shit kicked out of us by an unknown guerilla army... But maybe we could...alter...our objective...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meaning?</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM/VIDEO IMAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delighted with his own genius, MEKUM smiles triumphantly from the video screen as RUBRICK, SLOAN, and CHURCH exchange stunned looks and we...</context>
      <utterance>Nuke the joint...and get out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAINE 607</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It hurts!</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SNAP! TODD breaks CAINE 607's neck and watches the life go out of him. In the sudden silence as TODD, panting, stares at his defeated enemy, he hears a VOICE...her VOICE...very weak...</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD turns and sees SANDRA slumped against the wall where Caine 607 threw her. There's a trickle of blood coming from a nostril, more blood in her hair. Her eyes don't look right.</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant...</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD sees NATHAN looking at his mother with fear in his eyes. Struggling to his feet, TODD picks up NATHAN and puts the boy down close to his mother. SANDRA reaches out and takes NATHAN's hand. She holds NATHAN's hand toward TODD. TODD looks confused. There are tears in SANDRA's eyes as she pushes NATHAN's little hand into TODD's huge left paw. TODD looks down at the joined hands, then he looks into SANDRA's flooded eyes. Does TODD understand her gesture? His face is impassive. Maybe he doesn't. Just then a hand touches his shoulder. TODD turns to see JOHNNY face him, trembling but valiant, to ask the question the others are fearful of asking.</context>
      <utterance>Nathan!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD sees all the CHILDREN looking at him, their eyes big with hope and fear as we...</context>
      <utterance>S-sir...sir, are you our friend?  Sh-she said you were our friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We see that RILEY and three other VETERANS -- GREEN, CHESLEY, and MOORE -- are struggling to maneuver the heavy bomb along the narrow corridor and down a ladder hatch as SLOAN follows on their heels and CHURCH and RUBRICK, fretting, follow her.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Riley, you wanted a weapon, right? Now you got one! A real biggee!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What good'll it do just setting it outside? We don't know where the enemy is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't matter. For once Mekum's on the ball. This is a very dirty bomb! That wind will churn the radioactivity around like soap in a washing machine. This is gonna be one clean place in a very short time...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right horizontal?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHURCH relaxes, looks up at the clock, satisfied.</context>
      <utterance>Roger. Right horizontal checks green.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right we're "go." I'm allowing us three minutes to clear the atmosphere and get out of range. That means we can wait seven more minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck 'em! Let's just go!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHURCH considers for a moment, then shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>She's right! Four more casualties aren't gonna mean anything to anybody, especially when they're already obsolete.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess they wouldn't want to get old anyway.  Go ahead, lock the hatch.  Rube, punch up the port power cluster and --</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh? What was what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All they hear is the HUM of the air system and miscellaneous</context>
      <utterance>Sssshhhh! Listen! SLOAN is listening intensely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sounds...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHURCH frowns. What the fuck?</context>
      <utterance>Like a kid! Just then they hear it again, closer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then, as RUBRICK is pushed out of view, CHURCH appears, indignant and panicky, as CHESLEY hustles him past.</context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy? You can't do this, soldier! You're going to be in trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON THE PIONEERS, exchanging glances.</context>
      <utterance>I'm your superior officer, don't you understand that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHURCH breaks off, suddenly speechless at the sight ahead of him. Here comes TODD, laden with more CHILDREN, the tattoo on his cheek clearly visible. His eyes meet CHURCH'S.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you realize you're violating the chain of command? I'm giving you a direct order to...to...to...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weak at the knees, CHURCH is still stammering as CHESLEY shoves him ahead. And then SLOAN, in the grip of GREEN, is hustled by. She looks wide-eyed at TODD and the CHILDREN.</context>
      <utterance>S-sergeant? S-sergeant T-todd? It... You...! How...? How...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant Todd!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RUBRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, you don't understand! That bomb is triggered! It's on a timer!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to get out of here! All of us! You need us! You need us to operate the ship...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CHURCH and SLOAN are hunched desperately over the bomb in near darkness, the wind tearing at them. SLOAN tries to punch a code into the keys...</context>
      <utterance>Twenty seconds. Hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God, I can't remember if it's six-seven or seven-six...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLOAN punches the keyboard blindly.</context>
      <utterance>Try one! Try it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BAHWHOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOM! Everything is dazzling, blinding light!</context>
      <utterance>There! I did it! Did it stop? Did it -- ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MEKUM/VIDEO IMAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RILEY turns to TODD, looking a question at him. TODD meets his look and no words are necessary. RILEY reaches for the control switch as MEKUM continues babbling.</context>
      <utterance>...I need a report, Captain. It's not just my ass, it's yours too! You've got to stand by me on this. I want you to come in right now... right now! Do you understand me? Right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MEKUM/VIDEO IMAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is important for all of us, for our careers. There's going to be a Board of Inquiry and -- MEKUM'S IMAGE cuts out mid-babble.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>TODD and RILEY turn to see SLADE in the entrance to the cockpit addressing TODD and the VETERANS collectively.</context>
      <utterance>That was the boss, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD looks at RILEY, RILEY looks at TODD. What the fuck was that?</context>
      <utterance>Well then, I guess you fellas are all right. I guess I misjudged you some. Where I said you were "a buncha no good killer robots," I mighta just overspoke myself. As of now, till it goes otherwise, you got my sincere approval and support. With that, SLADE turns and exits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD looks back at the dot, considers it, looks back at RILEY.</context>
      <utterance>Cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD is thoughtful...finally asks the next question.</context>
      <utterance>Air? RILEY nods a yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Safe?</utterance>
   <speaker>RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TODD considers the dot on the map again, then looks at RILEY.</context>
      <utterance>But very cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That one.</utterance>
   <speaker>RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RILEY turns toward a console, but something makes him look down toward his feat. Then he looks back at TODD. TODD follows the look. Tiny NATHAN is looking up at TODD who's towering over him. TODD looks down without expression, the scarf from Jimmy Pig still wrapped around his neck. NATHAN puts his arms out to be picked up. TODD considers the outstretched arms. RILEY looks from TODD to NATHAN and back to TODD. What's this? TODD hesitates a half second more, then leans down and picks NATHAN up in his arms, lifting the boy to his chest. RILEY looks on. Never seen anything like it. NATHAN is close to TODD's face, looking right into it, trying a little smile, a nervous one, looking for a response. TODD hesitates, takes a breath, moves the muscles of his face. All he can produce is an awkward grimace, the distortion of a smile, almost comical. NATHAN reads the intention successfully. His face collapses into a huge friendly grin. TODD tries again, making a clumsy sort of rubbery wince. RILEY watches. Totally amazed. TODD turns, takes NATHAN to a porthole, puts his face up to it. NATHAN stares out at the darkness punctuated by a billion stars, a sky full of hope. As NATHAN looks out, TODD works his face again, trying for a smile the way a weak man might try to lift a heavy weight. NATHAN looks at the stars outside, TODD looks with him and suddenly TODD's face relaxes into an awkward grin, almost by accident. RILEY watches the two of them for a moment, confounded by what he's seeing. Then he turns to the console and...</context>
      <utterance>Aye, aye, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
