<movie id="506" title="Something s Gotta Give">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>A CHIC EATERY - DOWNTOWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The place is full. Everybody is somebody here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Maitre'd snaps to attention at the sight of him.</context>
      <utterance>Langer. ..</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Harry and his Girl wend their way around tables, we pass Other Couples. Young Couples. Middle-aged couples. Not talking Couples.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Langer, got your table waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what does a life of bucking the system all add up to?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Harry passes a table where a BEATEN SIXTY YEAR OLD dines with his AGE APPROPRIATE, WELL-FED WIFE. IN SLOW MOTION, Harry and The Beaten Man catch each other's glance.</context>
      <utterance>To never settle down with the right woman for a life of leftovers and Christmas mornings. No his and her IRA accounts, no mini van parked in the garage. I think it's made me what I am today.  The luckiest son of a bitch on earth. Look at me. I'm positively debonair. I should be illegal I'm lookin' so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't as if I haven't wondered what my life would be like if I was a Regular Joe and came in here once a month with a dame my age' for a porterhouse and a side of I spinach. I've wondered...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To all my thugs that be livin' it up, we say, what I do. To all my...  Oh! This is it. Make a right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So baby, you're rich... .</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, my mother is, sort of. Not really...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she lives within a mile of here, she's rich.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess a hit play will buy you a house in The Hamptons.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to meet your mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you wouldn't. I mean, she's great. She's totally brilliant, but she's not your type.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're overlooking one of the great things about me. I don't have a type.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry looks to Marin, feigning hurt.</context>
      <utterance>She's over thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, what?! Like you don't know you have a slight reputation for...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't look away.</context>
      <utterance>-- For what? Harry waits. RINGGG!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't look at me like that.</context>
      <utterance>For never dating anyone over 30.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just not true.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Sorry. Over 31?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so you wait 'til we get out to The Hamptons to let me know you're a wise ass.  Hold on. . .  It just so happens, my dear, that women of a certain age, don't date me. You ever think of it that way? No, it's always me. You dames are all alike.  Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin continues singing along with Ja Rule as Harry confidently slips his hand onto her thigh.</context>
      <utterance>Dames...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin turns up the CD, getting herself out of whatever just came over her, looks out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Make a right, left at the second fence.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have I mentioned how gorgeous your breasts look in this sweater?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you have actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin laughs, softening, as Harry turns down a dirt driveway, driving toward a DREAM BEACH HOUSE.</context>
      <utterance>So it would be too much to mention it again. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. It's the perfect beach house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. My mother doesn't know how to do things that aren't perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That got her. Harry parks. She looks over at him but he's grabbing some cigars for his shirt pocket, then looks up at her with an innocent look that suggests he did not just say such a lovely thought.</context>
      <utterance>Which explains you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, okay, right... They both grab their H overnight bags and step out of the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin sets her bag down, walks to Harry, wraps her arms around his neck.</context>
      <utterance>So, what are we gonna do out here, just the two of us, for two whole days?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me the truth, are you at all glad we waited?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin smiles then kisses him. He's one of those guys that lets you kiss them.</context>
      <utterance>I'm incredibly glad we're finally going to do it.  If that's the same as being glad we waited, then baby doll, I'm ecstatic.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go for a swim, how long will it take you to change?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin starts UNBUTTONING HER SWEATER as she dances seductively toward the front door, then notices Harry's cigars.</context>
      <utterance>Two minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Har... No smoking in the house. My Mom doesn't allow it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she allows you to strip in the front yard and bring men you're dating here to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She SLIPS OFF her sweater and DROPS IT ON HARRY'S HEAD.</context>
      <utterance>She doesn't know everything I do...Or when I do it.. or where I do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your pants, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin provocatively UNZIPS her pants and wriggles out of them. She's now in a TINY TANK AND BIKINI PANTIES.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin HEARS Harry's ZIPPER UNZIP. She turns, her EYES WIDENING as Harry's PANTS land on a chair. Harry is now down to his Boxers, an Open Shirt and a fearless smile.</context>
      <utterance>Gourmet kitchen's to your left where tonight I will whip you up a culinary feast of Mac and Cheese.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They arrive in a warmly decorated GUEST BEDROOM.</context>
      <utterance>.. O-kay, going quickly now... Master bedroom is that away...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this as they say on 'Cribs', your favorite show, is where the magic happens. Do we like it? Going once, going twice ...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry takes Marin's hand and pulls her OUT OF FRAME and ONTO THE BED. She playfully rolls on top of him. His hands cup her ass.</context>
      <utterance>Sold.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know when I first started auctioneering someone told me if I was nervous to just picture everyone in the audience in their underwear. This sort of gives that a whole new meaning.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? You're not nervous now, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm always a little nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So put on your bathing suit. I brought some champagne, I'll put it on ice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>E</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>out from UNDER THE DOOR. They don' t move.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica nods to Zoe, gesturing a nearby knife. Zoe grabs the knife. Harry pokes his head out from behind the fridge, equally confused.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God. What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, stay right where you are. We have a knife.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you... live here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Mister, look, I'm gonna dial 911 and you're not gonna move. Zoe, hand me the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, Harry SHUTS the fridge door. The Women see he's naked except for a Pair of Boxers. They both GASP. Zoe FUMBLES the phone over to Erica who dials quickly..</context>
      <utterance>You don't understand. I'm a friend of your daughter's.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? I don't think so. My daughter's in the city and you what, wandered in here,like high on Ecstasy..?.  Shit. I dialed 8-1-1.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honestly, if you just...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zoe can't believe she just said that -- no truth in it whatsoever.</context>
      <utterance>Back off. She was in the Israeli army. She can break you in half.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I have an intruder in my house. 29 Daniels Lane, Sagaponack.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm dating your daughter Marin. She invited me here for the weekend. She's in her room right now, changing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're dating my daughter?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God.  I'm sorry. False alarm. Yeah, no, I'm sure. No, he's not a burglar  He's dating my daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, I had no idea you were coming out this weekend, you said you had to write.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do. I thought I'd do it out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, man, this is really....</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awkward.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Totally.. .but....  You gotta admit, sorta funny You thought he was a burglar? In his boxer shorts?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, the world's nuts, I don't know the man. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, it's not really funny. I'm an idiot. I should've told you I was bringing someone out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry Langer. How are ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Sorry... Mom, this is my friend, Harry. Harry, my Mom, Erica... my Aunt, Zoe.  Harry's sort of a new friend. I think I mentioned him in an e-mail. We just, totally spur of the moment thought we'd get out of the city for a few days.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA AND ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course...Right...Great...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, does Harry have a robe?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin shoots her Mom a look. Help!</context>
      <utterance>You know what? Actually, I think I should just take off. Let you gals enjoy your weekend...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no. Don't be silly. Uh, look, here's what we'll do. Zoe and I will leave. We took a great walk on the beach, we'll go into town for lunch. You two stay. Harry, apologize about the near arrest.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you were impressive. Very strong, very... "macho".</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I was exactly "macho"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin watches. Dying.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Okay. Whatever...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All righty then...I'm definitely gonna hit the road.  Ladies...sensational meeting you.  Doll, call me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on. Hold on. Let's not get so dramatic here. What are we four teenagers? We're all sophisticated people. Why can't we all stay, for the weekend? Your mother's got work to do I've got papers to grade. You'll do your thing, whatever that is and if we want to hang together, we'll hang together. If we don't, we don't. There's no reason why any of us should give up this spectacular weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seriously. I can handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can totally handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can only go up from here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean a father substitute.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except he's older than her father. I can't even look at them. What is she doing with a guy that age?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marin was how old when you guys broke up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five years ago, so. ..twenty-three.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, so she was old enough not to feel Dave was walking out on her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that supposed to mean Dave walked out on me? Why do people assume when you break up after twenty years that the guy's the one who wanted out? Just because once we broke up he shtupped everything that moved...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy cowgirl. I didn't mean it that way. Just trying to figure out why such a smart girl is always with the wrong guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She started French lessons after she and my Dad split up. Part of her "Keep Busy, Don't Look Back" program. She's practically fluent now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marin, au cas ou nous prende un desset ou devrions jefaire quelgue chose?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laissons quelque chose d'achat. Et ce grand gateau de chocolat?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, not bad.. .</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then Erica notices who's next to her at the cheese counter. She sees her Sister, Zoe, reading a cheese label with her glasses on and next to Zoe are two sad looking Old Women in their Eighties with their arms linked. Almost woozy, Erica is snapped out of it when she is handed her package.</context>
      <utterance>It's an epidemic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OUNG FRENCH GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica heads down the aisle, passing Harry whose back is to her. Just as she passes, he turns and almost bumps into her.</context>
      <utterance>Merci madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woops. Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They so very badly do not want to actually touch. Erica hesitates. Harry gestures for her to go first then walks alongside her.</context>
      <utterance>My fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Harry... What do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm one of the owners of a record company among other things...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, really? Which record company?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drive by Records.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Drive By" Records??? Is that a joke? What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a Hip Hop label.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hip Hop? Oh, rap? Oh, right. Well.  Okay. That's... "interesting"...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me see if I get where you're headed here. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but, look, you know I hate rap, I mean I do. It's sort of violent and crude for my taste, not to mention just a tad misogynistic.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, a lot of people see rapping as poetry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica places her groceries on the check out counter.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but come on, how many words can you rhyme with 'Bitch'?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How we doin?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin places a plate in front of Harry then runs her finger along "the nape of his neck. They smile at each other as she continues on. Erica notices, tries not to respond.</context>
      <utterance>So, Mom, how's the new play? You gettin' happy with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the thing with me is that I'm about 90% hard word, 10% talent and so far the talent part hasn't exactly kicked in yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin and Zoe stop what they are doing and turn to Erica. She's hesitant to reveal this.</context>
      <utterance>What's your play about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About? Well, I'm not exactly sure which is a bit of a problem, but so far it's about a divorced woman, a writer, she's this high strung, over-amped, controlling, know it all neurotic. . .  Who's incredibly cute and lovable.  It's a comedy.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, how did you two meet?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At a Wine Auction at Sotheby's. Harry was the big buyer of the night.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I kept winking at Marin as she was conducting the auction and apparently every time I did that she misunderstood and I ended up buying cases of outrageously expensive wine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>17.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zoe and Marin laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever been married, Harry?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No, I haven't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Now why do you think that is?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some people just don't fit the mold. And so far...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, if it ain't broke.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry leans back, places his arm around Marin's chair. Erica takes note.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a second, aren't you like a famous bachelor?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't say I'm famous.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I think I read a piece on you in New York Magazine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess people find it interesting that I've escaped the noose for so long.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, wasn't the name of the article, "The Escape Artist"?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. I read that article. That was you? You were once engaged to somebody big. Who was it? Not Joan Collins.. .Wait. ..Carly Simon?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it was somebody cool like that.  Not Martha Stewart....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could just ..'ask him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, this is more fun. It's like I'm not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry was once engaged to Diane Sawyer. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Diane Sawyer. I love her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica pauses on that one.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, women your age love that about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a bad thing to say 'women your age'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...I'm sure it was a compliment.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was. ..just the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So when was this engagement?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(munches on his lobster)</context>
      <utterance>Long time ago. She was just this adorable lanky girl from Kentucky with the greatest pair of legs I'd ever seen... Never understood her ending up with a job where she never showed them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not serious? She's Diane Sawyer, she goes into caves in Afghanistan with a shmahtah on her head. Who cares about her legs?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just anyone who's ever had the pleasure of... You know what? I hate to eat and run but...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, wait. This is actually a very fascinating dynamic - what's going on at this table...</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>oe teaches Women's Studies at Columbia. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so this is gonna hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, come on, listen, here's the rub for women. Look at what we have here with you and Erica. Harry, you've been around the block a few times, right? You're what? Around 60, never been married, which, we all know, if you were a woman, would be a curse, you'd be an old maid, a spinster, blah, blah, blah... Okay, so instead of pitying you, they write articles about you, celebrate your never marrying, it makes you illusive and ungettable. You're a real catch. Then, take my gorgeous sister here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any chance of you stopping here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, this is interesting. I mean, look at her, she's so accomplished, the most successful woman playwright since who? Lillian Hellman? She's over fifty, divorced and still sits in night after night because the available guys her age want</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you, possessed? How could you say those things?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It just seemed so obvious to me. The injustice of it. Thank God men die younger than us. It's the only break we get.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you know what? Write a dissertation on it, don't announce to the world that I stay in night after night after night and by the way, one night after night would have been enough. Did you ever realize, I stay "in" as part of my job. Why do you think I married the director of my plays? He was the only man I ever saw. Anyway, I like staying in and I like this time in my life. Why do I have to defend myself? M I was married for 20 years. I'm done. arin ENTERS carrying more dishes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell was that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I thought I was onto something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, what are you doing with this guy? He's old, he's chauvinistic...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's fun? How is he fun? He's like.. .wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong can be fun, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not this wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we not do this now? He's actually incredibly smart and fascinating and if you had talked to him about something other than his marital status you would've found out how smart he is. He owns like 10 different companies...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean he owns ten different companies? He can't commit, that's what that means. Not that, God forbid, I want him to commit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that I get. Anyway, he said he thought you two were very spontaneous and nice and then said he's leaving as soon as the sun comes up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? His car doesn't have headlights?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. I have no right to get this nuts.  He's your friend. Not mine. I love you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No chance he said we were nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They HEAR MUSIC coming from Marin's bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Please. None.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they listening to?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica turns on the garbage disposal. Zoe sings along, "Let's get it on". .., Erica shoots her a look, turns off the garbage disposal, doing the dishes with vigor.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care...  Oy. Marvin Gaye. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then they hear Marin GIGGLING.</context>
      <utterance>I know she'll never see him after this weekend. She can't commit either.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin YELPS.</context>
      <utterance>He does sound fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then they hear Marin SCREAM.</context>
      <utterance>Admit it, he's got something. You felt it, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica covers her ears with her hands. Then they hear Marin SCREAM "MOOOOOOMMMMMMMMMMMM!!!!"</context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is nuts...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she say, Mom?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were fooling around and he said he felt funny Hthen he just collapsed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nothing. I'm okay maybe it was the lobster...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does your chest hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like an elephant's standing on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Call 911...tell them to send an ambulance. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marin! Now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mouth to mouth...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How we doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARAMEDIC #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's had 30 minutes of chest pain, nausea, shortness of breath, blood pressure's 170 over 100, pulse 104, respirations 18...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Nurse wheels over an EKG machine, Julian helps hook it up.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get an EKG. Mr. Langer, I'm Dr. Mercer. Are you in any pain right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feel some pressure in my chest...it's real tight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry clenches his fist over his sternum.</context>
      <utterance>Can you show me where the pain is?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were you doing at the onset of the pain?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was uh, kissing a beautiful...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you having intercourse?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Unfortunately, no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ense of humor in tact...  Hang a nitroglycerine drip. Mr. Langer the EKG shows you have a blocked artery which is not allowing enough oxygen to get to the heart muscle.. .</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm having a heart attack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna stop it. But I need to know what kind of medications you take?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I take uh... uh. . . Lipitor. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh... .Any thing else?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and a white one for blood pressure. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>procardia?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica, Marin and Zoe ARRIVE in the DOORWAY of the ER. Harry eyes them...stalls.</context>
      <utterance>What about, Viagra?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Langer? Did you take any Viagra today? Mr. Langer?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No Viagra.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're positive?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Women grab looks at each other, know they shouldn't be there. They turn away.</context>
      <utterance>I don't take Viagra. Don't need Viagra.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Just needed to be sure because I put nitroglycerin into your-drip and if you had taken Viagra, the combo would make your heart leap right out of your body...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's give him an aspirin and Metoprolol 5mg...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(clutching his chest)</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, had an audience...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. ..it was a great save.  Let's start the thrombolytic protocol. "4000 units of heparin. Mr. Langer, if this works and I have every reason to believe it will, it's going to reverse what's going on so there will be little or no damage to your heart. You with me?  Okay, here we go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know his family. I've gone out to dinner with the guy three times. I hardly know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gonna make it. Don't worry.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's like a bulldog. He'll make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a nightmare. I go out with a guy who's so old, he takes Viagra.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you nuts? You go out with a guy who's so old he's having a heart attack!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julian rounds the corner of the corridor. Marin rushes toward him, her face begging for good news.</context>
      <utterance>All I can say is, thank God it didn't happen when he was inside you. That could be life altering.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Dad's gonna be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he's not my Dad...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.  Your Grandad's gonna be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>oh we're not related. He's just a friend.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you so much. But he's not my...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His sweet apologetic smile is not lost on Marin. Zoe and Erica join them.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Dr. Mercer. Mr. Langer did have a mild heart attack. I gave him something to break up the clot in his artery and it worked beautifully.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His EKG returned to normal almost immediately which means I don't expect any permanent damage. He's very lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, whoever got him here so fast should be thanked. Another half hour and I don't know if this would've worked. Marin pats her Mom on the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica wipes away a tear. Nothing could surprise her more.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, man...  This was...intense.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're out of the woods. I've given him something to sleep, it might make him a little loopy at first but then it should knock him out.  You're Mrs. Langer?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no I'm just... No. I'm Erica Barry. . He was having dinner at our house. I just met him this afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Erica Barry?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The playwright?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Huge fan.</context>
      <utterance>What a pleasure. I'm a huge fan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Oh, thanks... This is my daughter, Marin, my sister, Zoe...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - A JAPANESE TEA POT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julian pours steaming hot tea into 3 paper cups.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>the steam.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera Pans to ZOE. Sitting next to Marin. She is also handed a Cup of Tea. Even she softens as she looks up at Julian.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is all beginning to feel a little like the Step Sisters trying on the Glass Slipper. Until we get to Erica, not paying any attention at all as she is handed her Tea.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. . .Hey. . .Ew. . .Hot. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome. May I join you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sure. This is very nice of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First year of medical school you learn what can keep you up all night without making you nuts. Green Tea beats everything plus it's a great antioxidant. Cheers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, urn, do you always work nights?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Usually two or-three a week, gives me a chance for a real life during the day. . .  You know, I heard you had a place in the Hamptons. I really am a very big fan. I honestly think I've seen every play you've ever written.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think some were written before your time. There are some Marin's never even seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zoe nudges Erica as a Nurse enters from the ER.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm pretty sure I've seen them all and I saw the last one twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor, we've got a walk in, may need stitches. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The second he's gone:</context>
      <utterance>I'll check on MI. Langer...if he's asleep; you all might want to get some shut eye and come back in the morning. Great to meet you Erica. Ladies. . . The Women wave and watch him exit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, now that's a perfect a guy for you. He's adorable.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother! I've never seen a man less interested in me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or more interested in you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? He's thirty years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he's older than that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who cares how old, he is. I mean, he's not my type, he's like a gorgeous wholesome doctor but, he's perfect for you and hot for you, which makes him really perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Harry stumbles into the corridor in his Hospital</context>
      <utterance>Stop it. He likes my work. Not me.  It's insane. I would never.  Shut. Up.</utterance>
   <speaker>Z</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gown, pretty out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuh-oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Confused, Harry turns around, a little lost, giving the Women a FULL VIEW OF HIS BARE ASS. The Women muffle screams.</context>
      <utterance>Harry....</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He faces them.</context>
      <utterance>Harry! Over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, I want to go home. Can you call Lowell to pick me up?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry wobbles. Is he going to fall? Marin freezes, looks to her Mom for help. Erica rushes to Harry.</context>
      <utterance>Lowell?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, you have to get back in bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woman. And I say that as a compliment... You saved my life.  Soft.. .  I don't remember your name but I thank you from the bottom of my...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ugh. Look at this, even unconscious, he's a lech. The Nurses rush out and peel Harry off Erica.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Langer, you shouldn't be standing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got to take a whiz girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry turns back to the Women, smiling. He likes that idea. LOVES that idea.</context>
      <utterance>We'll take care of that for you, Mr. Langer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he walks away, his bare ass shines like a full moon in a desert sky.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. You take care of it for me, sweetheart. I'd like to see that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the most insane night of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but just admit that was one great ass for a guy that age.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks across at a neat as a pin Man in his early forties, Prada suit, crisp white shirt, dark tie. He's a Gershwin tune of a man. A throwback to a kinder world. This is. LOWELL, Harry's Houseman/Chef/all around Man Friday.</context>
      <utterance>Now what can I do you for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julian ENTERS the Nurse's station.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here for Mr. Harry Langer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we discharging Hurricane Harry?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julian EXITS the Nurse's Station. Lowell, carrying the flowers, follows. He nods to TWO TALL LEGGY MINI SKIRTED ASSISTANT TYPES, KIM and LEXI who follow. Both pack cell</context>
      <utterance>Yes we are. Hi, I'm Dr. Mercer. Come on, I'll take you to him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you are. . ?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lowell St. James'. Mr. Langer's houseman, chef... general valet..</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that sounds like a pretty, interesting job.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They arrive at:</context>
      <utterance>Fifteen years. Never a dull moment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry sits up too fast, lies right back down. Lowell looks like he might cry. The Girls hold back.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Harry, looks like we're going to have to let you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy kids, I just sat up too fast. Doc, tell them. Am I in good shape? How were my tests this morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's doing extremely well.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I hug him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry stands and indulges Lowell in a deep hug. Lowell's shoulders shake as he sobs.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Okay. Let's not get goofy. We got no thin , but good news here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must say, you do look good... considering. You have a little extra baggage under your eyes, but I know how to fix that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See what good hands I'm in. Did you meet my gorgeous assistants?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not formally.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kim hands Harry a shopping bag full of CDs.</context>
      <utterance>Girls... .my Doctor, Julian Mercer.  Honey, did you bring the CDs?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are for you...  The man loves Hip Hop.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe not this much but...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lexi hands Harry another bag. Harry reaches in and pulls out a small leather box, hands it to Julian.</context>
      <utterance>And did you bring the other thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is just to thank you for your brilliance the other night. I hope it suits you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. This is.. .Jesus, this is the most gorgeous watch I've ever seen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- Oh, good. It's a Piaget.  He likes it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I love it and this is incredibly generous of you but I can't accept it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You save my life and you end up with some CDs?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I end up seeing you walk out of here and I do get paid you know -</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Knock, knock.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, I'll see you on the way out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone EXITS leaving Marin and Harry alone. Harry sits on the bed. Marin joins him. Harry places his hand on her thigh. All she notices is his hospital bracelet.</context>
      <utterance>We'll pull up the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, I'm some great date, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... Mr. Excitement.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me somethin', we haven't actually had sex yet, have we?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No we haven't. You're correct on that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin smiles, kisses Harry on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Something to live for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To prove her wrong, Harry rises quickly. Everyone stands by, ready to help.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on Tarzan, we're still movin' ...  Okay, now slow-ly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As soon as Harry spots Erica, he starts to wobble.</context>
      <utterance>Look at these faces. Will you tell them I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone grabs for Harry as he FALLS OUT OF FRAME AND THE</context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Whoa! WHOA!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, I'm sorry, but I think we jumped the gun.. .can't let you travel quite yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't goin' back in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to but I can't put you in a car right now and I can't leave you in the parking lot. I'd like you to stay nearby for a few days and let me keep an eye on you 'til you get your strength back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody tell you to starve me to death? Kim hands Harry the cell phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Russell.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kim hands Harry a NOTE that says:</context>
      <utterance>Rush? No, man, you're livin' the shit. I just got a clean bill of health.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the best turkey sandwich I ever had in my life. What kind of mustard is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, don't get pissy. It's not Dijon, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lowell ENTERS with the Bed Tray.</context>
      <utterance>Don't get pissy. ..you say that 'cause this, of course, would never happen to you. .1 come out here for peace and quiet and suddenly I'm a character in a Kaufman and Hart play.  And the phone does not stop.  And it's never for me!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to interrupt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fine Lowell, I'll take that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, please, allow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica takes the bed tray as Lowell EXITS.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, I'll take it. No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lexi ENTERS, all 5'10" of her. Dave suddenly looks alive. She carries an empty water glass.</context>
      <utterance>The man does not know my name and I'm doing his dishes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Erica. Um...where should I put</utterance>
   <speaker>E</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right here. I'll take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Harry has a headache. Do you have any Tylenol?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(reaches in cabinet)</context>
      <utterance>Tylenol yes. ..</utterance>
   <speaker>LEXI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm Lexi, Harry's second assistant.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica hands Lexi the Tylenol, she thanks her and EXITS.</context>
      <utterance>Hey...Dave Klein. How ya doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where should I put this? It's an empty water glass. What are the choices?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gettin' outta your hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're not ready to show me any pages? I'm not putting pressure on you, I'm just asking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't written a word. I'm on page twelve and the first eleven pages stink.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Erica can respond, Marin ENTERS.</context>
      <utterance>So you have one good page.  How tall do you think that girl was?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad! I didn't know you were here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just on my way out, bubbee.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I was just gonna drive into the city with Zoe but if you're driving back, I'd much rather go with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to meet someone before I go...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait wait wait wait. You're leaving, Zoe's leaving, the entourage is leaving. And I'm supposed to stay here with him alone?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The doctor said" he's 'sending over a Nurse in the morning...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The morning? That's nineteen hours from now...  Okay, I can handle this. I'm just going to get into a zen' place, play music, cook, write, focus...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She never changes...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Maybe that's a good thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he looks confused)</context>
      <utterance>Coq au Vin...</utterance>
   <speaker>H</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chicken cooked in red wine...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>French Food... French music...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Part of my play takes place in Paris so I'm hoping this helps me think. I'm hopin'...How you feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I walked all the way in here, only bumping into two chairs and an ottoman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry appreciates the thought. Before it has time to become awkward, the Phone RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone bumps into that ottoman.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, thanks for letting me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(hands the phone to Harry)</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, no...it's fine.  Hello. Yes, he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica can't stand this. She puts on her glasses and skims her recipe.</context>
      <utterance>Hello. Hey sweets...  Oh, you got the flowers? Are they pretty?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry squints, can't see what he's writing...backs his head away from the pad. Erica hands him her glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, can I call you in a little bit. What's your number doll?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... Call you in a little.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same prescription...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Harry, it's not like in any stretch of the imagination, I think you're all that right for my daughter but I don't really appreciate hearing you on the phone with other women. It's like I'm an accomplice to you cheating, it's...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your daughter knows I see other women.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She does? I mean, fine, it's none of my business...but...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She knows I'm not monogamous...We've discussed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great? And that's what? Why are you proud of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not proud. Just honest. Your daughter said she likes that about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daughter is confused when it comes to men.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry hands her the open wine bottle.</context>
      <utterance>I don't blame her. We're confusing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you hold a see, doll?  Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, here's the thing. I really don't want to play the part of the uptight Nurse to your bad boy patient. If you want to have another heart attack, go ahead, it's your life but I have work to do and I don't have time to make another run to the hospital because you're filling your already clogged arteries with smoke but more importantly, I'd rather not have my house smell like a pool hall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waits. She doesn't say anything.</context>
      <utterance>I have a question for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Do I Hhave to say what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes the water glass, waiting for the deposit. He drops the cigar in.</context>
      <utterance>Have you always been like this or do I bring this out in you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I've ever had this effect on a woman before.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what effect do you think you're having on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica rolls her eyes as she finishes cleaning up.</context>
      <utterance>I don't quite recognize it, that's how I know I've never had it before.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you don't sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only need about four hours a night.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too. Never slept eight hours in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me either. I wish I could. ..but...  Want me to shut these, sun comes in pretty strong in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. . . thanks. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who you talking to at this hour?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend in L.A. It's only ten out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's not past her bedtime?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you don't get more mellow as the hours pass?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night, Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you one other thing?  What's with the turtlenecks? It's the middle of summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now seriously, why do you care what I wear?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just curious.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like them. I've always liked them. I'm just a turtleneck kinda gal.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever get hot?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not lately.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry! Oh, God am I sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trying to find the kitchen!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back here???</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I-I got confused..! It was dark. I didn't really see anything. Just your tits and a little of your- Erica SLAMS HER DOOR. Photos on the wall shake.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is gonna be murder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good bye? You're leaving? That's not good.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fired? You just started.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica hardly looks at You Know Who who appears to be fresh out of the shower, wet hair, silk robe, bare chest and legs.</context>
      <utterance>Not fired darlin'. Just not needed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, not needed? Of course we need her. She's gonna take care of you and feed you and...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry hands her a wad of bills like she's a Maitre'd. Mrs. Gimble gives Erica a look of pity as she exits. Erica, now alone with Harry, self-consciously adjusts her sunglasses. Harry, on the other hand, slips his hand onto his bare chest, pats it.</context>
      <utterance>-- No, no, I'm actually feeling pretty perky today. Making quite a recovery. . .  Sorry for the trouble Mrs. Gimble... Take care, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, about last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. How 'bout we never talk about that?  I was at the drugstore. Your prescriptions were ready. They said take these two with food and this one without.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honestly, you were in silhouette.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that's talkin' about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really didn't see all that much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yip. There you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Won't mention it again but...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goin' to work, Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sound of a DOOR SLAM. - Harry flinches.</context>
      <utterance>You saw my ass, you don't see me acting nuts, wearing hats and glasses and weird get ups...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes or no. What's the deal, can I go?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still getting dizzy?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not as much.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of breath?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's Erica treating you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erica. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her? Oh, she's a major piece of work. The woman wears turtlenecks in the middle of the summer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's beyond uptight. Almost makes her fun to be around.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uptight? That's funny. I haven't noticed that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julian takes Harry's pulse.</context>
      <utterance>Try livin' with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I actually saw her naked last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't sound so uptight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was an accident. She thought I was asleep, I thought her room was the kitchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what Freud said - there are no accidents.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me. This was an accident. Although, why would she be walking around naked when she knows I'm 20 feet away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you think her bedroom was the kitchen?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was dark, it was two in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That could explain why she was walking around naked. Deep breath...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I've never seen a woman that age naked before.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, we're not all doctors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I think she's very beautiful and she's a fantastic writer, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erica Barry? She's pretty major.  So, you date her daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, now she's a great chick. Must take after the father. Which reminds me...Doc, what  When can I be up and running in that department?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Mr. Midnight needs to stay put for another couple of weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it won't kill me when I do it, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's exercise. It'll be good for you. And just so you know, I'm told after a heart attack, if you can climb a flight of stairs, you can have sex.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you're saying, he's not ready to travel at all? Not even by plane? Train?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so...  It's been tough, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's a bit of a workout.. .yeah.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he fired the Nurse after an hour, now says he doesn't need one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you holding up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, fine. .I'm fine, I'm...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Phone RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>One more fine and I won't believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shoot, hold on...  Hello. Hey...Oh, hi...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smitten. Just something about her. Watching her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not noticing, pouring water for her tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pick you up around seven?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>W-What about the patient?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ERICA Laughs. Even she knows this is funny. Harry arrives at her open doorway, timidly pokes his head in.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Walking Around The house!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I've decided to get over the whole "you saw me naked" thing. So, we don't have to deal with it anymore. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, 'cause I've been hiding from you all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. You want to come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to break your rhythm or anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry ENTERS cautiously and curiously.</context>
      <utterance>That would be wishful thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beautiful painting. So I'm gonna venture out there and go for a short walk...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You up to that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My doctor recommended it. I gotta build up to stairs and stuff like that. You wouldn't want to join me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That means you don't want me to?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I was asking if you wanted to.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, well, I would but...I don't usually like to break once I've started writing so I probably shouldn't, not that a little fresh air would hurt but...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just a walk Erica, not a marriage proposal.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erica Jane Barry. I looked you up on the internet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Did you know there are over eight thousand websites that mention you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That can't be possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's true. I know everything about you now. And not because of last night, but...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were the road manager for a group I sorta never heard of, started your own record label at 29, sold it at 45, then started buying and selling boutique companies then invested in a small record company which you turned into the 2nd largest Hip Hop label in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's exhausting just hearing about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but the truth is, it goes fast doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica bends down and picks up A FLAT WHITE STONE, then another and another...</context>
      <utterance>Like the blink of an eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I noticed you have bowls of those all over your house.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I'm crazy, I just think they're so beautiful...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why do you only pick up the white ones?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't only pick up the white ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so you really are crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I pick up only the white ones?  Oh, God, what does that mean? I'm controlling, unadventurous, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica is stunned that he caught on to that. Harry bends down, picks up a BROWN stone, places it in her palm among the white stones.</context>
      <utterance>So you're as hard on yourself as you are on everyone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something to remember me by.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So can I ask you something Harry? What's with all the young girls? I mean, what's the story there, really?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just like to travel light.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just like to travel light? Oh, please, what the hell does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now see a thirty year old gets that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean falls for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, accepts it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's what you want... a non threatening woman, who won't get your number, you get to run the show...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There he goes again. She can't believe he's cute like this.</context>
      <utterance>I think our relationship is growing by the way. Have you noticed?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm serious. Maybe we just needed to get out of the house. Now, you may notice, interestingly, we're walking back toward the house and its getting a little rocky again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it's getting a little rocky, we're talking about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I'll accept that slight hostility because I'm enjoying your company so much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I think I'11 stay down here and watch the sunset. You interested? Erica checks her watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big dinner date?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With your doctor.</context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah, as a matter of fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohhhhh, my doctor, 'cause he's not too young for you, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he's totally too young for me. But we're just having dinner. It's not a date.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does he know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll tell him, but I doubt that he thinks of it that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I doubt that you doubt that. Anyway, you may like it. Think of it this way -- he's not threatening, won't get your number, you get to run the show. You might have a hell of a time. Over, we HEAR, DING DONG.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, look who's answering the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And look who's at the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brought you something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>57.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julian hands him a take-out food box.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A heart healthy dinner from our cafeteria.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Both guys turn at once. She looks beautiful, wearing a dress, probably the sexiest one she owns. No turtleneck tonight. Julian walks to her, kisses her on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Hello...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind Julian's back Harry gives Erica the 'OK' sign.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ready..?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me just see how Harry's doing. It'll take two seconds. Har, have a seat. .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? That's not the face you want to see your doctor making.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry LOOKS AT ERICA'S LEGS again.</context>
      <utterance>Your pulse is a little fast but maybe you're just excited about something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica shifts, the hem of her skirt RISING even higher.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. I'm not excited about anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There it goes again. Racing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica rises, leaving Harry's eye-line.</context>
      <utterance>Doc... Impossible!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry winces then rises, looks to Erica as she throws a pashmina over her shoulders in SLOW MOTION. Harry rushes them</context>
      <utterance>Oh, there we go, now I feel better. Back to normal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, all right, good, have fun, don't rush back for me and don't do anything I wouldn't do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that wouldn't leave us too many options would it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Erica's shocked expression, the DOOR SLAMS.</context>
      <utterance>And do we wonder how she writes that snappy repartee.  Let him pick up the check. It'll make him feel older.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>his face. As the CAMERA moves we HEAR:</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, it's Marin, I'm not in so leave a message and I'll call you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thinking about you...</context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's me...just sitting around looking at your baby pictures...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>59.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hangs up, dials another number.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER YOUNG WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Harry hangs up then slowly sits up, letting himself feel as funky as he wants.</context>
      <utterance>Hi and HI, you've reached Brooke and Shannon. For Brooke push one, for -</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry rises dizzily, crosses to the bookshelves. He rummages around, finds ERICA'S SCRAPBOOK, pulls it out, randomly opens it, finds a photo of Erica in the 70's, wearing a turtleneck. Harry smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody's out but old Har.. .Old, old old old Har...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- So, when the land came up, I snatched it and the house was built in record time and...  It's like a thousand degrees in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, they say doctors fall for people who need rescuing, that we have a need to take care of someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? I never heard that one.  Julian, how old are you, like...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Thirty-three.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-three.-Okay, so, I'm twenty years older than you. More than twenty years older than you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look fabulous.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you but you know, I'm not sure where you were headed with that thing you were just saying, but in terms of us, you just want to be friends, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honestly? No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>want to be?</context>
      <utterance>Well, then, what is it that you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'd embarrass you if I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was embarrassed just getting dressed to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This may surprise you but some women consider me quite the guy. I've never been married. I'm a doctor. You wouldn't believe what catnip that is for some women.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes I would. But, you don't like girls your own age?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do very much. But I've never met one I've taken to quite like this and when something happens to you that's never happened to you before, don't you have to at least find out what it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose but, see, I don't date all that much or all that well...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on, you must beat them away with a stick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you're kidding, right? No, guys my age, the ones I've met...well, I'm not that regular a person and they really like regular.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(takes her hand)</context>
      <utterance>Men your age may be really stupid, you ever think of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I have. Many times.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ow. Right to the middle of her shoulder, then her neck. Julian kisses her palm, then her.</context>
      <utterance>There's something radically wrong with the idea that no one loves you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd smell good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just...soap...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much is soap that smells like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I got it at the market.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erica, you're incredibly sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, swear to God, I'm not...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm back...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was interesting. So... Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are cute...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is pretty unusual for me. I'm not used to having sleepovers.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me either.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? With your social life?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My, dear, you are confusing sex with sleeping. Sleeping is something I prefer to do alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, good to know.  So, what are you hungry for?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks through the fridge.</context>
      <utterance>What are my choices? I mean I know you think I'm not very discriminating but...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, what's the difference what I think. I can't imagine what you think of me. Okay, so... Pasta, left over coq au vin, turkey sandwich or grilled cheese.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pancakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Totally what I wanted. Blueberries?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever miss being married? I bet you were great at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I miss it. At night.. But not that much anymore. Was one of us just saying something interesting?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you can't imagine what I think of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, right, but you don't have to answer that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, if you had an opinion, I'd be curious but...'</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>will you tell me first why you only miss being married at night?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts mixing the batter.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, 'cause the phone doesn't ring as much at night and the "alone" thing happens at night and sleeping by myself took some getting used to. But I got the hang of it. You gotta sleep in the middle of the bed. It's absolutely not healthy to have a side when no one has the other side.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, now I'm convinced what I think of you is right.  You are a tower of strength.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ughhhhhhhhhh... .</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try not to rate my answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. It's just...I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're like a thoroughbred in a world of mutts. No, you know what you are, you're like a great portrait over a fireplace. Words have been invented to describe women like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Such as?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flinty and...Impervious.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you think I'm inhuman.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I think you're formidable.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But cold and distant. Like I'm frozen in some painting...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. I think you're strength defines you.  But it's thrilling when your defenses are down arid you're not isolated. That, I believe, is your winning combo. A killer combo actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... So I can't decide if you hate me or if maybe you're the only person who ever got me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moment is broken when they HEAR the FRONT DOOR OPEN and</context>
      <utterance>I don't hate you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin ARRIVES IN THE DOORWAY in a knockout of a dress holding a bag from Zabars. She looks fresh, vibrant, sexy.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Room service!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here at this hour?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>I</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica nods to herself. Oh, God, he sends them all flowers. Harry notes Erica's reaction.</context>
      <utterance>had this big photography auction tonight, then I went out with a bunch of people, I checked my messages and got this so sad message from Harry so bored out here. I thought I should come out and at least see how he was doing.  Thank you for the gorgeous flowers by the way. They were so huge...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how are you guys?  Oh, this is too sweet. You're making pancakes? Awwww. And you're both in your pj's. Now I feel I'm interrupting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be silly. You know I never sleep and this one doesn't sleep either. It's... .What's in the bag?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A quart of matzoh ball soup for Harry. I know it's not the remedy for heart problems but it is low cholesterol.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But high sodium.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin's cell phone RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, sorry. Stupid. For Mom, your favorite raisin-bread. And for me...  My favorite Vodka.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Mar, now that you're here, why don't you finish the pancakes and I'll get back to work...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pours a healthy Vodka into a glass, grabs some ice.</context>
      <utterance>Mom! I just got here, hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So your ex-husband stood me up today. We were supposed to have lunch at Barneys . He never showed up. Was he always like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as harry is about to answer, Marin's cell RINGS. She picks it up, looks at her caller ID, throws it back in her bag.</context>
      <utterance>This is what happens after a couple gets divorced, the kid inherits all the problems. Not that I'm a kid.  So how are you, how do you feel? When can you go home?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really am gonna do a little work. . . you two catch up. . . and just flip these Hin like two seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want pancakes anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, uh, I don't think I...I...  gorgeous, next to him No. I don't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm breaking up with Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cause I met someone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the two days you've been gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'd be nuts to keep this going.</context>
      <utterance>You know me, my life's crazy. I meet a thousand people everyday. Also, let's face it, the guy's insanely old for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>True, but you know he is....</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I know. He's soulful when you don't expect it, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's unnerving.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Mom, if you could handle this, I was thinking... you and Harry...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't handle it. Wouldn't want to handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're only saying that 'cause you think he and I have had sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Lower your voice. Haven't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>J</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ER, on his CELL PHONE.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've waited a reasonable amount of hours before calling you, even though you've been on my mind since I woke up at 5:15. I'm wondering when we could have dinner again? I have to work the next few nights and if we wait 'til next week, I know you'll chicken out so how's Friday? I know it's like a date night but I think that's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julian stops short.</context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm kidding!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you meet me at The Grill at eight?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Yes. That's seems fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, he's all yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop that. How'd he take it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just took care of it for me; He was an ace. Elegant. Said our fate was to be friends. ...Oh my God.  He was breaking up with me. He's a genius.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's impossible, he wouldn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin EXITS and the PHONE RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter, we're done and we both feel good about it.  I gotta get back.  Now Erica, try to think of this as the smartest thing you've ever done for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry and Erica talk while looking at each other through the Kitchen Window.</context>
      <utterance>Thought you'd like to know your daughter broke up with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Made up a story about meeting another guy. Guess I wasn't so cute with an IV in my arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I think she really did meet someone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's alright. Her mother didn't like me anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout I bring you out some lunch and a couple of blood</utterance>
   <speaker>H</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pressure pills?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a great woman, Erica.  Is this why my doctor is falling in love with you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just kissed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Relieyed, Erica kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>No, honey, I kissed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that one was me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her again and again.</context>
      <utterance>Try not to keep score.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soft lips...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I haven't used them for kissing in so long. They've been more like for wearing lipstick and whistling and... He kisses her quiet. Relieved, she finally fully kisses him back. A big gorgeo~s kiss.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad they still work.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both look down at Harry. Hello, Mr. Midnight.</context>
      <utterance>Well, well, now look who's got something that works...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you didn't even take Via-</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kiss me before you make it go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>S</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>he kisses him long and sweet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This could be world class interesting.  Having any doubts?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to kiss her neck but the turtleneck is in the way. He pulls it down, but it's tight and it's, difficult to get to her.</context>
      <utterance>But so far the kissing is spectacular.  I'm not grading you, just mentioning it. Brilliant.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries lifting the shirt from the bottom, it's awkward, he doesn't want to be down there yet. He comes back up when Erica reaches to her night table, slides opens the drawer, takes out a SCISSORS and hands it to him.</context>
      <utterance>Can't get past your damn turtleneck. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What a brilliant invitation. He takes the scissors and starts cutting from the bottom, right past her belly, up her torso, between her breasts. The turtleneck falls open from the center. When he reaches her neck, he gently tears at it and it easily rips apart and there she is. He takes her in.</context>
      <utterance>Cut it off... Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head, 'no' ...shuts her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You're beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open your eyes so I know you can hear me.  Beautiful... They kiss and she reaches down for his pants.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about birth control?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Menopause.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses between her breasts, her stomach, heads down and OUT OF FRAME. Erica can't quite believe life held this twist for her. Then:,</context>
      <utterance>Who's the lucky boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His head POPS BACK INTO FRAME. What?????</context>
      <utterance>I think we should take your blood pressure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's irresponsible not to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody but you would. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica grabs Harry's glasses, reads the results.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...so you're lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One twenty over eighty!!! Baby!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA TWIRLS AROUND and we FIND HARRY, sprawled nearby, catching his breath, satisfied, stunned, scared.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, I do like sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica arrives next to him, also out of breath.</context>
      <utterance>You certainly do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry smiles. He's trying to be his debonair self but something's off. He's very aware of himself. They lie there quietly for a second when Erica begins to tear up. Harry slowly, nervously turns to her.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. So this is what you're supposed to do on a rainy afternoon...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really thought I was sorta closed for business. Just never expected this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is crazy. I can't remember the last time I cried. I think I'm overwhelmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too. That's the perfect word.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby, I had sex three days after a heart attack and I didn't die! Erica pauses. Oh. That kind of overwhelmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Good sport Erica gives him a double thumbs up.</context>
      <utterance>That's gotta be some kind of record.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's not brag about this to our doctor, okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey I may not be many things but one - thing I am is a gentleman. Harry holds her close.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erica, Erica, Erica.  You know I'm not good at being monogamous, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her wondering if she's for real. She smiles as she wipes a small tear from the corner of her eye. Then he kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>Monogamous? Please, I hardly know you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>C</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ozy. Candles light the room. It's still raining.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- So there I was at nineteen, in New York, by myself, and I'd never seen snow before and I didn't have enough money for the bus, so I had to walk. Had no idea how far it was and I'm talking blizzard and I'm in sneakers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awwwww,. . .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, you guys okay out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're fine. Why? What's going on?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, it's like a hurricane. The news said the winds are like a zillion miles an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that. Oh, no, we're fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You are, aren't you.</context>
      <utterance>Are you having sex? Tell the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not. No. That is not going on now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, you already did it. Was it amazing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell me, was it amazing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin SCREAMMMMMMMMMMMS. Erica flips the phone shut, looks to Harry, embarassed.</context>
      <utterance>Yes and thank you for the wonderful opportunity.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I interested in buying aluminum siding. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Marin's selling aluminum siding? Erica buries her face in his chest.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--But why Paris?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just always wanted to write a play that ended there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where do you like to eat in Paris? E</utterance>
   <speaker>RICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I love this place called Le Balzar, it's just a little bistro on the Left Bank, best roast chicken in the universe.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be fun to go to Paris with.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a great city to stay up all night in.  When's your birthday?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>February.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine's in January. So, how 'bout if we still know each other by then we go to Paris for our birthdays.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Sorry. You just...  . I have no idea how to do this...be intimate but not...The color is draining from your face. Okay, look, I'm gonna pee,take one of your blood pressure pills then when I get back, let's not talk anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>79.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She gets out of bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has no idea how to take that. Decides to accept it.</context>
      <utterance>You're the funniest girl I ever had sex with.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's somethin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns, sees he's getting out of bed, approaching her.</context>
      <utterance>Honey... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'm gonna go back to my room...let you sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>so...okay.</context>
      <utterance>Let me sleep? Oh, right...you usually send the girls home. . .but I am home...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm an old dog, you' know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's perfectly. .. whatever. Good night. This was..This was a great night. For me...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica nods. She knows.</context>
      <utterance>Me too. At one point I even thought soul mates, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY FLOPS ONTO HIS BED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>stares straight up at the ceiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to try sleeping with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you see this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really but it looks like it says eleven.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is eleven...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can't be, that would mean we slept eight hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn and finally look at each other. Both look wrinkled, messy haired, a little wiped.</context>
      <utterance>Impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How ya doin' Ace?  Whoa Nelly...little dizzy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(getting out of bed)</context>
      <utterance>Okay, just stay still, here's the clicker. You know you have a doctor's appointmQnt in an hour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make us some coffee, get you your pills, whip us up some french toast, I have ,the best maple syrup ever. '</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica smiles, then walks away with the achey walk of a woman who hasn't had sex in many a year but has more than made up for it in the last 12 hours. She holds onto the wall as she exits the room, a little bow-legged, like she's just gotten off a horse. Alone in the hallway, she stops.</context>
      <utterance>Erica...  You are a woman to love.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are woman to love. What the hell does that mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, buddy, I'm sending you home. These past few days have done wonders for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I've been working on that stair thing. I can do it by the way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Way to go. How's Erica?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erica?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you must know her name by now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julian, suddenly riveted to these words.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do. Erica, as it turns out is an amazing woman. Does whatever she can to make me happy. Really. Turns out she's very giving.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very giving.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A real moment between them. Julian decides to take the high road.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well that's wonderful. I think she's wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she's wonderful too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give her my best...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julian shakes Harry's hand. Harry's eyes TEAR UP.</context>
      <utterance>Julian. Thanks for everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the...? This is the second time I've done this now. I get overcome or something. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everything takes on a new meaning.</context>
      <utterance>It's very common to become emotional after having an episode like you've had.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it's not crazy for a man to do something entirely out of character after having a heart attack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like crying?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah and totally changing their tastes. Like suddenly really liking something they never thought they could like...ever...and I'm talking really liking it. It's...unnerving.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you can expect just about anything right now. People have done some wild things after having a heart attack...selling businesses, getting divorced, moving... Some people say it saved their lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But most people go back to being themselves, right? I'll go back to being me, won't I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. What'd he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said you're wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, really, what'd he say...How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said I'm good..that I can go.</utterance>
   <speaker>. ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>. . great.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. So... Congratulations. That's really.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he said... by tomorrow for absolute sure. You think you can deal with me for one more night?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, here goes...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here goes what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here goes me singing to you...  Bought my own music.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew they had karaoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry makes his way TO THE STAGE, hands them his disc. He's handed a microphone. He looks right at Erica.</context>
      <utterance>Baby, it's why we're here. .</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Music begins and it is an instrumental version of one of Erica's French Songs, "I Wish You Love".</context>
      <utterance>This is for you, Ace...  wish me luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>arry takes out a sheet of paper and his glasses.</context>
      <utterance>I wish you bluebirds in the spring... To Give your heart a song to sing... And then a kiss, but more than this... I wish H you love...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Harry sings the rest of the song IN FRENCH. . .</context>
      <utterance>Don't want to blow this part...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you go, you can have these back now.  I confiscated them your first night here...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you darlin' ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try not to smoke them...  And I packed you a sandwich, just in case your blood sugar got low. And some of that iced-tea you like, and a nonfat, low cholesterol cookie. And a peach.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From behind her back Erica pulls out a Mason Jar filled with all dark beach stones with ONE WHITE STONE in the center.</context>
      <utterance>what a doll...  Got something else?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry hugs her. Erica awkwardly throws her arms around him and kisses him, then kisses him better. He's moved by her.</context>
      <utterance>Something to remember me by.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is that...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And hey, we'll always have Paris.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, no words can ever express my gratitude for taking me in and taking care of me and...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, your heart attack could be the best thing that ever happened to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry expression looks something like he's in pain. Then. . .</context>
      <utterance>I love you too...if that's what you said. I don't know if it ends in 'ya' if it's an official I love you but...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not like anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither are you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd call.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN - WALKING IN SOHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>on her cell phone, CRYING.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had breakfast with Dad this morning and we're talking and he starts looking all weir~ and then he tells me he met someone three weeks ago and it's "really something and then he  He tells me he's getting married. Why am I reacting this way? I'm almost thirty years old...  Yes, I'm crying, leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's he marrying?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Some chick he met three weeks ago. She's four years older than me and she's an Ear, Nose and Throat Doctor. Has he lost his mind? I have a huge auction tonight... Why do I have to be the one to deal with this? Can you please come in? I'm rea:~y upset, my shrink'~ away for two weeks...I know you're working but. . .please. . ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Look, I get that he has a right to get remarried, but he doesn't even know her and she's like my age. You know what that's like? It's like beyond creepy. And I know he's not replacing me so why does it feel like he is? This is crazy, right? Crying like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, if he's replacing anyone, it's me. And all the statistics say divorced men almost always remarry. That's just the way they're built.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, you want to know the answer to the big mystery of my life? Why I'm always with the wrong guy? This is why. Because the wrong guy can't do this to you. You have some control with the wrong guy. This thing I'm feeling right now. This is my big fear...that some guy could get me unglued like this, like nothing's connected. And this is just my father! I'm just not strong enough to handle this kind of drama.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The drama in life is what makes you strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's what makes you strong. You've never really understood this,but we're not all like you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, if I were you and my ex husband, the man who I still allow to direct my plays.! was getting married to some 33 year old Ear, Nose and Throat Babe, I'd be bonkers. And look at you.  You've never looked better, by the way.  My anti-depressant is obviously not working. It should cover events like this shouldn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when do you take an antidepressant?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ugggh, mother, do you know anyone who doesn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A KNOCK on the door.</context>
      <utterance>I rest my case.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE FROM OUTSIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marin, we're all set.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, can you do one other really big thing for me? Just say yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything bubee.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you come out to dinner tonight with me and Dad and the fiance?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely not. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. He wants me to meet her and I can not go alone. I already asked him if you could come and he said it was fine and she said it was fine. Look, you're gonna have to meet her too, so, we might as well meet her together. Come on, you know you can handle it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>90.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erica pauses, thinks M about it. She knows she can too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. That's it. See that look on your face. That's the gene I didn't get.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess I got stood up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to order or...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>AVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirsty?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've had a big week Dave, forgot how these slip right down. I'm fine. So, Kristen, where'd you go to...  --medical school? Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRISTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>University of Pennsylvania.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went to school in Philadelphia too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bryn Mawr girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRISTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's amazing. My Mom went to Bryn Mawr . . .</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. So not only are you marrying my father but our mothers went to the same college. Marin takes out a pack of cigarettes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRISTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'll just..have one.  So, this isn't going badly so far is it? I mean for a totally surreal situation like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall we order?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRISTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erica, do I like duck?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's rabbit you hate.  I'll give you a list of everything he likes and dislikes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's let her figure some things out on her own.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She did go to medical school.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean those things, Dave.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, not in front of the kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will tell you this...Dave has one truly great love in his life.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRISTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His balls.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I forgot to mention she can't drink hard liquor.  Why did you order her a Martini?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica looks at her menu then her eyes go right back to Harry. His Date is laughing at something Harry is saying. Harry leans in to her, whispers something to her. She touches his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica rises; grabs her purse, almost bumps into a Waiter as she passes Harry's table, knocks into someone's chair, a glass breaks. Everyone turns to her, including Harry. She now stands right at his table. He smiles up at her.</context>
      <utterance>You know what? Maybe I need a little air...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello... Harry.  Hello...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up her pace, starts running. Her cell phone RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, I'm so stupid...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Intercut Harry and Erica on their cells, a block apart.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She considers it.</context>
      <utterance>Slow down. You want to kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, I gotta go...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erica, she's just a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica reaches a corner, can't get across, turns the corner. Harry ARRIVES NEXT TO HER.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she looks like a buddy kind of a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, it's just a dinner...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Harry, here's the problem. I really like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry swoons and not in a good way.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I love you like you.  I do. I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think maybe you should consider that you're in love with the idea of being in love.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>o you? Okay. Oh, God...  I'm like the dumb girl who doesn't get it.  I've never been the dumb girl before. It ain't so great.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just calm down. This was just a a meal with a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Did you know I called you seven hours ago?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was gonna call you. I've been jamming all day, it's my first day back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had these plans before I met you. But I do like seeing you. I do. I'm always surprised by it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was I thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you weren't thinking for once and look what a good time we had. Let's not ruin something great.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, I won't be good at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Acting like I don't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have never lied to you. I have always told you some version of the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The truth doesn't have versions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you cut me a little slack? My life's been turned upside down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Mine too.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then let's each get our bearings.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want my bearings. I've had my bearings my whole fucking life. I felt something with you that... Oh, you don't want to-</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I do.  Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I felt something with you, I didn't know really existed. You know what that's like after a twenty year marriage? To feel something for another person that's so off the charts, that -  Okay, not your problem. This is why I'm not good in relationships. You know writers are like teachers, those who can - do, those who can't - write romantic comedies where THIS does not happen in the third act...and it certainly does not happen to a 55 year old woman. In the play I'll be 36 so it won't be as pathetic. I'm just too old to feel crushed.I've written this feeling but I never really got it.  You know what this is?  This is heart broken. How's that for impervious?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're killin' me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wish it had lasted more than a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a horrible thing to say.  The life I had before I met you. I knew how to do that, could do that forever. Now look at me...what do I do with all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we talk tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A TAXI pulls up.</context>
      <utterance>What for? I saw your friend you were having dinner with, if that's what you want, it's never going to work with me. Look at me. I'm a middle aged woman, don't let this brown hair fool you, I don't have a real brown hair on my head, I'm almost all grey...that would freak you out, wouldn't it? And I have. high cholesterol and my back hurts every morning and I'm post menopausal and I have osteoperosis and I'm sure arthritis is just around the corner and I know you've seen my vericose veins. Let's face it man, that's not quite the buzz you're lookin' for.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica opens the back door of the Taxi.</context>
      <utterance>And you know what? Everyday, I'm gettin' older. ..just like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is his chance.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. Erica turns.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just... the truth is... I don't know how to be a boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what you have to say after all this? You don't know how to be a boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're both out of words.</context>
      <utterance>That's not a small thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we done?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. He doesn't give. She ducks into the CAB and it PULLS AWAY. Harry stands on the street, watching her go.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs his heart.</context>
      <utterance>Ouch.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Came in by cab, 15 minutes of chest pain, no nauseau, some shortness of breath, was hospitalized a week ago with a coronary thrombosis.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. MARTINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang a nitro drip.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't. I took Viagra.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. MARTIINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have been through this before. Give him 5 mgs of Metoprolol. You h~ving chest pain right now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, and the pain I was having was sharp, not like before.</utterance>
   <speaker>. DR. MARTINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good. Not like before is we like to hear.  Give him aspirin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DR. MARTINEZ</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Based on what I see so far, your heart is not in distress but I'm gonna do a rapid enzyme test to be sure. What were you doing at the onset of the pain?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Having a fight with someone. A woman. Can a woman give you chest pain?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. MARTINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? Love hurts, haven't you heard?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but so far, I've only given pain, I never got any.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. MARTINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, well you're battin' a thousand here. Your enzymes look perfect, your EKG is normal and the pain doesn't sound like the kind of pain we worry about. I think what you experienced was normal chest pain associated with stress.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stress?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. MARTINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And incase you haven't heard, that can give you a heart attack. Mr. Langer, I donlt know what you're up to gallivanting out and about at this hour, but if you were my Dad, I'd make sure you were home, in bed, recuperating.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERICA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He realizes he doesn't know what to say, hangs up, then looks at her glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. It's Erica. I'm not here so leave a message.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lowell, I'm goin' out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Don't forget to put some clothes on.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, I should go out, shouldn't I? Since .when don't I go out? Just cause some Emergency Room Doctor tells me to stay in bed, doesn't mean I have to turn into a monk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there something you'd like me to do for you, Mr. Langer?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, no, just...well, what are you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watching Lucy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you hate making me something to eat?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny women are adorable, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never really thought about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither had I, but think about it. Funny's a unique thing in a woman. It's fun to be around.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's some reason we've been watching these two for 5O years.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. It lasts. We're not sittin' here watchin' Mamie Van Doren reruns.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No we're not. You feeling okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I've slept one night since I've been home. Every little ache and pain scares the shitout of me...can't get a handle on my emotional life, don't know what I want, don't know if what I felt was because I just had a heart attack or was real. Plus, I feel needy. I never used that word in my life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lowell, have you ever seen me like this? Be honest.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing even close.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, buddy, I'm a mess. And I'm no good at it.  Those are very nice pajamas, by the way. Did they used to be mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes but you gave them to me, you said you never wore them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're so elegant. Nice piping...</context>
      <utterance>I know. But why would I do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Langer, you're always giving away beautiful things.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry nods off and Lowell TURNS OUT THE LIGHT.</context>
      <utterance>Awwwww... How did I get like this?  I'm gonna shut my eyes for a few minutes. Keep Lucy on...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you crying?  I didn't know you did that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's my new thing. I've gotten abnormally great at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it Harry?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems I gotta learn how to do that love 'em and leave 'em stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fucking men. You don't care when I say fuck, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really. Sometimes. Not right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So now you get my theory about love? You gotta self protect. It's too dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marin, that theory... how can I put this so your feelings won't get hurt. It's just so crazy, it makes me want to SCREAMMMMMMMMMMM!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how would you put it if you wanted to hurt my feelings?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me... you cannot hide from love for the rest of your life because maybe it won't work out and maybe you'll become unglued. That's not a way to live.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're telling me you're happy right now? This is good what happened to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. This was bad. But for the three days it was good, it was electrifying. Marin's eyes fill up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you must consider the possibility that we are more alike than you realize. I let someone in and I had the time of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never had the time of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>what the fuck are you waiting "for?</context>
      <utterance>I know. And bubbee, I say this from the deepest part of my heart. . ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>H</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>aving fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry makes his way down the stairs, through the crowded entry and OUT THE FRONT DOOR. OUTSIDE, Harry steps into the QUIET STREET, looks up at his house and the party inside.</context>
      <utterance>Not quite.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julian, I hope you know I'm mortified by my behavior. I was going to get in touch with you, send you a note or something...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A note? That's a little chilly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm embarrassed. I just haven't been myself lately. What can I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell me you're sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you could kiss me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ulian nods.</context>
      <utterance>Kiss you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll forgive me if I kiss' you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica hesitates then gives him a peck of a kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica nods as Julian takes her in his arms and gives her a kiss that doesn't quit.</context>
      <utterance>No one on earth would forgive you for that kiss  May I?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica very distinctly begins to hear the BEATING of her own heart.</context>
      <utterance>I forgive you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the best thing you've ever written.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica leans oyer the sofa, reading over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>It's wonderful. It's sweet. It's smart. It's funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How great is it that I'm not intimidated by your brilliance? Erica gives him a small kiss of appreciation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>A</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>part of "The Sister".</utterance>
   <speaker>CTRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why can't we all stay for the weekend?</context>
      <utterance>Look, we're four sophisticated people.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica freezes, horrified. Turns, sees him.</context>
      <utterance>I need to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a minute?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So your play's about us?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I in it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A guy like you is in it but he's not you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens to this guy who's ..not me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't totally decided. He can live or he can die.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you leaning towards?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Death.  It's funnier.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He dies of a funny heart attack?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's sort of a schmuck who screwed around with our heroine, so it won't be too sad.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Schmucks are people too you know. Death doesn't seem a little harsh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Really...just stuff I made up.</context>
      <utterance>I just went where the story took me. It's a work of fiction, Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAGE MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erica, we're ready to do the hospital, 'Do You Take Viagra scene... Should we wait for you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>110.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erica nods, horrified.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'm going to be the laughing stock of Broadway.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, he's not you. He's a version of the truth of you. So to speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAGE MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to interrupt again but Dave wants to know, when Henry says, "I love ya", you want that to be 'Ya', not 'You', right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We now HEAR Louis Armstrong's La Vie En Rose play throughout the theater. The BEACH backing is 'raised and an EIFFEL TOWER BACKING is lowered behind them. They both try to ignore the music, but it's impossible.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they stand in front of the Eiffel Tower backing, FAKE SNOW FALLS from above...</context>
      <utterance>Well, you look really nice. You feeling all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know it isn't like I wanted to stop seeing you. We could've carried on a fun thing for awhile. Why is it you dames want all or nothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, we're just goofy when it comes to love... Look, Harry, if it's all right with you, I'd like to be friends</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not ready to be your friend. How's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, do you actually buy that horse shit.. .that men and women can be friends once they've had sex?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm friends with my ex-husband, but then again, we didn't just have sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't just have sex either.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what was it? Love to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I e-mail it to you when I figure it out?  This is perfect. I have given the `Can't We Be friends' speech for 40 years. I think I invented the 'Can't We Be Friends' speech. But you know what,now I get why they never went for it. You dames got one thing right. Sometimes sex does change everything. Call me crazy, but I just don't see us out on the town, being pals, having dinner, 'cause I'd bet you anything, at some point, one of us will have very unfriend like thoughts about the other then pass the bread becomes anything but pass the bread. You get what I'm saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to be friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not "don't". Can't. Can't be friends. Doesn't work that way.  Okay, I'm moving into another phase of this thing. I'm mad at you.  It almost feels good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'm mad at you too.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent. 'Cause I don't like thinking about you so much and worrying about how you are and if I ruined your life or...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- You've worried about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes honey, the schmuck who deserves to die, worries about you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>112.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>HARRY Sometimes worrying about you feels like a full time job.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, doll, I'm doing fine. So you don't have to work that shift anymore. Again, The Stage Manager...</utterance>
   <speaker>STAGE MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry and Erica TURN and SEE a CHORUS LINE of BALDING 60 YEAR</context>
      <utterance>Erica, they want you to take a look at the costumes for the dancing Henry's. These gonna work for you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God is a woman, I know that now. No man would punish me like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN JOGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Surprised, Harry turns, glances over at the Woman. She drinks from a water bottle then offers him an easy warm smile. She's adorable, mid-sixties, short grey hair.</context>
      <utterance>You never change, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know me or are you just talking to me as "man" in general, the beast women love to hate.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN JOGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, I know you Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Don't tell me. I dated your daughter.  Right? I broke her heart then she married some hard working Joe on the rebound, has three great kids. What is so funny?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WOMAN JOGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry now fully turns in her direction, totally clueless.</context>
      <utterance>You dated me and you broke my heart but after you I met the right guy. I've been married thirty-seven years, have four kids, eight grandkids and a ninth on the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dated you. .?  Did we. ever...?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN JOGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her hard but still doesn't remember her.</context>
      <utterance>No...we did not.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you give me hint? A year? A decade?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN JOGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sixties.  You took me to Shea Stadium.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To a Mets game? I must've really liked you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN JOGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You took me to see The Beatles.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God, I really liked you. You're Sandra. ..Cook. We did. We saw The Beatles together. How the hell have you been? What happened to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's see, after we stopped going out, I went back to school, got my doctorate in marine biology, went around the world a few times, met the man of my dreams at Oxford, married him, we lived in London for 25 years. I wrote and taught, we raised 3 sons and a daughter. I've just finished my ninth book and now I'm training for my first marathon. Now, I must confess, I actually remember the very last thing you ever said to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DR. MARTINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Langer... Back so soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is it, I'm dyin', I've had 20 minutes of severe chest pain, nausea, shortness of breath, blood pressure's gotta be 170 over 100.  Give me the nitrate, I didn't take viagra.  Plug me in to the EKG, I need an aspirin, I'm taking 2 beta blockers, blood thinner, Lipitor, Procardia and if I were you, I'd be pounding my chest. Ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a doctor, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a very sick man.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. MARTINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Langer, your diagnosis although fascinating, was entirely incorrect.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. MARTINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your realize a severe anxiety attack can masquerade as a heart attack.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'm nuts? Perfect! The one thing I'm not taking pills for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DR. MARTINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't want ,to end up in here every week, I suggest you do whatever it takes to decompress. Try something with me, okay?  Close your eyes...now give yourself a visual image of something that gives you a feeling of peace and serenity.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. A hammock...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. MATINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, good...what else..?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the SOUND OF LAPPING WATER, SEA GULLS. . . .</context>
      <utterance>Palm trees...clear blue water...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. MARTINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody there with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Beautiful women...in thongs...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. MARTINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. What else do you see, feel, taste...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>..miles of soft beach.. .</context>
      <utterance>A margarita...a Cuban cigar.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. MARTINEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as Harry keeps listing things, Camera MOVES IN ON HIM as the STEEL BAND gets LOUDER AND LOUDER.</context>
      <utterance>Keep going...you're doing great...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't believe you were calling from downstairs.  So great to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You couldn't look better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, I just wanted to stop by and say hi and tell you I'm sorry if I ever did anything to you that wasn't on the up and up or...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? You were great to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's refreshing. Good. Well, I don't know what you've done to yourself but you look absolutely radiant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm three months pregnant, that might have something to do with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HARRY,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Who's ..the, lucky guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Solid Citizen of a Guy joins Marin, loosened tie, glasses...</context>
      <utterance>My husband, hold on, he really wants to meet you.  Danny...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry Langer, my husband, Danny Yellin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've heard so much about you...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet.. .</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, with Hthe play and all...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm famous,huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just to us. In every interview my Mom does, she always says she made you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the guy in the play, he doesn't make it, does he?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He basically dies at the end of the second act, but it's very funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was hopin' she'd give me a reprieve, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marin is stumped by this little visit. Harry heads toward the elevator, pushes the button, then turns back.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Okay...Best of luck, kids...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Learning Italian, remodeling her apartment in the city.</context>
      <utterance>She's. . .  Really good. Up to her old tricks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now if I wanted to see her...how would that go over?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only one way to find out, except she's out of town right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Elevator arrives. Harry salutes his goodbye and steps INSIDE THE ELEVATOR. He turns, FACES CAMERA.</context>
      <utterance>Paris. She left two days ago, for her birthday. But she'll be back next week...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paris...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've come a long way to see you, Erica.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean we're not bumping into each other..? You came here to see me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I did.  I'm aware it was a bold move, one of those impulses that grabs you,' but...so far, we're okay; right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh, I mean, I'm just...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry takes off his coat and scarf, hangs them on a hook.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take that as a 'Yes'.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want a glass of wine or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just gonna give you a kiss hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neither is sure where to go. Cheek? Lips? He lands on her chin. .Not what he wanted, but he takes a seat across from her. She looks at him - utterly speechless.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember you said if we still know each other we should go to Paris for our birthdays, well, we still know each other..".</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's true, but, Harry, I haven't heard from you in six months.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know but I've certainly been thinking about you. There's a lot I have to say. First thing is... I'm not mad at you anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, 'cause I'm not mad at you anymore either.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Happy Birthday.</context>
      <utterance>That's a relief...since I did come all the way to France and everything. And...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And congratulations on your amazing success...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been quite a ride. Funny, I thought maybe I'd hear from you when it opened. Where've you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After I saw you in the theater that afternoon, I had another "episode...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was actually okay, but I was sure I was dying and the doctor in the ER said I needed to decompress. So I did. I walked out of there and changed my life, sold most of my businesses, packed my bags and moved to an island in the Caribbean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's where you've been all this time? In the Caribbean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually...No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Harry ENTERS THE CLOSET, reaches onto a top shelf ,and starts pulling down dozens of what used be called, "Little Black Books".</context>
      <utterance>So I decided to take another kind of pilgrimage...into my past.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My thought was -- if I retraced my steps and visited all the women I've dated... He blows dust off of the books.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Then, we see WOMEN of various ages SLAP HIM ACROSS THE FACE.</context>
      <utterance>A lot of the women wouldn't see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Harry reels backwards from one Hefty Mama.</context>
      <utterance>Or speak to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I was on a mission to save my soul.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>In a HOSPITAL ROOM, an Older Woman on life support, scrawls out a note and shows it to Harry who sits in a chair by herside. A Priest stands in the background. The note says, "As I remember it, you were wildly insensitive". Harry lowers his head in shame. She places another note in front of him. It says, "I forgive you." Relieved, he smiles. Then, one last note: "Now, scram."</context>
      <utterance>My losing streak finally ended when I got one to open up to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>In an Upper West Side COFFEE SHOP, Harry pas coffee with a Woman in her Mid Forties. She talks his ear off. Harry can' t deal with it. He looks away ~ The woman places her hand on his chin and pulls him right back to her and keeps talking at him.</context>
      <utterance>Hearing what they had to say was no picnic.</utterance>
   <speaker>H</speaker>
      <mode>V .O.</mode>
      <context>Harry WALKS down THE STREET with a ANOTHER WOMAN in her Thirties, who carries a cello. She never shuts up.</context>
      <utterance>But I stuck it out and I listened. Then I listened harder.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V. O. </mode>
      <context>At the corner, the Woman hugs Harry goodbye.</context>
      <utterance>And one of the things I realized was, I was actually giving closure to generations of women.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode>V. O. </mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Although I admit, some refused to give, no matter what I did. . .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A HAND lands on his shoulder and he HEARS:</context>
      <utterance>It took me six months to find them all. I visited 18 different states but I came the furthest to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>A MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry looks up and sees handsome young Julian in a beret. Harry looks to Erica, instantly deflated..</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry stands. The two Men hug, then Julian squeezes in next to Erica. Harry slowly takes his seat across from them.</context>
      <utterance>Me either.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should have told you he was coming, but I was so engrossed in your story.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What story..?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, maybe another time. ..So...  I guess I should've seen your play, then I would've Jknown how this ended.</utterance>
   <speaker>ULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, big twist, huh? So what are you doing over here, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a uh, vacation...never been to Paris in January...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's amazing to run into you. You look wonderful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't been on a gurney in six months so that's somethin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts what can only be a RING BOX on the table between Erica and Harry.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I've just been to every store in the city, this woman is impossible to buy for... But I think I finally found the right gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her. Harry watches, dying.</context>
      <utterance>Happy Birthday baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry rises, reaches for his coat.</context>
      <utterance>I'll open it later...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, you know what, I'll let you two celebrate...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry, stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't really.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? You have somewhere to go?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>125.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erica lights a cigarette.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing, you don't smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in Paris, the second hand smoke will kill you anyway...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julian puts his arm around her, pulls her close.</context>
      <utterance>She's very brilliant, but the woman can not hold her liquor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like that about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOTH GUYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guys exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, if I were writing this, this is where I'd write, 'an awkward moment' .</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erica laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, if you were writing this, I'd be dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Waiter drops the check on the table. Harry takes it.</context>
      <utterance>Never fails to amuse her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Harry, please, let us...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, I insist. I crashed your party.  At least let me buy you dinner on your birthday...  What time does that say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no idea...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait,' I have my. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They each take out EACH OTHER'S GLASSES and put them on. Erica points to Harry wearing her glasses and laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Me too...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you look so handsome in mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how long I've been looking for those?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry hands Erica her glasses. She hesitates. He snaps, gesturing for his to be turned over. She hands them to him. Julian watches all this, sobered by their chemistry.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="166" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOTH GUYS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry gestures for Julian to have the first dance. Julian takes Erica's hand and leads her to the dance floor. Harry watches them slip through the crowd. Erica turns back, Harry waves. Julian takes Erica in his arms, it's clear she's comfortable in his embrace. None of .this is lost on Harry and as he watches, the smile on his face more than fades, it evaporates and everything inside him begins to hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Want to dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGLE - THE DANCE FLOOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erica and Julian -- they're sexy together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="167" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops, looks at the mighty city surrounding him. Beauty's not supposed to hurt. Another tear.</context>
      <utterance>At the end of the day, I'm nothin' but a sap, a stupid old sap, standing on a bridge in Paris, crying my eyes out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wipes his eyes on his coat sleeve as SNOW begins to fall.</context>
      <utterance>Look who gets to be the girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else... .</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harry turns and sees Erica standing by a Cab with its motor running, snow falling on her hair and coat.</context>
      <utterance>Harry?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Julian?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He went back to the hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="168" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you have to say about that?</context>
      <utterance>He said when he saw me with you, he knew I was still in love with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's true, my life just got made.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you come here, Harry?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I realized what I was feeling for you, have always felt for you, was something I didn't understand, like a language I didn't speak...  It scared me so I did what I do. I snuck away. Turns out the heart attack was easy to get over. You were somethin' else.  And when I went to see all those women, I found out I was never really present for any of them. And something inside me at some point, had just...shut off. That's when I think my heart gave out and you saved me. I finally get what it's all about. I'm 63 years old and I am in love for the first time in my life. And that's what I came here to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, this is the best birthday ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I'm no spring chicken, I figure I only got another 30-40 years in me. Tops. But how 'bout we figure out a way to make this work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Barge drifts back under the bridge, La Vie En Rose piping out of it's tinny speakers.</context>
      <utterance>Okay? Okay! I'll take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, they're playing our song.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
