<movie id="509" title="Spanglish">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl and woman are enormously excited over this word even though, outside, her life's mate is being loaded into the back of a police car.(Note: Mexican police DO NOT duck the perpetrator's head WHEN LOADING THEM IN THE BACK SEAT..they just allow the concussion.) It seems the mother will save her child the trauma of her father being carted off; but the police turn on their siren and the girl turns to see her father as the car pulls away. The child is stricken. A tear starts to form in her eye. Her mother acts quickly. We are about to see powerful emotion reversed by sheer force of will..the mother leans down, gives three quick kisses - power pecks - to the girl's cheeks and then an admonition in Spanish.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Una lgrima...sola una sola...Haz la mejor possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"One tear..only one...so make it a good one." This was my mother's instruction to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The child is ardent..clutching at her heart...kissing her mother.. Holding her mother's face, talking directly into her eyes. The mother, enormously pleased, is nonetheless thrown by the extremes of it.</context>
      <utterance>Each night my mother promised me a wonderful life.. Each night I looked for a new expressive way to tell my mother how much I loved her.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just played and did my lessons and every time I looked up my mother was in the process of saving us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Desperation in her hands was our weapon.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With this weapon she had her marriage annulled - usually impossible for the poor - and somehow convinced an associate of my father's to transport two Mexicans North in style.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AMERICAN PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they taxi.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. How are you? I am fine..  ..happy, merry, joyful, glad, contented, frisky.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother's prayer for us, which she made me repeat exactly, represented a stunning look into our future. "Please God, let only the bad things change."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OTHER ANGLE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pilot taken with the mother's looks.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMERICAN PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Telephone? Por favor. Por favor.</context>
      <utterance>How can I reach you? Address?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>7.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>appreciation..an errant but decent man awed by the creature he is drawn to..</context>
      <utterance>He glances over..this is not lechery, it is art</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother had redefined her own passions. Blaming herself for the father she gave me, she would never again be lured by a man's rough edges..She had decided that goodness would be her catnip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mother hurries her along in the direction of distant lights.</context>
      <utterance>Texas...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Texas.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raises her fingers like pistols. Shoots, blows in them and reholsters them.</context>
      <utterance>Mam, Texas..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We moved into a place managed by my mother's aunt. My mother worked two jobs in two local stores paying a total of 450 dollars a week...</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..just ever so barely enough.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Please?</context>
      <utterance>Gee whiz in heaven...How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry..I'm not mad...I was looking for decoration to put on the glass so people would stop walking into it and instead of taking what they had in stock, which was awful, I special ordered. I'll design something myself which I should have done in the fi... Our heroine, seeing the blood flow from her aunt's nose, gestures that Monica needs help not conversation.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Shut up, Deborah.</context>
      <utterance>..and what difference does that make when your nose is bleeding.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you got it, Mom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, take these.  Was that strange to give you money..I just felt badly that..</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pockets the cash.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is my niece. She and her daughter live in the apartment I manage. Yolanda, who worked for you, lived there before she went back home. That's how I heard about the job.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So who am I interviewing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On our gal..as she, not understanding the word, smiles and nods.</context>
      <utterance>You're gorgeous.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our gal thrown. Not knowing how now to react.</context>
      <utterance>Vistosos.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She doesn't mean it as a compliment. It's more of an accusation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my daughter Bernice and this is my mother, Evelyn Norwich..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our gal smiles back in appreciation.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me...Glad you're okay.  Good luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, stay..this involves you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't want some kid around for my interview. You understand, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She eyes with disapproval her mother's empty glass.</context>
      <utterance>Strength of character..empathy..big heart..taste for futility - God I love you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>TO OUR GAL - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys want some lemonade?  Let's just talk. I have two children. My husband works nights..he's a chef and has his own place.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you work?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I helped run a commercial design company until ten months ago when</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The two visitors exchange a wide-eyed look. Which Deborah sees and understands.</context>
      <utterance>it was downsized to zip. Okay. I have two children. I like the house to be like me in that I'm very loose and meticulous at the same time. It's all about first names and closeness here but I care about the place, you know. It's what they used to call homemaker..</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad for you that it just never occurred to you to check on how much Spanish I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry what I say about you...don't hold it against her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monica squirms - unusual for her.</context>
      <utterance>I don't speak any Spanish. But I'm not an idiot - I talk for an hour and you say two words. What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As Monica paraphrases what has happened, her translation is DIALED DOWN for the:</context>
      <utterance>Never mind. You got your nose bopped. I got my feelings hurt. Onward.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will major in linguistics and make sociology my sub- concentration. Because it has been my experience that the barriers of</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>15.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NARRATOR  language are more than we dare admit. That, as much as we translate, finally we will never understand each other. My mother's name, for example, beautiful in Spanish, becomes leaden and awful when pronounced by a non-Latin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>IN THE CLEAR</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name? Llamo? One of my five Spanish words..</utterance>
   <speaker>OUR GAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pronounces Flor in the Latin way...lots of RRRR's with a curling of the tongue sound at the end.</context>
      <utterance>Flor Moreno.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pronounces it flat like the "floor" we walk on...throughout the following each of the women sticks to their pronunciation as indicated by the extra "r's.</context>
      <utterance>Flor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Florrrrr.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Florrrrr.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Florrrrr.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Florrrrr.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flor..what I walk on?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA AND EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Florrrrr.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Florrrrr.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means flower, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Flower. Florrrrr.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Florrrrr.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah is beginning to feel criticized...she takes a beat..eyes everyone with some hostility.</context>
      <utterance>Florrrrr.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did she say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She says..If you curl your tongue and let it be loose you will have it..that it's hard for Americans.. She says it's great that you try so hard. Many people wouldn't bother.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at Flor, who returns the smile.</context>
      <utterance>She gets me....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She pours some for Flor and Monica. Then she closes her eyes and pauses in utter dedication to a final effort:</context>
      <utterance>You want some lemonade? Take some lemonade.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>It is perfect..Flor grins at Deborah's victory...claps her hands together.</context>
      <utterance>Florrrrr.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah feels relief..free for a moment from the dark corridors of self-criticism..She is lighter, prettier, innocent..Wholly and completely attractive.</context>
      <utterance>Sublime.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernice rises like a shot to take off..</context>
      <utterance>Whew, dense but stubborn, right? Thanks.  What you just did with me is just what kids need..patience and encouragement. Alright, money...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, really..  Look forward to seeing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monica translates..Flor, embarrassed a bit by the directness, ducks the question..saying in Spanish -- "whatever you say.."</context>
      <utterance>Love you...  ... the job is six days a week, seven to seven..the kids and all housekeeping, how much a week would you like?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.. This is an important question..if you ask for too little it means you don't value</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>18.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor is dumbstruck by the challenge of this pop quiz but not without some native wit and style to maneuver around it.</context>
      <utterance>yourself..too much and you're taking advantage.  So?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah falls for it until Flor laughs..others join...Deborah now a big smile, snort of a laugh, putting her hand to her face and shaking her head.</context>
      <utterance>One thousand dollars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor shoots her a look of fear...a tense beat.</context>
      <utterance>Six hundred dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah kisses her..sort of on the mouth. In the midst of Flor's delight she is thrown by Deborah's kiss...it is the first of many borders to be violated.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the family..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he moves on, we see in the background the workers unwrap and react to a fantastic concoction. A caterer (who we may notice looks at him like royalty) falls in beside him and whispers to him.</context>
      <utterance>I brought some dessert.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATERER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She came down to check on the party and realized the gardeners hadn't finished rolling the sod.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She falls over the roll..getting filthy..but it gives and they gain momentum...one of the catering women falling down, one losing pace.. Deborah,however, gains the upper hand. Yet, even while succeeding, she remonstrates herself.</context>
      <utterance>We can do it. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As she looks at her handiwork - John looks at her..A grin..half laugh.. He loves the dame.</context>
      <utterance>Can you believe they left without finishing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>BREATHLESS - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks great, huh?.... You're not looking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not the answer she wanted..</context>
      <utterance>I was getting a kick looking at you look at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hits a switch at the door and the backyard area is now fully illuminated -- set up for a dinner party for 20 or so....all details thought about and done to a "T". This is the outdoor lighting nobody nails..the twinkling of a half acre..the path to the pool like a runway to heaven. As she looks at it all she has a wistful moment.</context>
      <utterance>I better get dressed again in case anybody's just a half hour late.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay..We're okay here.  Why can't everything be like sod? There's no wait, no dung, nothing you have to do right and yet it's perfect. It covers up all your dirt and makes things immediately pretty..then, the miracle, if you just give it time, it roots and you can't tell it from the real thing.  No reaction. Nothing to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh? Oh sure..I, uh..Well, no, I don't have anything particular to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somewhat crushed, she prepares to exit.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, John why don't you just take out a knife and kill me all together.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you get there..Hey, wait a minute..Deb..stop..come on.  I'd like to figure this one out. What would have been the great thing for me to say after you said the sod sentence?..Really.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's actually a good question.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There you go. I surprise sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would have liked, if after I compared the sod to life, if you had said, "Exactly!" She turns to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. But to say that and mean it I'd have to think the same way you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's worth a try...I had something else to tell you...it'll come to me..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor says something to her in Spanish..the daughter waves it off and when the mother persists, she translates.</context>
      <utterance>Could we have a table for two, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're celebrating.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOSTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before her daughter can translate.</context>
      <utterance>Smoking or non-smoking?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hostess laughs..They are seated at the two ends of a banquette and each automatically picks up her place setting and "scootches" closely together. Cristina picks up a menu and points to the prices.</context>
      <utterance>Dancing!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, expensive..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Flor, encouraging her daughter's spirit of adventure, places her hand over the prices in the menu.</context>
      <utterance>This is just for the starter?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOSTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The daughter translates...the hostess points out the early 30's, well dressed, quite nice looking businessmen. Flor addresses the men who are several tables away. Cristina moves uncomfortably but responds to her mother's nudge to translate.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh..And those men would like to buy you a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I would like to begin with the Jumbo Shrimp.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay...think SERIOUSLY about getting up. You don't have to get up yet but are you thinking seriously about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Georgie gets up..</context>
      <utterance>Yes..actual up..</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John pauses..aware his answer will have repercussions but integrity wins.</context>
      <utterance>You as mad at me as Mom 'cause of what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Georgie, I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you mad at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...okay, no..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning, good to see you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She notices the French Toast.</context>
      <utterance>Morning. Good too.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She demurs. Bernice holds out one slice on a spatula, indicating Flor should just tear a piece off which she does...One taste and she marvels -- her mouth dropping open at this kid's ability to make something mundane special..Bernice laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Try some.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Her mother enters on her way upstairs. She is thoughtful, tense and sweaty - her run having failed to exorcise her current demon. She greets Flor and then shakes her head, making a vain attempt to communicate her troubled mood to Flor in some sort of sisterhood based on life being a fucker.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernice prepares a plate for her mom while, in the b.g., a GOLDEN RETRIEVER named CHUM approaches Flor from behind with a ball in its mouth. Flor is checking out the kitchen... what's in each drawer, etc .....Deborah is impressed by the self-starter display and indicates same to Bernice.</context>
      <utterance>Tough day.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had an idea for a breakthrough in French toast so I made breakfast. I don't want to be teased about it.. No sarcasm. No tough love. Just try it and if by any chance you have a positive reaction...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right..mean ol' me. I can't play right now. I have to do something about your brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does..</context>
      <utterance>I had an idea for a recipe. When has that happened? I got up early to do this. At least taste it, for God's sakes!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's good...oh God, it's rich -- Oh God, it's good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>TO FLOR - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Chum is nudging Flor with the ball and Flor was about to accommodate him by taking it before Deborah's warning shout stopped her in mid-sentence.</context>
      <utterance>NO..NO! FLOR!....Never do fetch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ON Flor's stunned reaction to the outburst.</context>
      <utterance>I mean it, NEVER!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Then using her hands to demonstrate.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not mad. I'm thinking of you. This is me being nice..</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>CLOSE UP ON Chum going nuts with Deborah's hand passing in front of his face ignoring how urgently he offers the ball.</context>
      <utterance>Just no taking ball from dog.  Trust me on that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You and me. We are fine. Just a tip.  Girlfriends.  Could you make some coffee? Cafe?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah directs her to the most complicated cappuccino machine Italian overpriced artists ever devised.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't an argument, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes it is. So stop being so maniacally calm.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No..it's not. Because I understand your side.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah turns from the sink revealing one brown eye and one blue. She blinks, realizes one lens is not in and turns back to the sink.</context>
      <utterance>I can't be wrong about that too. This is a fight. We're having a fight. Yo, I feel anger.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>John exits into the..</context>
      <utterance>Can I have a moment?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>started doing. It's like this is your way of letting me know there's something deeply wrong with me because I'm not calm.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's not go all over the place..Can't we...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're going to talk to me please have the decency to raise your voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's make a break for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He signals her with his eyes and head and then takes a large but tentative step away from the spot where he was standing...then additional faster steps. He gestures with enormous energy for her to follow him to his new spot in the room. She eyes him suspiciously.</context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks to him...he puts an arm around her shoulder. And gestures back to where they were standing. He talks in an almost hushed, conspiratorial voice.</context>
      <utterance>Just for a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have to be those people. Nobody's watching. They've been masquerading as us for a while here..I'll distract them - you make a break for it and I'll meet you outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're ridiculing me because I care about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm not. I mean this..let's get away from those two in case they're as miserable as they look..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is looking at her with wit and conviction..trying to squirt lighter fluid at the flame of their love. Deborah looks up at him..intimacy of a different sort.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you a question..let me change the subject..Forget for a moment that you won't support me with Georgie..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She makes a noise of frustration to stop him..It works. John is rendered still and intimidated by her conduct but he is "man" enough for his jaw to set...to pause for a beat as he looks her straight in the eye..And walks back to the spot they occupied previously.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't think...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's the question. It's been on my mind more and more. Do you do that calm thing for the purpose of infuriating me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Why would ...  Why would anyone do something to someone they love for the purpose of messing them up?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hates that look of isolation on her face..He needs to make her feel better.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deb, since high school we've been able to read each other...take advantage of it..The answer to the question is,"absolutely not." Now take a look and tell me if you believe me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boy meets girl.</context>
      <utterance>Great God in heaven save me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns with a start to see Flor smiling at him. Gorgeous squared. His first word is inadvertent.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa...whoa...I didn't know Deborah had found someone... You work here? You're going to help with the house and kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Solo espaol.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of feet on the stairs..Deborah and Georgie enter.</context>
      <utterance>You work here and you don't speak any English at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All she has to do is dial 9-1-1 and press two for Spanish.  Flor...John.  This is Flor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah reacts, grabs some coffee and pushes Georgie along.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Flor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'll take Georgie to school.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor is trying to figure out what's expected of her then Deborah gestures impatiently for her to fall into step and come with her.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm doing it..show Flor the ropes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sniffles. Flor nods uncertainly. A small voice from the back seat..Georgie..</context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' hombres, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just didn't want to sing last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he's just two lines into an old blues standard:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Well you said you would..You said you wanted to. I asked you five times. Then when I have the whole party paying attention you refused. As she puts the car in gear...Georgie sings insanely well.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She presses a button on her dash and a glass partition comes up between front and back seat thereby cutting him off in mid- song. Flor is utterly baffled by the notion of putting a divider between parent and child. But Deborah is calling for her to pay attention to the car's navigation screen.. a Spanish voice says, "route guidance system starting."</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't do any good now, Georgie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The MALE SPANISH VOICE talks about imminent left turns. Flor is thrown by the amount of oddness..All the while Georgie is singing his little heart out in the back seat. Flor,amused by the boy, suppresses a smile...maybe the first time in her life she's had to suppress joy. But Deborah never misses anything.</context>
      <utterance>I've programmed it for Spanish.. Look, it will take you anywhere and then back home. If you figured out how to make coffee on that thing it's all downhill.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>TO FLOR - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is stop gap..You, kiddo, you're going to have to learn English.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the best place to stand, fella.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's me. You're the new helper, huh..</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two people head for John almost simultaneously. PEG, an arty looking woman in her late 50's..wild, scraggly gray hair, enters lugging an ice chest and the maitre d'.</context>
      <utterance>No..no..it's okay. It's me being bugged.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Maitre D' enters.</context>
      <utterance>You are going to be so happy..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAITRE D'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John makes a no-brainer of a decision pointing to the woman who promised happiness. She hefts her ice chest up on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>I have something very important to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fish is that special, a sentence that kicks out for a writer, the right brush stroke for an artist. You get it..</context>
      <utterance>Perfect cod this is John -- John, perfect cod..Best one I've seen all season and he was swimming twenty minutes ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid nods.. he picks up the fish.</context>
      <utterance>Knockout.  You want to learn something? You want to pack it away?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cradle it...Put it in the cooler but not on its side.. In the same position it swims.  And check the ice pack..make sure it can drain away..if it can't the chlorine can hurt the flesh. Do all that and nobody can put a fish in the fridge better than you...and that's a solid start.. First day and you already did something perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAITRE D'</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He whispers in John's ear..</context>
      <utterance>Oh, sorry..I forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn.. "ohhhh damn."</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, buddy, what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Victor spotted a food critic..</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The New York Times..I'll bet they sent her out just for us.  Here's what she ordered.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, if you're nervous take a walk..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need a walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>GWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll walk with you..I know a breathing thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to prepare for cooking.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think I'm worried about... how I'll cook? That's not the problem..  The lady wants fish. Get the fish.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I worked in a kitchen once in New York that got four stars. It was like a line formed for the chance to become an asshole. People's accents changed. The heart went out of the place. You understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I agree with everything you've said. I admire you for your feelings. I hope to adopt them as my own....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>34.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is talking quickly..almost to himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tastes a sliver of the food dish he is preparing.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what to root for.. the thought of one star makes me nauseous..but with four there's no place to go but, "Oh my God, they took away a star."  Three..three and a half. That's what you want..No. Wrong! Three and a half you feel disappointed that you just missed out on four. You know what you want? Three and a quarter..  That would be perfect!!  It would mean you're good..but you're not good enough to feel disappointed that you just missed out on excellent..but nothing truly bad happened, you still got your three and a quarter stars. Which encourages you to try and improve..And you still get enough respect so that you can get good people to work with you..Business is good but not crazy. You're right there underneath the radar where you get to mind your own business. That's a solid life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, man..this is amazing. No three and a quarter here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Spoken to directly like this, Flor is confused..</context>
      <utterance>God Bless the language barrier, it keeps you from being bored with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, she said, "aren't you Evelyn Wright?" First of all, that she recognized me from the old covers and then she .... Oh, please her name..it makes the story so much better...She said,  "Whenever I think everything is.."  Pardon my French..pardon her French  "a mother hmmmhmmm...I put on one of your records.."</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn looks transparently vulnerable for a second. Flor reacts. Bernie squeezes her grandmother's hand..Flor smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Awwww. How sweet....</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah enters, carrying a load of packages. With lightning speed, her eye picks out...the glass her mother is drinking from.</context>
      <utterance>Just such a lovely thing to come from the blue....</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mother...It's not even noon.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's almost two o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, where is this day going...Flor could you come with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grandma, tell Mom what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is going to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Free your mind...the president whose policies many consider responsible for the Great Depression...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name a vacuum cleaner..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Yes..thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this vacuum whooshed all this money out of everyone's pockets.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it. I no longer know nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Hoover was followed in office by..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just drawing blanks. I'm embarrassed. It's my own fault I spent my time on math, which I'm lucky if I don't flunk anyway and..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The guy we are looking for is not a ruse..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's ruse mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phony. So this president was not a ruse..He was the real thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ruse??</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah enters followed by Flor. They are carrying several boxes of clothes...</context>
      <utterance>Rusevelt..If I'd ever heard of the word before - that would lock it in..It's so stupid it might work anyway...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernie gasps..As she looks at a sweater..</context>
      <utterance>Surprise new clothes..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd I do right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernice tries on the sweater over her T-shirt..and mirth ends..The sweater is tight...Bernice picks up a blouse and then skirt and checks the size.</context>
      <utterance>Warehouse sale..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor tries to slide by..Something surreptitious in her behavior..Deborah suddenly turns to Flor.</context>
      <utterance>She's right between the two sizes..I thought about it..what am I supposed to do encourage her...what is it? - DENIAL? Or motivate her to get herself in shape.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She holds out her hand in a "we women understand" gesture. Flor does not waver..just meets her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Flor..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me puedo ir?..go..can go?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that fast they are gone.</context>
      <utterance>I'll drive you to the bus stop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I'm cracking. As he moves back to his side of the vehicle.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Flor hears this from inside and nods in agreement.</context>
      <utterance>Shiiiiiiit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Flor is flabbergasted..she peeks to see if he is actually crying. At first her heart is touched by John but then there is distinct disapproval (a real roll of the eyes) that the macho meter can read that low. He looks at her and she faces front quickly.</context>
      <utterance>But you know, you gotta watch out for the times you think you're absolutely right..But, man, Bernice has finals tomorrow. She didn't need this one..And just that look on her face when she got the gifts--  --like for a second she thought all her problems with her mother had been solved...</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, he has stopped for traffic near the end of the canyon. Flor takes the opportunity to bolt.</context>
      <utterance>My mother did not understand her male boss. His heart was good and he was rare in not flirting with her. But they were starkly different. Privacy and dignity were the same word to my mother. Naturally, when she found herself sitting next to a man who cried over his child's hurt she had no idea how to process the event.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the door and starts to get out though the car is still rolling a bit...</context>
      <utterance>Gracias.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly she re-enters the car..It rolls another ten feet to her bus stop and she gets out again.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? Let me take you all the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How weird was this ride? Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't quite know what that means...indicates same in a little helpless gesture..</context>
      <utterance>No es nada.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor asks her daughter how to say something in English.</context>
      <utterance>It was so unusual for my mother to ask my help that I realized immediately she was losing her battle to be uninvolved with the Claskys.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor asks again in Spanish...trying to find a precise phrase.. The nuance important to her.</context>
      <utterance>Try it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Flor knows the word "please"..it's not what she wants...what she wants is a way to say, "try it on" in a manner which is not a request..or order, but is, rather, friendly and caring. Her daughter works on the problem.</context>
      <utterance>Please try it on?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just try it on?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just try it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just try it on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's got it.</context>
      <utterance>Just try it on...just try it on..</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our culture embraces fullness in a woman. You, the women of the admissions committee, as intelligent as you are, have no idea how casual and complete such acceptance is back home, in the land of the size 16 bikini.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON FLOR..</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As she strides purposefully up the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is one of the cultural differences between us which I wish to explore academically at Princeton. American women, I believe, actually feel the same as Hispanic women about weight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And then passes.</context>
      <utterance>Left.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...dieting, exercising American women become afraid of everything associated with being curvaceous, such as wantonness, lustfulness, sex, food, motherhood..all that is good in life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor holds up the new clothes and indicates that they are beautiful.</context>
      <utterance>Hey..buenas dias, Flor..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Bernie starts her morning routine..her back to us when:</context>
      <utterance>Yes..Well, taste she has..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just try it on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!!!! When did you learn to...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just try it on..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor clearly doesn't understand..</context>
      <utterance>Too tight..it doesn't fit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor extends a blouse and skirt.</context>
      <utterance>Just try it on..Hey?!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps behind a closet door to try the clothes on, muttering pessimistically before she does so. CAMERA STAYS ON</context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'll show you..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chum, momentarily depressed, walks away..Bernie enters. She is a bit overwhelmed -- her voice breaking a bit even with one word.</context>
      <utterance>Lo siento. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor turns..Bernie moves to embrace her.</context>
      <utterance>Hey..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every time he has a nightmare, I teach him one of my old songs. That way the nightmares have a purpose.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't have to sing it for anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. You're clear on that..</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many did you sell of this song?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He likes to know that stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was huge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am okay.  Deborah around?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John nods and heads upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>She run.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Georgie enters the scene..</context>
      <utterance>No..nothing...just that..</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A kid offered me a trade..Let me show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>46.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He starts to follow him to his room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad!!! He can wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No..It's okay..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him wait..Yours is obviously important.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't even know how important the trade is..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her the newspaper...</context>
      <utterance>Let me just do Georgie.... Here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says he'll give me any three silvers for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Note: this is an involved discussion on both their parts..NOTHING in John thinks it is trivial.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know...This is the one you started with..You really want to give up your first card?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know..that's why I needed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..this is your favorite..</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he'd go higher.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are interrupted by a never quite heard before sound of exultation..</context>
      <utterance>But it's not numbers..it's.....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For God's sake..why did you...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>WHY?!!? CRAZY FATHER, WHY?!? Why aren't YOU screaming?..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting there..just the stunned thing has to get dealt with...</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John Clasky, who at 25 made his mark on the New York restaurant scene when JAMMED lived up to and survived its silly name, has re- emerged as a young and confident veteran taking chances with his combinations in so subtle a manner.."</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he gave me six...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn indicates to Flor that the good news is about John..and so she studies him a bit..</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, your sister's talking.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tears up...Evelyn rubs Bernie's back..looks at Flor and taps her heart...Flor indicates she should leave and does. Bernice continues reading with a lovely sense of mission and moment. John is taken with his daughter's delivery.</context>
      <utterance>"...beginning with the succession of appetizers, each one with its own stunning and fully realized agenda, is constantly yet casually daring."  Ah, Dad...this is so great...  Now here's the thing...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Eating at this perfect smaller, passionate restaurant inspires one's own abandonment of caution. To wit: John Clasky is the best chef in the United States."</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look how great you read it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn and Bernice hug him..</context>
      <utterance>Perfect, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John..John...Oh, my God you even look different to me....</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder what mom will do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rips at her own clothes and then exclaims in passion.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooohhch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow..."John Clasky es el mejor chef en Los Estados Unidos..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, bravo...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Deb?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He scoots to her side.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I guess I got used to you getting a little blue after intercourse...But DURING..??</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs something and starts walking toward the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Something else I do wrong.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've gotta stop walking away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I stay, I will say awful things to you that I might not even mean..You pick.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits to the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>See ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman tells Flor how to say it in English.</context>
      <utterance>Yo le la crtica buena.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He nods..still the light doesn't change.</context>
      <utterance>I read your good review.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The light changes.</context>
      <utterance>It's nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The light has changed - cars are beeping..she is about to let him go off but realizes he will wait for her answer.</context>
      <utterance>Not so far...How you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods and drives off.</context>
      <utterance>I do fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I stop answering? We're booked for two months solid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no, no, no....I want to keep some walk-in business..I want this to stay neighborhood.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impossible. There would be riots..You should hear the desperation in their voices..Best day of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll serve a full menu at the bar then.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then where do I put the people waiting for a table? It won't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do this for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do this for me or I'll set my hair on fire and start punching myself in the face.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah..you're right...that was an unusual way for me to make myself understood..But you'll do the bar thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course, John..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk into the cooling room.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, man..Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up? What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've gotten a fantastic offer for my own place..Everybody wants to back me since the paper came out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your reaction?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honestly? Because I've had this very unusual reaction.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've had a hard on almost all day and it won't go away. Like I'm riding on the back seat of a bus with bad shocks and every other passenger is a gorgeous woman with a yellow sports top whose leaning over. It's like every dream I ever had and some even I didn't have the balls to dream..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're considering taking it?...  Okay, here's the thing. I can't lose you and still keep the hours I'm keeping. I can't do my life unless I can hold onto you.  I think I just gave you an incredible bargaining position.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you gave away twenty percent of the restaurant without talking to me about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. If I didn't do it - I'd have been coming home just to sleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember the other day when you asked me the perfect response to something I said?...I'm asking you now..what would you like my response to be to your giving away twenty percent of the business without asking me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"You're ma man!"</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay! So that would be???</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dream response from you, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not quite there..Actually, I just had this flash that the reason women in the old days used to faint was to avoid doing acts of violence against men.  And I was all worried about figuring out the timing just to talk to you about renting a place for the summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I think you got your timing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>REALTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they pull away...</context>
      <utterance>I'm Mike..there's one great rental that just came on..so we're starting at the top..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll never be one of those girls whose hair blows perfectly in a convertible.</utterance>
   <speaker>REALTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Puzzled, she uses the electric lever and the seat budges forward..</context>
      <utterance>Move your seat forward..</utterance>
   <speaker>REALTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Realtor uses his switches and raises his window a bit..her window a bit less and monkeys the position of the half windows in back...Deborah turns around checking out the odd tweaking and then faces forward. Her hair blows perfectly and beautifully behind her...</context>
      <utterance>A little more..just..good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On his small laugh...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you must be trouble.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gorgeous, huh..Pretty, fabulous, beautiful. What word is the same in Spanish?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fabuloso.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She leads Flor to a small bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care if it's a rental..this place is getting a fixing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Flor doesn't understand..certainly doesn't want to.</context>
      <utterance>This will be yours..</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ask her if she could live in?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah uses her hand as if weighing something momentous like the law vs. the bible then with heavy sarcasm.</context>
      <utterance>Come on...there's no buses from her to here. There's no question. Double come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>When Flor gives no indication of anything - just standing, somewhat stupefied..Deborah takes her by the hand and leads her out.</context>
      <utterance>The Barrio - Carbon Beach..The Barrio - Carbon Beach. What to do?  Don't worry. I'm putting nicer stuff in here too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must learn English. Why won't she learn English? I'm going to have to learn, "you must learn English," in Spanish.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Flor is perfect and we should do all we can to keep her from changing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, you took the words right out of my mouthay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, good. Do you speak English?</utterance>
   <speaker>HISPANIC MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Flor..my God.</context>
      <utterance>Would you translate for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HISPANIC MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He speaks to her in Spanish..a lavish, poetic compliment. Flor, in full control, says, in Spanish.."Would you please just find out what she wants." Evelyn joins them.</context>
      <utterance>Sure...forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He translates along with Deborah's speech.</context>
      <utterance>Wait till I say something before you start in..  I rented a house here for the summer and now she must sleep at the house because of the bus schedule.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor talks briefly in Spanish.</context>
      <utterance>What? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>HISPANIC MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She can't because of her daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a daughter? You have a whole daughter you haven't mentioned..How old?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man translates.</context>
      <utterance>It's a little crazy that I don't know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The man says in Spanish to Flor.."You work for her?"--Flor answers, "just tell her that I can't live here." Deborah doesn't like that the man has initiated more conversation.</context>
      <utterance>Don't translate asides.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>HISPANIC MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She can't live here. Her daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man tells Flor..she answers directly to Deborah..</context>
      <utterance>Okay..  Her daughter can also live with us for the summer..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man asks Flor who speaks in Spanish..</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>HISPANIC MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. She just doesn't want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you please just tell me what she said.</utterance>
   <speaker>HISPANIC MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said, "I just don't want to."</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she didn't tell us about her child she has to have a deep sense of privacy. We can figure out how she can still live at home. Hell, I don't mind driving her at night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hispanic man translates the last sentence. Deborah and Flor stare at each other..Deborah's next words are somber and have enough body language to transcend the need for translation...the jig is up.</context>
      <utterance>Let's spare the world you on the roads.  Well, what do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Flor indicates there is no need to translate. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, my friend, this is what I need. It's just for the summer. I don't want to lose you. But ....</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo vivo aqu.</utterance>
   <speaker>HISPANIC MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man says something in Spanish to Flor as she starts to walk away and she is thrown enough by the statement to actually stumble as she looks back at him...then, before Deborah can admonish him.</context>
      <utterance>She'll live here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HISPANIC MAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, "God protect you from that boss."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dog goes crazy with excitement -- then, droll for a nine year old, Georgie turns to his grandmother (who is sunning herself and reading) and addresses her in precisely the same way. Evelyn has a drink in hand..</context>
      <utterance>Who wants to go swimming?..Yes, who wants to go swimming?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who wants to go swimming?..Huh..</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John enters the scene..</context>
      <utterance>Not now..But I promise I'll go in the summer after next.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to go swimming?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, you're off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think, wet suits?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wet suits are for wimps..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Georgie laughs..</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you're right..let me get mine..</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this child..Flor, you could make a fortune at surrogate pregnancy.... Flor looks to her daughter for some understanding of what Deborah said..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cristina is as nonplussed by the remark as her mother.</context>
      <utterance>Que?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm John..It's good to see you.  Great..</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. This is my daughter, Bernice..I'm Deborah..And out there...are Georgie and.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad to meet you. I'm a fan of your mother's.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As all acknowledge each other Deborah tugs at Bernie's top which is half tucked in.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Cristina.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>deprecation..Flor says something to her daughter in Spanish.</context>
      <utterance>No comparisons, please, no comparisons. Evelyn shoves her granddaughter for the self-</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother says it's best if we get out of the way and put our things away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever been to the beach here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John goes to a big toy box and opens it up..it is filled with beach paddles, Frisbees and boogie boards.</context>
      <utterance>I've never been anyplace but Mexico and Texas.....before today.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's the most important place in the house..grab this stuff whenever you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you..thank you so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very little accent?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Que?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sin acento.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cristina..</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Settle in..</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I am thrilled to be here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cristina looks around -- then up..</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Cristina...hey...hey..What are you doing up?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hi..so beautiful..I was just excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know..Would you believe I had to talk my husband into this?  Would you believe I had to talk my husband into it?...do you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...I just ..  I didn't know what to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to come with me? -- I'm going to the flea market.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what that...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the Rose Bowl... miles, actual miles, of great things for sale for God's sake...We can have brunch in Pasadena.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to wake my mother so early.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll leave her a note...I'll</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes to Cristina's bed...atop the bed is a note. She picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Cristina?</utterance>
   <speaker>INSERT..THE NOTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear Flor,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop thanking me. I love having the company.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was an adventure which I'll remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your English is genius. Do you dream in Spanish or English?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just recently I've had a dream in English.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am so sorry. I -- uh..I'd ..I uh, can't tell ..This is so uncomfortable.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could have just said you didn't remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, uh, guess so..but I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look who's sensational.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shows her the letter. Evelyn reads it and hands it back..She is about to offer something..Flor waves it off and enters the house..John comes in from the beach with his kids..boogie boards...Evelyn hands him the letter..</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>John moves after Flor as Bernie reads the letter..</context>
      <utterance>She's wild-eyed over this..</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, shit..  Sorry about the word, Georgie.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to know what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns..</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Flor..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He indicates his watch -- then holds his fingers together.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry..very sorry..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Flor starts to cry. She sits in a chair..He sits not far from her.</context>
      <utterance>They should be back soon..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Embarrassed, she says, in Spanish, to please leave her alone..she turns from him..He walks to the wet bar and gets a bottle of water...pours some..Her crying soft in the</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Flor..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He pats her on the back..She looks at him..</context>
      <utterance>Deborah made a mistake. I understand how you feel...Do you understand me at all, generally? Is simptico the word?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON FLOR..</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he coming on?..</utterance>
   <speaker>HER POV..</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His kind eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And when he seeks to add another pat, he misses, because she is out of her chair..(This is as intimate as John has been with another woman since he was married..) He calls out to stop her.</context>
      <utterance>Simptico, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops and turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>Un momento, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He taps his heart as an indication of sincerity -- then a flash of worry that he has inadvertently come on to her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm really sorry this is happening. I just want you to know that. I am real sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He makes a gesture of ardent love..</context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Makes a person to person innocent gesture..She finds herself smiling.</context>
      <utterance>I meant..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Something bad happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cristina, tell your mother I just played around with your hair..she can put it back..no hurt feelings.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor puts an arm around her shoulder, leading her off and speaking to her forcefully in Spanish.</context>
      <utterance>Not right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? --</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't just take someone else's.....</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn stops on a dime. She leaves. Deborah crosses to Bernice, who is highly concerned about Flor, and puts an arm around her. A pleasant surprise..</context>
      <utterance>Nuh-uh, Mom..don't go there..or I'll go there and you know where "there" is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAD WRITING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cannot take my child without my permission..And, if you had asked me I would not have given permission. Is this why you did not ask? Because you knew this. You have no rights over my private life.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you have any disagreement with this, I no longer wish to work here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor with enormous emphasis stabs her finger at her own chest.</context>
      <utterance>From?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Deborah exits to a bathroom and closes the door...leaving Flor in the hall with the letter..Cristina reveals herself and explains the situation to her mother. The last word we hear before scene's end is "maana."</context>
      <utterance>You are not yourself...This was written in anger. You sleep on it and then if you still want me to have it -- fine..I don't think you will once calm and rational thought returns. Just sleep on it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't even want us to know she had a daughter - then, on the first day, you take the kid without asking. I think that's...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Irresponsible? Perverse? Dizzy?</context>
      <utterance>What!?! Insensitive? Elitist?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him...He has been atypical...Her immediate emotional cocktail is panic, fury and deep, deep hurt. Her words are slow...her voice ragged...</context>
      <utterance>Dumb.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's over!! So get on board.</context>
      <utterance>When is anyone in this damn house or this damn life going to consider my feelings? I just tried to make a lovely kid feel welcome. There's no reason to rake it over...I let it go..and gave Flor the room to let it go. Which I'm sure she has!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am deeply and sincerely sorry to have upset you. Especially in light of the deep connection, as women, I believe us to have.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And to think I was worried about Flor living here with her kid?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out some sea glass.</context>
      <utterance>So here's the idea..I want to make a serving platter for serving fish using sea glass like this..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to hunt for this stuff every free minute when I apprenticed in Italy. This is bits of broken glass that the ocean sand blasts over the years..great looking, huh? So you guys go hunting and I'll pay 50 cents for any piece, a dollar for anything as big as this and five dollars for any color that isn't brown, clear or green.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we have to do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Georgie and Bernice start off..</context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CRISTINA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up and steps around to where she is...there is a battered wood table along the side of the house.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She overturns a large bucket and a small mountain of sea glass spills on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Hi..what's doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm broke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No..you don't have to pay..I'm sorry. Don't worry, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm kidding..Instead of a platter -- I'll just build a sea glass building and serve fish inside... Great, Cristina..Why don't you count it and..</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have... Many times..I didn't sleep. I counted.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes locked on his.</context>
      <utterance>So what's the damage...total?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes them from her pocket.</context>
      <utterance>It depends on whether you consider these four a color other than green, brown or clear..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this one is borderline.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, you found a blue..Nobody finds a blue..You know how a blue happens? I mean, before the ocean blasts it for 30-40 years. Somebody had to throw away an old Milk of Magnesia bottle. You know what Milk of Magnesia is?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles broadly. The kid's a trip. He likes her.</context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how much for the whole deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reacts..then..</context>
      <utterance>Eleven hundred and one dollar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I talk to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cristina nods...not comfortable breaking the rule of only speaking for her mother...She faces him, her back to Flor.</context>
      <utterance>You mean your mother....</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cristina begins translating as her mother speaks in Spanish..</context>
      <utterance>Sure you can talk to me..</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to sleep first?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor waves the money..Cristina waves an empty hand as she speaks for her mother.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you give this money to my daughter?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made this little deal..with all the kids to...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor advances on him past her daughter so Cristina now translates from the background.</context>
      <utterance>Please..</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't tell or ask the mother when you give a child a fortune for looking on the beach for stones..what is the word for this..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On hearing the translation of "sea glass" an exasperated Flor turns so that her back is to John as Cristina admonishes him.</context>
      <utterance>Sea glass?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No..not a name for the stones..a name for the act..what you did..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Engredo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes half a beat..finds the word and now spits it out.</context>
      <utterance>It's hard to translate.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John gets up and takes a conciliatory step toward Flor so that now Cristina is in the middle looking up at them as she translates for John</context>
      <utterance>Smug.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had no idea it would amount to that kind of money..I thought --- sort of tops fifty dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty dollars is a lot of money..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has no idea where to take it from here -- the two females look as he searches for the right thing to say..</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>That fast Cristina translates.. Before Flor can react. John talks directly to Flor..quiet,compassionate, a bit beaten.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, shit..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Flor lets it out...her daughter hard pressed to keep up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry....I get why you are upset. It might not look it but I am good at getting things. Doing something about it is something else..I was going to talk to you before I actually gave her the money..but maybe I should have checked before I started the whole thing.  I know what it's like when you feel your kid is being messed with..I get the message. It won't happen again. It's late..I'm sure we'd all like...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor hands John the envelope under her daughter's wrenching gaze. They begin to exit..but Flor turns inadvertently bumping into her daughter. Her voice softens.</context>
      <utterance>To what..sleep? If this was small enough to be helped by some little apology, I would be a fool to bring it up..I need to say more no matter what the result. I need to be impolite. You leave someone else's child alone. It's simple, no? It is too easy for children to feel contradictions..It encourages questioning their parents..and that makes them less safe. Your wife takes her for rides and changes her hair..You give her money. Here..  Take back the money????????????</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They turn to leave. John speaks with sudden volume and muscle.</context>
      <utterance>I did not mean to be angry to you - only emotional..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cristina turns back..confused..her mother asks her for a translation and she complies.. Flor then wearing the same confused expression.</context>
      <utterance>What about hypocritical?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you heard me. It's not like you didn't do the same thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor is confused and getting pissed but he is moving now and pointing a finger at her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. So go lecture yourself..you won't need a translator for that one...I mean what am I lately... A recycling bin?..just anyone dump in your garbage and hope I make something useful out of it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>translate..but doesn't get one..Instead her mother is a bit mortified and considerably humbled..the pie smack into the face.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, you did the same thing...you think I didn't know about altering those outfits for Bernie..She tells me her stuff....So, am I missing something? Is there a real difference between that and what you are complaining about? Cristina waits for a comeback from her mother to</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sin diferencia. Yo interfer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No difference. I interfered.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay......I'm still not sure I did the right thing keeping it to myself. It felt disloyal to Deborah..but my daughter really needed someone to be kind to her right then..so..so.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am very embarrassed. You are very right. Hypocrisy..yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you, it's pretty wild to say something and have the other person just concede the point. I'm dazed here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will leave whenever it is good for you and...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No..no..come on, man..</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how can I work for you after we talk like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't quit even if you want to and you know why.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor is worried as John looks right at her..Is he coming on?</context>
      <utterance>Yes, you do..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cristina doesn't have to check with her mother on this one.</context>
      <utterance>Because then Cristina will blame herself for costing you the job...and that guilt...I don't know if you know about guilt..</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Culpa, guilt, s. We know. We are Catholics.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Culpa, si..Por Dios, Si.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John gestures that there is nothing to be done. Flor nods.</context>
      <utterance>We know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles..gets up..extends her hand..they shake.</context>
      <utterance>So, welcome back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night, Mr. Clasky..</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night As they exit..their backs to John, daughter following mother...Flor speaks to her daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No te puedo tener haciendo esto por mi. Ahora tengo que aprender ingls.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA AS FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I must learn English now.</context>
      <utterance>I can't have you doing this for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That translates to "No, I meant that for you, not John." But Cristina does not translate the line. Nor..</context>
      <utterance>No, dije eso por ti - no por John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a wonderful mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Que?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nada.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waves it off and hurries to get her tape and get out of his way. Chum complicates the task, proffering the ball. Flor wearily throws it.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta do something about Chum..Your arm's going to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you sleep anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No..You get more if you keep at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're doing fantastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Your wife go out.</context>
      <utterance>Now I am like a three year-old.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She say where?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He staggers out. Flor watches his lonely back for a beat and then urgently gestures Chum to join him. Chum is reluctant, but relenting, runs and accompanies his appreciative master. Flor, now alone, finds herself staring at a framed picture of John in the den. He is younger and smiling. She studies the picture and then blinks when she realizes her own emotion and purposefully goes back to her lessons.</context>
      <utterance>Listen..I just forgot she was going out..don't be a smart ass.  Uh-oh..well, you and I communicate mostly in apologies anyway..I'm sorry. I should be whipped. I should be stoned- it's been a while - I meant to say, I think, don't be smart, don't be kind, don't be sensitive, don't be beautiful. I meant to say, "hi, Flor, good night Flor..that show you're watching is going to be a hit."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you get your mother to let you go with my mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernice nods. Then unconsciously moans.</context>
      <utterance>Well, your mother just said she could use my help on a few errands while you're in class...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Just that I hate summer school.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you go then?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure I can explain to you the concept of not doing well in a class..in this case math...and the system kind of insists on the illusion that you've learned math -- so they make you go to summer school..It helps them avoid facing that they have failed in their mission.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean they failed?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joking.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. I see. Forgive me, I don't have a real sense of humor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, God.  Joking...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The joke is?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah can't think of what single thing Bernice could possibly feel superior about. She is genuinely puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>That you're better at everything than I am...and I was thanking God for there being this one thing where I might have my nose in front.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernice deeply resents the question..She turns to her mother.</context>
      <utterance>And that thing is???</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cristina laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Sexual experience..</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at you girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cristina's already read, on her own, everything on Bernice's summer reading list..And she's two grades behind..Imagine if she went to Bernice's school..And they'd kill to give her a scholarship.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk to Flor...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah..she's so open to new things.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't find my keys.. Another woman, ARLENE FOLSOM, calls to her..</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deborah...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk to greet Arlene.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Arlene..  Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. This is Cristina..the girl I'm always raving about..This is Arlene Folsom..the school director.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi..</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah smiles with pride at the elegant first impression Cristina is making..all are grinning...the two adults suspiciously so...sharing their delight.</context>
      <utterance>Hello..a pleasure to meet you, Ms. Folsom. I couldn't believe how beautiful the grounds were as we drove in. I just think the balance of the buildings to open ground is so wonderful and must have been very difficult to achieve.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARLENE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like a little tour?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nuh-uh, Flor you are not pinning this one on me. I've got to finish packing up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just don't....Out of space this school wants her to go for free?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ran into the school head. They want diversity...Cristina knocked her out...I had nothing to do with it. By the way, the scholarship is worth twenty thousand dollars. And early registration is tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is too far from our home.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could move in with us in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never, thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, then don't..By the way..the phrase is "NO, thank you."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, dear God..Enter my mother's heart and make her understand what this school would mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. I look.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Flor, want some port?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thank you, Evelyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for never judging me..Love you. Love everybody. That's what's killing me.. Sleep well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?  Deborah will be home soon. I just talked to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John does not answer immediately. The brief pause is noted.</context>
      <utterance>I need real talk..Is it okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outside? Private?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances back, hoping to have his fears assuaged, they are not.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.....  You have me a little worried...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know about Cristina and your great school?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's happened. Is it driving you nuts?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, nuts. I have no idea what to do. Such an important thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a good school?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tops. It's tops.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you like it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I hate the damn school. But that's because they keep sending my daughter home anxiety-ridden, mostly over geometry..I mean you "get" Bernice..In a decent world her school should let her know how great she is, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, don't ask me..I'm worried about my own kid there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her..Out of nowhere overwhelmed by someone echoing and affirming his deepest most private thoughts about his daughter..It is odd..being this deeply touched before he knows what hit him..He makes little adjustments until the moment passes..</context>
      <utterance>You don't have to worry about Bernice. Nothing is going to change that heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um.....yeah..thanks...  It's great to hear someone else say that out loud..Hard to explain.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I "get" it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, man..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I was thinking about you..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your, "Ah, man" was for me? You think I am in trouble with Cristina?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just tough to be sane.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>89.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>JOHN  To know you're not just making something out of nothing. That when you think you're at some crossroads - you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How do you become that man?</context>
      <utterance>....I never know a man who can put himself in my place like you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...You introduce two Jews in the desert and wait five thousand years. Then, bingo, somebody else who can see trouble coming but can't do anything about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sustained gust of wind which celebrates her shape in a way which cannot be ignored.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I don't know what I'm talking about..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She sits. It helps.</context>
      <utterance>Will you sit down.. Get out of the damn wind.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you going to send her?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. But it does not feel good. I think if she goes there it will be one of two things..either she will be odd...or she will make herself the same as them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is EXACTLY the way I felt about Bernice going there..Exactly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>90.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>JOHN  I wasn't able to think it that clearly...But that's how I felt. So between odd and the same...you gotta root for odd, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera begins to pull back...early in the move John's words stop the movement.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, you gotta.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor nods ruefully..then suddenly off a glance at him.</context>
      <utterance>This was a crummy summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly there is a bit of danger..she rises quickly, changing mode.</context>
      <utterance>Not all crummy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, good night. I go sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns..</context>
      <utterance>Good night..Hey?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You speaking English...It's, uh..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gulps and exits...as the CAMERA PULLS BACK..ending the summer at the rented house...as we transition to....</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Just.... Nice meeting you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cristina taking it...</context>
      <utterance>I picked up your books yesterday..  This is one of Bernie's old..ancient backpacks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she shoulders it and almost falls over..</context>
      <utterance>Oh, thank you..</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a great school.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Flor's uncertain reaction is taken as a yes.</context>
      <utterance>It's from me and....Bernice.  Okay? It is a big day.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah hands Cristina a locket..then, noting Flor's expression.</context>
      <utterance>What did we get her?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's from ALL of us. Your mother too.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not from me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah has started to jog. As she approaches Flor, she calls for a clear path well in advance.</context>
      <utterance>There is a terrible crisis which comes when your own personality is not equal to the challenge you face. When being who you are no longer works.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor does not alter course though she does start to walk faster...</context>
      <utterance>Left...left.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Deborah is close behind now.</context>
      <utterance>Left...left...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Deborah looks up the street at a delivery truck.</context>
      <utterance>Why am I not surprised you're competitive?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Flor stays on task ..forces her stride. She just needs to win so very much..that's all..to her current surprise, that's everything...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, they're delivering my table.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Flor, even more upset and provoked by the words now lets it all out...</context>
      <utterance>You are fast.. Better pace yourself though..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feel okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I've given up drinking.  I had to do it John..I need every brain cell to watch out for all of us..given the current climate. Anyway. John, I think you're great and I'm going to act accordingly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's hope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flor? Deb..Look, sorry to call you so late, but they're still studying and I'm going out but I promised to get her back so if you want me to cut off the school work, fine...whatever you want me to do. Well, okay..you think about it..  And hey, if you're tired, or want to play, let her sleep here and I'll get her back there tomorrow. You still want to think about it? Okay.. She hangs up...and exchanges a mischievous look with Cristina.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Monica and her newly arrived mother are there along with the bride from an earlier scene and some of the girls who saw Cristina off to Malibu..Women cooking in the kitchen..She tells the girls, in Spanish, that Cristina may not make it. They are disappointed...Flor thinks - then says something to Monica who nods in agreement. Flor exits.</context>
      <utterance>Though it is possible to judge harshly my conduct toward my mother in my first year at school; almost all professional literature excuses my behavior as developmental, since I was entering an age where rebellion and narcissism were to be expected. And I was being mentored.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah turns, startled.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to talk to you privately, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Honey?"-- Can't now, Mom...I'm late..I was looking all over for you...keep an eye on the kids. You know my secret cell number.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just give me a moment to talk here..</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it? Are you buzzed?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I gave up drinking weeks ago.  Yes. Nobody noticed -- which shows I probably conducted myself pretty well as a drunk. But duty called and I'm sober so may I say just one thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One thing..go ahead...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs a deep breath and then turns and walks to the house.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks..Deborah, you're going to lose your husband and you'll never find someone as good. There will only be men who you know are cheap and shallow and have no real warmth in their souls. You may have gotten by on those surfaces once but now you've been spoiled by a good man and you can no longer glide on such thin ice. If you do not act quickly you will soon cement an awful fate for yourself. A life, with no hope of repair, which has already begun to turn desperate and dumb. That's it. Drive safely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've done it again, Mom, made me hate myself..One of the things I can count on..</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah considers that last thought for a long beat before she drives off..</context>
      <utterance>Honey, lately your low self-esteem is just good common sense.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But John hears Deb's crying from upstairs..</context>
      <utterance>John, better wait a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he is already moving quickly up the stairs..As he turns at the top of the stairs WE SEE THE DOOR CLOSE TO BERNICE'S</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. In all futility, can I urge you not to go up there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is about to leave the room...she is about to let him but an instinct leads her astray once more.</context>
      <utterance>Deb..Deb?..where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby, what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Baby?" Stay there, John...Sit down..I suddenly get what I have to do...I just have to get the guts.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it absolutely necessary to make it this...this scary..can you just say it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah..come on..it's me. We can talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I ever hope so...I've been seeing another man for the last eleven weeks and it was nothing and I ended it tonight..At first it was just keeping an eye on the real estate market..Then it was...what? Me being insecure and looking for some ridiculous vali...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>99.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A shock victim..he holds up a hand to stop her..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go -- hold on...hold on...I'm missing what you're saying..You can't just keep talking and expect me to follow it when you start the way you did.......</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just what did you hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him...a solid beat...</context>
      <utterance>Well there was the crack in the planet. That was noisy...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Briefly he does the noise...</context>
      <utterance>There's an actual noise in my head.....no kidding..</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John holds up a hand to stop her...he needs to gather himself to hear this..She waits...and waits...as he waits he grows flushed and stunned with dread. Finally a word..</context>
      <utterance>I met him about...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes that as a cue to start..</context>
      <utterance>You..</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts up his hand..</context>
      <utterance>I met him..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you talk that fast...I'll never hear you..there's a lot going through my mind....Have you said yet whether you slept with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So far I've just been talking about a flirtation because the really important thing for you to know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you said yet whether you've had sex with someone else? Because I really am missing most of your words. So help me out here..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been trying to explain that for the first ten weeks there was almost nothing to ...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still haven't said, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this your way of...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops... staggering on the threshold of a diminished future.</context>
      <utterance>This is my way of...this is my way of asking you whether..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man, once I ask it...give me a second.  I'm just trying to figure out whether there's any way to avoid knowing..no, damn  There's not...  Okay, you're on..real short answer, huh? Have you had sex with another..</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're very angry?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhhh...I'm getting there, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John?  I think if you let me tell you the full everything of this we'd be in a position to deal with it better..because eleven weeks ago when...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't believe that I miss your words..I get three or four tops...and then just see your mouth moving with nothing coming out and then I spin out and there's this noise...But there's no way to miss a "yes" or "no."</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made up my mind that I would answer every question you had..I'll answer anything and everything and more.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What other questions could there be?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you really that much nicer than me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He get up and starts to exit..</context>
      <utterance>Well, you don't set the bar real high.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doorbell rings...it's quite late...Deborah wondering what's up..she looks out the window.</context>
      <utterance>No. Please, please, please..I think if you listen to exactly what happened and then do whatever you need to...we'll..just let me tell you everything..</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's just Flor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want Cristina. I want to talk to Mrs. Clasky. I want to quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think you can do any of it right this minute..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes..Where's Cristina?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She awaits his answer..He has heard barely a few words..</context>
      <utterance>...then, when I was driving back tonight after I ended the whole yuck thing..I was feeling human. I'm done with what's his name..a relief... ..and now it can be like it never happened and then I thought that the only hope was that I own that it did happen and that I take my medicine here..because if I'm walking around with what I did and you don't know what I did..there is a real limit to how close we can be..you're with me and I'm this person who has this bad secret and we aren't really on the same page ever again..so the reason I took this chance in telling -- is because I want us to be good..I want us to be close. I want to feel like you're not nuts to be in love with me..So what I think is we should talk till we pass out .. Talk till we're so sick of each other that there's nothing left to do but take the first step out of hell..So please let's not leave this room until you've heard and said everything..please say, okay..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does. Just before he exits.</context>
      <utterance>I've got to get out of here..because you keep talking.  Stay put!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to say something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits.</context>
      <utterance>You are a terrible wife.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving....I have finally..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too..I'll drive you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes..come on...it's past midnight here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Have you no idea that I....</context>
      <utterance>If you truly don't know why I say "no" let me at last say the reason. At least that will be a relief.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look I have to get out of here right now..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John exits to driveway...Flor makes one last toss..these tosses have not made a dent in her anger and frustration.</context>
      <utterance>Go..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Another toss and Flor follows John out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Chum.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm taking you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor emits a crooning sound.</context>
      <utterance>Because if I don't -- I'll worry about you and I can't handle that right now, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhhhh.  I never made that sound over a man before..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please!?! Mandiln.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHER ANGLE..</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deborah watching them...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For John, the first clear thing he has heard in a while..</context>
      <utterance>Arrchhhhhyeeeeiii!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods..there is almost a moment of relaxation..then the anger fires an immediate need..She leans across the seat to deliver an urgent message to him. The words come out exponentially too forcefully.</context>
      <utterance>Yes! Exactly! Well put! Teach me that word sometime. I can really use it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His spontaneous and forceful reaction surprises her..</context>
      <utterance>I quit this job!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he turns onto Sunset.</context>
      <utterance>I quit this job!!!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the bus stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take you home.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Drop me at a bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shut up and stop telling me what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay...then let's do something besides driving me home where my daughter isn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay..we'll do something.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm supposed to figure out what because I'm a housekeeper and you don't have to think.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't do the class thing, man..You don't know where I come from.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, I know. But I can't be responsible no more for making sure nothing happens. That's another terrible job I quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? I take responsibility for anything within a block. You have nothing to worry about. That's my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent. So you're going to figure out what we do, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Okay. Big man figure out!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to a mall..He looks at her and pulls in.</context>
      <utterance>Stop there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You have never seen me!</context>
      <utterance>This is me when I'm not working..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you look familiar.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So,  "man," where we heading?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I can handle public..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, no...lots of people right now is..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were going to figure this out!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My place!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads for the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>I've never seen your place. Very perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to cook, Beautiful.  I'm going to cook beautifully.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns.</context>
      <utterance>Hey..please..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We both were not normal because we are angry and we act like we are angry with each other and we are not..I am not. I am glad to be with you. It feels comfortable to be with you. If I just left the job and never spoke with you it would have been sin. You understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands next to her and, for want of a better physical expression, pats her on her back..She eyes him, almost critical about the lame extent of his aggression....He can't quite look at her...He pats her again..</context>
      <utterance>Ummmmmmmmm...Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'm inventing a horrible new way of making out..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand keeps going..he now hugs her to him even though they both still face front.. like a loving couple on a walk to the market. His hand squeezes her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Not so horrible.....</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My hand is the only sane part of my body..every other part wants to jump off a cliff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs. He takes his hand from around her. It is a bit awkward.</context>
      <utterance>If the other hand could cheer up, you could lift me up and carry me off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how to handle that one. I think I already broke my record for smooth.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to the kitchen. She begins to explore a little. She goes to a cabinet and opens it to find a CD player. She digs in her purse and takes out a CD.</context>
      <utterance>It's me. I'm not making sense. But I can get you fed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing to be nervous about. You are not on a date...  Hey, Flor?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She enters the room...dancing a bit..</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up on one of the counters and sits there, her feet dangling...sings along a bit in Spanish. He is uncomfortable anew. The nervousness mounting.</context>
      <utterance>Just lighting candles and picking music.  Oooh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She considers the question totally..He is busy cooking..not realizing how weighty she considers his question...finally aware she has not answered and looks at her..</context>
      <utterance>You want a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She regards him levelly..then makes her decision.</context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets out a bottle of vodka.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, uh...don't think you should either.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to pour.</context>
      <utterance>Then excuse me, because if I had the equipment I'd inject the vodka.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I think it is so important that we are each clear-headed. He looks at her..a beat...he puts the vodka away. Flor beams..we have not seen her smile like this for quite some time.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is very good that you did not ask, "why?"</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep things real, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't have put it so well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will remember every taste..forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you the truth..I wanted a shot at cooking for you.  I'm very glad you liked it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at her...she has not been seen like this for a very long time, if ever.. lit up by a man.</context>
      <utterance>It's something watching you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if it's anything at your end imagine over here...scratch that..the last thing you want to hear is somebody going off on your looks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be crazy. Tell me every detail.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She squeals with laughter..He laughs a little himself and in so doing loses his courage..He looks down at his hands..shyness again belting him a good one..Still looking down.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Flor, yes I will...They should name a gender after you..Looking at you doesn't do it..Staring is the only thing that makes sense..and trying not to blink so you don't miss anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look..forgive me..I'm.....It's just that you are drop-dead, crazy- gorgeous..so much so that I am really considering looking at you again before we finish up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now he looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Soon, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He stands. She stands..He kids just a bit, clowning at weighing the two options and then:</context>
      <utterance>Right now....immediately..we have to dance or kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIS POV..</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her face..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss.</context>
      <utterance>No contest.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you're not Mexican.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I meant you talk like a Spanish song.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kiss like a Spanish fly..  Joking around. I don't know what I'm talking about...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She breaks and heads for the dining room. John has a moment to consider.. He does not have his wits about him..a condition every bit as fearsome as liberating.</context>
      <utterance>Yes you do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>113.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She begins to translate the lyrics.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He starts to make a comic gesture of awkwardness to get past the event..she shakes her head at him..driving the words -- pointing emphatically..she will not have her poetry laughed at..</context>
      <utterance>When I kiss you, entire oceans rush through my veins..  Gardens of flowers blossom in my body.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He laughs. She stops cold. Looks down..though just seconds long, this still constitutes the first depression of her life.</context>
      <utterance>And you wander along my fertile soil, picking its ripe fruit..A nightingale undresses on my tongue..And under its wings..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor..I'm sorry.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I don't know what I just took out of you but tell me how to get it back in there..I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON HER..</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The downcast eyes rise to see him..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her...they kiss..It is a kiss without an author. God at the controls. They break. There is a beat then..</context>
      <utterance>Then respect this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor looks at him with enormous warmth. Her arms looped around his neck..aware of the music.</context>
      <utterance>Here's something I never asked anyone..Did nightingales undress on your tongue?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they on yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Johnny, why is everything so damn confusing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor's pleasure zone is rocked. She smiles at his first Spanish word. She is wrestling with large feelings of pleasure and large ominous thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>Culpa.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is your mind racing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would say my mind has evaporated...but that there are remnants still standing waiting to fall. It feels pretty good.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think that will last?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's already gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand what I mean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is looking at her...she is disconcerted.</context>
      <utterance>That it's getting late. That responsibilities have entered your brain. Don't hide that from me. And really, one large reason we are here is because you respect me as a mother and I respect you as a father..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a great and wild mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him..they kiss...tenderness..heat...intimacy.</context>
      <utterance>You are a beautiful father.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>John considering and then the answer comes to him.</context>
      <utterance>When Cristina was young, I would say I want to take any man who wants me to the park and I will tell whether I want him from the way he is with Cristina. I wish you had been in the park then.  Any reaction?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly!..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I always think about when you...Oh, there's no point. I talk too much...  ...because I don't know if we ever talk again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wait.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey..How do you get there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you do. Be honest.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm being honest.  Look at us - I think I call it honesty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him again...starts to cry....looks at him..emits a small cooing sound.</context>
      <utterance>What are we going to do -- go home, let our hearts go back in our bodies, see each other a few more times. Make a tragedy out of us..</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhhhhhh.  There are some mistakes you cannot risk when you have kids...Please, are you ready to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods again..trying to gut things out...but as her foot touches the floor, she must say one last thing to him.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm not. No.  Stay put for a second. Stay here. Once our feet touch that floor, I'm going to get too many brain cells back. So don't be in such a hurry. That floor, Flor, is going to eat us alive.  So you think it was a mistake up to now.  That's rough.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The mistake....I love it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me again why I can't call him on the cell.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides that he turned it off?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forty messages start to look needy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother, you're enjoying this.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No..Definitely not in the way you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are enjoying it?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am enjoying actually being of use to my daughter. I am enjoying the fact that I really know how to advise you and the miracle that you are so deeply disoriented that you are gobbling up everything I say. Deborah nods in agreement -- then looks at her mother in a somewhat new way..as if Evelyn were an actual person instead of an upsetting extension of herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's one thing I'd like to say to you about you and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were an alcoholic and wildly promiscuous woman during my formative years so that I am in this fix because of you. It is your fault. I just needed..  ..that moment for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a solid point, dear. But right now the lessons of my life are coming in handy for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn moves to her.</context>
      <utterance>There's a car coming....</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Evelyn shakes her head "no."</context>
      <utterance>It's him...he's got to tell me everything..</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know that right now you are your own worst enemy..that you can't trust one thought in your brain?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duh.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then trust me and only allow yourself to say one thing to him..One thing..."I'm so glad you're back."</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I've got to know whether he touched her - where he touched her - how he touched her - if they broke a sweat --- what they said - who made the first move - how they left it -- if anyone loves anyone or has an intention of making contact in the future - what she wore - how he felt afterwards - whether anyone mentioned me..  ..whether they held hands when they left.. The distinct sound of a door opening and closing from downstairs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just those words I said. If you want a prayer of coming out of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're right..But..</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgot the sentence you said I should say.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I'm so glad you're back."</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay..do I have to wait here?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No..he may not come up here..go to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wouldn't he come up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I need a little makeup?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need a hose but you don't have the time. It's fine that you look like that. It's genuine..You can use genuine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a breath exits...</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, mom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John looks up at her - not knowing what to say...he is thrown. His demeanor has changed...deeper..serious..</context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad to see you  ..that you're back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wrong words start to form..she stops herself..</context>
      <utterance>It's late, Deborah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is on the stairway..he turns to go in the opposite direction.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I just wanted to say.. what I said..</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He turns back to her...she stops herself from straying into untried words but gestures whether he is coming upstairs to bed.</context>
      <utterance>Uhhhh..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This rocks her..panicked she grabs at her life preserver.</context>
      <utterance>I can't sleep upstairs with you.. Just can't for now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah's suddenly classy demeanor provides just the barest of footings for them...He looks at her directly for the first time since she told him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just so glad you're back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods..then goes back up the stairs..</context>
      <utterance>Yeah..okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deb, I'm done tonight. I don't think we can jam anything else in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He springs from the bed and opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>It's me, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just thought I'd check that you were back and okay and all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom was crying for six hours straight and Grandma was in with her all that time mostly saying, "he'll be back..he'll be back." I've got to get back to Georgie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just hate that you had that kind of a night.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's good for me to worry about something that really matters instead of the stupid stuff that's usually on my mind...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surviving.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're fantastic, Bernie...I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You don't know what to say?</context>
      <utterance>It's a slant...  Hey..I know there's a lot you went through but I knew all along that Grandma was right about you coming back..I mean totally knew it so I wasn't that worried. But still I...  I really appreciate it, Dad. Thanks....Stop staring at me..what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. I don't know what to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just what you taught me..You're welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss.</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...  No..and we must say "goodbye." I don't work here anymore. She then talks Spanish to Cristina..admonishing her not to embarrass them..something about Flor being prepared to go nuts all over her daughter if she hurts their dignity...but it is said with total calm.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I have to get out?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Georgie..Stay. I think you are a wonderful boy..be good..like you are. There are no monsters.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernice climbs out of the pool. Meanwhile, a flabbergasted Cristina is staring at her mom who gives quiet two and three word proddings in Spanish.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks..thanks. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe you didn't get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flor said.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to get you wet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me wet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bernice hugs her. Evelyn hugs Cristina..</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You...are...a...trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a beauty. Amazing girl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BERNICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My last chance to have some of you rub off on me..  I'm sorry you're so sad but this could have been so much worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now Deborah calling "Flor" is getting hard to ignore but Flor manages..</context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor flashes a look of thanks.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you run upstairs and say goodbye to Deborah?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upset, Cristina runs off. She kisses Bernice..and walks toward the house. As she passes under the bedroom..</context>
      <utterance>I'll be in front.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then a crying Cristina appears on the deck. Flor glances up and keeps moving underneath the deck where she faintly hears the beginning of their exchange</context>
      <utterance>Please come see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor enters the house...</context>
      <utterance>It's okay, honey..we'll see each other at school..I'm going to keep an eye on you..I will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Flor just looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>What's with avoiding me, am I this horrible person?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. It's a ridiculous question but sometimes I'm ridi...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's a good question. A fine question. Complicated.  I was just thinking to answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh stop. Come on. Weren't we close?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm very, very disappointed to hear that. It makes me feel like a fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We weren't close..but we were connected...in a bad way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor pauses for less of a beat than we would have imagined.</context>
      <utterance>You know something, I think we're saying the same thing...Look as long as we're doing closure..What did you and my husband, John, do last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can only tell you what I did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That will be sufficient.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now please..I am exhausted.</context>
      <utterance>I became sure of what an incredibly lucky woman you are and I must make myself not envy you which is hard. No, it's not hard. It's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEBORAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deborah would hug..but it's only an eighth of a gesture because Flor has turned to exit, calling for her daughter to hurry as she goes.</context>
      <utterance>Same here - believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cristina, aprate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flor shakes her head "no." She looks away for a beat so the next thing she does is a considered action. She leans forward and kisses him on the lips. John looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>I was hanging out here waiting. Can't give you guys a lift?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is killer.  Incredibly hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gate opens and a sniffling Cristina is holding an armful of loot.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Cari..</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let her have it..party favors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cristina..</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She offers her hand, which John shakes while patting her on the back.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Mr. Clasky..I am very sorry we will not see each other as frequently.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. They turn and begin walking down the street.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first minute we were alone, my mother told me that I would no longer go to the private school.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRISTINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then Cristina moves her hysterics to Spanish as she stops walking and her mother takes her hand and pulls her along with enormous dedication. CAMERA BEGINS A PULL BACK. Cristina dropping presents..picking them up..one of them left by the wayside..People noticing..Cristina's conduct violating tacit zoning laws.</context>
      <utterance>No. No..You can't. I won't be able to forgive you..It will be the end. I won't let you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSER SHOT..</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we can see their faces in the struggle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cristina moves closer to Flor, who senses it immediately and wraps her in her arms.. kisses her head.</context>
      <utterance>For that reason should you choose to grant me your scholarship my mother, at my request, will be relocating to the New York Metropolitan Area so that she can stay close during my time at Princeton.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope my essay has done her justice. I love her with all my heart.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
