<movie id="511" title="Spartan">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you expect me to do...?</context>
      <utterance>...your Dad's napping on the sofa, your Mom's watching Let's Make A Deal, and God is Dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I'm tired, Sir...Sir, there's no way...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause, as the man tries again to get to his feet. Scott looks up at the young woman on top of the ridge and gives her a "hold" gesture. She stops, at his command. Scott nods, as if to himself, and then kicks the young man in the ribs. The man starts, his eyes grow, and he gets to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>There's always a way...Don't You tell me there's no way...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves into the now-standing young man, and hits him, not heavily, but convincingly, several times.</context>
      <utterance>How 'bout that? That's called 'Adrenaline'. You said you Wanted In.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions with his head. In the BG we see the young woman nod, and begin running again. We see her, for a moment, breast a hill, and disappear again... ANGLE, on the young man, as he looks at Scott, empty, now, of self-pity, as if he just realized something.</context>
      <utterance>This is where you get in. The mugger don't care. The shooter don't care...get up...Or I will beat you to death on this fucken hill...Now: you better Catch her...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD on Scott for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing but the mission... The young man begins to climb the rockface.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>3.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She stands, waiting, as she finishes his note.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well done.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>JACKIE BLACK</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A signal honor to work with you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts away from her, and she raises her hand slightly, to indicate she has something more to say. He turns back to her.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir: Day or Night. Black or White. You reach out for me. "Black, Jaqueline A. US 24191489."</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, and walks off. Scott walks toward a mess tent. He is joined by George Blane, a very military-looking figure of an older man. He wears an informal fatigue outfit, mismatched jacket and trousers, without insignia. Scott is greeted by him, as they walk toward the mess tent. Scott shows the notebook to Blane, and Blane refers from the notebook to what we see are a group of eighty young men, in the mess tent, two of them the men we saw on the hill. Blane takes the notebook and walks off, as Scott enters the mess tent. ANGLE HIS POV, Scott enters the tent. Several of the young men react to him. He nods to them. Among them, we see the young man Scott berated on the hill, who rises and comes over to Scott. ANGLE, on Scott, who sits, as a uniformed man brings him a tinfoil tray with some food on it. Scott takes out a stiletto from his pocket, presses a button and the blade emerges. He begins to use it to cut up his meat. The young man from the hill, Anton, stands sheepishly near Scott, till Scott turns, acknowledging him. Anton takes a card out of his pocket, the size of a credit card, old, creased cardboard: It reads, "Rogers Rangers, Rules for Engagement. 1782". There is a line drawing of a man with a musket, and we read, on the card, beneath it, boldtype rules for fighting guerilla style. Written on the card, in old faded ink, "SGT. Anton, M. US. 3149584, United States Special Forces." The young man (Anton) shows the card to Scott.</context>
      <utterance>I'll remember, Sergeant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this then?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was my father's, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they speak, we see, in an insert, the printed rules - "Dated 1759". "Rule 4: Tell the truth about what you see and what you do - there is an army depending on us for correct information. You can lie all you please when you tell other folks about the Rangers, but don't never lie to a Ranger or an Officer".</context>
      <utterance>He carry it Over There?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He come back?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. He did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott pauses again. As he looks at the young man, who is obviously unable to express his gratitude, and sense of occasion.</context>
      <utterance>Well, so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blane's Aide calls the men to order.</context>
      <utterance>You carry that card, son. It might save your life.  ...You could use it to light a fire, or something...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANE'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men start to come to their feet, and leave the mess tent.</context>
      <utterance>The Candidate Cadre will fall in on the White Line...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to say, sir...That, to meet you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Scott. As he thinks a very brief moment, as if reluctant to become philosophical, and then turns back to Anton.</context>
      <utterance>...I can't imagine how they live with it...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anton shakes his head, sadly, at the spectacle of the failed men.</context>
      <utterance>Make sure you can't imagine it, cause, if you can, it's just one step to doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...they'll be back where they came from by Morning, and all this is just a Bad Dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Anton steps away.</context>
      <utterance>Do I need to know?  If I want Camaraderie, I'll join the Masons.  There's just the mission.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANE'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera pans over the smiling faces of the eight very proud young men. ANGLE on Blane and Scott, off to the side. Beyond them, we see the bus holding the failed candidates, filling up.</context>
      <utterance>Congratulations on completion of this evolution. I know you would probably like some sleep, but I do not think you'd mind sparing ten minutes for Induction.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Bobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all, Sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...You going home?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...weather permitting, Sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANE'S AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Anton, nodding to himself at the proudest moment of his life. ANGLE, CU Scott, looking at him.</context>
      <utterance>...as I call your names:  Grossler, Anton... These two men steps forward.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BLANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott gestures to the Aide, "One Moment".</context>
      <utterance>...would you bolt the door, please...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Scott, as he looks at the candidates, as they get the picture. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>...are you tired, Gentlemen?  This is the completion of the evolution:  Only one of you may join the unit. The first man through that door will be inducted. He gestures at a far door in the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CU Scott as he looks, interrogating the two men, weighing them, as they look at each other. Beat. Grossler starts to advance on Anton, in a fighting crouch. Scott gestures to the Aide that that was what he wanted to see.</context>
      <utterance>...yeah...you wanted to know the 'secret knowledge'...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"...Betty Coed, has hair of red for Harvard..."</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not current.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on them as they arrive at a small equipment room. Through the door we see a young government type, Gaines, his suitcoat off, his shoulder holster empty, being interrogated by several colleagues.</context>
      <utterance>Why not...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands a small log book to Scott, and points to an entry. Scott looks down the entries, and glances up, now and then, at the man being interrogated.</context>
      <utterance>It seems she got a makeover today. We're working on it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4PM. Cut n'Curl...</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gave her a crewcut, dyed it platinum blonde...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Aide shrugs, meaning, "That's it..."</context>
      <utterance>Met with her boyfriend at ten. Then...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...he's on Post until he turned her over to the Nightwatch...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says he was...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller gestures to an associate, who comes forward, passing photos to Scott, as Miller goes to look through the glass at the young man being interrogated.</context>
      <utterance>Who else you got...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...we got the boyfriend, Michael Blake.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We are shown a photo of an Ivy League preppy chap around 18. He is on a sailboat.</context>
      <utterance>...where is he...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was not in his dorm last night, we're shaking the trees...And...  Professor Gerald Sloane, notably chummy with his female students, of which she was one. Weekend home, Martha's Vineyard...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...for sure...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a photo, obviously from a school catalogue, of a youngish bearded man, in front of a blackboard. We see Miller in the BG finish his meeting and turn to the group.</context>
      <utterance>Been there since Friday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Aide hands him a sheet of paper, obviously a roster. Scott, looking at the board. He puts down his head for a moment, and blinks his eyes, trying to clear his head.</context>
      <utterance>I'm light. I'm light, people...I need another team on the Professor, I need an overwatch on the boyfriend...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just come from the Cadre.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long since you've slept?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not significant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Are you up for it?</context>
      <utterance>You take a team, and Bulldog.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, "this Marine pisses av gas and farts blackpowder, Sir."</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you for coming, Bobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An Associate comes over and hands him a piece of paper. Miller shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding, sir...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have the bodies. Call em in...call em in...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once more:</utterance>
   <speaker>GAINES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She, uh. She had lunch with her father.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lunch with her father - you seconded to that detail?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAINES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir. I just had her.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"...you just had her..."</utterance>
   <speaker>GAINES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tucked her in. At Ten. And she...</context>
      <utterance>I. Uh...uh. I had her all day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...yeah, "she had a tiff with her boyfriend..."</utterance>
   <speaker>GAINES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I...</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Michael Blake -</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was it about?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAINES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he makes gestures of haircutting)</context>
      <utterance>I think it was about her...her...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her haircut...  So it wasn't a serious...?</utterance>
   <speaker>GAINES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no.  No.  And then I,  I held the post until relieved...  Miller motions at Scott.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then, we've got a little problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>GAINES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>23.12 Hours, 19 May. Harvard Yard, Northeast Corner, Lowell House, reveals no Secret Service Presence, neither this post nor adjacent...  ...a second tour, 23.30, reveals, similarly...</utterance>
   <speaker>GAINES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was there, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Miller, who gives an infinitesimal sign to Scott who steps forward and slaps Gaines across the face.</context>
      <utterance>Who's lying?  You or him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes a move toward Gaines.</context>
      <utterance>You son of a bitch, I've got fifteen years in, and three kids, and you're gonna sit there, and lie away my Pension...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...don't you tell me you were there...</utterance>
   <speaker>GAINES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was On Post...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller gestures to a couple of the types who take Scott out of the room and sit him forcefully, in a chair...cautioning him to stay still.</context>
      <utterance>...you lying swine...Don't you tell me you were On Post!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>16.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD on Scott who uses the pause to review the documents he holds, the photos of the girl, of the Boyfriend, of the Professor. He picks up another glossy magazine showing the redheaded girl - the caption reads "America is Seeing Red".</context>
      <utterance>Miller now stands by him.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall I tell you what's gonna happen to you, when we find you out?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>...I...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I...Uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you fucking her...?  We're gonna find out...</utterance>
   <speaker>GAINES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I...um...</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott turns, to Miller, who is seen, beyond the door, in conference with several government types. Scott leaves the room, and is seen, on the outskirts of the conference.</context>
      <utterance>...Where Is She?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got until her Monday Morning Class, and then it's Meet the Press; and "Where is she...?"  Who's got the Professor...? Where is he...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AN AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Martha's Vineyard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's got him?</utterance>
   <speaker>AN AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jones and Shannon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD on Scott, at the back of the group, taking notes. We see him holding several newsclippings. One of them shows the girl, and the headline reads "America is Seeing Red." We see the photo blown up, of the ravishingly beautiful young girl with long red hair. It features a small, red enamel crescent earring. The second photo shows the same girl, in the same pose, but now her hair is short and platinum blonde and spiky. The agent opens two boxes and begins distributing the photos to the group.</context>
      <utterance>Wake him up, shake him up. He don't want to talk...  Here's what we have him doing with his Female Students, show 'em to his wife...The Photo...?  Here is the last known photo...of the girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An agent comes up and hands him a sheet of paper.</context>
      <utterance>The lab ran it up, based on the testimony of the beauty shop. We have not told Boston or Cambridge PD, nor have we...</utterance>
   <speaker>AN AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Professor...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had him in his home...</utterance>
   <speaker>AN AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, we were in Error, we...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AN AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best guess puts him on his boat. Last seen out of West Tisbury, Martha's Vine...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An Aide comes in, hurriedly.</context>
      <utterance>Find him. Put the guard on him. Get me an overflight.  I'm light, I'm light, people.  Shake the Trees. I'm light, here...I'm 25 men light. Get 'em in. Who's got the Coastguard...What's the name of his boat? Professor Gerald Sloane...</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller points at Scott, who rises.</context>
      <utterance>It's the boyfriend. He's moving...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got him...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before the Press wakes up.</context>
      <utterance>...I've got two days to run in.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott exits, and we HOLD on Miller giving orders to his group.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever it takes, sir... Miller nods his appreciation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Boy, Blake, moves his hands away from his body, to show a screwdriver. Scott motions him away from the mailbox, which we see is in the process of being demolished. Scott reads the name on the mailbox.</context>
      <utterance>Could I see your hands, son...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>L. Newton.  You lose your mailbox key, Mr. Newton...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You a student here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could I see some identification, please...? Mr. Newton?  Ten-Twelve patrol, requesting...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to advance on Scott, who draws a nightstick, and keeps him at bay.</context>
      <utterance>No, please...please...  Please, Oh, God.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down, Son. It's gonna be what it's gonna be...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE EXT. THE VESTIBULE. The young Asian girl, now walking with a male friend, pass in front of the vestibule. Beyond them we see Blake and Scott, as Blake motions to the mailbox, and moves to the mailbox and takes out a letter. ANGLE INT. THE VESTIBULE. On Scott, as he watches Blake take a letter out of the jimmied mailbox.</context>
      <utterance>One minute, could I please talk to you for one minute...Look look look: I broke up with My Girlfriend...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura.  Laura Newton?  Laura Newton? Is that 'the' Laura Newton...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We broke up. Alright? Laura Newton. They know who I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Secret Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Secret Service?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, that's right. They know who I am. You...They've "cleared" me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They didn't clear you for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>You, you hear me out, and, if you want to, Then...  Okay? Okay???</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to call it in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please...please. Five minutes...That's all I want. Please. Please...She would...she...  Maybe she's in her room!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tried the bell, you called her...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe she's ill...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to fumble with keys at his belt. ANGLE INT. THE ROOM. Several agents, obviously involved in investigating the room, wearing plastic gloves, stop. One, silently, unlocks the door. We see Scott enter the room, "miming" using a key, and turn on the light and look inside. We take him to her desk, where he finds several photos of her and her father - and a note on he desk, reading "Dear Dad-Thanks for coming-signed %-)". We see the boy, Blake, out in the corridor, unable to see into the room.</context>
      <utterance>...Mzz Newton...?  Mz Newton...this is Campus Security...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, in the hall, as Scott and Blake stand there, a young girl comes down the hall and stops, opposite her room.</context>
      <utterance>Mz Newton...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Scott, as he looks at the letter.</context>
      <utterance>...I was just...trying to retrieve the letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...this is not very nice language.  How old is this girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's...just turned 18.  I was mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..."everything that's going to happen to her"...What was going to happen to her?  You hurt her...?  Did y'hit her, son...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hit her? No. I...  I called her...I called her a whore...I...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She must...she must...she must have gone home...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this sign?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>It's how she signs her letters.  Cause she looks at everything cockeyed...Like Picasso - she said they called her "Picasso".</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who called her that...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, her, her...  He saw her yesterday! Maybe she's...maybe she's with him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you fight with her, Son...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>She, uh, she got her hair done...She cut it off. She dyed it blonde. I said she looked like a slut...and...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>Beautiful young girl like that. We've all seen her pictures. What'd you care how she dyed her hair?  What'd you care...? Why's that make her a slut...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She...  Uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, INT. THE VAN. We hear the conversation, and see the tape machine moving.</context>
      <utterance>She seeing another fella...?  ...just between us. Off-the- record, son...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I was young once, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>I...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's this, um...Teacher...I shouldn't, I, I shouldn't tell you this: She...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She sleeping with a teacher...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She says she isn't. I said she looked like a slut. She wants to fuck old guys, she should go to The Regency. Go all the Way.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Regency, what's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE. From inside the windshield of the van we see, through their body language, that Scott is "giving the boy a break", the boy is very thankful. Scott is admonishing him and the boy is contrite. Now Scott begins to walk away, and we see him minutely, signal to the van, we see the driver of the van pick up a phone and speak softly into it. ANGLE, Scott, walking down a sidestreet. The boy in the BG, we see the young Asian girl, take up a tailing position some half-block back of the boy, as a car glides to the curb. And Scott gets in. ANGLE, tight on Scott in the car, as he rubs his eyes, beyond exhaustion. The car pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>S'the Club, by the Fenway...it's like a joke at school, it's like a rumor: this or that girl, made a thousand bucks, went with a businessman for One Night... Look: it's a Lover's Quarrel. I said something I regret. I sent her a note which I regret, and I assure, you, Officer. If...  If you would...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No morgue. No hospital. No note.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent, nods, shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>The parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The mother,  You know where she is...He's holding up...  He was in town yesterday. To see her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Miller, in the BG, in a hurried conference, nod at Scott.</context>
      <utterance>...we snuck him in, and out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk off, an Aide talking to him.</context>
      <utterance>"The Colophon - 36-foot sloop". Where is she...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott and the Agent stop in front of the interrogation room, where we see the agent, Gaines, a guard over him. Gaines is sitting, looking as if he had been weeping. The guard addresses Scott and the other agent.</context>
      <utterance>...the Coast Guard has a watch over this area:  And they have scheduled the Colophon first...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He copped to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He copped to what?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hope she was worth it...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott stands wearily, watching several large men berating the seated Secret Service Agent. An agent appears with a tearsheet showing the ad for "The Regency Club". We see the ad for exotic young companions, and the address is Boston. Scott gives instructions to the Aide. ANGLE INT. WASHROOM. Scott, having stripped off his shirt, is washing himself at the sink. The "Regency" ad, and a description of the club is pasted with water to the mirror before him. We read, in the mirror: "REGENCY. 243 Charles Street, Boston, Mass. Owners of Record..." Et Cetera. In the mirror we see the Aide bring a fresh shirt and a tie to Scott. Scott turns, as the door swings, and he sees, in the BG, ANTON, just entering the establishment. ANGLE INT. THE BOATHOUSE. A Swat team is laying out its weapons and assault gear, on a long table. HOLD on Anton, who is standing, unassigned, and looking it. We see, on an improvised bulletin board, photos of the Boy, Blake, the Professor, and the Girl, blown up from a newspaper shot, and in various photos. As we watch an Agent walks up with a box full of photos, and tacks one up on the board. It is an altered shot showing the young girl with short, spikey platinum hair. ANGLE on Scott, dressed in a clean shirt, a tie, as he takes a photo from the box. We see him put it next to the original, blonde photo, and look at both.</context>
      <utterance>Uh huh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ran it up from a description of the colorist from the Beauty Parlor...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Agent takes off his suitcoat, and gives it to Scott, who puts it on. ANGLE, on Scott, as he holds the photos, and the Regency description. He walks toward the door, through the mass of agents. He stops by Miller, who is on the phone, looking at a photograph of the Professor, as a tech hooks up a video feed of a house on the water, the Professor's house. A photo of a sailboat is tacked up. We read 'The Colophon' on its stern.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme your coat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller gestures "Just a Moment", and then waves to an Aide, meaning "Do It".</context>
      <utterance>I need five thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long do we have? Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It hits the papers, and we're done.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller shakes his head, he holds up the "Regency" note...</context>
      <utterance>No...note? No...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller, gesturing around the room, meaning "what you see is what you get". All the occupants of the room are engaged on some task, save Anton, who sits alone on a bench. Scott looks at Anton, who glances at Scott, trying to keep the appeal out of his glance, "Please take me".</context>
      <utterance>I've got it...  Can I have some backup?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're scraping the bottom of the barrel here, aren't we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott looks at Anton and shakes his head. He is summoned to the front of the room by a young woman, who is putting cash into an envelope. Scott comes over to her, and we see her filling out a slip of paper. She hands him the cash in the envelope, and the slip of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to sign it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sign it.  Come on, Wallflower...  Scott turns to Anton.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is the sound of a gunshot. Scott and Anton instinctively take cover against the side of the building, drawing their sidearms. HOLD TIGHT on Scott. As he looks through the half-open door. We see several of the Swat men, taking up positions, one of them kicks open a door, and his partner enters. Pause. We hear the partner call "clear". ANGLE, on Scott, as he re-enters the building, and proceeds, pistol out, toward the room. ANGLE HIS POV. On the floor, we see the dead Secret Service Agent, a pistol in his hand. We see Miller turn to his team. An Agent kneels to the fallen Secret Service Agent, and prods a small hideout pistol from his hand. Scott turns to leave, and sees Anton standing next to him.</context>
      <utterance>Now: your mouth shut. Your eyes open, and form on me...Here's where we're going...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Anton and Scott as they leave. In the BG we see Miller et al. Miller giving directions.</context>
      <utterance>Don't look at him. Don't look at the Downed Man. He's dead...  Kick the fool overboard...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIGHT on Anton and Scott as they exit the building.</context>
      <utterance>...who is the girl he went to see? Get her in...The girl he was fucking...Who's got the Coastguard...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(beat)</context>
      <utterance>I'd hate to be the Lucky Duck who frisked him...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was off-post when they snatched the girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Well, apparently, he felt bad about it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Closing up...  Can't sell you booze after 3 AM.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures to the bills on the bar. The Bartender swoops them up, and gestures to the back bar, meaning "What'll you have?" Scott points to a bottle of Bourbon, the Bartender pours for him.</context>
      <utterance>No, no. I just came buy to pay you that money I owe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...how about them Sox, huh...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yuh. Whaddaya gonna do...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Curse of the Bambino".</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>...that's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice place you got here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You from out of town...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you know, actually, I was just looking for my Daughter...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that's what you're looking for...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I. Uhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...ask, because a lot of out-of- town guys, come in, lookin, someone else's daughter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I...Oh, no...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He brings out his case, with the photo of the platinum- haired girl. The Bartender comes over and glances at it. ANGLE XCU on Scott as he looks incisively at the Bartender, who displays no flicker of recognition.</context>
      <utterance>Abso, absolutely...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...girl like that been in tonight...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...pretty girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Scott, who looks around the club. We see him eyeing the lovely young scantily clad waitresses, who return his looks with disdain. The Bartender, observing him, comes back to him.</context>
      <utterance>None prettier.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...I'm looking for a girl like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bartender smiles.</context>
      <utterance>...You're sure it was your daughter...? B'cause, a lot of guys, come in here, guys your age, go home with some...some rather 'younger' girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Bartender leans close and hesitates. Scott takes out several more bills and passes them to the Bartender.</context>
      <utterance>Well, why would a, one of these 'younger girls'. What would they want to do with me...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Howdy, Pard'.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello. I wonder if you could help me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zimmer starts for the front door, and Scott falls into step with him.</context>
      <utterance>I love you, Baby, but the season's over...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...my friend says that you're...you're sort of a 'matchmaker'...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera takes the two out of the front of the club, where Zimmer tips the bouncer, who his putting on his coat, preparatory to going away for the night. Zimmer begins walking into a parking lot, where we see several run-down employee's cars, and his, Zimmer's prime Mercedes. Scott tags along.</context>
      <utterance>Izzat what he says...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I put her back in your space...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was looking for a girl...a young girl...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't we all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes out money from his pocket. Zimmer begins to speak slightingly, dismissively to the 'hick'.</context>
      <utterance>My, my, my, my, my, my question was: why would a young girl want to go out with an older man like me? And, if you could "answer" that...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zimmer starts to open his car door. He turns back to Scott, and we see, Zimmer's POV, Anton, standing behind Scott, at the doorway to an alleyway. Obviously backing Scott up. ANGLE CU, Zimmer reacts infinitesimally, to the sight of Anton. ANGLE XCU, Scott, sees him, and slams him against the side of the car. Zimmer reaches through the half-open door, and comes out with an automatic pistol in his hand. Scott kicks him in the stomach, Zimmer tries to raise the hand with the gun, and Scott throws him to the ground, the pistol falls on the concrete. ANGLE on Scott as Anton emerges from the alley. Scott directs him to drag Zimmer into the alleyway, near a dumpster. Anton thrusts his hand into the car and starts to reach for the dropped pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Bub...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE INT. THE SMALL ALLEYWAY. As Anton now pulls off Zimmer's sportcoat, and begins emptying the pockets. Scott interrogates Zimmer.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch the piece, don't touch the piece, don't touch the piece, th'out your gloves on...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I think you broke my arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seen this girl before...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I think it's broken...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zimmer turns away from the photo.</context>
      <utterance>You seen her tonight...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I think it's...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anton pulls Zimmer to his feet. Scott puts a lock on Zimmer and breaks his arm. Zimmer screams.</context>
      <utterance>Pull him up...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now it's broken.  What's her name...?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHAT'S HER NAME...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Break his other arm...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know her name, then who is she...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some, some 'girl'...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anton, tossing Zimmer's coat, comes up with a small medicine vial. He holds it up to Scott. Who takes it, looks at it, sniffs it. Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Some 'girl', some 'pal' of yours? Where is she Now...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>Oh no...  Oh no...this isn't Rohypnol...  Is it...?  Izziz Rohypnol? Is this "Rho"?</utterance>
   <speaker>IZZIZ A ONE-SIDED CONVERSATION...?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatzisname?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Donny Zimmer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anton tossing Zimmer's clothes comes up with an envelope. Scott takes it, and leafs through many bills.</context>
      <utterance>Donny. Donny: where's the girl...?  You dose her...?  Where is she? Donny...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what is this? Ten, what is it, Fifteen thou...? For what...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never saw that girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE CU, Scott.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, alright, then we've got to let you go...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you take the girl, Donny...?  You touch his piece?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott gestures to Anton to let Zimmer go. Zimmer hesitates, knowing he must not move. Scott holds the photo to Zimmer's face.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE XCU, Anton looking at Scott, to say "Really"? ANGLE XCU Scott, nodding back, "Really".</context>
      <utterance>That's not what girl...?  Where'd you take her...?  Put your glove on. Pick up his pistol. Two knees, the other elbow,  Mozambique...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott starts to walk away. Zimmer begins screaming.</context>
      <utterance>You bet your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIMMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait...Wait...Wait...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...beautiful night...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott walks up to him, and pushes him back into the vestibule. ANGLE TIGHT on Scott as he flicks open his switchblade, and holds his knife up to the Businessman's throat and whispers.</context>
      <utterance>'Less you got hayfever...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. The Businessman looks frantically around, beyond him we see Anton taking his Chauffeur out of the car. The Businessman turns to the intercom and pushes a button. We hear a female voice answer, after a beat, "...yes...?" ANGLE on Anton, holding a machine pistol, behind a corner of the wall.</context>
      <utterance>...you left something back inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a beat. And the far door in the vestibule is buzzed open. As it opens several men in Swat gear stream through the vestibule and up the stairs. Scott hands the Businessman over to an Agent, who takes charge of him, and camera holds on Scott, standing, wearily, at the bottom of the stairs. He motions for Anton near him to hand him a cigarette. Anton does so. Scott lights up. From the top of the stairs we hear screams, sounds of breaking, yells, commands being shouted. Beat. An Agent comes to the top of the stairs, looks down, and shakes his head. Beat. Scott turns and finds the handcuffed Businessman in his field of vision.</context>
      <utterance>...I left my case inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. The Businessman, terrified, is silent. Scott holds out the photo of the girl in the black hair.</context>
      <utterance>...they got some young girls up there...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Businessman looks at the photo. Scott gestures at Anton, and passes the photo of Laura Newton to Anton. And then looks as if to say "In or Out?" Anton hesitates a moment, and then strikes the Businessman.</context>
      <utterance>You see this girl...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on the Businessman, on the ground. Terrified. He looks back at Scott, as if unable to focus. Scott gives him a beat, nods, as if to say, "What would you expect", and starts up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Did you See This Girl...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beyond them we see Miller. And a very attractive European- looking woman in her forties. In a room beyond two bodyguard types are handcuffed, watched over by a Swat officer. Scott moves back to watch Miller interrogating the woman, the Madam, who speaks with a middle-European accent.</context>
      <utterance>...she was trying to scrub the thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>MADAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...an escort service. There is no impropriety, and there is no...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...who is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller waves the rest of the information away. Miller shows her the photo.</context>
      <utterance>...Nadya Tellich, Serb. Green Card, in...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen this girl...?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Scott, who stands by the Tech, who is trying to reconstruct the broken computer. It prints out a file, on which we see photos of various faces. Each girl holds a placard with a number on it. ANGLE on Anton, who looks down. ANGLE HIS POV. The wastebasket. In the BG we hear Nadya going on about the benefits of working as a Hostess. He motions to Scott. Scott squats to the ground, and pours out what are revealed to be several polaroids of beautiful young women. He uses his knife to rearrange them without touching them. They are now alighted and we see the numerals twelve, thirteen, fifteen, on placards which they hold up. ANGLE on Scott, as he walks back into the interrogation room, holding the sheet printed out by the computer.</context>
      <utterance>We see a lot of girls. They apply. For the job, as Hostesses...</utterance>
   <speaker>NADYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...a contact for Personal Services...They pay us so much for each call, and...The girls pay us! We are just a -</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They show you proof of their age...</utterance>
   <speaker>NADYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, of course, I...you think I...What do you think, I...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>Where's Number Fourteen?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I don't understand you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>...where's Number Fourteen?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller takes the photos of Laura and shows the platinum- haired one to Nadya.</context>
      <utterance>I want my Lawyer...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Was she in here?</context>
      <utterance>...is this the Girl? Is this her?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, wait, I no...I...I want to talk to my lll...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Scott, as he steps away. He takes us through the Whorehouse. In the adjacent room we see a bank of video monitors, showing people in various sexual activities. On the screen for a moment comes the face of what looks like a very young girl indeed, camera swerves onto the face of the Businessman we saw outside the Whorehouse, he is disrobing,...</context>
      <utterance>Izzat her? It's her, isn't it. She was here. Is that her...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode>ON TAPE</mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Scott. As he looks to the Businessman, himself, who is seated in a chair, presided over by several agents, forced to watch the video. He turns his head away.</context>
      <utterance>...come over here, you little bitch...That's right, get your sweet ass over here...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make him watch it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I...I...listen...listen: I'm a wealthy man. I am, I am not- without-friends in, in the Administration...  ...whatever it takes to...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott holds the card. He shakes his head sadly. Scott nods to the Interrogator and Scott throws the card into the Businessman's lap.</context>
      <utterance>This here, sir. This is a piece of cardboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE CU, on Scott, as he looks disgusted. Anton stands on one side, looking to Scott for a cue as to how to react.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you look away, you son of a bitch...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRUTH OUT OF HIM...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anton succeeds in pulling Scott off the Businessman. He drags him around a corner. We see the terrified Businessman in the background, as Anton tries to reason with Scott.</context>
      <utterance>Come in here, try to buy me off? I've got Three Daughters...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Scott, now appearing transformed, and easy. He gestures "shusshh" to Anton, meaning "It is all an act". In the BG we see the Interrogator browbeating the Businessman.</context>
      <utterance>...maybe we'd...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I thought when you wanted to pet little girls, you picked on your Daughter...Ain't that what you rich people do...now you step off the Reservation and you want to buy me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Businessman is terrified. He looks around the room in panic. ANGLE on Scott, as camera takes him to where the Female Agent is interrogating the Young Whore. Anton follows.</context>
      <utterance>Where Is This Girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WHORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I...She was sick...she was Not Very Well. She came in here...and...and...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...who was she...?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WHORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno...some young girl. I dunno...They took her, I told Nadya, she shunnt be here, they took her...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who took her?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WHORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that was her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was she here?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WHORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Scott, as he turns back to Nadya.</context>
      <utterance>I think that's the girl...they took her. The two, two men...they...  ...they gave her a shot...</utterance>
   <speaker>NADYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am entitled to my rights, and I am entitled to a phonecall to my lll...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your lawyer ain't going to help you...want to guess 'why'?  Y'understand the picture...</utterance>
   <speaker>NADYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Miller, as he beckons Scott. Anton starts to come and Miller signals him to stay behind.</context>
      <utterance>...ohmigod...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller nods and the three walk out of the room. ANGLE on Scott, as he and Miller retreat behind a door. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>He's with me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott moves back to Nadya.</context>
      <utterance>They don't know who they've got...they just snatched "some Young Girl". When they find out, they're going to have to...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was here. She was here, where is she...? WHERE IS SHE?  She was here -</utterance>
   <speaker>NADYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I...I don't know if this is the...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>She was here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NADYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...they'll kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did you call. How did they know, to come get her?</utterance>
   <speaker>NADYA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller pushes a pad of paper and a pencil across to her. ANGLE TIGHT on Scott. As he looks on. Beat. He nods, as if to say "We're getting there". There is the sound of a phone ringing, and an Agent comes in, and beckons Miller, who waves him away. The Agent indicates, "No, you have to take this call." Miller steps back from Nadya, not wanting to break the mood, and moves toward the phone. Scott moves to stand by the girl. ANGLE on Scott as he pushes the paper toward her, again, forcing and willing her to put down the number.</context>
      <utterance>I...it's just a number, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...hello...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...where's the girl...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, we believe she was abducted, from this club...  That she was taken to...that she was taken to a bordello...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...here in Boston...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yessir, and, that...that...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, let's hear it:</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>That she may have been...that she may have been delivered - for sale - that she may have been sent down the pipeline and overseas.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How certain are you she was the girl in the whorehouse?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...we...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was the girl in the whorehouse?  What about your other leads?...the Boyfriend, the...Professor...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Professor, where's his boat?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Coast Guard is on the...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to be quiet - and to pay attention to the drama in the next room. ANGLE INT. THE STEEL LUNCHROOM. As Burch and Stoddard interrogate Miller.</context>
      <utterance>...we just go where we're sent and do what we're told when we get there...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got the fucken Service Agent, shot himself...you're you're telling me, your best bet, some cocksuckers nabbed her, took her, took her, they don't know who she is. And they're gonna sell her down the river...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Detail Agent. Was he fucking her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Secret Service Agent, was he fucking Laura Newton...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>He was off-post, with his girlfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>The Professor, the Boyfriend, "...you behave like a slut...", this is who you like...?  Aah...fuck  She dyed her hair. What do they do, her hair grows out, what do they do when they realize who she is...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They kill her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're fucken A Right they kill her. Okay. Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Scott, and then Miller, looks at Burch's clean-cut and very fit assistant, Stoddard. There is a pause, and then Burch motions Stoddard to leave the room, which he does. Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Now: Let's talk some commonsense:  What can you do for me?  ...who is that...?  ...Get in here...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what can you do for me? What can you do for me - I need it now - I need it before the Press gets it on Monday. Cause they will kill her. The jackals start a feeding frenzy, and she's red. Help me. Miller nods to an Aide, who comes forward, with a white scrap of paper. He hands it to Burch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir: This is the number of a public phone in Downtown Boston.  It's a cutout, between the Bordello, and the abductors. A call is placed when they have a package to deliver.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you going to stake out the phone...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Regularly.</context>
      <utterance>We have a watch on the phone. More importantly: N.S.A. reports calls placed to that phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They can track calls to a payphone?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In this case they can.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were made from a Federal Prison.  This is Eli Assani. He is a Lebanese National, serving life without, for kidnapping. He was the head man in a white slavery scheme.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in Lewisberg. We have a Plan...  I hesitate to...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on an Aide who comes in and passes a piece of paper to Miller, who reads it and looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Give it to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott and Anton start to get to their feet.</context>
      <utterance>They've got some action on the Payphone...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, Anton, as he looks around, down at Scott, and then up, at a man in a suit, some thirty yards away, walking towards the car. Anton, as the man draws closer, looks down at Scott, as if to say "How did you know"?</context>
      <utterance>...who's walking up on us...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Scott, relax for a moment. And then, putting Anton out of his misery.</context>
      <utterance>Boston. P.D.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...always a reflective surface...  "...in the city, always a reflection. In the Woods. Always a sound..." HOLD. On Anton, as he digests this. BEAT.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and in the Desert?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, EXT. The Phonebooth in Copley Square. We hear the phone begin to ring.</context>
      <utterance>You don't want to go into the desert.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what is this...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...it's a wedding ring.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anton nods, and begins to work the ring off his finger. ANGLE THEIR POV. Far ahead, the speeding sedan turns off the highway, onto a "feeder" road. Anton and Scott in the backseat. As we see Anton take out a machine pistol from his "Go" bag, and check it. Scott looks at him. A chatter comes over the radio, and Scott addresses the two men in the front seat.</context>
      <utterance>...take it off.  ...the ring clicks against your riflestock, some sonobitch hears that noise, hundred yards out, and you're gonna get me killed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Driver hands a printout to the shotgun man, who reads.</context>
      <utterance>...where's he going...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somerville, Mass...</context>
      <utterance>One Five Four Nine, Alpha Sierra, Mass Reg. William Barak.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Agent shakes his head, looks down at the paper.</context>
      <utterance>That's where he's going?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also, owner of Record, In Essex...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Agent looks at the piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Izzey going toward Essex?  ...what sort of place is it...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It...it'd be a Beach house...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me there.  Get on the net. Call 'em off. Everyone off. Just me.  Just me and him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody out there...  Just. Him.  You indicate that you heard me.  Put it out.  How you doing bright eyes...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anton looks at Scott inquisitively, not sure he has heard right.</context>
      <utterance>...breathe through your nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It stills the heartrate.  You got my back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, Yes, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE the Sedan, on the deserted highway. HOLD. We see another car come screaming up behind it, doing one-ten, a red light on the roof, flashing. ANGLE INT. THE SEDAN. A middle-aged man watches the other car come up, and disappear around a bend, going furiously fast.</context>
      <utterance>...alright, then...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you want me to Come Through the Door...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the small handful of grass and throws it into the air, watching the way the wind takes it. Scott gestures to Anton to take up a position beside a small run-down boat shed.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you go through the door without an Overwatch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAN FROM THE SEDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what the fuck...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sedan Man is put a bit off, as the comment makes no sense. Scott uses the moment to advance toward the man.</context>
      <utterance>...I heard the TV, so I came in...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE EXT. THE BUILDING. Where we see the man, and Scott. We see the scene in green, through a sniperscope. ANGLE, on Anton, looking through the scope. ANGLE CU Anton, as he sees something in the scope. ANGLE, in the house. Scott advancing toward the man.</context>
      <utterance>...what the hell you got the TV on for, there's nobody here...?  I don't wanna hurt you. Why would I hurt you? I just wanna know why the TV's on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man backs up, past a half-open glass French door. ANGLE, on Scott, as he advances toward the man. ANGLE, ANTON'S POV. Through the sniperscope. The faint traces of what might be the Picasso symbol. ANGLE, on Anton, as we see him move the sniperscope and adjust its magnification toward the symbol. In a corner of the scope, we see another man, in a dirty white shirt, emerge, coming up the stairs from what might be the basement of the beach house. We see this man take in the scene in the next room, and secrete himself behind a wall.</context>
      <utterance>...I just wannit to know, I just came to ask you that question...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, Anton, inside the house, in a covering position, watching out. Scott comes up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Coming Up...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Anton take out a walkie and talk into it, Scott proceeds to the Sedan Man. He kneels by him.</context>
      <utterance>Call em in...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...where's the girl...? You're dying, pal. Even it up. WHERE IS</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. The man begins to shudder, violently, and then stops, obviously dead. Beat. Scott throws the dead man down onto the floor. Beat. ANGLE, on Anton, who turns to look back. He stares at the dead man.</context>
      <utterance>You're dying. You're dying, man. Where is the girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...well, you wanted to know...  Anton looks at Scott. Beat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BRUNETTE TALKING HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...apparently, had her hair restyled, and cut today, our Newsteam interviewed her stylist, and has reconstructed...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE. He is summoned, into the next room. By Burch et al. Burch and his Aide. As Scott comes in with Anton, followed by Miller. Burch takes Scott aside.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...here's the deal:  ...this is the man.  ...you're covered in blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, it ain't mine.  On my team, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How deep is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...He's on the team.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burch walks a few steps away. Thinking. Scott looks at Anton, questioning.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well. He may have to be a little more than On the Team...  I've been speaking to the father.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about if we had to go "off the meter"?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burch thinks for a moment. And then draws Scott aside. Burch glances over at the television, spewing information about Laura Newton, and shakes his head with disgust.</context>
      <utterance>...With the Mission, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to Scott. And gestures him into a small room, and closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>...I'm out of time...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...man to man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The door's closed, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he is hard-pressed to continue)</context>
      <utterance>I. Need. To Ask You. To do something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burch thinks a moment, he rubs his face, and shakes his head, and looks up as if to say "This is all we have, this is the best we have". Pause. He nods, as they do not move. Burch takes out a photo of a bearded middle-eastern looking man in a business suit, and another, in a mugshot marked "Lewisberg Federal Penitentiary".</context>
      <utterance>I am here to get the girl back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Police Radio chatters: "Two Twelve Sierra, come back...Two Twelve Sierra, come back, we have your request for Code Seven...please come back with your Twenty."</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAVYSET CONVICT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Scott driving. He looks behind him. ANGLE, POV. In the rearview mirror. A dust cloud settling over the deserted highway. ANGLE INT. THE OWL. Various techies, in the kitchen, monitoring the broadcast of the microphone in the Police Car, Anton among them. The Trooper comes in, taking off his bullet-proof vest, and sits to listen, where we find Miller and his Agents. The 'Restaurant Owner', who we now see is Anton, takes off his jacket and his bullet-proof vest and picks a slug, fired by Scott, out of the center of the vest.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, two twelve sierra took all the 20 he's gonna take...Oh, man, you left him there...</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAVYSET CONVICT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...yeah. You marked him Paid in Full...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you got to pull over, you got to stop...I'm bleeding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HEAVYSET CONVICT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he done ate from the tree of knowledge, our Sierra Two Twelve.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...help me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes his pistol and walks toward the farmhouse. HOLD on Assani, and the other Convict, Assani is holding a rag to his bleeding neck.</context>
      <utterance>...drag him out...  ...got some business to do...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...help me...</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAVYSET CONVICT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Scott, as he walks past a clothesline heavy with drying clothes, he is seen to go into the house. We hear a woman's scream, and then two shots are fired. ANGLE INT. THE HOUSE. As Scott is found at a table in the kitchen next to which are various foodstuffs laid out. Inside the house we see a female techie, at a table by the wall, various communications gear in front of her. Scott begins loading up his pockets with food. The techie hands Scott a slate on which is written, in large block letters, "The helo is standing by, will assault in support when you have found the girl. On your command." Scott gestures for the slate, and writes on it, and hands it back. Scott nods, and walks out of the house.</context>
      <utterance>...yeah, I heard yah...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HEAVYSET CONVICT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Baby. Pass some my way...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to the Heavyset Man, and fires his revolver at him twice. The man falls, dead. Scott turns his revolver at Assani, who begins to scream.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, my man...traveling light...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't shoot me, don't shoot me, I have what you want. I HAVE</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why in the world would I believe a lying convict like you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott advances on him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, ah, ah, but you do believe me...I see it...you do. I can get us out. Help me. I SWEAR TO YOU. HELP ME...and I will treat you like a brother...I...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My brother used to beat me  Nice guess, though.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. Listen to me...listen...make one call. One call - go in the house. Make One Call. ONE CALL. An Aviation Company. Tell...tell them...tell them the word I say, and they will say: THE PLANE WILL MEET</utterance>
   <speaker>YOU AT...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You a fag my friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  I am not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why the hell you looking at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking...how fucking surprised you're going to be.  Because, Baby, you just did that fucken good turn, going to Make You Rich, Fat, and Happy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...just get me on that plane.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't they tell you...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Assani grins, as if to say, "Just Wait".</context>
      <utterance>All I heard's a voice on the phone...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you like girls...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott grins, and Assani shares the moment with him.</context>
      <utterance>Better question, where you've been so long, do you like girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have. You will have...the most beautiful...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...most beautiful women, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not women, Baby. Girls. You got to trust me, I'm the Doctor here...All young. All blonde...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this all takes place Where...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In Dubai. In Yemen...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's a long way from Tiperrary, pal...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what do you have here...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Assani laughs)</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I'm not cut out, to live in a fucken tent.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he smiles broadly)</context>
      <utterance>If you think you can imagine luxury...I am here to tell you, my friend...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, may it Just Be So...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we get to Maskala...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, now, what's Maskala...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...when we get to Dubai, better...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's Maskala...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that's where we clean them up. We ship them Rough, we make them Smooth, and everybody's happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then, you're a philosopher...huh...? How 'bout making me happy tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's a girl, in the pipeline, tonight, you shall have her, what do you say to that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Assani joins with him in the joke, nodding his assent.</context>
      <utterance>...I say you're a stone cold whoremaster...</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How do they get it...?</context>
      <utterance>No, no baby. Take it to the bank. The Arabs, Man. All the oil - all the money in the world. What can't they have? Booze and Pussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Assani begins to swoon. He puts his hand to his neck, and it comes away covered in blood, where it was cut by the glass fragment.</context>
      <utterance>You the candy man? Is that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah. Hell...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ASSANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, no. I'm bleeding bad here, friend...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, Sedan. Holding Anton and several agents, listening to the broadcast from Scott's car.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we just, we got to get some...yeah, you need, all we need, some tailoring tools.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE EXT. ANTON'S CAR. As it increases speed. ANGLE INT. SCOTT'S CAR. As he tries to staunch the fellow. Scott steers with one hand. And turns off the highway at an exit, showing two miles to a town.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, in my wishlist, we had a drugstore, get us some morphine, some...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the helo just went down...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...don't whisper to me, Baby, it draws heat. What helo?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the assault helicopter. You've got no backup, at the house.  You'll be in there, alone, the first few minutes...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there you go, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said "Never go in without an overwatch".</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all fine, lad, "But this is the fleet".</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know you deliver him in the door, you know they're going to waste you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anton takes out the magazines in the pouches on his belt. And starts to strip off the rounds.</context>
      <utterance>...gimme whatever nine mil you've got...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anton takes the pistol from his belt. Scott checks it, and puts it in the small of his back. ANGLE EXT. THE STORE. Assani, in the pickup, sees through a small window in the store. ANGLE on Anton and Scott. Scott is walking away from him, and Anton puts a hand on him, and turns him back.</context>
      <utterance>...just gimme the mags...  ...gimme your piece.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Anton, as we see something occur to him. He turns to the other officer with him, and asks a question, and we see the other officer hand Anton several magazines of ammunition. ANGLE on Scott, as he is coming out of the back door. ANGLE on Anton, as he follows him.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Scott, turning to look at Anton. And, then, back at the obviously dead Assani.</context>
      <utterance>A...I'm alright...I'm alright...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your partner's going to be alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not look at the downed man, Sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller nods, and starts to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller turns back, understanding Scott's request.</context>
      <utterance>...Sir...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Air Force Assault is airborne, five minutes out.  Standing down's a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stand down when the girl's back, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out of the window we see a medical helicopter. Its rotors just starting to turn. We see two white-coated medical types, carrying bags, run toward the medical copter. An Aide comes in, and gestures to Miller that the copter is ready to go.</context>
      <utterance>They'll get her out, if she's in there...  You did your part, what the fuck do you want, a Citation?</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller turns to leave. Scott stands wearily.</context>
      <utterance>...sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the dustoff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir...? Sir...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no room.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pleading with you, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him hear the assault on the Net...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller shakes his head - at the door, turns back for one last word to Scott. And then he stops. ANGLE. HIS POV. The television, in the next room, playing a news program. Scott looks inquiringly at Miller, who is transfixed by the television. ANGLE the television. A "Breaking News" story. We see an overturned sailboat, and the talking head narrating: "...the tragic, the stunning...the...Jim, I don't know what to say..." The woman's co-anchor, obviously very shaken, takes up the story, and we see live footage of an overturned sailboat being towed into a harbor, then inserts of "Our Redhead" Laura Newton, and, after a moment, the Professor.</context>
      <utterance>I want to see the girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode>TALKING HEAD NEWSCASTER</mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on the TV. On two bodies being taken from the water by medical technicians. ANGLE, the woman, as a shot of the political man we saw earlier in the newspaper, comes on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>The death, just reported, the death of Laura Newton. The... the...</utterance>
   <speaker>TALKING HEAD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...her father, on the eve of the campaign...  Jim, can there be any doubt...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tracey, the Secret Service, for obvious reasons, their records, the DNA, fingerprints... the... and, she had just been in the water a scant, less than four hours, the...apparently the boat swamped... she -</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was sailing with...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Tracey, as she is overcome, and tries to steady herself. ANGLE, on Miller, and the Troopers in the room. Miller looks away from the screen, to Scott.</context>
      <utterance>With her professor, Professor...?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...a Tragedy, such as this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An insert of Laura's father, his sportcoat slung over his shoulder, comes onto the screen.</context>
      <utterance>...particularly. Particularly, Tracey, coming, right at the start of his Campaign...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE. On Scott. As he is found, standing, near the television. Off to the side, behind him, we see Miller, intently, on the phone, listening.</context>
      <utterance>Will he delay the start of the Campaign?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...his grief...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...he was very close to his daughter, wasn't he?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, indeed, he saw her, the day...that would be, the day before last. He was in Boston for the Strategy Meeting, and saw her then...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her boyfriend called her a slut. She went off to prove it. Her and the Professor. Coked up, boat capsized...Both bodies washed up naked. Coast Guard dressed 'em up...full of Ecstasy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...he killed her...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller looks down at the artifacts.</context>
      <utterance>He was fucking her, they're stoned...the boat capsized...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...so much death.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Miller leave, as Scott turns away, and lights a cigarette. Miller turns back.</context>
      <utterance>...rock crushes scissors...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about your man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you care...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fucked up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...in what way was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...but I was trying to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott takes a pill vial from Anton's jacket. Takes out a pill, and administers it to him.</context>
      <utterance>What? Do you want some more Dope? Whaddaya want, a Dr. Pepper...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...but I was trying to help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anton gestures Scott to draw close.</context>
      <utterance>...yeah, well, that's when people generally do fuck up. Wait for that to kick in.  You're gonna take that fight to bed for a while. You don't got to do it all now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE XCU on Scott as he turns away.</context>
      <utterance>I saw the sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott turns away.</context>
      <utterance>...uh huh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw the sign...at the Cape. In the House.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saw-the-sign. What sign?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...when I dropped the guy. The girl's Picasso sign...  She was there. At the Cape. The girl was there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The girl wasn't there. She was on a boat. She fell off the boat. She's dead.  You did what you could. You did what you were trained to do.  You did what you could.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I saw the sign...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...then you are Truly Blessed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>INTERROGATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He extends his hand to Scott. Scott looks inquisitively at him, then pauses, then stands. ANGLE EXT. THIS BUILDING. Scott exiting, as Blane comes out of his office. They walk through the compound. And to the camera, toward the Mustang.</context>
      <utterance>...from the house, a house, a holding facility, a compound? called Maskala. The girls are taken from Maskala, to the ...Royale Hotel, in Dubai.  As time passes, you may remember other aspects of...well,  You've heard this speech before...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...would be most grateful, sir, to be included on the mission. "At Such Time..."</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...on a mission to Dubai.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Blane, who looks at him to say "you know better than to ask."</context>
      <utterance>Is it in contemplation, sir...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.  If and When, Sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLANE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott puts down the small yellow duffle he carries, next to his Mustang. The young man who drove it in stands by, as Blane and Scott shake hands. Scott looks at the training facility. ANGLE HIS POV. The lecturer, executing unarmed combat moves against a trainee, who holds a knife. The lecturer puts the trainee on his back. Scott starts to walk toward this facility. He stands outside, by an open double-door, next to a water cooler, and draws himself a cup of water, which he drinks. As he watches the lesson. He turns back, as he sees the young man who drove in the Mustang pick up the yellow duffle, to put it into the car.</context>
      <utterance>You need a rest, Bobby.  Thank you, Bobby...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, Scott's POV, as he turns. We see the young female sergeant, Jackie Black, in the BG, walking across the area. Scott nods at her. She nods back. Scott starts to get into his car, and then turns back. ANGLE. SCOTT'S POV as the trainee on the mat gets up, and the lecturer gestures at the knife he has dropped on the mat.</context>
      <utterance>...please don't touch that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...pick it up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you studying here...? I'm talking to you, son... What are you studying?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAINEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lecturer pauses, looking down at the ground. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, this Candidate is studying knife fighting.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Trainee goes into a knife fighting stance.</context>
      <utterance>Hold your ground, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Trainee lets his attention drift for a second, in the direction the Lecturer has pointed. And the Lecturer screams, steps in, disarms the Trainee, throwing him to the mat. As the Trainee picks himself up the Lecturer turns to the class.</context>
      <utterance>...you, and your friend...</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Trainee puts his hand to his head, and discovers he is bleeding. The Lecturer nods his permission, and the Trainee walks to a water cooler, next to which Scott is standing. Scott looks at the shamed Trainee.</context>
      <utterance>There are two ways to fight, you can fight fair, or you can fight to win.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on the Lecturer, who calls another Trainee up.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you study knife fighting, son. You Learn to Kill. And then, f'you meet some other fellow, studied knife fighting, you send him to hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next man: A Trainee stands.</utterance>
   <speaker>LECTURER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now: I want to see some evil intent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, fuck it, Huh...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott gestures for another round to the bartender. Who is serving some rough trucker types, two of whom are at the bar with a couple of very attractive young women. One is a stunning redhead, who looks back at Scott.</context>
      <utterance>I've always thought so.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He piss in the punchbowl?</context>
      <utterance>How'd the puppy like it out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard he caught poison ivy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did okay. Why? You goin' out?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You recruiting?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would I be recruiting?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You speak Arabic, huh...?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what the Arabs tell me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, reason I ask: you going in the Sandbox...?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't you overdue for some Down Time?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott is distracted. He is watching the talking heads, on the bar TV talking about Laura Newton. We see the photos of her in high school, with her father in some African country, et cetera. ANGLE. On Grace, watching Scott. Who shakes his head very sadly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just saying:</utterance>
   <speaker>GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Scott. Caught in the image of Laura Newton, on the television.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. You Marines are a weepy bunch of motherfuckers.  ...you get a chance to bowl in that tournament...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on the truckers, near the television, looking at Scott. One comes over to him.</context>
      <utterance>...beautiful girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you say something, Mister...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you, "own" something?</context>
      <utterance>No, I was looking at the television.  I was talking to the television.  That girl's too good-looking for you anyway. What are you "rich"?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or are you "funny" or something...?  Siddown. Lemme buy you a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, not sure how to take Scott.</context>
      <utterance>You peel the apple?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...well. You should wipe off the blade.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...it's an odd knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I got it from a Russian fellow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it a gift...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. As I remember, he seemed rather reluctant to part with it.  It's just a knife.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PROPRIETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you been, John...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...workin hard...</utterance>
   <speaker>PROPRIETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...bet you have...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Proprietor pours Scott a cup of coffee from the pot on the back counter. He mixes in sugar and cream. Billy nods in response to Scott's question.</context>
      <utterance>How you, Billy...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROPRIETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...one gallon goin to do it...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you been lookin' at my house...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROPRIETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, On Billy, as he moves to a new customer, a farmer, who comes in, and nods at Scott.</context>
      <utterance>Nope, just trine a sell you some paint...  ...but, now you mention it...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEW FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...John...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Reese, how are you...?  That new saw blade come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, John. It did not. I beg your pardon. I know that's your baby...I'm gone call them up and get Right On That.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...'spected you back a few days ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE Scott, who is looking, over his coffee, at something on the street. And we see, his POV, a very city rent-a-car which is now across the street. We see a man getting out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>I took the Long Way Home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could I see your Right Hand, please...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing in my right hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anton holds up his right hand. Scott relaxes, and comes forward. Anton gestures, meaning, "what was that about"? Scott takes Anton's right hand, by the wrist, and turns it over. He explains:</context>
      <utterance>Could I see it, please...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You put your wedding ring back on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...yes...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anton gestures at the "Oilchange" sticker on the Mustang's windshield. ANGLE from INT. The Car. We see the sticker reading "Mike's Service Station, Bradford, PA". And beyond it, the actual old, tin sign of the garage, reading "Mike's Service Station". ANGLE, on Scott and Anton.</context>
      <utterance>Then I have to guess you're not "on assignment".  You're in the wrong place, baby.  How did you find me...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess I'm not as smart as I thought I was.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Scott shakes his head, as if in a sad comment to himself. He sighs.</context>
      <utterance>I need to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw the sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"You saw the sign". You were up for a week, you coulda seen Jack Ruby, you don't know what you saw...your first-time-out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw the sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...then, you tell me: you saw the sign, how is it, they found the girl, the DNA...why would they do that...? Her father? Her father would do that to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...maybe he doesn't know...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>Well. You're living in a fairyland of your Own Devising. You're seeing snakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>Who's going to Dubai...?  They've got a white slave ring, in Dubai, with American girls there - are they going in?  Are they sending you in...?  Ask them...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You Got. To Leave it for your Betters.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you want to know?  Listen up, Pal. THEY don't go through the door. WE don't ask why. That's not a COST, it's a Benefit. Because we Got to Travel Light. You wanna lose sleep over it, get over it, or get out.  You wanted to go Through the Looking Glass. How was it? Was it more fun than Miniature Golf...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two old ladies come down the small main street.</context>
      <utterance>Why would I do you a favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning, John, who's your friend...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fella wants to buy my car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>89.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The old ladies walk on. Pause.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saved your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well what were they paying you for...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bobby, I saw the Sign...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>My name ain't Bobby.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw the sign.  I Saw it. At the beach house.  I'm going back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the beach house.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(Anton shakes his head)</context>
      <utterance>They took it apart with a tweezers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was there. The Girl was There. I'm going back.  I want you to do something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would that be?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Secret Service Agent. Offed himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...he was off boffing his girl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He shot himself with a hide-out pistol.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Scott, obviously off-balanced by the question. Hold.</context>
      <utterance>Who frisked the sonofabitch?  You ask them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number one, the girl's dead. Number two, the hide-out gun the Agent shot with's registered in his 1020 for the past five years. The man who tossed him has been sacked. His name is none of your concern. Now: what the fuck are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I am not here to question...</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then, what the fuck are you doing here...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, as he said, he is here to apprise you of a security leak...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miller gestures to him to shut up.</context>
      <utterance>...and...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To call your attention to what may be a problem in discipline with this...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Granted. Granted.  Granted. Fine. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And. Sir...If I may...</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When the operation is staged in Dubai...</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He...</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what the fuck are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am merely saying, when -</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it. Walk away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...you're a pit bull. I said forget it. How do we contact Anton?</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Anton...</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott shrugs, as if to say, "Is that the way you want it?"</context>
      <utterance>Your partner...He's gone to ground...</utterance>
   <speaker>MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stoddard gestures to an aide to call a number.</context>
      <utterance>And, wait, wait, wait, wait, what does this mean...?  When and if, any operation is staged which may require your talents, I give you my word...  You impertinent motherfucker. What the fuck is with you, you've got on your "thinkingcap" all of a sudden...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to finish what I started.</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>And I'm telling you to Stand Down. Where's the kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Aide hands Stoddard the phone. Stoddard answers. Listens for a moment, and then points at Scott.</context>
      <utterance>Is there no operation in Dubai...? Stoddard shakes his head in exasperation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...sucker did the Dutch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard it was a training accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope, he Ate the Gun. Didn't you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been out of town.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Scott, as he sees something. Scott takes a book of matches and starts to light a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Punched out early, off with the girlfriend, his Principal wanders off, winds up dead: hari-kari...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Scott, who takes out the Anton "Rogers Rangers" card. He motions the driver to pass him a phone and Scott looks at the number on the card and dials. Beyond him we see, just at the limits of the gravesite. Holding himself apart. A young man in a raincoat. The young man turns at the sound of a limo driving up. ANGLE Scott, looking at the limo. Out of the limo, which stops near the grave, we see Burch emerge. There is a susurrus among the crowd, which, visibly, straightens a bit, at the honor of Burch's presence. We see Burch walk to the gravesite, and have a word with the widow. Burch puts his hands on her shoulders and comforts her. ANGLE, on Scott, looking at the man in the raincoat. We hear rifle fire, and Scott flinches. ANGLE his POV. The Marine Honor Guard, rendering a salute. We see a Marine bear the flag to Burch, who presents it to the widow. He shakes several hands, and then moves off, back to the limousine. He beckons Scott over to him. ANGLE, Scott and Burch, walking through the cemetery. Burch shakes his head. He hands Scott the program from the funeral, and reluctantly begins.</context>
      <utterance>...rather you didn't smoke in here. Scott gets out of the car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Didn't I...?</context>
      <utterance>I put myself in your hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not follow you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I reached out to you.  I put my life into your hands. I entered into a conspiracy with you. To commit Murder. Because it needed to be done.  I trusted you with my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would never betray you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I trusted you with my life. And yet you cannot trust me.  There are things you have not been told. That's right.  And now you're all out-of-line, "Play me or trade me..."  ANGLE, on the two.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is an Arab World. To penetrate it makes trying to join the Mafia look like a walk in the park. How would you do it, Scott?  We're dying. We're at war. And we have no intelligence. How Would you do it? How would you infiltrate their clan structure? Where is the interface?  It's at the whorehouse. That's where they go to get frisky, and that's where we listen to them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the few, priceless hints that we get from that fucking sandpile.  Had the girl been there, we would have moved heaven and earth - you know we would, and, we would have got her out. She was not there. She got drugged up and fell off a boat, and drowned. She's dead.  That man,  That man a sworn office of the Secret Service, went to get laid, and she died. And you are risking the lives of men and women in the field, because you won't take orders. How are you better than him? Yes. You had best look sheepish. What the fuck have you got to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No excuse, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're goddam right.  Now: where's this new kid who got you all bothered. Where's your partner?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I'll call him off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE. Over the Honor Guard, packing up, we see Scott hand a scrap of paper to Burch, who makes one or two more points, to which Scott nods, submissively. Burch walks off. Camera follows the Honor Guard, down the path, toward Scott, who, passing, nods at them.</context>
      <utterance>The fuck you will. You've got nothing to say to him. He's gone to the ground. Where is he...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man nods. Beat. He turns back to Scott, looking for sympathy. Anguished.</context>
      <utterance>Terrible thing.  Did you know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know him...?  Where did you know him from?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wasn't in the accounting office. You knew that...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man begins weeping heavily. Scott puts his arm around him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I Did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he looks for sympathy)</context>
      <utterance>I didn't think, he told anyone what he did. Because...because...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man takes out a small photo in a leather case - we see it is a smiling photo of the Secret Service Agent, Gaines.</context>
      <utterance>A few of us knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(the man is now overcome)</context>
      <utterance>And all he cared about was doing his duty...that's all...that's all... He used to tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott nods his understanding.</context>
      <utterance>He was supposed to see me that night...After his "shift"...We...His wife...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she know? His wife. Did she know?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could she? How could she...she didn't know him...  Oh, the poor children...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...he was going to come to me that night...after...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...after his shift.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on a Burly Man, in construction clothes, who is standing next to them.</context>
      <utterance>...his shift - yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURLY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...excuse me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...after, after he'd finished driving him...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...him...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURLY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...driving him..? Did you say "him"?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURLY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns Scott around, and pushes Scott deeper into the room, away from the other man, who is now going out of the door. Scott moves toward him and the Burly Man tries to stop him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's a man's world, pal - but you're in the wrong bar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SECOND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the B.G. We see the first man rise from the sidewalk, and move toward Scott. Scott struggles to follow the bus, when the second man assaults him. Scott is now fighting the two men, who manoeuvre him toward an alley. As Scott's back is to the alley we see a Third Man emerge from the shadows, and throw a garrotte around Scott's neck. Scott headbutts this man, who hauls Scott off his feet. Scott belts him again, and stomps on his instep. And turns into him. He elbows this man as the other two men advance toward him, in the alleyway. The garrotte man falls. Scott kicks the garrotte man in the temple. And draws his pistol. Beat. The men in the mouth of the alleyway retreat. ANGLE. On the street. We see them get into a van which has just pulled up. ANGLE on Scott. Standing. Shivering. As he looks around the alleyway. He moves back to the fallen garrotte man. ANGLE. Scott standing over the man. He sees something and bends down. ANGLE HIS POV. In the man's backpocket is a program from the funeral. ANGLE, Scott standing, looking at the program. We hear the phone ringing. Scott puts the phone to his ear.</context>
      <utterance>...what the fuck did you do to my friend...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...where are you...? No. Tell me later. Look: LOOK: Forget the boat house. Look:  Yes, tell me in...tel...look: tell me when...GET OUT OF THERE.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I...I brought you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why're you screwing with the door...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott frisks him roughly. The terrified Bellboy shows a "Do Not Disturb" sign, which he holds.</context>
      <utterance>Why're you screwing with the door...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took the...I took the sign off...  You had the sign on the door. F'they saw me...f'they saw me, knocking on a door, the sign on...they'd...  An, I...I figured, you needed...  You told me you wanted this at Ten...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...yeah. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I don't know why you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to look through his pockets. As the Bellboy stands, looking at the television. ANGLE on Scott, the television beyond him. As he goes through the pockets of his jeans. He then goes through the pockets of his jacket, and throws various objects on the bed. Some coins, some scraps of paper. A book of matches, some crumpled cigarettes. He hands some bills to the Bellboy.</context>
      <utterance>You're right, I'm wrong...I'm wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There you go, Pal. Hold on...</utterance>
   <speaker>BELLBOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. I just...I just wanted to help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises a shotglass to his lips, and drinks. He makes a "another one" gesture. Pause.</context>
      <utterance>It's been...quite a while since my last confession. That...that "transpired". On the rear face of a hill, in a mortar attack.  And I confessed that I was frightened.  And I have to confess, I'm frightened now.  'Nother "irregular Confession".</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, as a waiter comes, with a fresh drink. We see that we are in a very dark, quiet, smoky, panelled bar. The waiter leaves, and reveals, beyond him, Jackie Black, the female Sergeant we met at the training facility scenes. The waiter looks at her, inquiring silently, if she wants anything. She shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>...I'm about as frightened as I'm comfortable being.  And that's why...I involved you.  Which, I suppose, was shameful.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACKIE BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott, looks around, he takes up a tabloid newspaper, which has been resting on the seat of the booth. We see it is a "funeral" edition, concerning the death of Laura Newton. We see the large, color photo of Laura, her red hair, and, in an insert, her father, at the gravesite, hiding his face. The caption reads "Goodbye, Baby". Scott leans over, and whispers to Black, his deepest secret.</context>
      <utterance>Now: you did me the honor to Call me. Now: you tell me how I might help.  There in't nobody here, but two people in Green.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...this girl's alive...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then, you'd better go get her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Scott turns to her, to see a lovely woman in her late fifties, sitting on a lounge chair, a robe over her legs, indicating the weeping woman. Scott nods, and takes something from his pocket. He starts toward the weeping woman, but the other woman holds him with her voice.</context>
      <utterance>...terrible thing, grief...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott nods his acceptance of her wisdom, and begins to start toward the woman.</context>
      <utterance>...you want to comfort them, but you don't know how.  I always think it's better to Leave Them Alone...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A relative?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>A psychic.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well.  Can we blame her...?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott begins to move toward Mrs. Newton. The woman on the lounge chair sits up.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...who are you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman moves her blanket to reveal a pistol which she holds.</context>
      <utterance>United States Secret Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens his hands to show the red crescent earring. We see the demeanor of the woman in back of him change, as she sees the earring. She comes up to Scott, and he turns around. She looks up, asking, mutely, what it means.</context>
      <utterance>Guess again, 'cause I'm the Secret Service, and you follow my directions or I will shoot you dead. Spread your hands to your sides, please...  Open them...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the motherfuckers pulled the Detail off of her...He was in town. Her father was in town, they pulled the Secret Service Detail off her, to take him tomcatting. He's been doing it for years. That's what they do. They turn the Secret Service into a bunch of pimps. He took her protection, she got snatched...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A female Agent knocks at the door and sticks her head in and Donny gestures "rotate".</context>
      <utterance>He'd let her die?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donny gestures that she has heard. The Agent leaves and the door is closed.</context>
      <utterance>...leaving the post...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The start of a campaign: Your daughter got kidnapped because you were out getting laid?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her father would let her die...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who knows if he knows. His 'people' would let her die in a heartbeat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...her mother...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes out a small, tattered, cheap earring box. ANGLE INS. We see the empty place for holding two earrings, and a small arcade photo of a five-year-old Laura Newton, and this woman, Donny, fifteen years younger. They are hugging. Scott turns over the photo to read, in a childish scrawl, "Donny, you can keep the box, cause I'll never take them off". Donny starts to weep.</context>
      <utterance>I'm her mother...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need some money.  I'm going to get the girl back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need money. I need a lot of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been signing her checks for years.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright...  Can you go this high, that's what I need...</utterance>
   <speaker>DONNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, their POV. One of the Secret Service Agents, looking askance at Scott. Does a double-take. And begins to raise his cuff mike to his lips to speak. ANGLE, on Donny, as she sees this, and turns around. ANGLE, her POV. The empty room. Scott vanished.</context>
      <utterance>...I...I don't...is there anywhere else you... ANGLE. Both look to the side.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't they tell you not to come?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess I wasn't paying attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five years ago they told me you were dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Avi motions Scott to come with him.</context>
      <utterance>You want to gossip, or you want to do business...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bobby; this is an American girl...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that were so?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Avi nods, meaning "yeah, sure".</context>
      <utterance>If that were so, why don't your people go and fetch her...? What if I'm speaking for them...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...they send a hitter to negotiate...?  My question is: have you forgot your catechism...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what's the answer?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The answer is Go Home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's a good one.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you're at the Big Table here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know where I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then, you better talk to me using the Decimal System.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your intel. Two men. Infil, exfil, hardware, and com.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And com to what? I cannot give you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you could, when you where in the Boy Scouts.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but I am not in the Boy Scouts anymore. You heard the private sector?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He writes a number on a sheet of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Well. That's where you found me. And here's what it costs.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you're out of your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're out of your fucking mind, and you're out of your league, and my advice to you:...before some mercantile soul shops you.  ...for this job, that's what it costs...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that's what it costs...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what it costs you.  Go home, Bobby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE Scott, as he takes out the Businessman's card, and looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>Remember me...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...well, I guess you do have friends in High Places...I mean here you are home, n'all...  And now we're gonna see if you also got all that money that you spoke of.  This here's a Short Subject, if you know what I mean. Of you in Carnal Congress with an Underage Girl. A PROSTITUE, A MINOR, AND</utterance>
   <speaker>SOMEBODY'S DAUGHTER...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's another...you know how cheap it is to make a copy...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want what you promised me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I've, I've already made a deal with...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He brings over a telephone, and gives it to the Businessman. Scott finds himself behind a large desk. He looks down at photos of the smiling Businessman, in various poses, with two young girls, obviously his daughters.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but you haven't made a deal with me...So, today is Your Lucky Day, cause you get to Do, what Most Men only Dream of: You get to make Another Human Being Happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Businessman pauses, then picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>You had your fun, now pay for it, Jim. Get your bank on the phone. We're going to transfer some money.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..."how about that".</utterance>
   <speaker>BUSINESSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...do you know how much trouble you're in...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. And that's the difference between you and me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maskala is a suburban villa, in Dubai. The Friends of your Friend,  Operate there, if you will, a "halfway house". For the young women they have induced, coerced or drugged into spending their short lives. As the whores of Arabian tourists. Of late the girls have been, in the main, from the former Sov-Bloc. Now and again, a North American Girl, if she is exceedingly lovely,...blonde, usually blonde...  Will, unfortunately, find her way to Dubai. They travel drugged, they are -  - "tidied up", and sold. For some reason, most of them are sold to Yemen.  The girls are generally held, in Dubai, until the end of the month.  When the Merrymakers fly in to examine them. And take their purchases home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and then?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is "and then".  This is a floor plan of the building where the girls are held, this is the security arrangements, this is the watch plan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Scott opens another envelope which Avi has passed him. As he looks at the documents he pours out.</context>
      <utterance>The girls are taken from the house in Maskala, to the Royale Hotel, I presume you will hit them in transit...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..."Jameson Construction"...They know we're there...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope not.  The conex container for the exfil, also Jameson Construction.  A passport for the Young Girl...  Between fifteen and twenty-five, they all look alike.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that your experience...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Scott, as he looks, questioningly at Avi. Avi takes a photo from his desk and passes it to Scott. It shows, through a long lens, blurry and grainy, a photo of what is obviously the platinum-haired Laura Newton, sitting on a bed, in a barred room.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. It is. Nonetheless, we tried to match it to a Current Photo...</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...she was there twelve hours ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who took the photo?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>How would I know...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does the bonus cost?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott scoops up the documents, and stands.</context>
      <utterance>A gesture of Friendship. But. We thought: if you see some of the Yemenins -  Any of these, in particular...would you say Hello to them?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Avi shakes his head, and wags his finger, as if to say, "No, in all sincerity..."</context>
      <utterance>Who else have you done a favor for, Avi?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Scott takes an envelope, and hands it to Avi, who opens it. He opens his mouth to speak.</context>
      <utterance>Bobby: the world runs on manners.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The last third on exfil, in Geneva. Me and the Girl. As agreed.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what I was going to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he exits)</context>
      <utterance>What were you going to say...?  ...the Last Third in Geneva...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera takes him to the middle of the street. A right- hand turn, a tight corner. He looks to his left. ANGLE HIS POV. Beyond him, we see, several streets off, the sign of the "Royale" hotel. Scott beckons, and the man, Smith, comes out of the shadows. He and Scott walk to a small passageway, at the corner. Camera takes them through the passageway, where we see Jones, standing by his car, in an alley.</context>
      <utterance>...fourteen, fifteen, sixteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, tight on Scott, and Jones.</context>
      <utterance>It's good.  It's very good.  The charge takes the car out...  We got the flashbangs fore and aft, You hit the driver, follow down the driver's side, the car ain't going nowhere, the muscle gets out, I cap em, I go with the girl.  You exfil on your own, we're on to the airport.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the airport. When we hit the Conex. When you Seal Us In...you walk away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cannot have heat on it. Now: I know: that you want to protect the package. But: you have to walk away. And que sera, sera.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't look back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith nods as if to say,"If you say so". Scott reaches over to a box of Q-Tips, which sits on the table along with other cleansing paraphernalia, and dips one in the solvent bottle, and begins to clean the interior of his switchblade. ANGLE XCU on Scott, as he cleans the interior of his knife. His face freezes...Scott leans over, and gestures at a tweezers as part of Smith's cleaning kit. Smith nods "okay". ANGLE INSERT. The interior of the knife. A small, wafer thin electronic device adhering to the interior. ANGLE on Scott. As he turns his back on the group. We see, in an insert. He holds the electronic device up for scrutiny, in the tweezers. He walks toward the windows of the warehouse.</context>
      <utterance>...it's an appleseed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Johnny Appleseed", eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear a car driving up, outside the warehouse. He looks out of the window.</context>
      <utterance>...yeah, I'm just a Man of Peace...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He uses the rope outside the window to improvise a sling, for Laura, and drapes it over her head, and under her arms. Scott picks her up, and holds her for a moment. She starts to speak. And he answers her question.</context>
      <utterance>...who...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates for a moment. We hear another explosion, he nods, as if to say "That's what we're waiting for", and passes her out of the window, and begins lowering her to the ground. ANGLE EXT. THE BUILDING. Laura, on the rope, reaching the ground. ANGLE INT. THE ROOM. Scott, as he turns to the sound of the door opening, two men come through the door, and he shoots them. ANGLE EXT. THE BUILDING. Scott puts Laura into the SUV and gets behind the driver's seat. He puts the car in gear, and it begins to drive off. ANGLE INT. THE CAR. Laura turns to face him.</context>
      <utterance>Stay by me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...they said they were going to take care of me...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to take care of you. You hold on, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you remember, Baby, we went to high school together...  You dropped your earring.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws the Picasso sign on the windshield, she looks at it, having trouble focusing.</context>
      <utterance>You're Picasso, right...? That's who you are...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...they're going to send me to a Party.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE EXT. THE CAR. Moving through the streets. The airport just becoming visible in the background.</context>
      <utterance>No, Baby, you're going Home.  You're just taking the long way home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see her wake and look around, trying to place herself. ANGLE on Scott, as he takes out a notebook and begins to make notes in it.</context>
      <utterance>...I told you to stay on the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you're going travelling.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes out a crumpled pack of cigarettes, and extracts the last one. She takes out a match.</context>
      <utterance>...we're going to take a little trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...put that away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I need a smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down his list, and nods. He takes a bandana from his pocket and hands it to her.</context>
      <utterance>Y'can't smoke it. American tobacco. Smell. Carry. In the desert air.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put that on. Over your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatsamatter, you don't like Blondes...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whole world likes Blondes. That's why you're here. Put the bandana on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, EXT. The window. The first gleam of dawn. And, far off, a Muezzin is heard chanting morning prayers. Laura moves toward him, unbuttoning her blouse.</context>
      <utterance>I need a smoke.  ...gimme the fucken smoke. He shushes her, and moves to the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slaps her lightly in the face.</context>
      <utterance>I could make you give me the smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reacts violently to the sight of the needle. Beat. Then, she sits on the bed and cries self-pityingly.</context>
      <utterance>Keep it together.  Keep it together, or I'm gonna give you a shot and carry you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody Cares about me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that's right...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I'm just a whore...They wouldn't even come get me...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott looks at the pile of tobacco. He extracts the "Rogers Rangers" card from his pocket and looks at it. We read, in an insert: "Rule 13: Every night, you'll be told where to Meet, if Surrounded by Superior Force". ANGLE, on Scott, as he very precisely peels the card into two thin halves, and rolls one of the halves into a cigarette, using the reclaimed tobacco from the ashtray. He takes the cigarette to Laura. As a peace offering. She takes it. Beat.</context>
      <utterance>They sent me...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did my father send you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Scott, as he hears a car outside the window. He draws a pistol and moves to the window, and looks down. He gestures Laura to be quiet. ANGLE EXT. The window. In the small, deserted street. A car pulls up. A man gets out, and looks around. Beat. Another man, and a woman, and two small children come out of the low house and get into the car, which drives away.</context>
      <utterance>One riot, one Ranger, you ever hear that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leonides, the King of Sparta, when a neighboring state would beg for Military Aid. Would send One Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...well, there you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you ever hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her. Beat. She hands him the cigarette. And he takes a drag, and passes it back. He checks his watch.</context>
      <utterance>No. I think we went to different schools.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...put the bandana on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear the one about the king who turned his daughter into Gold?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. She turns away, and cries.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah - I heard that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I don't want to go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't ask you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know where we are...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE Scott as he looks up to the sound of a plane. ANGLE HIS POV. Directly over their heads, a small bizjet, on final, about to touch down. ANGLE, the chainlink fence. Scott and Laura at the fence protecting the airport. Scott moves aside the pre-cut section of fence, and gestures him through. ANGLE, inside the fence. Laura and Scott moving to the protection of a small hangar. ANGLE, beyond them, we see the bizjet come to a halt, on the tarmac, and turn. We see blazoned, on its side, "Global News". ANGLE, on Scott and Laura, now inside the small hangar. Scott moves to a small locker and extracts a set of coveralls, and a cap, and takes them to Laura.</context>
      <utterance>You just keep it together.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You put this on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. He turns to the sound of a car. ANGLE HIS POV. A car, on the tarmac. It comes to a stop by a private plane. Beyond this private plane, we see the "Global News" bizjet, being directed to a stop. ANGLE, on Scott, as he watches the tarmac. ANGLE HIS POV. Stoddard and several of his men, get out of the car which has stopped by the private plane. A man in fatigues emerges from the plane, and hands Stoddard a piece of paper. Stoddard begins giving this man directions. ANGLE INT. THE CARGO HANGAR. Scott and Laura, who now has on the mechanics coveralls.</context>
      <utterance>You...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE EXT. THE NEWS BIZJET. Where a man in a safari jacket, and a woman emerge from the plane, and glare at the sun. We see this man consult his watch. ANGLE, on Scott and Laura, as he walks her out of the hangar, and towards the news bizjet. In the B.G. We see Stoddard, and his men, at their plane. Another car pulls up to Stoddard, disgorging a man, who goes to conference with Stoddard. ANGLE, these two men.</context>
      <utterance>A little walk-in-the-park.  See there...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...all of the passenger terminals, and all access-points to the Cargo and General Aviation...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you know what my mistake was...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops and picks up a pair of "paddles" from their position, leaning against the nose wheel of a plane. They walk on. In the BG we see Stoddard and his crew, searching.</context>
      <utterance>...what was that...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what was your mistake...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you think we bring our troubles on ourselves...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts laughing, getting hysterical.</context>
      <utterance>I'm certain of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to break free and Scott manoeuvres her into a small hangar area. She is struggling mightily. Scott has his hand over her mouth. ANGLE. We see their feet moving through a pool of oil on the concrete floor - we see she loses her footing. We see Scott tighten his grip on her, and is furiously trying to calm her.</context>
      <utterance>No, no...come on baby...come on, come on girl: just walk to the plane: Just Get On the Plane...WALK TO THE PLANE...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see him work a small hypodermic kit from the pocket of his jacket. We see Laura see it, and her eyes grow wide.</context>
      <utterance>Shussh, baby... shussh... shussh... it's going to be alright...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura reacts to the hypodermic, which Scott is bringing toward her. And screams.</context>
      <utterance>This's going to make Everything Allright...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave her Alone.  Don't shoot him, don't shoot, you'll blow the thing sky high...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Laura...</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Laura, standing between the two men. She is completely confused. She looks from one to another.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God we Found you. You know me. I work for Mister Burch. I've met you...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said that he came to get me...</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points at his bizjet, outside, on the tarmac. Laura walks, unsteadily, in the direction pointed, and we see a female attendant, in a vaguely military getup, get out of the plane, and begin to walk toward Laura.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, Laura...Walk away from him. Walk to the Plane...He can't hurt you now. Walk to the plane...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts toward Laura. And Stoddard and his two men interpose themselves between Scott and Laura, who is approaching the plane. Stoddard's two men approach Scott. One draws a knife. ANGLE on Scott, who hangs his head, wearily. He looks down at his empty hands. ANGLE on the man with the knife, approaching him.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man handcuffs Scott behind his back. ANGLE on Scott shaking his head to clear it, as he now struggles to his knees. ANGLE, his POV. Laura Newton, walking toward the bizjet.</context>
      <utterance>Cuff 'im...</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...well...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>Let the girl go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...wait till she lifts off, take him outside and shoot him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...why can't the Girl Go Home?</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode>CU</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because she's dead.  You had to know the Secret Knowledge. Didn't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is the Secret Knowledge?</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE. On the tarmac. Laura, walking toward the plane, the petroleum storage hangar behind her. We see a vaguely military uniformed woman fall into step beside her and take her arm. Laura looks at her. We see Laura full face, and just the shoulder of the woman escorting her. Beyond them we hear the engine of the bizjet start up.</context>
      <utterance>The Secret Knowledge is: There Is No Secret Knowledge.  You went Beyond What Was Permitted. And the Gods Are Angry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I'm so tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laura looks at her questioningly.</context>
      <utterance>...I'm going to ask you to do Just the One More Thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, to show that the stewardess, who descended from the bizjet (the vaguely military clad young woman we saw earlier) is still on station outside of the bizjet, and that the woman who is walking and talking with Laura is Jackie Black, the young female sergeant we met earlier. Laura looks at her uncomprehendingly. Laura begins shaking her head pathetically, and protesting, drawing away from Jackie Black.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to ask you, now, to walk away from this plane, and come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, INT. The Petroleum Hangar. Day.</context>
      <utterance>No...leave me alone. No - I don't know you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Laura and Jackie Black. Standing immobile. Laura looks down at something. She then looks up, her face transfixed. ANGLE, on Jackie Black's hands, she holds the cheap jewelry box we saw earlier, and, in it. The photo of Laura and Donny, and the legend: "Donny you can keep this box, cause I will never take them off." ANGLE XCU, on Laura, as she looks at Jackie, who now moves Laura away from the bizjet, and towards the assemblage of newspeople, who are on the tarmac, around the "global news" jet. ANGLE, EXT. The Global News Jet. A female reporter, gossiping, with some of her crew, looks over in the direction of Laura and Jackie, and does a double-take.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, take him outside...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Stoddard, his man, and Scott. As they leave the hangar. Stoddard looks around. ANGLE, his POV. Inside the hangar, the fallen man, that Scott has killed. Stoddard goes back inside, to drag this man away. He looks up. And, as he does so, he sees Laura, walking with Jackie Black, toward the Global News Plane.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God...</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Jackie Black and Laura, walking toward the plane, where we see the crew hurriedly setting up a camera. ANGLE, on Stoddard, as he draws his pistol, and fires toward Laura and Jackie. We see Jackie move to shield Laura, and then, struck by a bullet, she goes down.</context>
      <utterance>Wait...!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, on Scott, in the grip of Stoddard's henchman.</context>
      <utterance>Keep walking...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FEMALE REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside the jet we see various monitors, and one switches from an innocuous travelogue, to the scene at the airport, and the caption "Live". We see the shot is taken from inside the plane. We see Laura stumbling toward the bizjet, and see the female reporter run out of the plane, and move her to safety inside the cabin.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme an uplink Gimme an uplink... GET IT ON THE SAT. Now Now Now...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera shifts to the image of Laura Newton, going out live. Behind her we hear the crew shooting commands, and see the door to the Global jet close, as the jet begins to taxi. ANGLE, INT. The Petroleum Hangar. We see Stoddard, reloading his pistol. In the BG we see Scott step through his handcuffs, that is, bring them in front of his body. He takes a pistol from the henchman, who is writing on the floor. He raises the pistol and shoots the henchman. He turns on Stoddard.</context>
      <utterance>On her. On her, get it on the girl...Get us Out of Here...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks toward Stoddard,who is fumbling, trying to reload his pistol.</context>
      <utterance>The girl ain't dead, baby, you're dead. You see: that's the difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>STODDARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>WAIT: WAIT. The girl's home. You brought her home. Now, listen to me, because I am going to tell you...now, you wanted to be "inside"...I am going to take you as far inside as you can go: Z'at what you want...? Is that what you want?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE, INT. The Bizjet, as it taxis. Laura Newton turns her face to the sound of the shot. ANGLE, her POV. Jackie Black, on the tarmac, Scott, kneeling to the fallen Stoddard, and then running out of the hangar toward her. ANGLE, on Scott, running, as we see he has the key he has taken from Stoddard, and is releasing his handcuffs. ANGLE Jackie Black, bleeding, as Scott kneels to her, and cradles her. Scott looks down. Black is weakening, and obviously expiring.</context>
      <utterance>No, I just wanted to bring the girl back. He shoots Stoddard, who falls.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...is she safe?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, she's safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE BLACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE on Scott, cradling her. Weeping, as he smoothes her hair.</context>
      <utterance>...well, then...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that's right, Baby...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
