<movie id="513" title="Spider Man">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a WHOOSH, the WINDOW EXPLODES, showering the TWO with shards of GLASS, and throwing them to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, whoa, whoa... what's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We begin again... let's kick in that new transducer. See if we can double the power output.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIZ ALLEN is also a senior. She's beautiful and intelligent.</context>
      <utterance>Hiya Peter...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya Liz... how're you doing...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'm I doing what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HARRY is the school nerd. A quirky kid who, like PETER, can be a little backward around girls, especially pretty ones like Liz.</context>
      <utterance>Peter! Peter! Wait up!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it? what...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did the Astro-Physics Journal really accept your paper?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... well... all I got's the data but they've agreed to publish it when it's finished. You know... it's my calculation on the Planetary Conjunction.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isn't it?</context>
      <utterance>And its influence on the anti-force.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Look, Harry, I am busy with...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Every one is busy with Liz.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you and the rest of the class.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A HAND reaches in and smacks her bottom.</context>
      <utterance>Peter?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, cupcakes...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss and walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Flash...!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Flash is the busiest of them all...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HARRY makes a gesture dismissing OCK as crazy.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Harry... we'll be late for Octavius.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ock is nuts, don't you agree?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ock is a genius, Harry. Crazy, Yes! But, a genius misunderstood, and unappreciated.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doctor Octavius!</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Octavius! You are late for your lecture. The students are waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LIGHT above THORKEL's head EXPLODES. Then all the LIGHTS behind him EXPLODE in succession. THORKEL and ROZ look amazed...</context>
      <utterance>Your friend is impossible Professor Rosomorf, I told the board we should let him go.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he doing in there, not his crazy experiment again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean his anti-force theory... one day they'll give him the Nobel Prize for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meanwhile he is demolishing our university. Octavius!!  Open the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FOUR WALDOS (three-fingered, snake-like mechanical arms) suddenly thrust themselves into the CHAMBER and begin working, each at a different task. OCK is an acknowledged master at manipulating these WALDOS. He flicks a switch and a searing BLUE-WHITE BEAM lances down from a FOCUSING CONE and strikes a GRAM WEIGHT marked, "1,000,000"), illuminating it and filling our ears with a splitting BUZZ TONE. The knock on the door grows louder. WEINER comes up behind OCK.</context>
      <utterance>The anti-force experiment has now reached the limit of electronic overload safety. Therefore, Weiner, you will disconnect the overload safety device...</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, Doc... someone's at the door...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>World class scientific mind and they stick me in the basement with this third rate cyclotron... INSERT: The DIAL marked "RELATIVE GRAVITY" reads "1,000,000" but suddenly it snaps to "0.999999!"</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WEIGHT begins to jiggle and, for an instant, it appears to lift ever so slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Okey! Dokey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Peter?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, gentleman can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell your boss, that his class is waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ &amp; THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Professor OCK turns and looks at the bewildered men.</context>
      <utterance>Professor Octavius!!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, come, you must see this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, your students...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The imbeciles can wait... I have better things to do than teach introductory Physics Rosomorf. Undergrads are kindless adolescence.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see he is impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thorkel you are the dummiest administrator our university has ever had.  Don't go Thorkel!! Come! Look! He starts to play his machines handles and buttons.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The university pays you to teach something to your students.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, do you mean nothing... or do you mean something but you won't tell me what it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean plain nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess that's about as nothing as you can get... plain nothing. A beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liz...!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh, it is something.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The equipment on her TABLE is starting to vibrate. They look at it, curiously. We hear the cyclotron's WHINE begin to build...</context>
      <utterance>No... look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am going for 20 percent power!</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NO!! Don't do that...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ock! Its dangerous...</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WEINER crosses himself. The CONSOLE erupts in sparks.</context>
      <utterance>Ock I warn you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep calm, everybody keep calm. Use the front door. Everybody out the front.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liz! Come on...!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. Help me!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wades into the fire, but is beaten back by the FLAMES. His sleeve is on fire. He pats it out.</context>
      <utterance>I'm coming!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flash appears and tries to help but Thorkel stops him.</context>
      <utterance>Peter!</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIZ smashes at the WINDOW, but this is an inner city school and the WINDOWS are covered by STEEL GATES. Liz wraps her fingers in the GATE.</context>
      <utterance>Get back, you idiots. You can't go in there!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Outside the WINDOW the air is clear and people come and go. Some are stopping to look up at the girl on the second floor who screams (but they can't hear, of course) down at them as the FLAMES close in behind her. PETER comes flying in with a FIRE EXTINGUISHER. He fumbles with it. FLASH pushes Thorkel, grabs the extinguisher away from him with a scowl of disdain. LIZ turns to face the FLAMES. Suddenly there is an eruption of CO2 CLOUDS and the roar of a FIRE</context>
      <utterance>Help! Help me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for your help Flash.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem wimp.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our hero has a real way with words.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSOMORF peeps in, worried -- faces Thorkel.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, why don't you grow up. PETER is stung, insulted, turns away.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK comes in, starts his lecture calmly as if nothing has happened.</context>
      <utterance>This man will bring a disaster upon this university.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLASH hands the EXTINGUISHER to PETER. LIZ embraces FLASH, throwing a glimpse at PETER who tried so bravely. He looks away and turns the last of the EXTINGUISHER on the last of the FIRE.</context>
      <utterance>The universe is made up of forces... and counter-forces. Science is the study of the forces!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I... Professor Otto Octavius... have devoted my life to the study of the counter-forces! Good job, Peter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THORKEL has walked slowly and uncomprehendingly toward the front of the huge LAB. He simply cannot believe OCK'S behavior.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Professor.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it, I simply don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we carry on Mr. Thorkel.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe... oh, all right carry on Professor.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well! This week my dear students I have made a stunning breakthrough...</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, wait a minute... you've got fire forms to fill out, Dr. Octavius.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THORKEL steams out and bangs shut the DOOR.</context>
      <utterance>I have no time for forms, or administrators who persist in interrupting me, Mr. Thorkel.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WEINER backs away from the BLACKBOARD to reveal a word that OCK has scrawled in large letters. It says "Anti- Force."</context>
      <utterance>I now believe its possible that these counter forces can be... collected... the way the magnifying glass collects the sunlight... and focused into a hard beam I call... Weiner!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK is plugging a HUGE CABLE into a small LUCITE BOX with a SILVER BALL inside it.</context>
      <utterance>I call it, the Anti-Force!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This anti-force, once harnessed, is capable of undoing any natural force at which it is aimed... for instance...  Gravity! LIZ scribbles down a note and mouths the word "gravity." Then she turns to PETER.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK is "playing" his COMPUTER like the Phantom of the Opera at the organ.</context>
      <utterance>It's alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights flicker and go dim.</context>
      <utterance>We patch in the cyclotron...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK peers through the LUCITE BOX at us, distorted by it. The BOX is a miniature version of the cyclotron's experimental chamber, and now the BLUE-WHITE glow begins. It crackles round the SILVER BALL.</context>
      <utterance>Pay no attention to the lights... I of course steal its energy, and it looses power. We patch in the cyclotron... and we gradually apply power. The power that I am stealing... As the WHINE builds in the LAB...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LIGHTS go totally dark. The kids react with WHOOPS and CATCALLS.</context>
      <utterance>And so we stand, four square against the fundamental force that orders and maintains our universe... gravity... which is holding down this goddamn ball. Rise!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a crock...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up Harry... this is very interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Parker! Have you some... interesting observation you'd like to share with the class?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK peers at us through the LUCITE BOX as the SILVER BALL begins to rise. OCK'S face is ecstatic.</context>
      <utterance>Then shut up! And pay some attention to the experiment.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SILVER BALL suddenly shoots up, shattering the top of the box. It flies up to the ceiling where it shatters a</context>
      <utterance>Rise! Rise!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CYCLOTRON WHINE cuts out and OCK wheels to the COMPUTER. He hits a KEY and several COLORED PROJECTION BEAMS lance out of the back of the room. They pierce the smoke and light a PROJECTION DISPLAY in the front. TWO COLORED SPHERES one, YELLOW, one BLUE touch where their circumferences meet. Behind them is a BLACK depiction of "space".</context>
      <utterance>Now that's what I call an experiment!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK hits another COMPUTER KEY and a hole appears where the TWO SPHERES touch. The BLUE AND THE YELLOW MARBLEIZE with each other. The colors swirl until both SPHERES are</context>
      <utterance>You are looking at a representation of two universes. Our Blue one. Our real universe... something we can touch and feel and see and draw calculations about. This is us. The Yellow universe... this is something else. Some other dimension... something... on the other side!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it were possible to generate enough power behind it, the anti-force could wipe out not just gravity... but all our universal forces at the same time. In effect... it would blast a hole between this universe and the next. Each...  would flow into each other. No blue universe. No yellow. End, finished, over.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds like a scenario for the end of the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My girl, it is! It is. It would mean wiping out everything that's known... and letting in everything that's unknown.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't that a little dangerous?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry yourself, true inter- dimensional penetration is still purely theoretical, but one day... Maybe very near... maybe in the 21st century...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, it's just... I don't know... when you and Flash go after each other like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not my type.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't have to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER looks at FLASH who's a few LOCKERS down. FLASH has taken a FOOTBALL from his LOCKER and is spinning it on his finger with great joy and concentration.</context>
      <utterance>And besides, he's not all bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't get nicknamed Flash because you're a rocket scientist, Liz.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it up, Parker. You'd die for a nickname like Flash.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIM comes by and leans seductively by her LOCKER. KIM is a ripe one and hot-hot-hot!</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, of embarrassment.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Flash... I'm scalping a pair of the Midnight Madness Wrestling Match tomorrow night.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Slammies??? I'd kill for that!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you pay $125?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh, I... gee... if... can I tell you tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You snooze, you lose. Hiya Liz...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIM is pulling her pet, a foot long SALAMANDER, out of her LOCKER. She wraps it around her neck and turns to the boys. They go bug-eyed!</context>
      <utterance>Kim, you know Peter and Harry? This is my new roommate... Kim Nickson.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hellooo, Peter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peter looks at KIM. Wow. Then he looks at LIZ who's adjusting herself in a small MIRROR. HARRY jabs him in the ribs. Yeah, yeah!</context>
      <utterance>We're going to the Student Reunion Meeting. You coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't... I gotta go over to the Daily Bugle. I'm trying to sell some photos.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soooh, a photographer...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just an amateur. Well... nice meeting you, Kim.</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... I bet it would be.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I be your date for the reunion ShooShoo?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No Jerk!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I say...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody leaves and Harry is left alone, he throws his bag down.</context>
      <utterance>It's not what you said, it's how you say it, ShooShoo!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER turns to go and comes face to face with the hulking</context>
      <utterance>Damn!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter, Doc Ock wants to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About my data I bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knows about my work on the Planetary Conjunction, doesn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Professor Octavius.  I really admired your experiment.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a lot of interests in common, Peter. Perhaps we should put our heads together, if you know what I mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be... great.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you take the Planetary Conjunction. This Saturday night we will witness Saturn, Jupiter, the Moon, the Earth, the Sun... all in a row. Never seen within the memory of man, or measured for its effect. The total gravitational force must be quite exceptional. Isn't that the subject of your paper...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir, I've worked out a new way to calculate the combined gravitational effect.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a busy man, Mr. Parker. But I think I could find the time to go over it with you. Make sure it all... checks out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I'm sort of working with Professor Rosomorf and he suggested we kind of keep it between us. He thinks that my theory is... well, I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The scoundrel...  I want to see that data, Peter!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Professor Octavius... if I knew you were interested... sorry, I've already given it to... Professor Rosomorf, and he is after all the head of our Physics Department... and I couldn't... OCK turns sweet again. He smiles too broadly.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm certain something can be worked out. Run along, young man. PETER begins to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a minute... how about if I show you my discoveries... something I never showed to any other student... as a matter of fact to anybody at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I am really flattered, I mean I'd love to... but I...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well shall we say if you come here tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Professor I don't now if I should...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK turns to WEINER who slouches against the wall smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Make it eight sharp... I'll be waiting for you... Right here... Peter looks worried then leaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The same academic world that's so keen to embrace that boy's undergraduate work, ridicules my anti-force theory as quackery. I ask you, Weiner... what is our society coming to? Ha!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are all a bunch of brainless assholes, that's what I say...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weiner! Go get me that boy's data!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cost you fifty bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just get it. We'll negotiate your fee when you have the data, alright Weiner?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bag ladies. I hate bag ladies.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JAMESON is 50ish, grey at the temples, brush cut on top. He too is forties. His chewed up CIGAR is forties. This guy is a hard case.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little kids... I hate little kids. This is a daily newspaper. We need news value photographs, not artsy-fartsy shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JAMESON comes to a picture of a BUSINESS SUITED MAN with a MOHAWK. PETER smiles in anticipation.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid? You want a pro's assessment?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Because if you are...</context>
      <utterance>Your photos suck.  Parker, my readers are morons. I gotta grab them by the eyes. Every time you press the button of that Nikon of yours it costs you fifty-five cents. So the next time you're about to take the plunge, ask yourself, am I taking dog bites man?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I know. You want man bites dog...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parker, this is the post modern 20th century. I want man eats dog! Get out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing in there worth stealing!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the understatement of the year.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aunt May, you're trespassing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just so desperately bored... I thought I'd come over and make you dinner...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am old enough to... to make my own--</utterance>
   <speaker>MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I didn't feel like getting to know your roaches.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll introduce you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. And those foul chemicals in the pots...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I take pictures, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs her coat, crosses back to Peter and tugs on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Anyway, I've decided to kidnap you for dinner in Forest Hills...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Friday night...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Do you have a date?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Professor Rosomorf, what happened here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone tried to rob me of some paper... I suspect they were looking for that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Award winning stuff.  Peter Parker's data on the Planetary Conjunction. Damn lucky I hid it in my computer under another title.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, what's going on in our school? First Professor Octavius almost blows up the Physics lab... Now this. You report it in triplicate, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thorkel, be careful when you talk to Octavius. Remember... the man is a very fragile genius. One day he'll bring us all the Noble Prize.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off screen the voice of the CYCLOTRON WHINE begins to build.</context>
      <utterance>Rosomorf, the man is a very dangerous crackpot!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's him again. He's working day and night.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell you the man is very dangerous.  Come on Rosomorf, let's stop him before this building will explode.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK ignores him. WEINER touches OCK'S shoulder. OCK ignores him too.</context>
      <utterance>Shut it down, Octavius.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've blown half the circuits in the Science Center.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call an electrician.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have called the locksmith.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points toward the worker who's working on the lock on the main door.</context>
      <utterance>What... what is he doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to shut your lab down and take a look at the lines.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Otto, we must lock it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're denying me access to my cyclotron?!</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK glares back and forth between the TWO MEN, the WORKER, and WEINER. Then he pulls BACK the RED POWER THROTTLE. The WHINE descends. The WALDOS pull back and dangle from their panel. The WHINE dies.</context>
      <utterance>You bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ha... Tomorrow you can have this room...</context>
      <utterance>Okey, dokey... just give me till tomorrow. I want to clean up my papers. Tomorrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... well Thorkel... few more hours won't make a difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He signals to the worker to stop.</context>
      <utterance>I hope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another brewski?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm fine, Uncle Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah! Way to do it. Alright!  You don't follow the Mets like you used to, do you, Pete?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not so much anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny. When your Mom and Dad, uh, passed away... I had this idea... I wanted you to be the best baseball player that ever was. Geez, what ever happened to that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little league.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AUNT MAY enters.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... Babe Ruth you wasn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEN nods, rises sluggishly and slowly, and turns the sound off only. PETER moves toward his AUNT in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>It's on the table! Turn off the TV!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that girl you told us about, Peter?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liz? She's great... But she has a boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A boy your age should have a girlfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aunt May... she has a steady boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter, any girl that's worth your attention is of course gonna have a boyfriend... But if she really gets to know what you have to offer she'll... you get my drift?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, just leave him alone, okay. When he's ready for girls he'll be a holy terror.  It's in the blood.  Lookit, how are you fixed for money, Pete? Maybe I can help you out a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>that'll bring me some money...</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm alright. My scholarship covers almost everything, and I sell some photos here and there. Today my physics professor asked for some of my work... he wants to study my data. They might publish my work in the science magazine...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Publish your work?! You hear that May...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, in fact I have to leave a little early tonight, to meet Professor Octavius... He offered me to be his assistant...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Did you hear that May...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Peter, you promised you'd spend the night...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I can't, Aunt May. Professor Octavius wants to discuss my new findings.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter, what you should be finding... is a nice girlfriend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll show them... closing the cyclotron on me... Weiner!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Professor...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he? It's ten past eight o'clock...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>That must be him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll reimburse you.</context>
      <utterance>You are late.  Weiner, go outside and get us something to eat. And don't steal it! Just buy it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want anything Parker?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thank you, I just had dinner at my aunt's...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WEINER leaves. PETER wanders around. He goes into the experimental chamber, he overlooks the SPIDER which is scuttling away and crawls inside the open WINDOW... and into the chamber.</context>
      <utterance>Piss off, Weiner!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okey, dokey, Parker... how would you like to take Weiner's place... I mean, be my assistant?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Professor, that would be a great honor, but I'm already working with...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rosomorf... that imbecile. Don't you understand, kid, that I am about to uncover the greatest discovery since Einstein came up with his theory of relativity... The "Anti-Force."</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow! The theory of the Anti-force! You should go for the Noble Prize Professor...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK begins the experiment. We move in past the shattered WINDOW. We see the SPIDER crawling on the chamber's GEAR.</context>
      <utterance>Noble Shmoble, I am going for a much bigger prize kid. Okey, dokey. Let me show you, kid, what I got here.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Present maximum anti-force power to date is 38 percent of theoretical limit. I have patched in the variable particle-wave accelerator...  I will now try to reach 50% power...  And if your paper has any value... I can use it to get the power I'm missing to create the anti-force, to break through and beat any other form of power in our or any other universe, capish!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK is angry... Ock now sees the SPIDER. He shoots out a WALDO to try and crush it but the SPIDER is too fast. The WALDO slams against the wall of the chamber. He starts to push every button or switch in sight. A deafening whining starts. An URGENT WARNING TONE causes OCK to look at the "Relative Gravity" DIAL. It is at "4.999999KG" but suddenly the numbers start to tumble rapidly. INSERT: The glowing 5KG WEIGHT. INSERT: The POWER DIAL inches toward 50% POWER!</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Professor, I can't do it. I gave my word to Professor Rosomorf.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>50 percent... anti-force... 50 percent... that's all I'm missing! Parker, we can be rich together!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry... I'd better go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another URGENT WARNING TONE causes OCK to look at the monitor SCREEN. On it, flashing RED, is the word, "OVERLOAD!" OCK pushes the RED POWER THROTTLE forward! The WHINE increases to a PULSE and THROB.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be sorry, Parker. PETER leaves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hears the police sirens approaching, he runs away.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God... what happened here...</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I better get out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no danger. Please go back to your dorms. I repeat, there is no danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CROWD closes on THORKEL.</context>
      <utterance>Spill it out, Professor! The public wants to know!</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jameson, Daily Bugle, Chief Editor, now what really happened here?</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This elicits a flood of AD LIBS: "I heard a terrible explosion?" "Nuclear accidents?" "Meltdown?" "Genetic engineering?" "Are you guys making mutants in there?"</context>
      <utterance>There will be a press announcement in the morning Mr. Jameson... now if you'll excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the back of the crowd are PETER, HARRY, LIZ, FLASH and</context>
      <utterance>I have nothing to say... there will be an announcement. Now, please go home... everybody... we must clear the grounds...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think they'll cancel classes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must... the whole building must be contaminated with some kind of poisonous gas.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about nuclear contaminations?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But nobody moves.</context>
      <utterance>My God... lets beat it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could anyone be in there, Peter?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He usually works late...</context>
      <utterance>I don't know... Maybe Professor Octavius.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That nut, I bet it was all his doing...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER pushes forward.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Parker! Peter Parker!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's going on?</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Jameson! What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's for them to know, and for you to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But sir, they wouldn't tell us. You heard Thorkel... he said...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A press announcement tomorrow...! But we must know tonight Parker. This is your university, right...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got your camera?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, but I can't--</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hundred dollars says you can?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get inside and get pictures, fifty bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just said a hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seventy, but I want blood and gore.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dashes off. FLASH shakes his head in dismay at this guy.</context>
      <utterance>Seeya guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he going?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To make fifty bucks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy. Take it easy with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Now we see ROZ and THORKEL following 2 GUARDS carrying OCK in a stretcher. They all wear RADIATION SUITS. A waldo sneaks out from under the sheet and hits Thorkel, as fast as lightning. He falls back. He's covered with a SHEET and attached to LIFE SUPPORT EQUIPMENT. Octavius moans.</context>
      <utterance>Take him away and never bring him back!</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was what?</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What hit me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What hit you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It was so fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER gets off a shot and ducks into the MEN'S room leaving the DOOR ajar for a peak. A WALDO slips down from the SHEET. PETER'S eyes go wide at the sight. What in the hell has happened here?</context>
      <utterance>You're going to be fine, Otto.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER throws the SPIDER to the ripply tile floor where it scuttles unsteadily out the door. Sweat starts to bead on PETER'S face. He shakes his head to clear it. His vision becomes uncertain. He lurches against a WEIRD SINK. PETER'S POV is not just uncertain, not just fuzzy, not just moving in and out anamorphically. It's all of that!</context>
      <utterance>Ow!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel a little funny...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just get out of here...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Well, I ain't laughing. Get out...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get yourself over to the Police lines.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Police lines.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, scoop, whaddaya got?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... got pictures of the Professor... in there... it's so strange in there... so bizarre...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The great, bespangled, NEW YORK CITY is his backdrop as PETER jumps and turns and does loops in the air. With the agility and tactility of a spider, PETER leaps from the RAILING to a WALL to a FLAG POLE to another WALL where he lands sideways and sticks.</context>
      <utterance>Very weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaps off the WALL and lands at the edge of the roof. He looks down. No one's looking back. So, he takes a step back and leaps the alley to the next roof.</context>
      <utterance>Very, very weird.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a kid who's going places, and I'm gonna point you the right way.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Max Reiss, models, strip dancers, escort girls, blue movies...</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(exchanges cards)</context>
      <utterance>Oops... sorry, wrong card.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Max Reiss, Talent management.</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a big outfit. Got a lot of departments.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... well... why you approach me? I'm not...</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes you are... very talented. The three questions of show business success. One do you think you possess a unique talent?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two... what are you gonna do with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three... how much money you got in your pocket?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You invest half of that with me and I'll make you a star.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm talking about fame. I'm talking about fortune. I'm talking about the chance of a lifetime. How'd you like to be on MTV tomorrow night?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MTV...? Me? Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It screeches to a stop.</context>
      <utterance>Taxi!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid! Tomorrow night. Same place, same time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the TAXI roars off...</context>
      <utterance>How do you know I'll show up?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? Aunt May?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter? What time is it? Are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, no, I mean yeah I'm fine, but listen... Aunti, the craziest thing happened to me tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does this have to do with a certain girl we talked about at dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, look, there was this radioactive experiment... I was poisoned!</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was bitten by a bug.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! I get it, you mean a love bug.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... No... A spider...</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter, did you at least talk to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aunt May, listen to me. I got bitten on the hand... by a poisonous spider.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She bit you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I was in the bathroom and...</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you did it in the bathroom? Peter, this is craziness, why don't you use your bed? You're up all night. You're in the radioactive labs. You never take time to eat or sleep. Am I right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Aunt May.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you eat something today?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Aunt May.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Peter go back to bed, and remember we love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Exit booth. He BANGS the PHONE BOOTH. Goes out and-- jumps lightly onto the phone booth roof.</context>
      <utterance>And I love you too, Aunt May.  And by the way, I got a mess of super powers today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CHIEF SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at these brainwave readings. The mental activity is ten times of any normal man...!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAINMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Equipment malfunction...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, yeah... his.  My God... I thought I'd seen everything...</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is so freaky...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You alright?</context>
      <utterance>Nurse! Number seven scalpel. Arthroscope stand by. Read out parameters in progress. Let's go in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... Yes, of course. Everything's online.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slaps a HUGE ONE into his palm. He takes a deep breath and goes to work. MASKED heads gather round him. The SCALPEL is poised at the line where skin meets steel. We make an incision. The INSTRUMENTS go crazy. WARNING BELLS and BUZZERS sound.</context>
      <utterance>Scalpel! No... no... a larger one... the largest we have!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill the alarms!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAINMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WALDO flashes around the steel leg of the operating TABLE and clanks tight!</context>
      <utterance>He's going off the chart!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mop. Mop! Sutures and clamps! Hurry up!</utterance>
   <speaker>SURGEON #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A HEART MACHINE is rushed in. They work frantically.</context>
      <utterance>We're losing him. Defibrillate!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF SURGEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zap him!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAINMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SURGEON 2 applies the CARDIAC SHOCK PADS.</context>
      <utterance>Stabilizing alpha waves...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves OCK and THORKEL alone.</context>
      <utterance>You have a visitor, Doctor...</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Octavius, I'm afraid I have bad news for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cyclotron is damaged...</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What used to be the cyclotron was permanently shut down this afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But my work!</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your work is a disaster! Look at yourself!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Myself? I don't matter. Nobody matters anymore. To enter a new dimension we must first destroy our own...</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK gets off his bed throwing away his sheet waving with his 4 WALDOS and 2 arms.</context>
      <utterance>What are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Destroy life. Life is... insignificant. Bags of sleepy, sluggish flesh. What would you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God, what are those horrible things sticking from your body?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thorkel, if I told you that for one moment in time I broke all the laws! For one brief glorious moment, I broke through to the other side. I saw... I felt... I became creation.</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What on Earth are you rambling about?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Destiny!!! My destiny! I see it all so clearly now. Universal destruction, yes. All I need is the power... then I can destroy this illusion you call life. It is my destiny to lead us to the light!</utterance>
   <speaker>THORKEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a madman.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you are a fool. I will end the universe as you know it. And in that final moment... I'll laugh my ass off while you're kissing yours goodbye!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okey, dokey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MTV Wrestling?!</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAX REISS gets out, he is carrying a BOX.</context>
      <utterance>That's the place. Pay the man.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Mr. Reiss... I'm not real interested in watching a wrestling match.</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who said anything about watching a wrestling match? You're here to win a wrestling match!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REISS hustles PETER inside.</context>
      <utterance>Me? You must be kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hop around. You know, the way you did last night. Your opponent gets tired. He falls down. The ref counts to three, you win, and we pick up a thousand bucks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really gonna love this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, really, I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to know. I know enough for both of us.  Change in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slaps the BOX against PETER'S chest and all but pushes him inside.</context>
      <utterance>A costume... something that fits your talent. Go put it on. I'm sure you'll like it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does it look? I feel like it's Halloween.</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cover your face with the mask.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mystery, my friend. Nobody should know who you are...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RING ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mysterious... Incredible Superman...</context>
      <utterance>And now, a new challenger, for the thousand dollar fight, weighing in at one hundred and fifty pounds... from parts unknown! Here is the Amazing...</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not Superman... Spider-Man...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RING ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CROWD BOOS the slender newcomer who climbs awkwardly through the ropes. Rock music blares. TWIN REDHEADS in RED BIKINIS ring a bell. CRUSHER COLE and SPIDER-MAN circle. COLE is twice SPIDEY'S size. SPIDEY spots a TV CAMERA for the first time. He momentarily freezes. CRUSHER sneers the CRUSHER sneer. Then he charges! With the agility of a spider, SPIDEY leaps out of the way. CRUSHER comes back at him. SPIDEY leaps again, bigger! The acrobatics get more and more dramatic as CRUSHER COLE works himself up into a theatrical rage. Taunts erupt from the CROWD.</context>
      <utterance>...Spider-Man!!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDEY, really getting into it now, begins playing for the</context>
      <utterance>Kill the sucker, Crusher!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HIPSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatsamatter, Crusher, can't you crush that bug?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUSHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He misses SPIDEY again!</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Web Face, this is it!</utterance>
   <speaker>HIPSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(his blondes titter)</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Crusher, you need a insecticide!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you look at this Spider-Man guy! He is absolutely incredible!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liz, get a load of this outfit! I wish I had it for the Halloween party... it's quite sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you two shush. I'm trying to work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One...!</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get up...! Get up...!</utterance>
   <speaker>REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not realizing his own strength and panicky about being squashed, SPIDER-MAN throws CRUSHER COLE off him and up into the air. Way up! Reiss cheers... Spider-Man comes down and knocks CRUSHER for the first time. CRUSHER flies away and out of the arena, eight rows back! The HIPSTER sees CRUSHER coming at him and bolts from his seat. CRUSHER lands on it, in between the TWO BLONDES who break into utter hysterics. SPIDEY, surprised at his own strength, watches CRUSHER land.</context>
      <utterance>Two...!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow...</utterance>
   <speaker>REF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The REF raises his hand in victory. The CROWD BOOS and DEBRIS rains down. But some in the CROWD CHEER wildly, recognizing the new sensation. SPIDER-MAN steps down from the right as REISS leads the</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and Gentlemen, history is made today, we have here the first man to win a thousand dollars against the mighty Crusher.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Max! Am I really gonna get a thousand...</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER turns with REISS and comes face to face with CRUSHER COLE. Two ominous beats.</context>
      <utterance>We are going to get a thousand--</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUSHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, who are you, kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Peter Parker.</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is Spider-Man, and I handle him... Whenever you want a rematch call me. Next time it's gonna be ten thousand, what do you say... Crusher?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, look, Mr. Crusher, I'm really sorry about what happened in there. Really...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRUSHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, well, I don't know what happened to me tonight...  I really don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>REISS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know... you lost. Big man you lost to the Amazing Spider-Man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know who that is?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... he's some clown we saw on TV last night... boy does Flash think he's hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He does...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love wrestling.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrestling is all bluff. Do you really believe this little guy in a stupid Spider-Man suit beat the Crusher?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, we better rush... visiting hours will be over soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hold for a beat. When LIZ takes a step forward to look around we expect the worst. But nothing grabs her. PETER sees a pile of PLASTER on the floor. He looks up and sees the hole in the ceiling. LIZ and HARRY look up too. OCK is not there.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor Octavius? You have visitors. Doctor Octavius?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ock is not here!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God, what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd better call the doctor!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KIM screams.</context>
      <utterance>You'd better call the police!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hears a NOISE behind him and reacts. And here comes WEINER. Bedraggled, shuffling through the CONTROL ROOM door. He eyeballs the incredible wreckage.</context>
      <utterance>What a wreck. What a useless, wasted wreck. Okey, dokey. We rebuild you, my damaged darling. Bigger, better, hotter! A world class, super cyclotron!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK turns, WALDOS writhing. WEINER sees them and kind of ducks, remembering how he was hit by them once.</context>
      <utterance>There you are, doc... where have you been... whoa this place is messed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, doc! You look a little messed up yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where have you been, you imbecile?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went to the wrestling...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrestling...</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went after the kid. You still want that Parker guy's data, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, did you get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I followed him... but I lost him in the crowd.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lost him? You--</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>soon... maybe by tomorrow.</context>
      <utterance>I'll find him, Maestro... I promise...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how was the wrestling?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fantastic! There was this new wrestler... beat the mighty Crusher. You won't believe it... a nothing of a guy... calls himself this stupid name... the Amazing Spider-Man... would you believe it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly OCK throws out his WALDOS from under his long white coat, grabs WEINER and, lifts him up in the air, smiles cynically and with cruelty!</context>
      <utterance>Spider-Man, huh? Well, maybe I'll just go and wrestle myself one of these days... with all my new arms... I'm sure I can beat Crusher or any other monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will I beat him, this Crusher, will I beat him or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Please... I'll do anything for you...</context>
      <utterance>No... no, please... I mean yes, yes... you'll beat him easily... let me down...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Parker data... get me the Parker data, you hear?!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>REVERSE ANGLE - CAMERA'S POV.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SPIDER-MAN is clinging to the side of a WALL.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WHITE EYES narrow to a slit. CLICK. Suddenly he spots WEINER climbing onto his roof. He hides. WEINER tiptoes into the roof apartment. SPIDER-MAN jumps in and grabs him.</context>
      <utterance>And one like this...  And one looking real sincere.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for Peter Parker.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDER-MAN throws him back onto the roof so that he almost slides over the edge. WEINER turns, facing SPIDER-MAN.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes... so why not use the front door?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I know you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw you crushing the Crusher.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDER-MAN jumps and reaches WEINER.</context>
      <utterance>You like wrestling?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDER-MAN picks up WEINER, throws him up to an antenna above the building, to which WEINER clings desperately. SPIDER-MAN circles the antenna.</context>
      <utterance>I love it! You are the best wrestler I have ever seen... please don't hurt me!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, please... don't kill me. Please help me down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I'll help you down. I am Spider-Man... the good guy, am I not?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDER-MAN jumps to the CHIMNEY, picks WEINER up in his arms and whispers to him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... yes, you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDER-MAN jumps with WEINER in his arms to the edge of the roof.</context>
      <utterance>And by the way, Peter Parker does not live here anymore...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDER-MAN drops WEINER off the roof, three floors straight down into heavy bushes below.</context>
      <utterance>And tell the Professor he can't have Peter's data. Goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy cow, whattaya building, fella, a cyclotron?  Okay... lets see here. Page three. We got 30,000 feet of 50-gauge copper co-ax... twin 550 XK transformers... cadmium accelerator rails, a half dozen... a GBC relative multi-phase transducer... and one yellow thermos.  That'll be $475,989.65...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrap it up...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the money... or do you pay by credit card?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cash! I'll be back soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BANK GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WALDO knocks him over. OCK rips the DOOR off! The TRUCK is full of MONEY BAGS.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cash!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look, he's flying in the air!</context>
      <utterance>Doesn't he look amazing in that one?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care if he flies to the moon. He's just another wrestler in a silly costume. Look at this, Parker, right off the wire. This is the guy who hit that armored truck this morning. They say he has metal arms... get me a picture of this character!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Metal arms?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ock...?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The web faced weirdo... He is a joke in a Halloween costume... don't make me laugh. He tears up PETER'S SPIDEY PHOTOS.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now get out of here and don't come back without something I can use!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(stops, and turns back)</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A mega baloney... A bug in blue tights... what next?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Journal said he was a mega-smash on</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WALDO whips around WEINER'S throat... AARRRGH!</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to the Masquerade. It's Halloween tonight Doc, aren't you coming to the School Ball? Whoa, you could go without an outfit.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to any ball, clown. You're going to get me Peter Parker's data...</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look at all these bruises...</context>
      <utterance>I was almost killed on my last try...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care if you come back dead. Just get it!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WALDO coils tighten around WEINER'S throat.</context>
      <utterance>Cost you a thousand bucks, if I get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right... boss please let go...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should have worn a costume. I told you to wear a costume.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's... embarrassing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIZ is crossing the dance floor dressed as an INDIAN PRINCESS in an MINI-DRESS.</context>
      <utterance>There's Liz...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROZ, dressed as a COWBOY, ambles over.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... howdy partners.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER/HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Professor Rosomorf.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any word on Doctor Octavius?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You boys must have had an extraordinary classroom experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir... oh... I'm going to be a little late with my paper on the Planetary Conjunction, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whenever you're ready... I'll look at it. I know it's going to be an important work... and Peter, take my hat. He hands PETER an oversized TEN GALLON HAT.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER and HARRY make their way through the dance floor to the table. PETER can't take his eyes off SPIDEY.</context>
      <utterance>It is a costume party.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, there's Spider-Man!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the real one, I'm sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can never be sure... all kinds of crazy stuff can happen at a masquerade ball...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they take seats, PETER sees that SPIDER-MAN is trying to read the BUGLE'S sports section by party light. KIM waves. PETER nods and the BIG HAT falls over his face.</context>
      <utterance>I bet I know who it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIZ moves to Flash, who's dressed in the SPIDER-MAN costume.</context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Liz...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Peter. Who is in the Spider-Man costume?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a very clever outfit you've got there, Flash.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a hike, asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you recognize him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His pretty blue eyes give him away...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, who'll be sitting with you at the Halloween Ball?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna dance... Hey, Spider-Man... Shall we Flash dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH/SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIZ turns with a mild pout. Nervously, PETER ponders his chance. HARRY nudges him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm reading the paper, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HARRY turns to KIM and does a clanking shimmy in the SPACE</context>
      <utterance>Take her now, it's easy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna dance, Schechrezaa?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pooped.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches for HARRY'S hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy jumping jelly beans, willya look at these pictures of Spider-Man? Wow! Is this guy great or what? LIZ looks. She shrugs. Then she shrieks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Peter! These are your pictures!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't be...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER reacts, then looks over FLASH'S other shoulder. INSERT: There are three PHOTOS of SPIDER-MAN in the paper. PETER BLUSHES, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>It says here "Photos by Peter Parker."</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know this guy, Parker?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah... sort of...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow... I'll give you anything if you introduce us.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIZ joins him provocatively.</context>
      <utterance>Will you grant me this dance...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Flash-Man... Wanna dance...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER is left alone, PETER leaves toward the entrance. At the REAR DOOR a BIG LIZARD passes a NOTE to a DALLAS COWGIRL who passes it to a KANGAROO. The KANGAROO hops across the dance floor to the STAGE where he hands the NOTE to a YOUNG WOMAN in a BASEBALL UNIFORM. She climbs the STAGE where she is bathed in a SPOTLIGHT. She gets a DRUM ROLL from the band. There are some BOOS as the bad stops.</context>
      <utterance>Well, why not.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>mouths, "Me?" (The REAL) SPIDEY drops from the ceiling and lands in a pose. The CROWD cheers. He does a flip to LIZ and extends a hand. The BAND starts up. LIZ demurs.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, thank you. We have a special surprise guest tonight.  The Empire State University Masquerade Ball presents... The "Slammy" winning star of MTV'S wrestling tournament... The Amazing Spider-Man! FLASH, amazed turns to LIZ. He points to himself and</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIZ takes SPIDEY'S hand and they move slowly and sexily onto the dance floor. They do a short simple number. SPIDEY returns LIZ to FLASH.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead... go ahead!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One day you'll know...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sound very familiar.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER/SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jumps away and disappears, leaving the CROWD aghast and LIZ in love.</context>
      <utterance>Sure I do... I'm your friendly neighborhood Spider-Man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, May. Wake up and go to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Can't you go any faster?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'm I in, a race?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I get this tingling in my brain, like some danger is lurking just ahead. I'm worried about Aunt May and Uncle Ben...</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your family?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they are kind of my parents. They raised me. I lost both of my parents in a car accident... please step on it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Step on it... so now you want to kill yourself in another accident... not with me, Boychick.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm telling you... I've got this--</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... tingling... I know. And I got ulcers... Everybody's got something to worry about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please... Faster... Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, you asked for it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? It's nothing... go back to sleep...  Oh, I'll go look. Go back to sleep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some crazy kinda town, huh? You hear about that hold-up? The guy with the six arms? Hey, I see it all on this job.  What kinda outfit is that, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm really in a hurry. BANG! A BLOW OUT. The CABBIE fights the wheel to the side of the road. Then he turns to SPIDEY.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said the magic words, we have a flat Boychick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up to see SPIDEY go by, stuck to the side of the TRUCK like a spider.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! You wanna hand me that lug wrench?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some crazy kinda town...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I want it the kid's computer crap!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go before I blow your brain's out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You let go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uncle Ben!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER rushes to BEN.</context>
      <utterance>Peter...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER tries to revive BEN, while WEINER runs out.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God... Uncle Ben...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AUNT MAY and PETER embrace, leaning on each other for support.</context>
      <utterance>Ben gets through everything. He'll be alright. The doctors are...</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER rises, nods. As AUNT MAY wipes away a sniffle...</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. You the nephew?</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your uncle's a brave man. Apparently, the perpetrator was after something of yours. Your uncle didn't know what it was but he stood up to him anyway. You ought to be proud of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A grim-faced DOCTOR walks slowly across the room to them... MAY stands up slowly.</context>
      <utterance>I am... how is he...</utterance>
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask the Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's my... how's my husband doing...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MAY collapses.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Parker, I'm sorry. We tried.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Detective pulls PETER gently away. The STAFF works on</context>
      <utterance>Crash cart! STAT!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DETECTIVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let the medics handle it.  Look, if it makes you feel any better. We're gonna nail this guy. He crashed his getaway car. We got him trapped in a warehouse on Jackson.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's alright. She just fainted. We'll have to check her for symptoms of shock. If you want to wait, you can get some coffee on the third floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I... I think I wanna go out for some fresh air.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That place is loaded with solvents and chemicals. If we blast our way in, it's gonna go up like a roman candle.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could go in through the fifth floor wash room.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COP 1 directs the BEAM of the SEARCHLIGHT.</context>
      <utterance>What's that up there? Throw a light on that!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COP #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got an accomplice up there! And we got a clear shot. Do we have a go?</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WEINER whips around and fires. SPIDEY leaps to avoid it and lands on a STACK of PAINT CANS.</context>
      <utterance>Say your prayers, Weiner!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDEY gathers himself tighter. He leaps. A second GUN BURST comes in behind him, Several PAINT CANS erupt in cascades of COLOR.</context>
      <utterance>You ain't takin' me... Spider-Man... who ever you are...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WEINER aims and fires, several times. He is emptying his RIFLE. SPIDEY leaps away and lands on the top of a CASK marked "CAUTION-FLAMMABLE SOLVENT!"</context>
      <utterance>Hey, creep!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CASK gives way and SPIDEY is plunged into the FLAMMABLE SOLVENT. WEINER smiles his stupid grin and takes aim. SPIDEY leaps out of the CASK and sticks to the roof BEAM. He's sopping wet. His hand slips down the BEAM as the SOLVENT works against his sticking power. He falls to the floor and scrambles behind some PAINT CANS. WEINER, crazed, fires wildly. One of the CANS EXPLODES. PAINT flows from it... burning! SPIDEY peeks out and sees a YELLOW RIVER OF FLAME creeping toward him. He sniffs his SOLVENT soaked outfit. He backs down a "corridor" of PAINT CANS. The YELLOW FIRE follows, now joined by a RIVER OF BLUE FIRE from another can. They're following the trail of SOLVENT he's dripping! He's trapped!</context>
      <utterance>Try again.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whoa... stay back down there! SPIDEY is inches from being torched. He sees a PIPE. He reaches out and grabs it. He swings out above the flames. But the PIPE begins to bend! The PIPE bends down... down... and then breaks! SPIDEY hangs precariously as WATER cascades out of the PIPE and puts out the FIRE. SPIDEY drops down and rest his head in his hands to collect himself. Then looks up. The GUN is at his head.</context>
      <utterance>Stay back!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDEY stands.</context>
      <utterance>Stand up, you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have thirty seconds to come out!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDER-MAN hesitates. Then he begins to raise the MASK, but stops and shakes his head no.</context>
      <utterance>You're my ticket outa here. Gimme that stupid mask!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for the mask and SPIDER-MAN flips him across the room. WEINER lands in a CARGO net and becomes ensnared.</context>
      <utterance>Then I'll take it myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, look what we've caught in our web...</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't hurt me, man. Please don't hurt me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WEINER is hanging from the ceiling in the the CARGO NET.</context>
      <utterance>Hold your fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He falls down, immediately encircled by the POLICE OFFICERS. SPIDER-MAN flies above their heads, crashing through the WINDOW and disappears into the dark of night.</context>
      <utterance>Get me out of this madhouse!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shuts it down. The WHINE whirs down.</context>
      <utterance>Amperage, okay. Flux, 14. Negative variable differential... good enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK hides the WALDOS under his coat and leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>Okey, dokey... now all I need is Parker's data. Where the hell is Weiner? Damn it... I can't trust anybody.  Only you, my babies... only you can I trust... Okay... If I have to do everything myself... I'm going to do it.  I'll be back... my babies... my new babies!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Peter! Are you finished with my computer yet? I got a paper too, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hides his SPIDER-MAN COSTUME.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God... oh, it's you, Liz... I didn't expect you... uh... give me a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Liz. Come on in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were you doing in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cleaning up. Come on. I'll get your computer. Where's Flash parked? He picks up the COMPUTER and turns to her, but she's already looking around the apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flash didn't come.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIZ walks into the room.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well... how are you going to get it home?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She discovers the PRINTS of SPIDEY that PETER has taped up around the apartment.</context>
      <utterance>Taxi... I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER looks and sees that he is tethered to the wall. Embarrassed, he puts the COMPUTER back down.</context>
      <utterance>You must spend a lot of time with this Spider-Man guy... Peter! Don't you think you ought to unplug that!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is about to open the door when FOUR WALDOS smash through it, obliterating it. OCK stands in the shattered doorway, WALDOS writhing.</context>
      <utterance>Peter...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor Octavius...! You're... You're...  You're so weird!... with those... what do you call those...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waldos... Did you hear about Spider-Man?  That's me... the real Spider-Man... now tell me, where is that jerky friend of yours... Parker?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't think he'll be back for awhile.</context>
      <utterance>Peter?... oh... he's not here. He's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't lie to your Professor now, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not. Why would I lie about a thing like that? Really. He's... out.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK grabs LIZ'S HAIR with his WALDOS.</context>
      <utterance>We'll wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing... let me go! Please... take those things out of my hair!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Waldos, you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK shoots out TWO WALDOS. Simultaneously each grabs a CHAIR from different parts of the room and brings them to the TABLE.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever you call them... please...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does. He does, too, and folds his WALDOS across his chest.</context>
      <utterance>Sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a nice boy. A little nerdy maybe, but nice, wouldn't you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ONE of OCK'S WALDOS rests on the TABLE curled around the COMPUTER. LIZ lets her hand rest on it. OCK warms immediately.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know. Maybe. He's very inexperienced.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, you're a fascinating young lady...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're so refreshing. You're so...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shocking...?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I wouldn't say shocking...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sticks his WALDO in the ELECTRIC WALL SOCKET behind the COMPUTER! The CURRENT sizzles through him and he leaps up, WALDOS akimbo, like the "cartoon cat." LIZ runs out the door. OCK extricates himself from the current and gives chase.</context>
      <utterance>I would!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks both ways for PETER, doesn't see him, and takes off! OCK bursts from the doorway and runs off after LIZ.</context>
      <utterance>Peter...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait here...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liz?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PETER springs into action. He grabs his SPIDEY SUIT out of a drawer and starts taking off his clothes.</context>
      <utterance>Peter! Help! Peter!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>OCK looks across the street. There, on the top of a tall building, is SPIDER-MAN.</context>
      <utterance>Put her down, Ock.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what's happening to you, Ock. I've been through a lot of changes myself lately. You have to listen to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spider-Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spider-Man...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lot of crap, clown... I am Spider-Man, not you.  Ask you girlfriend.  Tell him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK thinks for a moment, then he begins to extend the kicking and screaming LIZ out over the street, ten stories up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a good friend of Peter Parker's Ock. Just like that girl you're holding. Now let her go.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let her go? What an excellent idea. If you do not deliver your friend, Mr. Spider-Man, yes. Yes, of course, I'll let her go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIZ is having none of this. She kicks, she fights. She twists. She flails around, making things a little worse. The ground is yawning death beneath her. RRIIPP! PART of her BLOUSE tears away and LIZ plummets! SPIDER-MAN swoops down on a WEB-STRAND in his characteristic compound curve. He reaches out for the falling LIZ and misses her cleanly. The WEB is too short.</context>
      <utterance>Put me down, you mechanical mutant!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He THWIPS her with a second WEB and together they swing to a HIGH GIRDER where he deposits her safe and sound.</context>
      <utterance>You jerk!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell your friend Peter next time I'll get the taxi myself...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Octavius. Just stop and think.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am thinking, insect. I'm thinking about exterminating you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WALDO lances out and catches SPIDEY flush on the jaw. It knocks him to another GIRDER. SPIDEY hangs on and rolls over. He rubs his jaw.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, if that's the way you want it... Let's see what those chrome knuckles can do, Doc...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDEY gets ready to go into action and gets pummeled by another barrage of blows from above.</context>
      <utterance>Great...</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK throws a roundhouse WALDO that nearly knocks SPIDEY off the GIRDER. He's just barely hanging on. But SPIDER-MAN'S not done yet. He THWIPS a HIGH BEAM and swings into a better attack position. The two SUPER- ADVERSARIES engage in battle. With OCK swinging from his WALDOS like a metal monkey and SPIDEY swinging from his WEBS like, well, like SPIDEY, they clang and bang through the GIRDERS of the</context>
      <utterance>Now I must kill you, you cretinous clown.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once I dispose of you, Spider-Man, no one will be able to stop me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop you from what...?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK throws his biggest punch yet. SIRENS can now be heard in the street. SPIDEY avoids WALDO strike after WALDO strike. OCK eludes WEB after WEB. But SPIDEY'S agility soon has him turning circles.</context>
      <utterance>My destiny!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over here, Octopus!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Professor Octopus to you Spider Jerk!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK takes three steps and soars through the air.</context>
      <utterance>Give it up, Professor. You'll never catch me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There he is!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's that Spider-Man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that SPIDEY leaps way out and he and LIZ swoop away on a WEB-STRAND.</context>
      <utterance>I'm rescuing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks but nooooooooooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He won't get away this time!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold your fire! He's got a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like he's got a hostage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDEY hounded by the Police, rejected by the girl.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. Where are you taking me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoots out another WEB.</context>
      <utterance>I better just take you back where you belong.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on tight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are standing on the ROOF of the CENTRAL TOWER of the EMPIRE UNIVERSITY BUILDING. LIZ opens her eyes. It's an extraordinary sight.</context>
      <utterance>Open your eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>put me down.</context>
      <utterance>If you're trying to impress me Spidey, I want you to know I'm not easy. Okay, I'm impressed... now put me down, Spidey...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like the way you say Spidey... Nobody calls me Spidey... now we go...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>there's Flash, if I'm not mistaken.</context>
      <utterance>Wow... look, this is our dormitory. I can get to my room. Hey, wait a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liz?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know my name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liz, listen to me. There's something I have to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, put me down and we can talk, alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know who I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I know is you're the Amazing Spider-Man... or better you're Spidey the good guy on the block... you're a weirdo in a clown spider suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's all you know about me?  Okay, lets get your boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many do you have? I meant Flash.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Flash is not exactly my boyfriend...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not? Then who is?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's someone I like, but he's too shy to notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flash!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(a beat)</context>
      <utterance>Liz!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, they won't let up, man!  They keep calling you an accomplice in that burglary murder. But that's a crock, ain't it? I'm with you, Spidey, 100%</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liz?</context>
      <utterance>By the way, what are you doing with...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She needed a lift.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... okay! This calls for a beer! A lot of beer!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, but I have some business to take care of.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He disappears. LIZ comes, tentatively, to the WINDOW where SPIDEY squats, desire and passion in his WHITE EYES.</context>
      <utterance>Well... take care of that later. Wait here. I'll get the beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you know this was Flash's place?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter Parker told me all about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter told you all about Flash?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he jumps away)</context>
      <utterance>No... he told me all about you. See you later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But SPIDER-MAN has disappeared.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, where'd he go? Hey, Spider-Man!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter told your Hero all about me...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He would, wouldn't he... that jerk!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kim! Have you seen Harry?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, lots of times. What a brainiac...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... have you seen him today?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, un unh.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter...!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi... have you seen Harry?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. What a night, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that was some ride home... must have been pretty exciting.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was... okay. Look, I got two tickets to Les Miserables... wanna go?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry... I'm really busy... I mean, not tonight... see you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Peter... how did you know about last night...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My exciting ride with Spider-Man...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... Sorry... I gotta hurry... I have to find Harry... I'll see you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PETER runs off. He sees a car approach and flags it.</context>
      <utterance>Peter!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Can I get a lift downtown?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLASH gets out of his car, and crosses the lawn toward</context>
      <utterance>Take your shoes for a walk, Dork.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSERT: The COMPUTER SCREEN displays Peter Parker's name and ID number and the title, "The Planetary Conjunction and it's effect on Earth Gravity."</context>
      <utterance>We are new inserting Peter Parker's data on tonight's Planetary Conjunction.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSERT: NUMBER SEQUENCES appear on the SCREEN. Then a GRAPHIC of the EARTH moving into line with SATURN, JUPITER, the SUN and the MOON. In the corner a NUMBER rises.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes! Go on! Go on!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Parker calculations add 4% gravitational force at the moment of full Planetary Conjunction. (hits some keys) Adding this to present maximum power potential, I get... He looks up and sees the SCREEN a GRAPHIC "HOLE" opening up right through the EARTH! The widening HOLE is swallowing everything!</context>
      <utterance>Enormous. It's enormous.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A LARGE DIGITAL DISPLAY reads, "13:00:03." The last seconds count down to, "12:59:59!"</context>
      <utterance>I knew it. I knew it! Universal destruction! It's doable! I am putting a countdown clock on the Planetary Conjunction now!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts hitting KEYS on his COMPUTER.</context>
      <utterance>Okey, dokey. Now let's see if I have enough power to drive this beast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta remember to have that fixed.  There you are, I've been looking for you all over town.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went to the wrestling, wanted to see that Amazing Spider-Man, but he didn't show up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Harry something terrible happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Planetary Conjunction papers... they were stolen...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God... Are you sure...? Who would do such a thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ock...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course... but why...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to find out, sit down.  I want to access Dr. Octavius' main program. I want to know about his experiments with the cyclotron. Can you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can try. I could access the system in the dorm. Okay. And through that I could crack the main line.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. Now if we can just disrupt the Octavius file...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HARRY cracks his knuckles like a safe cracker and bends to the task. The PHONE RINGS. PETER hits his jerry-rigged SPEAKER PHONE. HARRY keeps hacking.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's try.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Parker? Peter Parker? This is J. Jonah Jameson!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Jameson, you got me at a bad time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>PETER hangs up. The DIAL TONE cuts off JAMESON.</context>
      <utterance>I need pictures of your friend, the Amazing Spider-Man. But I need bad guy shots, you got it? Lots of bad guy shots. We're gonna pin that insect to the wall. Whaddaya say?</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about that kid? On the job already?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSERT: DIGITAL CLOCK display: "06:00:03"</context>
      <utterance>Got something!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me see. It's some kind of countdown clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Countdown to what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but whatever it is, it's only six hours away.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Planetary Conjunction?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or Doc Ock's end of the world experiment... Or both!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. You're not telling me you think the world is gonna end tonight...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to wait around till midnight to find out?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another set of numbers roll up on the SCREEN. They are accompanied by ELECTRICAL SYMBOLS.</context>
      <utterance>Let's see what else we've got.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It might be a calculation of the amount of power he needs to create the hole between the force and the anti-force.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lot of energy. What could generate power like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, the lights flicker and then dim and they return.</context>
      <utterance>The closest you could come is the New York City Subway System.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY/PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta talk to Professor Rosomorf!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The signs EXPLODE! The COUPLE stops in their tracks. The BOY looks at the GIRL.</context>
      <utterance>Make up your mind!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ARC of ELECTRICITY now shoots between the LIGHT PILLARS of the SUBWAY STATION on the corner.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get back! Get back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several PASSENGERS climb out of the WINDOWS of the TRAIN or pry open the DOORS.</context>
      <utterance>Henry!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here? Get out of here! Get out of here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Spider-Man!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUCK DRIVER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get outa here, you bum!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what are you talking about?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go Spidey! Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slides the WINDOW down and flips inside. He walks through the parting PASSENGERS to the BUILDING WALL. He feels it.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, everybody...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurls himself at the fused GLASS portion and bounces back onto the floor. He rolls over, flexing his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, everyone, stand back and stay cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>First the WOMAN, and then all of them, take up positions on the BATTERING RAM.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody wanna give me a hand with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They ram the GLASS and it shatters.</context>
      <utterance>On three. One... Two... Three!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Come on. That's it. Step lively now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry, the rugs!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a nice evening, Ma'am... and you too, Henry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He scampers down the GRAB-HANDLES to the people below. FOUR PASSENGERS cling to SEATS and BARS.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, folks, just hang on...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A FAT WOMAN makes a "who me?" gesture. SPIDEY throws her over his shoulder. INSERT: THE COUPLING which holds the two CARS at right angles begins to bend open. SPIDER-MAN, the FAT WOMAN over his shoulder, goes hand over hand to the top and the WOMAN is dumped into the</context>
      <utterance>Okay, one at a time. You first, Ma'am...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIDDLE CAR.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDEY helps the TEENAGER and the SKINNY GIRL out of the CAR. She takes the dreadful step between cars. She looks down. She screams. She steps across.</context>
      <utterance>INSERT: THE COUPLING bends open a little more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FIREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme more ladder! I need more ladder!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative on that, you're at full extension!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Doctor Otto Octavius' work. I must get back to my university. I must stop Ock... he's gone crazy. Can you help me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Come on... give me your hand.</context>
      <utterance>Sure thing, just don't take the train.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The COUPLING shrieks and the CAR lurches.</context>
      <utterance>Spider-Man! Listen to me! If he can do this with the train, if he's come this far, then I can pretty well predict his next step. He'll go to Plutonium SL 270 for the power. He must be stopped... or else he'll destroy our world.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get you out of here first, Professor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait Spider-Man. I don't think I can make it... You mustn't waste time saving me... you must save the world! You must go and stop Ock!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where can I find him...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CAR lurches on its side and ROZ flies out of the DOOR. SPIDEY THWIPS out a WEB that girdles ROZ'S waist.</context>
      <utterance>He is looking for Plutonium SL 270 I'm sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think Rosomorf, think where one can find Plutonium? Where could he find SL 270...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's only one place he can get the Plutonium SL 270...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDEY swings ROZ in an arc to the FIREMAN. He misses ROZ on the first pass. ROZ looks up at SPIDEY who stands in the doorway, manipulating the WEB. The FIREMAN grabs ROZ. Then, with an awful SCREECH of steel, the CAR pulls loose from the COUPLING. With SPIDER-MAN inside it, the CAR plunges ten stories to the street below.</context>
      <utterance>Toxic... toxic dump... any toxic dump would have SL 270.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put your hands up, Spider-Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're making a big mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDER-MAN shoots a WAD of WEB GOO onto the COP'S GUN and leaps up onto the LUXURY CONDO... and swings up out of the frame. The COP aims and shoots. The BULLET makes a THWUMP noise. The WEB GOO stretches out about three feet and falls limp.</context>
      <utterance>And you're looking at twenty years.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're as lovely as Peter said you were.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. He really wanted so badly to come see you. He called me up out of the blue.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about Peter. What's he been up to? He seems so preoccupied.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you know Peter... he's all caught up in some kind of study he's doing. Things are really crazy at the university now. Things are crazy... everywhere. I guess Peter's just... well, you know... pulled into his shell.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When Peter was little, he loved to hide. In the closets. Under the sink. He always needed a secret place. But when I'd look for him, he'd always laugh... he wanted to be found.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>My friend Flash is picking me up.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... well. I don't think he wants me to find him... Well, I'd better be going.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Flash... he isn't your boyfriend, is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... not really... I think you can guess why... They smile knowingly at each other. LIZ goes toward the DOOR.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finders keepers, losers weepers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>AUNT MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I used to say to Peter when I found him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down at the traffic. We PAN across the many CARS until we come to a non-descript GREEN CAR.</context>
      <utterance>Got to find Ock... got to find the toxic dumps.  Oh! Oh! Oh... yeah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up, Ock?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WALDO smashes through the WINDSHIELD but misses SPIDEY. OCK leaps from the CAR.</context>
      <utterance>You!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a doomed bug, Wall Crawler. I've no time to waste on you now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you big OCK, why don't you pick on someone your own size?!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK leaves the COP and attacks SPIDER-MAN, shooting his iron fist at him. OCK runs to the end of the alley. SPIDEY staggers to his feet and resumes the chase. OCK breaks into a red Corvette convertible, starting it with a WALDO. SPIDER-MAN comes out in time to see the Vette drive away. A CHINESE LAUNDRY TRUCK is passing. SPIDEY THWIPS it and is whipped away. He crawls over to the WINDOW.</context>
      <utterance>Alright Spider-Bug... here I've come for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The surprised CHINAMAN lets loose a stream of CHINESE expletives, complete with appropriate suggestive gestures. SPIDER-MAN crawls to the top of the TRUCK and surveys the situation. He sees a sea of moving traffic. He THWIPS up a WEB and swings away. SPIDEY swings along from BUILDING to BUILDING. The RED VETTE is making headway. Suddenly, SPIDER-MAN spots a blue MG with its top up.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, driver. Could you follow that red Vette for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flash Thompson... I never thought I'd be happy to see you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about that!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spider-man! This is unbelievable...!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flash, I need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You any good with this thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... catch that Vette!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swerves. SPIDEY falls all over LIZ. They begin to careen through traffic, three peas in a very small pod.</context>
      <utterance>Roger, wilco, over and out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is he going to New Jersey, and who is it in that shitty red car...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you recognize him... it's Ock!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New Jersey has the largest toxic waste dump in the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does he want with toxic waste?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car has to slow down... it's in a traffic jam.</context>
      <utterance>He's looking for Plutonium, my dear...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDER-MAN jumps out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry... can't do anything about this traffic.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Speeding along the BRIDGE, OCK sees no one. But high above, SPIDEY swings from TOWER to TOWER after him. At the last TOWER, SPIDEY leaps down onto a BIG TRUCK. The VETTE weaves and SPIDEY crosses to another BIG TRUCK. For a moment he is caught between the TWO TRUCKS, but he makes it across. The VETTE takes an exit. SPIDEY leaps to the next SIGN. He aims his WRIST GIZMO and waits for the next car to take the exit, but none does. Deflated, he drops to the ground. He looks up to see a sign on a CYCLONE FENCE. It says, "DUMP NUMBER 7 -- KEEP OUT -- RADIOACTIVE MATERIAL!"</context>
      <utterance>Try to stay with me. I don't want to lose him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bingo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okey, dokey...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open that now, and you'll spoil Christmas. SPIDEY'S peering in from a HOLE in the ROOF.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK hurls a DRUM at SPIDEY. It erupts in a sizzle of LIQUID and GAS. Then the SIX-ARMED FIEND runs for the door with his SL 270.</context>
      <utterance>Insect! I am going to squash you to death... Once I lay my Waldos on your skinny bones...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets a hold and slides down to within a foot of the POOL. Its weird light shines up at him. He looks up at the starry sky.</context>
      <utterance>Noooooooooooooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Empty... now what do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you've avoided the nuclear pool, have you, Spider-Man?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, so far so good. But I can't hold on much longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pity...!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on, Ock, be a good sport. Let's talk this over face to face... throw me a line... SPIDEY reaches out.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK, way up at the opening above, raises a huge DRUM above his head. The DRUM leaks toxic waste in ORANGE TENDRILS. He is about to drop it down on SPIDER-MAN...</context>
      <utterance>Okay... face to face... Catch this!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We now see FLASH and LIZ in the BLUE MG.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do it, Professor!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you... and you, young lady. Both of you are in my physic class, aren't you...? Come... you can help me. I need to get some of these drums to my laboratory... help me... and I'll give you special grades. What'd you say? Suddenly he catches FLASH with a WALDO and starts to choke him. LIZ screams and tries to help FLASH.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROZ now appears on the scene.</context>
      <utterance>Leave him alone!!! Another WALDO grabs her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave them alone Otto!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another WALDO grabs ROZ by his arm.</context>
      <utterance>But, they won't help me. Everybody is trying to destroy my experiment. And so are you, Rosomorf.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Otto... I was wrong. I've gone over your research. It's brilliant, Otto. It's mad, but it's brilliant. You have much work left to do. I want to help you, Otto. For the sake of science, go and do your experiment. Leave... these kids alone and I'll help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both FLASH and LIZ shake their heads okey dokey. OCK gestures to FLASH and LIZ.</context>
      <utterance>You will? You too?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help me with these drums, I need to get them to my laboratory immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK pushes FLASH and LIZ with his iron arm. Gripping LIZ be her hair, he shoves her into the CAR.</context>
      <utterance>Do as he says.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drive, Flash, before I flush your girl right down the toilet!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROSOMORF finds a rope and looks into the well.</context>
      <utterance>Professor Rosomorf, it's no good, double dealing... why did you help him...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't lose your energy screaming. Catch this rope and climb up, come on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been through the Octavius data. He has enough power with his Plutonium. Especially if he gets his hands on Parker's data, there he has enough power to do what he wants to do. And we are not going to stop him in time before the Planetary Conjunction occurs tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're in the middle of RIVERSIDE DRIVE but a PHONE BOOTH is coming up on the right. INSERT: ROZ'S foot stabs the BRAKE.</context>
      <utterance>Stop the car. I have an idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Harry?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter, where are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSERT: The COMPUTER SCREEN displays a graphic of the SUN, EARTH, and MOON lining up with JUPITER and SATURN.</context>
      <utterance>Your Planetary Conjunction data? It's too late... Ock's got your paper, it's in his computer already.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But don't worry... he can never use it without Plutonium.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got the Plutonium, and he's on his way back to the lab! And he's got two prisoners with him... Liz and Flash!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry... he needs a huge amount of power... thousands of volts of electricity... to get to the Anti-Force.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can get to the power. Electrical power... to the max. Nuclear power... SL 270. And now, at the moment of full Planetary Conjunction. When all the planets line up with the sun... maximum gravitational power. The Conjunction is Ock's final power source.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn... the Conjunction is due at midnight! What are we going to do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK leaves. LIZ and FLASH are tied together in the back seat of the CAR.</context>
      <utterance>Okey, dokey... have fun, young ones... for the last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We kiss the world goodbye. If he is right, all there is left to do is...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait... I think I can release my right hand...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I can get some help... I can teach anyone how to work a code in five minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then do it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all run from COMPUTER to COMPUTER.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, this is easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Harry I need help.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HARRY types in KARNAKY LTD and gets the same response. He looks at his DIGITAL WRISTWATCH. "01:00:02" becomes "00:59:59" as we watch. Then a WARNING BUZZER!</context>
      <utterance>Coming!</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got one! I got one!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HARRY hurries to KIM'S side and elbows her out of the CHAIR. The SCREEN is flashing "WARNING, Security Breach!" HARRY'S hands fly over the keys. The KIDS gather around. LINE DRAWINGS of the CYCLOTRON (progressing from large to small detail) appear one after the other. Finally, a PIPE. There is a CIRCLE around a JOINT. And the legend</context>
      <utterance>Harry! Get over here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A goddamn water leak...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, look at this. Empire State University. This is our cyclotron, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it say?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says "no information on net."</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn... we can't do it...</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean... we can't stop loony Ock...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean the world is in danger...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must find Peter, he knows these computers better than all of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but where the hell is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the lights dim. A heavy noise. An earth quake.</context>
      <utterance>I bet he is with Spider-Man...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at the moon... I have never seen it so big.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that...</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We now see the sky. With the sun on one side, and the moon on the other. They watch it, shocked, frightened out of their wits.</context>
      <utterance>Must be the sun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look across the campus and a strange LIGHT is coming out of the SCIENCE CENTER.</context>
      <utterance>It's started. Step on it Professor, or we'll never make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDER-MAN massages his arm.</context>
      <utterance>Our campus... right there... see those beams from Ock's lab. We're late... it's coming... the Conjunction will happen in a few seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop the car...! Come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDER-MAN SHOOTS out a WEB and flies toward the SCHOOL BUILDING taking ROZ with him.</context>
      <utterance>Where...? What...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aha! You never included the Conjunction in your calculations, did you?! Rosomorf!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn the calculations! My God, Otto, you have to hear me! The world we know will collapse! Everything we have devoted our lives to... all the patterns, all the harmonies... everything will be destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A new world waits! Rosomorf! It is my destiny!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ROZ flings himself through the MELTED WINDOW into the EXPERIMENTAL CHAMBER. He grabs for the "BULLET" but the WALDOS grab him and throw him back. ROZ staggers backward... into the arms of SPIDER-MAN.</context>
      <utterance>It is cosmic suicide! You have no right!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to stop him... Spider-Man you have to stop him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDER-MAN attacks OCK, trying to push him away from the THROTTLE. OCK pushes SPIDER-MAN away from him so strongly that SPIDER-MAN is knocked down. OCK nudges the POWER THROTTLE forward and the WHINE increases to an ear shattering pitch. The COUNTDOWN CLOCK reads, "00:06:48". We are at 96% POWER!</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid we're too late.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in there. I know Peter is in there. She breaks into a run.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELECTRICITY flashes across the doorway, stopping them.</context>
      <utterance>Liz, don't... Liz come back... come back! LIZ runs inside. They run after her. A BOLT OF</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okey, dokey!! My energy storm has started. My Anti-Force is on! History is being made... Spider-Man, Rosomorf cheer up friends... we're on our way to the unknown cosmos... we three are about to visit heaven... real Gods heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spider-Man! The Conjunction! It's happening!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They run forward but as they reach the FRONT STEPS the building lurches upward. The bottom step becomes a wall of STONE and DIRT, six feet high.</context>
      <utterance>Liz! Liz come on out!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get back! Flash... get back!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the building lurches upward again! This time it pulls FREE from the ground. The KIDS take cover as WATER LINES BURST and ELECTRICAL WIRES SPARK.</context>
      <utterance>Wow...!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The building lurches throwing her back across the HALL where she crashes through another door.</context>
      <utterance>Peter!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God... Liz is inside there!</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Professor Rosomorf and crazy Ock.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Peter? Is he there with them?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but I bet Spider-Man is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is it going Otto?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Other worlds, Roz, other times, other dimensions, who knows? Who cares?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then... why?</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truth, Rosomorf. Look at it! The new truth! The new way!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't listen to him Professor Roz.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WALDO reaches in and rips ROZ off SPIDEY, flinging him back against a WALL. ROZ lands in a heap beneath a FIRE</context>
      <utterance>No, you don't listen to that clown, he can't save you, or the world for that matter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK knocks SPIDER-MAN with a real BIG BLOW with his WALDO. OCK is slowly dragging SPIDER-MAN to a HUGE HOLE that's been ripped in the floor by the BEAMS of ELECTRICITY. We see New York a half a mile down through the hole. We see SPIDEY being drawn across the HOLE. Then ROZ comes flying in with the FIRE AXE. ROZ hacks away at the WALDO and chops it off! The stump withdraws. OCK examines it in pain and fury!</context>
      <utterance>Once and for all, Spider-Man... once and for all we'll end the legend of your powers.</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were my teacher! And you want to destroy my experiment. You are a scientist for heaven sake... don't you want to know what's up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The floor begins to craze and then crack like ice around a hole on a pond. BANG! BANG! SPIDEY comes to just as the section of floor beneath himself and ROZ gives way and falls through. SPIDEY grabs hold of the edge and dangles. He looks down and sees ROZ falling away beneath him, disappearing into the dark.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but not on account of our world. We have only one world... only one life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spider-Man! Only you can save us now...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roz!!!  Murderer!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget that old fool, insect. My Spider-Man... Come join me on my fantastic voyage to the 7th heaven.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bizarre DUEL takes place. The CENTER pitches this way and that. SPIDEY and OCK move from foothold to foothold, from WINDOW to LEDGE to PARAPET. Now the CENTER pitches to a 45 degree angle. They DUEL upside down! A WINDOW GRATE crashes open and LIZ comes flying out, holding onto the GRATE for dear life!</context>
      <utterance>Let's have it, old boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK seizes the opportunity to whack SPIDEY across the head. SPIDEY loses his footing but the building now lurches back and LIZ goes flying back inside. SPIDEY ducks inside too and pulls the GRATE. SPIDER-MAN uses his great strength to move a HUGE PIECE of SCIENTIFIC MACHINERY in front of the GRATE.</context>
      <utterance>Liz!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Peter? He must be here somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's around, don't worry... we'll find him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This building is flying. I'm in a goddamn flying building...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIZ looks at some WIRING, apprehensive about even touching it.</context>
      <utterance>I think we have to pull some of these cables. Try those over there. I'll work on these. We gotta slow this thing down somehow. We got helicopters coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She yanks out a CABLE. The building pitches. But when SPIDEY pulls one out, it rights itself.</context>
      <utterance>Pull!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The UNIVERSAL BULLET begins to GLOW. The GLOW sharpens to a POINT of LIGHT. SPIDER-MAN holds on tight against a rushing ENERGY FLOW that's pulling everything in the room towards the POINT of LIGHT.</context>
      <utterance>Spider-Man. You're end is coming. Life in its present form is ending... new dimensions, new horizons...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIZ starts to slip away into the flow. She struggles against it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't... hold on! SPIDEY THWIPS her and she grabs onto the WEB.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OCK drops calmly, beatifically, to the floor of the room. He moves slowly, under his own power, into the LIGHT.</context>
      <utterance>Hold tight, Liz, hold tight!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cut my power... there's too little power... It's so tiny... so tiny... there's only space... for me. But I've done it, Spider-Man. I have broken through... I've broken through!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do it, Dr. Octavius!</utterance>
   <speaker>OCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he nears the LIGHT he actually becomes a part of it. He radiates LIGHT. He shimmers and shines. He fills the room with BLINDING LIGHT. SPIDEY and LIZ shield their eyes, and as the light diminishes, the storm subsides. They're safe. Except for the fact that they're in a floating building, 10,000 feet above the city!</context>
      <utterance>Okey... dokey... Now that's what I call an experiment!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't control her. She's dropping too fast! Alright... let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about Peter? We've got to find Peter!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he grabs her)</context>
      <utterance>Peter will be okay, I promise you... Let's go before it's too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go where?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A HUGE CRACK opens above them.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe there's another way...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's breaking apart!</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They scale the maze, but as they emerge on the other side, half the floor falls away! Central Park awaits, 8,000 feet below.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, keep moving, a step at a time!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks across at the door. It is midway up a diagonal wall. He shoots a WEB up at the ceiling between themselves and the door. Then he extends a hand to LIZ.</context>
      <utterance>We can't go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPIDER-MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swings across and lands on the LEDGE of the DOOR. Then he swings the WEB back to her like a trapeze. LIZ catches the WEB and looks across at SPIDER-MAN, furious.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, have it your way.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I supposed to do with this!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPIDER-MAN bends his back to the task. It take all his strength, but with a comic AAAAARGGHH! He bends the DOOR open.</context>
      <utterance>The door is stuck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>END.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A long, long beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>LIZ looks up and sees PETER hanging out the WINDOW two stories above her. He throws out a ROPE LADDER. LIZ grabs it. She begins to climb.</context>
      <utterance>Liz, Up here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the way out?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We are looking at the HUGE AMERICAN FLAG.</context>
      <utterance>Right there!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, help me with this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He ties some ROPE around her waist.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, stand still.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this going to work?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just adore confidence in a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move to the edge of the ROCK and look down. CENTRAL PARK is still a couple thousand feet down.</context>
      <utterance>Come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it you say when you jump?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They SCREAM as the building lurches again, knocking them to the ground. They start to slide across the ROCK. They reach out for each other but their hands don't quite reach. Slowly, they inch back together, but the FOUNDATION cracks between them.</context>
      <utterance>Your prayers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a lot to thank your friend Spider-Man for.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somehow, I don't think we've seen the last of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter...! Finders, keepers...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...? What is it? Why do you look like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'm in love.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are...</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With your friend...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spider-Man? You're in love with Spider-Man?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am... you think we'll see him again?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>We might... you never know.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.  This may be the end of a beautiful friendship you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They land in the center of the park under the parachute. They stay there and kiss... completely covered by the flag. Camera pulls up to show the building floating away.</context>
      <utterance>Nah.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
