<movie id="518" title="Star Trek Nemesis">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SENATOR 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... but if we hesitate we'll lose this important source of dilithium. A trade agreement is in the best interests of the Empire.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Senator Tal'Aura grunts slightly at the word "negotiations." Praetor Hiren glances to her.</context>
      <utterance>Praetor, I recommend we dispatch a diplomatic mission to Celes II to open negotiations.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRAETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senator Tal'Aura, you disagree with the motion.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAL'AURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Praetor nods. Tal'Aura stands and leaves the chamber... but she had left something behind on her desk. A small, silver box with unusual etchings on the surface. The discussion continues as we focus on the silver box...</context>
      <utterance>No, sir. I would say "negotiation" is to be advised. I support all "diplomatic" overtures. But if you will excuse me, Praetor, I have an appointment with the Tholian ambassador.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRAETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Senator at the desk next to Tal'Aura's glances over. The silver box is moving. The Senator watches, amazed, as the box begins to slowly fold open. Then "legs" appear. The box unfolds like a spider, standing on its legs. Then it is still for a moment. The Senator looks at it, puzzled. Suddenly -- a bright beam of green light shoots up from the spider -- the Senators are stunned -- the beam shoots to the high domed ceiling of the chamber and then cascades around the interior of the room, enveloping everything in a glowing shroud of green energy. In a way, it is bizarrely beautiful. And then just as suddenly the light disappears. A moment of silence. The Praetor and Senators are baffled.</context>
      <utterance>Then I will call for a vote on the motion to open trade negotiations with Celes II...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRAETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A plant behind the Praetor begins to shrivel...</context>
      <utterance>Would someone please tell me what that was?  Alert security --</utterance>
   <speaker>PRAETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Praetor stops suddenly -- as the flesh begins to melt from his face. Every bit of organic matter in the chamber decays. Flesh melts from bones while the Senators scream in agony. Every living thing in the chamber is dead within ten seconds. A stunning moment of silence as we take in the carnage. Then a transporter effect ripples around the spider-weapon. It disappears. And the Romulan Senate is no more. We fade to...</context>
      <utterance>-- and have them run a --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duty... He lets the word resonate and then continues.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uproarious laughter. We pull back to reveal the wedding reception of WILL RIKER and DEANNA TROI. The Enterprise CREW is gathered with invited GUESTS, some from other "Star Trek" series. Riker and Deanna sit at the center of a long table.</context>
      <utterance>A starship captain's life is filled with solemn duty. I have commanded men in battle. I have negotiated peace treaties between implacable enemies. I have represented the Federation in first contact with twenty-seven alien species. But none of this compares to my solemn duty as... Best man.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deanna nods her head and coos sympathetically. Hearty, wonderful LAUGHTER!</context>
      <utterance>Now, I know that on an occasion such as this: it is expected that I be gracious and fulsome with praise on the wonders of this blessed union... But have you two considered what you're doing to? This is all a damned inconvenience...  While you're happily settling in on the Titan, I'll have to train a new first officer; no doubt a stern martinet who'll quote the rule book at me and never... ever... allow me to go on away missions.  ... Then there's the matter of my new counselor. Undoubtedly some soft-spoken, willowy thing who'll be probing into my darkest psyche as she nods her head and coos sympathetically. Isn't that right, Deanna?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I notice Dr. Crusher laughing along with the rest of you. As most of you know, the doctor will also soon be leaving the Enterprise, to assume command of Starfleet Medical. Again, I'm forced to ask, Beverly, have you considered what you're doing to little ole' me?! I'll probably get some old battle- axe of a doctor who'll tell me to eat my vegetables and put me on report if I don't show up for my physical on time!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter, laughter, laughter! He looks to Riker and Deanna:</context>
      <utterance>It'll serve you right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles and raises his glass, looks at them deeply.</context>
      <utterance>Really, it's not too late to reconsider. No? Very well then...</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drink.</context>
      <utterance>Will Riker, you have been my trusted right arm for fourteen years; you have helped keep my course true and steady. Deanna Troi, you have been my conscience and best guide, the touchstone to the better parts of myself. You are my family. And in proper maritime tradition I wish you full sails and a clear horizon... My friends, make it so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="46">
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort of like losing a son and gaining an empath, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Beverly, this is hard enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, GEORDI LA FORGE sits with his girlfriend.</context>
      <utterance>If you start tearing up I promise to beam you out. Level one medical emergency. There's no crying in Starfleet. They head off toward Riker and Deanna.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never seen your Captain so nostalgic. Maybe he's getting soft in his old age.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not likely. After we installed the new Series Four replicators, he tried to order his usual tea and there was a glitch. Had us remove the whole bunch of them and put the old ones back in.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There! Nostalgic about old replicators.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her gently as WORF comes to them. Poor Worf is still suffering a bit from the bachelor party. He plops down beside them, belches.</context>
      <utterance>He just likes things the way he likes them...  Of course, so do I.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Romulan ale should be illegal.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is, old chum.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He groans and rests his head on the table, acts like he's going to heave. Meanwhile, Riker and Deanna are talking to Picard and Beverly.</context>
      <utterance>Then it should be more illegal.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really, Captain, it was a lovely toast.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm a talking head.</context>
      <utterance>The least I could do for you, Deanna. Besides, you know me...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you needn't worry. I'll brief your new counselor on everything she needs to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you will. You know too much about me as it is... Now you promised there are no speeches during the ceremony on Betazed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DATA stands with the band.</context>
      <utterance>No, no speeches. No clothes either.  Picard looks at him. Deanna laughs. Then the band stops playing. All turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Riker shoots an amused glance to Deanna. Conjugation? Data turns to the band leader.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and Gentlemen and invited Tran gendered species... In my study of Terran and Betazoid conjugal rites I have discovered it is traditional to present the "happy couple" with a gift. Given Commander Riker's affection for archaic musical forms I have elected to present the following as my gift in honor of their conjugation.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The band launches into a jaunty, swing version of the Irving Berlin standard "Blue Skies."</context>
      <utterance>If you please, Mister Band Leader, a-one and a-two and...</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Blue skies, smiling at me, Nothing but blue skies do I see. Blue birds, singing a song, Nothing but blue birds all day long. Never saw the sun shining so bright, Never saw things going so right..." The crowd is appreciative. Loves the song. Except Worf, he momentarily raises his head from the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His heads thumps down again, is about ready to BARF! Meanwhile, Riker is anxious as a kid to join the band:</context>
      <utterance>Ugghhh... Irving Berlin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Riker eagerly joins the band. Grabs the trombone and starts jamming with the orchestra. The song really swings.</context>
      <utterance>All right, go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I have this dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, Geordi leads Leah to the dance floor as well. Beverly goes to Worf.</context>
      <utterance>With pleasure, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commander Worf... Do Klingons swing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not a swinger. I am unwell.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls him to the dance floor as:</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, I'm a doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad you made it back to the Enterprise before I left.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was not suited for the life of a... diplomat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been saving this. Chateau Picard 2267. Batten down the hatches... He carefully uncorks the treasured bottle as:</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pours two glasses of the wine, then raises his glass, a toast.</context>
      <utterance>They say a vintner's history is in every glass. The soil he came from. His past as well as his hopes for the future.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... To happy endings.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard carefully takes a tiny sip, savors the flavor, finally swallows. Enjoys it. Ahhh. Data mimics Picard. Taking a tiny sip, savoring the flavor and finally swallowing. Ahhh.</context>
      <utterance>To happy endings.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir. I noticed an interesting confluence of emotion at the wedding. I am familiar with the human concept of tears through laughter and its inverse, laughter through tears, but I could not help wondering about the human capacity for expressing both pleasure and sadness simultaneously.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand why it would seem confusing. Certain human rituals -- like weddings, birthdays or funerals evoke strong and very complex emotions. These rites carry great weight with us because they denote the passage of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you were particularly aware of this feeling because Commander Riker will be leaving to assume command of the Titan?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will and Deanna joining the Titan. Dr. Crusher going to Starfleet Medical...</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this makes you "sad"?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. I suppose it does a bit. I'm very happy for them, of course, but I'm going to miss them. The ship will seem... incomplete without them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is because you have a familiarity with them. You can predict specific reactions and behavior and are comfortable in that knowledge.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes another sip of wine. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. And, frankly, I envy them as well. They've made important choices; they're going to have great challenges ahead of them. New worlds to conquer...</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Data thinks about it.</context>
      <utterance>Seeing Will and Deanna today made me think about some of the choices I've made in my own life. Devoting myself to Starfleet... Not marrying or having children... All the choices that led me here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The choices I made have led me here as well. This is the only home I have ever known. I cannot foresee a reason for leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never know what's over the horizon, Data. Before too long you'll be offered a command of your own. Data looks at him; he has never really considered this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I were... I believe my memory engrams would sense the absence of your specific reactions and behavior. I would "miss you."</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, you make a toast.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To new worlds...</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drink.</context>
      <utterance>New worlds. Yes Data, brave new worlds...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fleet commanders are nervous. They've agreed to remain at their given coordinates and await his orders. But they're anxious to know what's going on here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONATRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A voice, from the shadows:</context>
      <utterance>I don't blame them. We can't keep them in the dark forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He is a terrifying sight A powerful, monstrous alien creature; a tall, ashen-skinned ectomorph who bears a disturbing resemblance to the original Nosferatu. He is vampiric and lethal. He is a Reman.</context>
      <utterance>But in darkness, there is strength. Donatra and Suran stop. And the VICEROY steps from the shadows...</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads them along the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you agree?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He is a dynamic young human in his twenties. Very handsome with pale, almost white skin and shining, golden hair. He wears a striking Reman military uniform. He stands in the center of the eerily deserted chamber. The entire floor is a large star chart.</context>
      <utterance>Consider it The great symbol of the Empire... But the bird-of-prey holds planets. Romulus, Remus. Their destinies conjoined... And then we see him... SHINZON!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Senator Tal'Aura (the female Senator who planted the weapon in the Senate chamber earlier) and two other ROMULAN COMMANDERS sit. Cadres of Shinzon's fearsome REMAN WARRIORS stand around the chamber. They are his sinister children of the night. Even more chilling now in the flickering torch light. It's like something out of Tim Burton. Donatra and Suran enter the chamber with Shinzon's Viceroy.</context>
      <utterance>Yet for generations one of those planets has been without a voice. We will be silent no longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Join us, Commanders. Now what's the disposition of the fleet?</utterance>
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're holding position.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will obey, Praetor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's imperative we retain their allegiance or our great mission will be strangled before it can truly draw breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONATRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon looks at her. A quick beat. Shinzon decides to respond with benevolence. He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>They support your intentions, sir. But they require evidence of your... sincerity.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands on the area of the map that denotes the Neutral Zone between the Romulan Empire and the Federation.</context>
      <utterance>And they'll have it.  Tell the fleet that the days of negotiation and diplomacy are over. The Almighty Federation will fall before us. As I promised you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He carefully steps into the area of the map marked with the Federation symbol. He looks down at the star chart.</context>
      <utterance>The time we have dreamed of is at hand. The time... of conquest.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Donatra watches him carefully. Something in his quiet words disturbs her.</context>
      <utterance>Cut off the dragon's head and it cannot strike back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many Warbirds will you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at him, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>None.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Praetor. You have the whole fleet at your disposal. They supported the coup, they'll follow you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Scimitar will serve my needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But surely --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Commanders and Senator Tal'Aura rise and leave. Shinzon looks to his Viceroy.</context>
      <utterance>I came this far alone...  We came this far alone. We require no assistance from the fleet. Now leave me to my thoughts.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we prepared?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Praetor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So many years for this moment.  Bring him to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's tradition,Worf. You of all people should appreciate that!  Besides, I've already seen it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>vulnerable.</context>
      <utterance>A warrior does not appear without his clothing. It leaves him...</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think we're going to see much combat on Betazed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Worf groans. Picard emerges from his Ready Room as:</context>
      <utterance>Don't be too sure. Mother will be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't do what, Mister Worf?</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain. I think it is inappropriate for a Starfleet officer to appear...  ... naked.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deanna laughs. Then a readout on Worf's console attracts his attention:</context>
      <utterance>Come now, a big, strapping fellow like you? What are you afraid of?</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm picking up an unusual electromagnetic signature from the Kolarin system.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Worf looks up. Glances at Data.</context>
      <utterance>What sort of signature?</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Positronic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's very faint but I've isolated it to the third planet in the Kolarin system.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we know about the planet?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uncharted. We'll have to get closer for a more detailed scan.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Theories?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since positronic signatures have only been known to emanate from androids such as myself, it is logical to theorize that there is an android such as myself on Kolarus III.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many of you did Dr. Soong make?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought only me, myself and Lore.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Diverting to the Kolarin system takes us awfully close to the Romulan Neutral Zone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard glances at Data, recognizes the android's deep desire to explore this possible connection to others like himself.</context>
      <utterance>Still well on our side...</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's worth a look. Don't worry, Number One, we'll get you to Betazed with time to spare.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes.</context>
      <utterance>Where we will all honor the Betazoid traditions. No cold feet, or any other parts of our anatomy. Now, if you'll excuse me. I'll be in the gym.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Branson, set course for the Kolarin system. Warp Five --  -- Warp Seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELM OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>MISTER BRANSON</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plotted and laid in, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Engage.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, Geordi and Data remain at the Engineering Station, studying the displays.</context>
      <utterance>You better believe you're engaged!</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data doesn't respond, but the curiosity on his face is apparent.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think, Data, a long- lost relative?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I read six distinct positronic signatures, spread out over a few kilometers on the surface.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we know about the population?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isolated pockets of humanoids. It appears to be a pre-warp civilization at an early stage of industrial development.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, I don't recommend transporting, that ion storm doesn't look very neighborly. It could head this way without much warning.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard, Data and Worf start heading toward the turbolift.</context>
      <utterance>Understood. Data, Worf, you're with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, I hope I don't have to remind you --</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate your concern, Number One, but I've been itching to try out the Argo.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir --</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps into the turbolift with the Data and Worf.</context>
      <utterance>Captain's prerogative, Will. There's no foreseeable danger... and your wife would never forgive me if anything happened to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bridge crew heartily enjoys Riker's momentary demotion to house husband.</context>
      <utterance>You have the bridge, Mister Troi! The turbolift doors slide shut.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The closest signature is two kilometers to the west... that direction, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard clearly enjoys driving. He roars over the desert terrain at breakneck speed, having a hell of a good time. His comrades don't exactly appreciate his free-spirited driving panache. Worf clings on to the mounted phaser canon for dear life. Data steadies himself by grasping onto the rollbar</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Data.  Let's see what she can do. He roars off in a cloud of dust!</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard smiles and drives a little faster.</context>
      <utterance>I will always be baffled by the human predilection for piloting vehicles at unsafe velocities.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue on. Before long they can see something on the level desert floor before them. They approach and stop to discover... An android arm. The fingers patiently drumming the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Over that rise, sir... half a kilometer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It appears to be...  ... an arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is it moving?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like me, it has been designed with modular power sources.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Worf climbs from the jeep and carefully approaches the arm. Gingerly picks it up. The arm responds to being picked up, the hand starts feeling around in the air like something from a horror movie. Worf shudders. He returns to the jeep. Quickly sets the arm down in the rear cargo area.</context>
      <utterance>Mister Worf, if you please.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Time passes as they continue on... coming across another arm... a leg... a torso... another leg... various disassembled components of a Data-like android!</context>
      <utterance>The next signature is one kilometer to the south. Picard starts the jeep in motion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The final signature is approximately 300 meters up that incline.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Worf, accompany Data please.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To find the head, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Worf and Data climb up into the hills in pursuit of the final piece as Picard opens the jeep's hood and checks the engine.</context>
      <utterance>If you don't mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Worf pulls his phaser, ready.</context>
      <utterance>Ten meters...</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data's head. Or the spitting image anyway. Lying inert in the dust before them.</context>
      <utterance>I think it unlikely you will need your phaser to recover the cranial unit. Of course, it could bite you. Then they see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the head's eyes suddenly pop open. It looks up at them with a sort of blank, childlike wonder.</context>
      <utterance>The resemblance is... striking.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why am I looking at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You are looking at me.</context>
      <utterance>You are not looking at yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do not look like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>May I do that?</context>
      <utterance>I would like to pick you up now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a pretty shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data gently picks up the head. Looks at it. The two identical faces gaze at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then BLAM! -- a boulder near them explodes. Worf and Data spin to see... A nomadic tribe of desert ALIENS swarming toward them firing primitive plasma weapons -- Data and Worf race back down the canyon, toward the jeep -- some open-field running and a bit of phaser action -- Worf firing to distract and slow the aliens, not kill them -- through all of this the head is chattering away blandly:</context>
      <utterance>Fascinating...</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The action continues. Then Data finds himself almost surrounded --</context>
      <utterance>I have two arms and ten fingers. Do you know where my arms are? I cannot see where we are going. Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Worf turns -- Data throws the head to Worf like a football, a perfect spiral -- the head is still chattering away -- Worf catches it --</context>
      <utterance>Commander!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you wouldn't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The head looks up at Picard.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard glances at the head.</context>
      <utterance>You have a shiny head.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is very observant.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard turns to see that they are being pursued! The aliens are racing after them in crude desert-terrain vehicles --</context>
      <utterance>Captain!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a red shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not an appropriate time for a conversation.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because the captain has to concentrate on piloting the vehicle.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Data!</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue to speed over the landscape -- bouncing and flying over natural rises in the terrain -- trying to evade their pursuers -- Picard puts the pedal to the metal and races through the alien vehicles -- weaving in and out, avoiding their fire -- Worf blasts away with the phaser cannon -- an exhilarating adventure -- Finally they are within sight of the Argo -- but they see it is surrounded by more of the aliens!</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data punches some buttons on a dashboard console -- and the Argo LIFTS OFF by remote control -- Data uses the console to swing the Argo around and lower the rear cargo doors -- it hovers over the surface -- Picard floors the jeep -- using a natural rise in the terrain as a ramp -- the jeep FLIES THROUGH THE AIR -- over the aliens -- and into the cargo bay --</context>
      <utterance>Mister Data. Let's make like the wind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="63">
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We pull back to reveal she is speaking to Data. Data stands with Picard, Riker and Geordi.</context>
      <utterance>I think you have nicer eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The android is in a framework rig that holds the various body parts in place. The parts are not yet assembled</context>
      <utterance>Our eyes are identical, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geordi?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he seems to have the same internal mechanics as Data but not as much positronic development. The neural pathways aren't nearly as sophisticated. I'd say he's a prototype. Something Dr. Soong created before Data.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have a name, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the B-9.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be-nign. Dr. Soong's penchant for whimsical names seems to have no end.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a fuzzy face.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes. Geordi and Data begin to reassemble the B-9 piece by piece like the Tin Man as:</context>
      <utterance>Keep me informed, Number One, and, please, put him back together.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you tell me how you came to be on the planet where we found you?</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was taken from my homeworld by people called the "PakJeds." They are fat. They traded me to a ship belonging to the "Bolians." The "Bolians" are blue. They put me in a seat and asked me questions. Then they were attacked by another ship... Time passes... And still the B-9 is yammering blandly away. He is more fully assembled By this time Beverly is thoroughly bored.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then people called the Delviciansans picked me up. They have long teeth. They asked if I do anything to help them. I told them I could do whatever they wanted. They asked me to clean out the matrix manifolds. I told them I did not know what an Matrix manifold looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She quickly exits.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. I have some diagnostics to run on some medical scanner things.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And still the B-9 is yammering away. He is almost completely assembled by now. Riker is bored out of his mind.</context>
      <utterance>And after they showed me the "engine manifolds." Then they showed me something called a "plasma mop" Time passes...</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... then the "Cardassians" put me into something called a "garbage chute" and I went out into space again --</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - ON COMM</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worf to Commander Riker. I have the tactical manifests ready, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He escapes.</context>
      <utterance>Worf! Wonderful! I'll be right there!...  Duty calls, gentlemen. Carry on.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuzzy face is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, please continue.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And still the B-9 is yammering away. By this time Geordi is slumped in a chair and only Data is listening. The B-9 is fully assembled.</context>
      <utterance>I was in space for a long time. Then a ship belonging to the "Talosians" picked me up. They asked me where I came from. I told them people called the "Pakleds" took me from my homeworld. They are fat... Geordi groans. Time passes...</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. The B-9 is finally done with his tale...</context>
      <utterance>Then I opened my eyes and saw you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know who I am?</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. My name is Data... I am your brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and after the ceremony on Betazed, three entire weeks for our honeymoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going sailing on the Opal Sea. We've booked an old-fashioned solar catamaran. Just us and the sun and the waves.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems a very... soft honeymoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's meant to be relaxing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Klingon honeymoon begins with the Kholamar desert march where the couple bonds in endurance trials. If they survive the challenge they move on to the Fire Caves of Fek'lhr to face the demons of Gre'thor.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that sounds relaxing too.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They see Data enter the lounge, carefully leading the B-9.</context>
      <utterance>It is... invigorating.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So they've got him up and running.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a very unusual android</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cup of tea appears. He takes it as the door chime sounds.</context>
      <utterance>Earl Grey, hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come.  Counselor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have a moment, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, sit down. He sits at his desk She sits across from him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about Data I've watched him with the B-9 and I'm troubled. Data's desire for a "family" is very strong. I'm afraid he may be investing too much in the B-9.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're speaking of emotional investment?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The B-9 is like a slow child, sir. And Data, in his own way, has assumed the position of a parent or guardian. I'm afraid he has expectations based on his own experiences. He'll be disappointed when the B-9 cannot meet those expectations.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As much as we care for him, Deanna... we have to remember that Data isn't capable of disappointment.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A quiet beat.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe that, sir. We've shared many disappointing journeys.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to miss you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are interrupted by a comm signal:</context>
      <utterance>And I you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - ON COMM</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, you have an Alpha Priority communication from Starfleet Command.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Acknowledged...  ... I'll talk to Data</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes. Picard activates his desktop viewscreen. ADMIRAL KATHRYN JANEWAY appears on Picard's monitor. Janeway is the former captain of Voyager. Her new rank fits her well, she has lost none of her dry humor and down-to-earth charm which made her a household name and beloved cult figure.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Admiral Janeway. Good to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEWAY</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean Luc... How'd you like a trip to Romulus? All expenses paid?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With or without the rest of the fleet?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEWAY</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A diplomatic mission. We've been invited, believe it or not. Seems there's been some kind of internal political shakeup. The new Praetor, someone called Shinzon, has requested a Federation envoy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New Praetor?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEWAY</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's more... as always. He's Reman.  Believe me, we don't understand it either. You're the closest ship so I want you to high tail it over there and hear what he has to say. Get the lay of the land, If the Empire becomes unstable, it could mean trouble for the entire quadrant.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Understood.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEWAY</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're sending you all the intelligence we have, but it's not much. I don't need to tell you to watch your back, Jean Luc.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not with the Romulans.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEWAY</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Son'a, the Borg, the Romulans, the evil Soran and that pesky Nexus. You seem to get all the easy assignments!</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just lucky, Admiral.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEWAY</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context>Picard sits for a moment, intrigued. Then he goes to the bridge</context>
      <utterance>Let's hope that luck holds. Janeway out. The transmission ends.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crew is shocked.</context>
      <utterance>Lay in a new course... Take us to Romulus. Warp eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELM OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye aye, sir. Course plotted and laid in...</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Romulus?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid the Opal Sea will have to wait, Number One... Engage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Various grainy and unclear new images appear to illustrate Data's words:</context>
      <utterance>As you can see the habitable half of Remus is always in darkness because, like Mercury, one side always faces the sun. Due to the extreme temperatures on that half of their world, the Remans live on the dark side of the planet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Very obscure images of Remans appear, the crew can barely make out the monstrous figures:</context>
      <utterance>Almost nothing is known about the Reman homeworld, although intelligence scans have proven the existence of dilithium mining and heavy weapons construction.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Remans themselves are considered an undesirable caste in the hierarchy of the Empire.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they also have the reputation of being formidable warriors. In the Dominion War, Reman forces were used as assault troops in the most violent encounters.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cannon fodder.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how did a Reman get to be Praetor? I don't get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to assume he had Romulan collaborators.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A coup d'etat?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard considers this.</context>
      <utterance>The Praetor's power has always been the Romulan fleet. They must be behind him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The images end. There are no images of Shinzon.</context>
      <utterance>What have you learned about Shinzon?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starfleet intelligence was only able to provide a partial account of his military record. We can infer he is relatively young and a capable commander. He fought seventeen major engagements in the war. All successful. Beyond that, we know nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The meeting breaks up.</context>
      <utterance>Well... it seems we're truly sailing into the unknown. Keep at it. Anything you can give me would be appreciated. Dismissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At present he serves no useful function. Dr. Soong created us to become active and useful members of society. I do not believe he would have wanted the B-9 to live out his life in his present state.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe the Captain went along with a memory download.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Picard agrees that the B-9 was probably designed with the same self-actualization parameters as myself. If my memory engrams are successfully integrated into his positronic matrix, he should have all my abilities.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You feel comfortable with that?</context>
      <utterance>He'd have all your memories too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel nothing, Geordi. It is my belief that with my memory engrams he will be able to function as a more complete individual.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An individual more like you, you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geordi completes his work</context>
      <utterance>Maybe he's not supposed to be like you. Maybe he's supposed to be just like he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geordi removes the computer connections from between their heads. He carefully closes the panel in Data's head as:</context>
      <utterance>Okay... we're done.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know where you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks blankly at the console lights.</context>
      <utterance>I am in a room with lights.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you remember our father?</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data glances to Geordi.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know the name of the Captain of this vessel?</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that your final answer?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know my name?</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a soft voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data has been studying some circuitry in the B-9's neck.</context>
      <utterance>Data, he's assimilating a lot of programming. Remember, he's a prototype, a lot less sophisticated than you are. We just don't know if his matrix will be able to adapt. Or if he'll be able to retain anything. We should give him some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What purpose does this serve?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems to be a redundant memory port. Maybe it's for provisional memory storage in case his neural pathways overload?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Soong must have found it unnecessary in later versions.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's possible the extra memory port is interfering with the engram processing. Mind if I keep him here and run some diagnostics?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I do not mind. Data looks at the B-9 with a sort of sadness.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I believe he will prove incapable of performing higher functions.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give up hope, Data. I know, I know, you're not capable of hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data stands. The B-9 stands to follow.</context>
      <utterance>I am not.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The B-9 sits. Data goes. Geordi watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>No, remain with Commander La Forge. He is going to try to make you well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain's Log. Stardate 47844.9. The Enterprise has arrived at Romulus and is waiting at the designated coordinates. All our hails have gone unanswered. We've been waiting for seventeen hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't they answer our hails?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's an old psychological strategy, Number One. To put him in a position of dominance and make us uneasy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's working.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Counselor?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard stands and walks to the viewscreen. He gazes at Romulus below and the black infinity of space beyond. They're out there, Waiting.</context>
      <utterance>They're out there, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I recommend we raise shields.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet, Mister Worf.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, with all due respect to diplomatic protocols -- the Federation Council's not sitting out here, we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patience. Diplomacy is a very exacting occupation. We can wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon's magnificent Reman Warbird, the SCIMITAR, decloaks directly before the Enterprise.</context>
      <utterance>Captain... And on the viewscreen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God...</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I raise shields?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain -- !</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tactical analysis, Mister Worf.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty-two disruptor banks, twenty- seven photon torpedo bays, primary and secondary phased shields.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not out for a pleasure cruise.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a predator.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're being hailed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the image on the viewscreen transforms to: Shinzon's Viceroy. He stands on the Scimitar's bridge. The bridge is as unique as the rest of Shinzon's ship. Instead of the usual mechanical clutter, this bridge is designed with an almost Asian simplicity. Like the rest of Reman design, it is spare and elegant. Since the Remans are more comfortable in the darkness, most of the light comes from the three steadily pulsing warp core relays which dramatically soar up through the floor of the bridge. The crew gazes at the bridge and the monstrous features of the viceroy.</context>
      <utterance>On screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enterprise. We are the Reman Warbird Scimitar.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Praetor Shinzon, I'm pleased to --</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context>The transmission ends abruptly. The Scimitar reappears on the viewscreen.</context>
      <utterance>I am not Shinzon. I am his Viceroy. We are sending transport coordinates.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not very chatty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard, Riker, Deanna, Worf and Data head toward the turbolift, energized now that the endless waiting is over.</context>
      <utterance>Away team. Transporter room four.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you'll forgive the darkness... we're not comfortable in the light.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon moves toward them a bit, becoming slightly more illuminated, the low light shining off his golden hair. The crew cannot see him clearly in the dim light but it is evident he is human. Assuming that he was Reman, they're surprised by this realization. Shinzon just stares at Picard through the darkness for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Praetor Shinzon?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data scans him with a tricorder as:</context>
      <utterance>Captain Picard... Jean Luc Picard... I don't mean to stare, it's just -- well, you can't imagine how long I've been waiting for this moment. I always imagined you taller, isn't that odd?  You may scan me without subterfuge, Commander Data.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're not as we imagined you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are human.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>and as my brother.</context>
      <utterance>Commander Worf.  I greet you as a valiant warrior...</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon laughs, maniacally.</context>
      <utterance>I'll save my greetings for a better brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon does not answer. He is staring deeply at Deanna, moans softly.</context>
      <utterance>Why have you asked for our presence here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Praetor?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slowly moves toward her, still hidden in the shadows.</context>
      <utterance>I've never met a human woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm only half human.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deanna Troi of Betazed. Empathic and telepathic abilities, ship's counselor. All of this I knew... But I didn't know you were so beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon moves even closer to Deanna, not taking his eyes from her.</context>
      <utterance>You seem very familiar with our personnel.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am, Commander Riker...  ... May I touch your hair?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Praetor, we've come to Romulus on a matter we were -- assured was of great importance. If you have anything to say to us as representatives of the Federation, I suggest you do so now. Shinzon continues to stare at Deanna. It is strangely seductive. Almost disquieting in its intensity. Deanna handles it with grace, her level gaze never leaving his.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the world I come from there's no light. No sun. Beauty isn't important. I see now there's a world elsewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Praetor Shinzon. We're not here to discuss your lack of a social life.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm sorry, Captain.  There's so much we have to talk about.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would be interested to know what we are talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard and the others are stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Unity, Captain! Tearing down the walls between us to recognize we are one people. Federation and Romulan. Human and Vulcan and Klingon and Reman. I'm speaking of the thing that makes us the same. We want peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to end the centuries of mistrust. I want to be your ally, not your enemy. As a first step I propose we eliminate the Neutral Zone and begin a free and open exchange of goods and ideas.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the Senate supports you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>I have dissolved the Senate.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now, you're thinking this all sounds too good to be true?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're wondering why the Scimitar is so well armed. Is this the ship of a peacemaker? Or a predator?  ... But you're also thinking the chance for peace is too promising to ignore. Above all, you're trying to decide if you can trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the first time the crew can see Shinzon clearly. Picard actually gasps when he sees Shinzon's face. The rest of the crew doesn't understand his reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Then perhaps the time has come to add some illumination to our discussion. Computer, raise lighting four levels. Lights shoot up around the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard watches him carefully. Wary and strangely intense.</context>
      <utterance>Allow me to tell you a story that I hope will clarify my position. When I was very young I was stricken with an odd disease. I developed a hyper-sensitivity to sound. The slightest whisper caused me agony...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one knew what to do. Finally I was taken to a doctor who had some experience with Terran illnesses and I was finally diagnosed with Shalaft's syndrome. Do you know of it, Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crew is dumbfounded at Picard's unusual reaction.</context>
      <utterance>You know I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps toward Picard who holds his ground.</context>
      <utterance>Then you know it's a very rare syndrome. Genetic. All the male members of my family had it. Eventually I was treated. Now I can hear as well as you can, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard stares at him with a mixture of realization and curiosity. It is as if Picard is looking into a strange, remembered mirror: Shinzon's face is nearly identical to his at that age.</context>
      <utterance>I can see as well as you can. I can feel everything you feel.  In fact, I feel exactly what you feel. Don't I, Jean Luc?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Do you trust me now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need to talk, just you and I.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come to dinner on Romulus tomorrow. Just the two of us. Or just the one of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I need to verify this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crew is utterly confused. Their confusion turns to outright shock when Shinzon calmly pulls out a Reman knife and cuts his arm, drawing a little blood. He hands the knife to Data.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard touches his communicator pin:</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow then, Captain. We have so much to discuss.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They dematerialize, the shimmering glow illuminating Shinzon's features. Picard's eyes never leave Shinzon as the transporter effect ripples around him.</context>
      <utterance>Picard to Enterprise. Five to beam out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat as the confirmation sinks in.</context>
      <utterance>There's no doubt, Captain. Right down to your regressive strain of Shalaft's Syndrome. He's a clone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When was he... created?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About twenty-five years ago. They probably used a hair follicle or skin cell.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think a skin cell's the more likely of the two.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes, Deanna following.</context>
      <utterance>Believe me, Number One; I'm going to find out. Contact Starfleet Command and inform them of the situation. I need to know where the hell he came from. Deanna.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would say he's been trained to resist telepathy. What I could sense of his emotions were erratic, very hard to follow.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he sincere about wanting peace?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.  Sir, the strongest sense I had was that he's more than curious about you. He very much wants to know you.  The same way you want to know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could I not?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, don't assume he's anything like you are. You should resist the urge to think you know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes.</context>
      <utterance>I not only know him, Deanna, I am him... and he is me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Riker tosses a padd on the desk. Rubs his eyes. Looks up her.</context>
      <utterance>Will, you need to rest.  As ship's counselor, I'm recommending you get me sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and goes to him.</context>
      <utterance>Some honeymoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls him up.</context>
      <utterance>We have time.  Come to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss deeply. She pulls him across the room and they fall into the bed. It is passionate, erotic. Her arms undulate around him sensually... her fingers snake through his hair, but something is wrong. Riker's hair is now blond. She starts back, her eyes growing wide. Riker is gone. She is now embracing Shinzon!</context>
      <utterance>Imzadi, what am I going to do with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imzadi. This is so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He caresses her face...</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can never know you as I know you... He can never touch you as I touch you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't real.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her neck -- but when he raises his head again. It is the monstrous Viceroy! Holding her. Caressing her. She is frozen in horror. But is it the Viceroy at all? Shinzon's voice seems to come from the Viceroy's lips:</context>
      <utterance>Can you feel my hands... are they real? Can you feel my lips, my loins?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>And then it is Shinzon again, kissing her:</context>
      <utterance>I'm with you, Imzadi...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll always be with you now. Now and forever...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes him away...</context>
      <utterance>You sick bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is Riker. She stares at him, then clings to him desperately.</context>
      <utterance>Deanna?! What's with the name calling?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... then I don't understand the reason for the delay!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And bringing the Enterprise here?! What possible purpose could that serve?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a purpose.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then perhaps you will enlighten us?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tense beat. Shinzon regains his composure.</context>
      <utterance>Silence, Romulan!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must learn patience, Commander. Do you know where I learned it? In the dilithium mines of Remus. Spend eighteen hours every day under the lash of a Romulan guard's whip and you'll soon understand patience.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Praetor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Donatra turns just as she is leaving the chamber, she sees the Viceroy going to Shinzon. And then do something odd. The Viceroy puts his hand on Shinzon's chest, leans very close and talks to him quietly. This is an ancient form of Reman telepathic medical diagnosis. This strange sight perplexes Donatra. The doors close, blocking her view...</context>
      <utterance>Now go. I have some personal business. Suran and the others go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when I was ready they were going to replace you with me, an exact biological duplicate. Put a Romulan agent at the heart of Starfleet to influence your command structure. It was a bold plan.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard pours a glass of Romulan ale.</context>
      <utterance>As happens so frequently here on Romulus, a new government came to power. They decided to abandon the plan -- frankly, I think they were afraid I'd be discovered and it would lead to war. They weren't ready for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Romulan ale -- I'm surprised. I can't stand it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. They look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>You'll acquire a taste for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not quite the face you remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not quite. I envy the hairline.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lifetime of violence will do that. My nose was broken four times. And my jaw... But so much is the same. The eyes, you recognize the eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. The eyes have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our eyes reflect our lives, don't they? Yours are so confident.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you end up on Remus?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. He glances to the Romulan crest on the wall.</context>
      <utterance>They sent me there to die. How could a mere human survive the dilithium mines? It was...  ... I was a slave. And a monster. The only thing the Romulan guards hated more than the Remans was me. But one man took pity on me: the man who became my Viceroy. He taught me how to survive. And in that dark place, where there was nothing of myself, I found my Reman brothers. They showed me the only kindness I ever knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For thousands of years the Romulan Senate has met in this chamber and dictated the fate of its sister- planet... But the time has come for us to live as equals.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're doing this to liberate the Remans?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard is impressed with Shinzon's quiet words.</context>
      <utterance>No race should be a slave to another.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no reason to.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you do. If you had lived my life and experienced the suffering of my people... you'd be sitting where I am now. At least I hope you would.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if you had lived my life you would understand that there is a great responsibility in representing the Federation. I can't let my personal feelings unduly influence my decisions.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>All I have is my personal feelings. I wasn't raised with the ideals of the Federation. But I'm trying to understand them now. To live up to them To live up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to know where I come from. The Remans gave me a future. You can tell me about my past.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's so much, and so much of it is dull...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were we always explorers? PlCARD No. I was the first Picard to leave Earth. It caused quite a stir, In fact. But I had spent my whole life...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking up at the stars.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you dreamed about what was up there. About...</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both reach for a carafe of water at the exact same instant. Stop.</context>
      <utterance>New worlds. A beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After you, Praetor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard smiles, pours a glass.</context>
      <utterance>Age before rank, Jean Luc.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'm not as tall as you expected?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always hoped I would hit two meters.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With a full head of hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A quiet beat.</context>
      <utterance>There is that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shinzon... I'm trying to believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's one ideal the Federation holds most dear it's that all men, all races, can be united. From the first time the Vulcans came to Earth we've sought a future of peace. Nothing would make me more proud than to take your hand in friendship. In time. When trust has been earned.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm honored to think I might someday speak with such eloquence.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In time, Jean Luc.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gentler than I thought. And he has a sense of humor.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't forget our mission, Shinzon. We should act. Now. Time is running out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tense beat.</context>
      <utterance>My time. I'll spend it how I choose.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Prepare yourself for the bonding.</context>
      <utterance>We'll return to the Scimitar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, we've had an unauthorized access into the main computer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going to take some time to find out -- the data stream was rerouted through substations all over the ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What programs were accessed?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I don't get -- it's mostly basic stellar cartography: star charts; communications protocols; some uplinks from colony tracking stations. It's not even restricted material.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Set up a security program to detect any unusual data stream rerouting. If it happens again, we want to be ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard is shocked.</context>
      <utterance>There's something else. I was reviewing the sensor logs...  When the Scimitar decloaked there was a momentary spike in the tertiary EM band -- there -- You're not going to believe this but it's Thalaron.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I thought Thalaron radiation was theoretical.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is why our initial scans didn't pick it up. But he's got it, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As I remember, Thalaron research was banned in the Federation because of its bioqenic properties.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has the ability to consume organic material at the subatomic level. I can't overestimate the danger of Thalaron radiation, Jean Luc. A microscopic amount could kill every living thing on this ship in a matter of seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard goes. Data thinks for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Understood. Keep on it. I need to know what he has and how to neutralize any threat. Give me options.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Geordi head out. Beverly returns to some medical displays showing Thalaron research, her expression deeply concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor, will you excuse us for a moment? Geordi, please come with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come...  ... Beverly, come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits, notes the picture of Young Jean Luc.</context>
      <utterance>You're working late.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a bit proud as I recall.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a damn fool. Selfish and ambitious. Very much in need of seasoning.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises, goes to a window, gazes at the Scimitar in the distance. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>He turned out all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I so wanted to believe Shinzon. But the Thalaron radiation can't be explained away. Whatever he's after, it's not peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he very much like you were?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data interrupts on comm:</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - ON COMM</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Data to Captain Picard. Geordi and I have identified the source of the unauthorized computer access. And, I believe, we have also discovered an opportunity to gain a tactical advantage.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On my way...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jean Luc -- whatever you were -- right now you're the man you've made yourself. He's someone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I could believe that, Doctor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Shinzon stands across from her.</context>
      <utterance>Imzadi...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very logical, Deanna... But your heart doesn't constrain itself to mere logic.  ... Your heart longs to discover me. To know me...  ... To leave all of this behind and be with me. He pushes her against the wall, with passion and almost violence.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She forces herself to concentrate... to resist telepathically... it is a mighty effort... this Romulan is hot. And the world around her appears to be changing... bending... And she is momentarily in a cabin on the Scimitar. Although entirely a telepathic experience, it is as if she has actually traveled. She sees Shinzon kneeling over a small flame, she realizes she is looking through the Viceroy's eyes. On the Scimitar, Shinzon looks up at the Viceroy/Deanna:</context>
      <utterance>I can feel your desire, Deanna...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deanna is on the turbolift. Shinzon is pressed against her, whispering:</context>
      <utterance>I can feel your hunger to know the Reman ways... the old ways. Then the world changes again...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is alone. She sinks to her knees. Overcome with emotion.</context>
      <utterance>Don't fear what you desire... She forces him away from her and --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bond is broken.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find her again.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- this is wasting time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Reman officer interrupts on comm:</context>
      <utterance>Do as I tell you!</utterance>
   <speaker>REMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Praetor, we've received the transponder signal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to go -- but suddenly stops, a wave of illness overtaking him. The Viceroy puts his hand on Shinzon's chest. A strange moment as the Viceroy shuts his eyes and feels Shinzon's chest. His mind... probing. Then the Viceroy looks up at him, grim.</context>
      <utterance>On my way.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's accelerating. You have no more time for games.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes.</context>
      <utterance>Have the doctors prepare. I'll be on the bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An Engineer activates a transporter and the B-9 materializes!</context>
      <utterance>Transport.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reman engineers go to the B-9 and open the panel in his neck, begin connecting computer conduits to the extra memory port we saw earlier. (Note: Although the audience will not know it yet, this is actually Data pretending to be the B-9.) Shinzon goes to a replicator unit and orders:</context>
      <utterance>Welcome home.  Begin the download.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cup of tea appears. He takes it and sips as he watches his Engineers connecting the conduits to the B-9.</context>
      <utterance>Tea, hot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aside from slightly elevated adrenalin and serotonin levels, you're completely normal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at Picard, tears in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Can you describe it, Deanna?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Riker takes her hand.</context>
      <utterance>It was... a violation.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shinzon's Viceroy seems to have the ability to reach into my thoughts. I've become a liability... I request to be relieved of my duties.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before the words are out of his mouth... he begins to dematerialize!</context>
      <utterance>Permission denied. If you can possibly endure any more of these assaults. I need you at my side. Now more than ever I...</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Picard is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Worf! Raise Shields !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Jean Luc.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why am I here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods to a guard. The guard deactivates the force field. A Reman doctor enters and raises a hypospray toward Picard.</context>
      <utterance>I was lonely...  Perhaps I'm not aging as well as you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doctor takes a quick sample of Picard's blood as Picard glances to the B-9.</context>
      <utterance>I need a sample of your blood. What do your Borg friends say? Resistance is futile.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Reman doctor leaves the cell. The force field is reactivated. The doctor goes to the mysterious medical apparatus and analyzes Picard's blood. As:</context>
      <utterance>Yes. The bait you couldn't refuse. I learned there might be an existing prototype from a Cardassian historian, then went to a great deal of trouble to find it and scatter it about on Kolarus III. I knew it would pique your curiosity and conveniently make the Enterprise the closest ship to Romulus when I contacted Starfleet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of this so you could capture me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be so vain. After we found it, we made a few modifications. An extra memory port, a hidden transponder. Perhaps your eyes will be a bit less confident when you learn I've gained access to Starfleet's communications protocols. I now know the location of your entire fleet...  ... You may go.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The B-9 obediently leaves the room as:</context>
      <utterance>Out of my sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'll train it to do little tricks for me like your robot does. Or maybe I'll snap its ugly head off.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about destiny, Picard. About a Reman outcast who --</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not Reman.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm not quite human. So what am I? What do you see?  Do you see a life you might have led? Lost youth never to be recaptured?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see a young man trying desperately to deny who he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I see the man I will never be.</context>
      <utterance>I see an old man, set in his ways, afraid to live without a uniform to prop him up and a Starfleet regulation to tell him what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't defend my life to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My life is meaningless as long as you're alive. What am I while you exist? A shadow? An enigma?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If your issues are with me... This has nothing to do with my ship and nothing to do with the Federation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, but it does. We will no longer bow like slaves before anyone. Not the Romulans and not your mighty Federation. We're a race bred for war. For conquest.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think about what you're doing, Shinzon. Are you ready to plunge the entire quadrant into war to satisfy your own personal demons?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It amazes me how little you know yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm incapable of such an act, and so are you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon looks at him deeply.</context>
      <utterance>I think the facts speak for themselves. The same noble Picard blood runs in our veins. Had you lived my life, you'd be doing exactly as I am. Look in the mirror, and see yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to go.</context>
      <utterance>Consider that, Captain. I can think of no greater torment for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard's probing gaze makes Shinzon a bit uneasy. He glances to the ghoulish medical preparations.</context>
      <utterance>It's a mirror for you as well... Shinzon turns back to him. A beat. Picard gazes at him evenly.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes.</context>
      <utterance>Not for long, Captain.  I'm afraid you won't survive to witness the victory of the echo over the voice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geordi is hard at work at the Science station. Riker stands over him:</context>
      <utterance>No response to our hails.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His cloak is perfect... no tachyon emissions, no residual antiprotons.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beverly arrives on the bridge, urgent. She carries a medical padd.</context>
      <utterance>Keep at it, Geordi. Find a way in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will, I need to talk to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Reman Guard deactivates the force field.</context>
      <utterance>I am to take the prisoner to the Praetor.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads Picard out.</context>
      <utterance>If you resist, I will incapacitate you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you taking him?</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Viceroy turns his malevolent gaze on Picard.</context>
      <utterance>Praetor Shinzon wants him on the bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, human... you've met your better self!</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing to Counsellor Troi?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm preparing her for Shinzon... To sooth him as she soothes you. To stand at his side as she does at yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That will never happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to him, android. Such a small and weak creature. Yet he roars so valiantly...  It would take me but an instant to tear that valiant heart from your chest.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There'll be another after me. And another after that. You'll find we're a resilient species.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The B-9 prods Picard's back roughly with the disruptor. Picard grimaces in pain</context>
      <utterance>I look forward to the sport.  Take him.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Viceroy continues away down the corridor. The B-9 leads Picard along.</context>
      <utterance>Move.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are silent as they pass a few Reman guards. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sir. I thought it added a touch of reality to the performance.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mission was a success, sir. I have discovered the source of the Thalaron radiation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good work. The download?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data assumes the B-9's posture again as they pass some some Reman Warriors.</context>
      <utterance>He believes he has our communications protocols. But they will give him inaccurate locations for all Starfleet vessels.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass the Warriors.</context>
      <utterance>Move, puny human animal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bit less florid, Data.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads Picard down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Aye, sir... This way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>High above them, at the very top of the chamber, is a gigantic version of the spider-weapon we saw kill all the Romulan Senators before. It is breathtaking.</context>
      <utterance>This entire ship is, essentially, a flying Thalaron generator.  All its power relays lead to that device.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A weapon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data rotates his left hand and then slides it forward, exposing a hidden compartment in his wrist. He removes a small, silver disc. This is a cool new piece of Federation technology called an ETU. (Emergency Transport Unit.)</context>
      <utterance>It would appear so.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geordi equipped me with the prototype for the Emergency Transport Unit. I recommend you use it to return to the Enterprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll only work for one of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Recommendations?</context>
      <utterance>We'll find a way off together.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data inserts the ETU back into his wrist and they leave the chamber.</context>
      <utterance>There is a shuttlebay 948 meters from our current location.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon looks at him, confused.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Picard?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sprint down the twisting, dark corridors -- Reman warriors suddenly appear before them! -- Data fires the disruptor as Picard launches himself into them -- A fight -- Picard uses a dazzlinq series of Starfleet hand- to-hand maneuvers -- he dramatically subdues the Remans. More Reman warriors appear down the corridor. Picard grabs a disruptor. And instantly spins to fire a blazing disruptor. A battle breaks out in the corridor -- the energy beams and explosions illuminating the violent fire fight in strobe-like bursts. They run to another corridor and finally arrive at the shuttlebay door -- it does not open.</context>
      <utterance>This way, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data tosses his disruptor to Picard -- Picard catches it and instantly spins and fires -- he uses both disruptors to fire down both ends of the corridor like a Western sheriff -- keeping the Remans at bay -- As Data uses both hands to punch numbers into the shuttlebay door security panel at an amazing rate --</context>
      <utterance>It seems to have an encrypted security system. Reman warriors are closing in on them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alacrity would be appreciated, Commander.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are trying to override the access codes. Reman is really a most complex language with pictographs representing certain verb roots and --</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard lays down a blistering barrage of cover fire as he and Data duck into the shuttlebay.</context>
      <utterance>While I find that fascinating, Data, we really need that Goddamned door open! The shuttlebay door slides open.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you imagine this is?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard shoots him a look and presses some controls. The Scorpion lifts off. Hovers a few feet over the deck. Picard elegantly swings it around toward the large shuttlebay external doors as:</context>
      <utterance>Port thrusters, sir. Would you like me to drive?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you open the shuttlebay doors?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Affirmative, sir. Negative, sir. They have instigated security overrides and erected a force field around the external portals.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swings the Scorpion around again so it is facing the doors they came through, the doors back into the ship. Data is dubious.</context>
      <utterance>Well then... only one way to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think this is a wise course of action?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're about to find out... Power up disruptors and fire on my mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the Scorpion's forward disruptors fire! The doors into the ship explode! Picard powers forward!</context>
      <utterance>Fire!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worf! Lock on transporters!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tractor beam! Now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Enterprise is immaterial! They won't make it back to Federation space.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This has gone far enough!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we discussed patience, Commander.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context>Shinzon stands and briskly pulls down his uniform tunic exactly as we've seen Picard do a thousand times.</context>
      <utterance>And mine is wearing thin, young man! We supported you because you promised action. And yet you delay and you waste your time playing games with Picard while --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Does that satisfy you?</context>
      <utterance>Commander Suran, the games are over. In two days the Federation will be crippled beyond repair.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when I return... you and I shall have a little talk about showing proper respect!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="51">
   <speaker>DONATRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does anyone in this room harbor any illusions about what he means by "showing proper respect"?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAL'AURA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening to his face?</utterance>
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want opinions. He is clearly out of his mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SURAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But can he complete his mission?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONATRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at her.</context>
      <utterance>Should he?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONATRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Are you prepared to have your hands drenched in blood? He'll show them no mercy. And his sins will mark us all for generations. Is that what you truly want, Romulans?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONATRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and stalks out.</context>
      <utterance>I think you should consider that question now -- or else you may have a lifetime to think about it in the dilithium mines.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The more I studied his DNA the more confusing it got. Finally I could only come to one conclusion... Shinzon was created with temporal RNA sequencing. He was designed so that at a certain point his aging process could be accelerated to reach your age more quickly, so he could replace you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the Romulans abandoned the plan...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a result the temporal sequencing was never activated. Remember, he was supposed to replace you at nearly your current age. He was engineered to skip thirty years of life. But since the RNA sequencing was never activated, his cellular structure has started to break down. He's dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dying?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wasn't designed to live a complete, human life span. PlCARD Can anything be done for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not without a complete myelodysplastic infusion from the only donor with compatible DNA. But that would mean draining all your blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why he went to all that trouble to capture you. PlCARD How long does he have?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard considers this.</context>
      <utterance>I can't be sure but the rate of decay seems to be accelerating.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then he'll come for me as a donor.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brother. I cannot move.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I have only activated your cognitive and communication subroutines.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you are dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have been programmed to gather information that can be used against this ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know anything about Shinzon's plans against the Federation?</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any knowledge of the tactical abilities of his ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Can I move now?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I must deactivate you.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For how long?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indefinitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Data gazes at the B-9 deeply.</context>
      <utterance>How long is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data reaches forward and deactivates his brother. The B-9's eyes lose the spark of life. He stands, frozen. Data stands before him.</context>
      <utterance>A long time, brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's called a Cascading Biogenic Pulse. The unique properties of Thalaron radiation allow the energy beam to expand almost without limits. Depending on the radiant intensity it could encompass a ship... or a planet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's exactly what he's going to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His hatred of the Federation is apparent. He would have built a weapon of that scope for one reason. He is going after Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh boy. Destroy humanity and the Federation is crippled...</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the Romulans invade.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you be certain?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>I know how he thinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And there's no way to penetrate his cloak?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He could pass within 10 meters of every ship in Starfleet and they'd never know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we do have one advantage.  He needs your blood to live. He might come after you first.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm counting on it... We've been ordered to head to sector 3274. Starfleet is diverting the fleet to meet us there.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strength in numbers?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat as he looks at them gravely.</context>
      <utterance>We can only hope so.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Riker knows exactly what Picard is saying: the Enterprise is expendable.</context>
      <utterance>He can't be allowed to use that weapon. All other concerns are secondary. Do you understand me?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard stands. Presses a comm button.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All hands. Battle stations.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The montage ends as...</context>
      <utterance>Captain's Personal Log. Supplemental. We're heading toward Federation space at maximum warp. The crew has responded with the dedication I've come to expect of them. And like a thousand other commanders on a thousand other battlefields throughout history, I wait for the dawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To seek out new life and new civilizations. Zephyr Cochran's own words. When Charles Darwin set out on the H.M.S. Beagle, on his journey into the unknown... he sailed without a single musket.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was another time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to go --</context>
      <utterance>How far we've come. Let me know if you need anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Jean Luc...  ... He is not you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>What makes us who we are, Doctor? Can you tell me that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A matter of hours now -- Shinzon shoves him away. Stands.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon slams his command chair in fury. The Viceroy watches him carefully. A beat. Shinzon regains his composure. He sits again in his command chair.</context>
      <utterance>If you don't begin the procedure soon you'll never make it back to Romulus. You shouldn't have delayed. You should have killed Picard the moment --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long until we reach the Rift?</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon leans back, satisfied. And looks at the viewscreen. The image on the viewscreen is shocking. The Enterprise only a few hundred yards away.</context>
      <utterance>Seven minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The images before them quickly change to show another sector and a blip representing the Enterprise.</context>
      <utterance>Show me our current position.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long until we reach the fleet?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The images before them change to show sector 3274. We see blips denoting Starfleet ships moving into position. Picard gazes at the projection of stars before them for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>At our current velocity we will arrive at sector 3274 in approximately 40 minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"For now we see but through a glass darkly..." He said he's a mirror.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not agree. Although you share the same genetic structure, the events of your life have created unique individual.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But so much is the same. On a biological level he is... and I will not accept the idea that there is nothing I can do. I have a responsibility to try to make a human connection with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He would deny a "human" connection is possible. He considers himself entirely Reman.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He may have already rejected my humanity, but you also have a twin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir, it is not possible. The B-9 is physically identical to me, although his neural pathways are not as advanced. But even if they were, he would not be me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you be sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>I aspire, sir. To be better than I am. The B-9 does not. Nor does Shinzon.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the projections before them sputter with static for a moment. Flickering.</context>
      <utterance>We'll never know what Shinzon might have been. Had he stood where I did as a child? And looked up at the stars. Picard's words linger in the air for a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are passing through the Bassen Rift. The projections will return when we have cleared it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's interfering with our uplink from Starfleet cartography?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. The Rift effects all long-range communications --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the viewscreen, we see disruptor blasts streaking from the Scimitar -- slicing into the Enterprise.</context>
      <utterance>Target weapons systems and shields. I don't want the Enterprise destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you learn to see in the dark, Captain?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Report.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's firing through his cloak. We can't get a lock.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He disabled our warp drive with his first shot. We've only got impulse.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long range communication is impossible as long as we're in the rift -- The ship SHUDDERS again --</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worf, prepare a full phaser spread, zero elevation. All banks on my mark. Scan for shield impacts and stand by photon torpedoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye, sir The ship ROCKS again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fire!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are losing dorsal shields --</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Full axis rotation to port! Fire all ventral phasers!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Minimal damage to the Scimitar.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geordi, get those shields online.</context>
      <utterance>Defensive pattern Kirk Epsilon.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Counselor Troi, report to the bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless we can disable his cloak we're just going to be firing in the dark. PlCARD Agreed.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, we're being hailed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon appears on the viewscreen. He is on the bridge of the Scimitar.</context>
      <utterance>On screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Picard, will you join me in your Ready Room?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't trace my holographic emitters, Captain. So don't bother. And you can't contact Starfleet. We're quite alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just the two of us now, Jean Luc, as it should be... Your ship and mine... You and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To accept your surrender. I can clearly destroy you at any time. Lower your shields and allow me to transport you to my ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what of the Enterprise?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have little interest in your quaint vessel, Captain. If the Enterprise will withdraw to a distance of one hundred light years, it will not be harmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know that's not possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know... you'll all gladly die to save your home world.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard looks at him deeply, relentlessly refusing to give up.</context>
      <utterance>Look at me, Shinzon! Do you feel the blood pumping inside you? Your hands, your eyes, your nature, are the same as mine. Buried deep inside you beneath the years of pain and anger is a capacity you've forgotten. It's the one way our mirror can reflect the two of us exactly because it's the very thing that truly defines us. To be human is to try to make yourself better than you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you as well as I know myself, Shinzon. There was a time you looked at the stars and dreamed of what might be.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so long.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Childish dreams, Captain. Lost in the dilithium mines of Remus. I'm what you see now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard steps toward him.</context>
      <utterance>I see more than what you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon slowly backs away as Picard continues to move toward him relentlessly.</context>
      <utterance>I see what you could be.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is better than that!</context>
      <utterance>The man who is Jean Luc Picard and Shinzon of Remus won't exterminate the population of an entire planet!</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon looks at him, questioning.</context>
      <utterance>And what will he do with that life?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon doesn't respond.</context>
      <utterance>If I were to beam to your ship... let you complete your medical procedure, give you a full life... what would you do with the time?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You once asked me about your past. Your history. When I was your age, I burned with ambition. I was very proud and my pride often hurt people. I made every wrong choice a young man can... But one thing saved me... I had a father who believed in me. Who took the time to teach me a better way. You have the same father.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if I gave you my life, what would you do with it? Would you spend the years in a blaze of hatred as you are now? Or could you change? Could you try to remember a mother's touch you never felt? A father's words you never heard? Could you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon doesn't respond. But Picard knows he has made a connection. For this brief moment reconciliation is possible. He proceeds quietly:</context>
      <utterance>But you want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon looks at him with an aching sadness. What might have been.</context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you about our father.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's your life... not mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can still make a choice! Make the right one now!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon backs away, unable to fight his nature:</context>
      <utterance>I have no choices! I can't fight what I am!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon ends the transmission and his holographic image flickers and fades away. Picard stands alone, drained.</context>
      <utterance>I'll show you my true nature. Your nature. And as Earth dies -- remember that I'm forever Shinzon of Remus! And my voice will echo through time long after yours has faded to a dim memory.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before the Viceroy can move the Scimitar suddenly ROCKS -- attacked from somewhere! Shinzon is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Disable their weapons!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Report!</utterance>
   <speaker>REMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Romulan!</context>
      <utterance>Two ships decloaking, sir!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe it or not, I think the cavalry has arrived.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're being hailed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the viewscreen: Commander Donatra shimmers into view.</context>
      <utterance>On screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONATRA</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Picard, Commander Donatra of the Warbird Valdore. Might we be of assistance?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your timing is impeccable, Commander.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONATRA</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Empire considers this a matter of internal security. We regret you've become involved.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the viewscreen, the Valdore ROCKS from a disruptor blast.</context>
      <utterance>When this is over, I owe you a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONATRA</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context>The transmission ends.</context>
      <utterance>Romulan ale, Captain. Let's get to work. Valdore out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coordinate our attack with the Valdore's tactical officer. Triangulate fire on any shield impacts.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Enterprise ROCKS from a photon torpedo impact --</context>
      <utterance>Aye, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aft shields are down to forty percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Auxiliary power to forward shields.</context>
      <utterance>Keep our bow to the Scimitar.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Target the flanking Warbird. All forward disruptor banks on my mark.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forward shields are down to ten percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring us about!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let her pursue -- drop cloak on the aft port quadrant and prepare for full emergency stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's almost on us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the viewscreen we see the Valdore in pursuit, gaining. The Reman crew is getting nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Praetor...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DONATRA</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid that drink will have to wait, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have life support?</utterance>
   <speaker>DONATRA</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the moment. But we're dead in the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Understood -- Then the ship ROCKS --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have lost structural integrity on decks twelve through seventeen, sections four through ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Emergency force fields are holding.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deanna goes to Picard:</context>
      <utterance>Evacuate those decks and reroute field power to forward shields.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain -- I might have a way to find them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Counselor?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The one thing he may have forgotten in the course of battle: me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She quickly goes to Worf at tactical.</context>
      <utterance>Make it so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the viceroy suddenly stiffens, alarm in his eyes --</context>
      <utterance>Prepare a lateral run -- all starboard disruptors.</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?! Focus on your job!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VICEROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, we have lost ventral shielding on deck twenty nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An alarm klaxon suddenly rings through the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>Divert power and compensate --</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Intruder alert!</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Riker and Worf quickly head toward the turbolift as:</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data immediately assumes Worf's position at tactical.</context>
      <utterance>Security detail to deck twenty nine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's getting his cloak back. We have exhausted our compliment of photon torpedoes. Phaser banks are down to four percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if we target all phasers in a concentrated attack?</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard thinks.</context>
      <utterance>The Scimitar's shields are still at seventy percent. It would make no difference, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the hole in the hull, Picard sees the Scimitar slowly turning. Slowly advancing. They see another part of the Scimitar disappear, the cloak returning.</context>
      <utterance>They're stopping...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to look me in the eye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He thinks he knows exactly what I'm going to do...</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits in his command chair and begins quickly entering command instructions in his chair console.</context>
      <utterance>We've got him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are being hailed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deanna, stand by.  Open a channel.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you're still alive, Jean Luc.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Picard continues to enter command codes -- transmits them to Deanna at helm -- she receives the commands, nods. All of this as Picard buys some time:</context>
      <utterance>Don't you think it's time to surrender? I'll have my cloak back in a matter of minutes and your poor ship is shot to pieces. Why should the rest of your crew have to die?</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard indicates for Data to end the communication. Then:</context>
      <utterance>I never told you about my first Academy evaluation, did I? I received very high marks for my studies. But I was found lacking in certain other areas. Personality traits, you might say. In particular I was thought to be extremely...  ... over-confident.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geordi, put 211 power to the engines. Take it from life support if you have to -- everything you can give me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aye, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deanna, on my mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard leans forward in his chair:</context>
      <utterance>Ready, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(to Deanna)</context>
      <utterance>All hands, brace for impact!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data joins Picard as:</context>
      <utterance>Data, I need you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Computer. Auto-destruct sequence Omega. Zero time delay. Recognize voice pattern Jean Luc Picard. Authorization Alpha Alpha Three Zero Five --</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Then the ship gives a final LURCH. The Scimitar is free. An eerie moment of silence after the explosive tearing and grinding. Picard watches through the gaping hole in the hull as the Scimitar backs away. Another section of the Scimitar disappears. Shinzon almost has his cloak back.</context>
      <utterance>Auto-destruct is off-line.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Target disruptors. Destroy them.</utterance>
   <speaker>REMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Shinzon looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Disruptors are off-line, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deploy the weapon. Kill everything on that ship. Then set a course for Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>REMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Picard?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our greater goal is more important, brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>REMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shinzon gazes at the Enterprise on the viewscreen.</context>
      <utterance>But, Praetor, you won't survive without him...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some ideals are worth dying for, aren't they, Jean Luc?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long until he can fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The targeting sequence should take about four minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how can he? He'll kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard's face is set, resolute. He knows what he must do. Picard grabs a phaser rifle from a weapons locker as...</context>
      <utterance>This isn't about me anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prepare for a site-to-site transport.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, we won't be able to bring you back. It's a one way trip. Captain, I don't know if the transporter --</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's an order, Commander.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, allow me to go. You are needed here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deanna takes Data's arm. Looks at him. She knows this is something Picard must do himself.</context>
      <utterance>Sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard powers up the phaser rifle as:</context>
      <utterance>Let him go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have the bridge, Commander. Use all available power to move away from the Scimitar.  Now, Mister La Forge.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geordi nervously works some controls on his console and Picard dematerializes. Then the transporter panel explodes in a shower of sparks.</context>
      <utterance>Aye, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data thinks for a moment. Then:</context>
      <utterance>That's it. Transporters are down.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads toward the turbolift, Geordi following.</context>
      <utterance>Counsellor Troi, please assume command. Geordi, if you will come with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is our approximate distance?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>400 meters.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Data backs up a little more He looks at Geordi again. Deeply.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Geordi operates his tricorder and the force field at the end of the corridor snaps off -- The void of space fills the corridor and Data takes a running start -- he races down the long corridor and leaps --</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Geordi. Deactivate the field.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O</mode>
      <context>Suddenly -- a MASSIVE BLAST as the doors to the bridge explode in. Shinzon spins to see -- Picard framed in the doorway, phaser rifle ready. Picard instantly fires for the Cascading Pulse control -- but Shinzon dives to cover it -- the phaser blast hits Shinzon in the chest -- he recoils, slamming to the deck, stunned. The few remaining Remans on the bridge spin to Picard, firing disruptors -- Picard dives for cover and battles them with his phaser rifle -- He succeeds in stunning the Remans but a final disruptor blast knocks Picard to the deck -- the phaser rifle spins away --</context>
      <utterance>Forty-seven. Forty six...</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Shinzon pulls himself up and races to snatch up a disruptor from a fallen comrade -- As Picard leaps up, grabbing a piece of wreckage, a long metal rod -- Picard thrusts it forward like a spear -- Impaling Shinzon. A stunned moment of silence as Shinzon gazes at Picard, almost with a look of disbelief. Blood spews from his mouth as he lets out a tormented cry. And then, amazingly, Shinzon forces himself forward -- pushing Picard back against a wall -- Shinzon slowly walks toward Picard, forcing himself down the length of the spear -- the spear point explodes through Shinzon's back -- the weight of Shinzon's body is pinning Picard against the wall -- time is running out --</context>
      <utterance>Twenty nine... Twenty eight...</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Shinzon forces himself down the spear:</context>
      <utterance>Eighteen... Seventeen...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHINZON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finally thrusts himself down the whole spear and clasps his dying hands firmly around Picard's throat --</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad we're together now -- our destiny is complete.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Data sprints to the bridge -- He instantly tears open his wrist and pulls out the small, silver disc we saw earlier -- the Emergency Transport Unit -- he slaps it on Picard's shoulder. A final look between them --</context>
      <utterance>Ten...Nine...</utterance>
   <speaker>COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Data activates the ETU -- Picard dematerializes. Data looks at the space where Picard was and says simply:</context>
      <utterance>Seven.. Six...</utterance>
   <speaker>DATA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he spins and pulls out his phaser -- And fires point-blank into the Scimitar's warp core relays -- the bridge explodes -- Data is incinerated --</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard doesn't answer, he just stares forward. Deanna goes to Riker.</context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Riker looks toward the glowing debris field in the distance. He puts an arm around Deanna. Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Data.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, we're being hailed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On screen...  ... Open a channel.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONATRA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Commander Donatra of the Valdore. We're dispatching shuttles with medical personnel and supplies.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The transmission ends.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Commander.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geordi... prepare the shuttlebay for arrivals. They don't know our procedures so just... open the doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of it, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and heads toward his Ready Room. The others watch him go with great sadness. When the Ready Room doors close behind Picard, Deanna finally allows herself to cry. Riker holds her closely. Slow fade to...</context>
      <utterance>Number One.  You have the bridge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see it is the now re-activated B-9 sitting across from him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know if all this has made sense to you, but I wanted you to know what kind of man he was. In his quest to be more like us, he helped show us what it means to be human.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My brother was not a human.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he wasn't... But his wonder and his curiosity about every facet of human life helped all of us see the best parts of ourselves. He embraced change... because he always wanted to be more than he was.</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Worf interrupts on comm:</context>
      <utterance>Well, I hope someday you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - ON COMM</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, the Hemingway has arrived to tow us to spacedock.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The B-9 does not respond. He is looking rather blankly at the padd on Picard's desk. Picard begins to leave when a sound stops him... humming. He turns back to the B-9. The B-9 is still looking blankly at the padd... but he's humming lightly to himself... then he begins to sing, very softly...</context>
      <utterance>On my way. Please notify Commander Riker...  ... We'll talk later?</utterance>
   <speaker>B-9</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard watches him for a moment; great emotion playing over his features, and then goes.</context>
      <utterance>"Blue skies, smiling at me, Nothing but blue skies do I see." Then the B-9 is silent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard stops, looks at Riker deeply.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry you won't be here for the re-fit, but I know the Titan needs you immediately. Riker does not respond.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Titan's a fine ship, Will. And she's getting a captain worthy of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's the most beautiful ship I've ever seen.  ... But she's not the Enterprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promise you in time, she'll become your home... If I could offer you one piece of advice?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When your first officer insists that you can't go on away missions... Ignore him --</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment.</context>
      <utterance>I intend to.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Serving with you has been an honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The honor was mine. Captain Riker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... what's the old man like?</utterance>
   <speaker>OPS OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Commander Madden prepares himself.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you go in and find out?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't imagine them, Jean Luc. They're kids! All with advance degrees in xenobiology and out to conquer every disease in the quadrant.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reminds me of a young doctor I used to know...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're running me ragged. Nothing but questions day and night... I love it! Come to dinner and I'll tell you all about it. There's a Bajoran band at the officer's mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not tonight, I have work here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEVERLY</speaker>
      <mode>ON VIEWSCREEN</mode>
      <context>Commander Madden enters quickly -- he did not use the door chime so Picard is surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Soon then. I'll save the last dance for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard stands, they shake hands as:</context>
      <utterance>Commander Martin Madden reporting for duty, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome aboard, Commander. I hope, your transfer didn't come as too much of a surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was... honored, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I needed you immediately to help oversee the re-fit...  ... Your service record on the Talos is exemplary, but there are a few things I would like to discuss with you regarding my requirements for a First Officer. Shall we say dinner in my quarters at 1900 hours?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard heads toward the door, carrying a few padds.</context>
      <utterance>Very good, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commander, I don't know how they did it on the Talos, but we have door chimes on the Enterprise. We use them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard goes to the bridge, Madden following...</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Picard goes to them:</context>
      <utterance>You don't understand the Captain -- there should be no changes until we have discussed the modifications with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your new chair, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENSIGN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>command interfaces with --</context>
      <utterance>It's the Mark Seven, Captain. State-of-the-art ergonomics...</utterance>
   <speaker>WORF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told him you're comfortable with your old chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He settles into his new command chair. Looks around for a beat at his new bridge crew. Fresh-faced kids. A new generation to teach and nurture. He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Let's give it a try.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Worf and Geordi exchange a look, surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Feels good.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He presses the button again and the restraints zip back into the body of the chair. He is delighted. He turns to Madden:</context>
      <utterance>It's about time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madden sits in the First Officer's chair, Picard shares a padd with him.</context>
      <utterance>Commander, please sit down...</utterance>
   <speaker>PICARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And we cut to --</context>
      <utterance>... We've received our first assignment. We're going to be exploring the Denab system. It should be exciting. It's a place... where no one has gone before.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
