<movie id="523" title="Starship Troopers">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YOUNG PEOPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mobile infantery logo: LIGHTNING BOLTS ON A BLACK SHIELD.</context>
      <utterance>I'm doing my part... Me, too... Are you ?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Join the mobile infantery and save the world ! Service guarantees citizen-ship. Would you like to know more ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BRIGHT EXPLOSION in space out beyond the moon.</context>
      <utterance>The Bugs send another meteor our way !</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Would you like to know more ?</context>
      <utterance>But this time we are ready ! Planetary defenses are better than ever !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>orbits a twin star system whose brutal gravitational forces produce an unlimited supply of meteorites... A "You are here" map of the KNOWN GALAXY shows the Earth in relationship to the BUG PLANETARY SYSTEM and Klendathu.</context>
      <utterance>Klendathu, source of the bug meteor attacks,</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To ensure the safety of our solar system, Klendathu must be eliminated ! Would you like to know more ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The teacher JEAN RASCZAK, 38, a rugged veteran who proudly displays his missing hand, scowls at Johnny, bemused.</context>
      <utterance>The end of another school year, and for me no doubt another failure... Rico, pay attention !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But as soon as Rasczak turns back to the class, Johnny begins to sketch a cartoon on his desk's touch screen.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Mr. Rasczak.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Democracy when social scientists brought the world to the brink of chaos, and how the veterans took control and imposed a stability that has lasted for generations since... You know these facts but have I taught you anything of value ? You. Why are only citizens allowed to vote ? Rasczak points at LANNY, 17, with his stump</context>
      <utterance>Here in History and Moral Philosophy we've explored the decline of</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasczak is crestfallen, makes a big show of patience.</context>
      <utterance>It's a reward... what the Federation gives you for doing Federal Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter. Johnny's cartoon, meanwhile, is taking shape: Johnny and Carmen flying round planet Venus in a space ship.</context>
      <utterance>No. Something given has no value ! Haven't I taught you dimwits anything ? I guess they ought to revoke my teaching credential...</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CARL JENKINS, 18, a superintelligent geek, jumps in.</context>
      <utterance>When you vote, you're exercising political authority. You're using force. And force, my friends, is violence, the supreme authority from which all other authority derives.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter. Rasczak grins.</context>
      <utterance>Gee, we always thought you were the supreme authority, Mr. Rasczak.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DIZZY FLORES, 18, athletic, pretty, no nonsense, chimes in.</context>
      <utterance>In my classroom, you bet. Whether it's exerted by ten or ten billion, political authority is violence by degree. The people we call citizens have earned the right to wield it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother always says that violence never solves anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really ? I wonder what the city fathers of Hiroshima would have to say about that. You. Rasczak points at Carmen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny presses "SEND" on his desk, and the cartoon appears across the way on Carmen's screen.</context>
      <utterance>They probably wouldn't say anything. Hiroshima was destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Rasczak looks away, Carmen throws Johnny her wonderful smile, and Johnny's gone, checked out, flying round Venus.</context>
      <utterance>Correct. Naked force has settled more issues in history than any other factor. The contrary opinion 'violence never solves anything' is wishful thinking at its worst.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy notices the dreamy look on Johnny's face. So does Rasczak. He points at him with his stump, snaps Johnny to.</context>
      <utterance>People who forget that always pay... They pay with their lives and their freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>if any, between the citizen and the civilian ?</context>
      <utterance>You. Tell me the moral difference,</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>responsibility for the safety of the body politic, of which he is a member, defending it, if need be, with his life. The civilian does not.</context>
      <utterance>The difference lies in the field of civic virtue. A citizen accepts personal</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you believe it ?</context>
      <utterance>The exact words of the text. But do you understand it ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bell rings. Rasczak shrugs, indifferent.</context>
      <utterance>Of course you don't. I doubt if any of you here would recognize 'civic virtue' if it bit you in the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's it. Have a nice life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, let's see if they've posted the math final test yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Rico, we gonna take Tesla ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How should I know ?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're captain of the team !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen enters her name, receives her score: 97% ! She beams.</context>
      <utterance>First thing Fleet Academy looks at is your math scores. Wish me luck !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she spots Carl across the way talking with MARCO, 17.</context>
      <utterance>Your turn...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen rushes off. Johnny checks his score: 35% ! Crushed, he makes sure no none else has seen. Carl walks up to him.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on... I wanna talk to Marco. His sister's at Fleet !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still haven't kissed her yet ? Don't lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the hurry ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl points out Dizzy, talking with friends.</context>
      <utterance>Others are waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you read her mind ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's true. You can tell by the way she looks at Johnny.</context>
      <utterance>Don't have to... Some mating semaphore is pretty hard to miss.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I want Carmen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen returns to Johnny as Carls heads off.</context>
      <utterance>You got it bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen blushes, covers.</context>
      <utterance>Don't forget about this afternoon.  He's always late when he walks you home to fish for a kiss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's flying starships !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reflexes are critical</context>
      <utterance>Marco's sister. Can you imagine maneuvering half a million tons through crwoded space lanes... You gotta have nerves of steel !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen notices the way Dizzy's looking at Johnny, doesn't like it one bit, takes Johnny's arm.</context>
      <utterance>I have good reflexes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon Johnny, we'll be late for Biology.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eeuch !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, c'mon, it's just a bug.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIOLOGY TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nature's finest achievement. I'm afraid it isn't true. This Arkellian Sand Beetle is superior in many ways. It has fewer moving parts, can reproduce itself in vast numbers, and unboud by concerns of ego and mortality, makes the perfect selfless member of society.</context>
      <utterance>Just a bug, eh ? We humans like to think we are</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny slices the abdomen open with asurgical laser. Green fluid sprays from the slit. Carmen turns away looking ill.</context>
      <utterance>Better put your goggles on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we 're intelligent. Human minds have invented art, mathematics and interstellar travel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIOLOGY TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to an insect evolution chart that starts with a common ant and ends with a two meter tall ARACHNID WARRIOR.</context>
      <utterance>True, we know of no insect society that has produced a Shakespeare, an Einstein or a Cherynkov, but before you let that go to your head, take the example of the Arachnids, a highly organized, highly evolved insect society.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if that's the crop, that must be the gastric caecal...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads for the door, hand over her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me...!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>35% on the math final ! No one could be that dumb with numbers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, at least you didn't lose your lunch over a bug. How embarassing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who cares about bugs ? You can't go anywhere if you don't know math.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be so sure. I like you even if you are dumb with numbers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how come you won't hold hands with me at school ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want everyone to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why won't you kiss me when we're all alone ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come that's all you talk about anymore ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indeed, they are all alone now. The look in Johnny's eye says how about it. Carmen grins, reaches for Johnny's hand.</context>
      <utterance>It's all I think about anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't walk me home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were going to help Carl.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carl can wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny's face darkens with frustration.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny, my Dad's home today.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he got against me... I mean, I 'm a teenager. You can't be a citizen when you're only a teenager !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not you, Johnny. Your parents are rich they don't need to be citizens, and that stuff means a lot to my dad. He's a veteran.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if your dad doesn't like me, how come we're such good friends ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen steps into the flux. ZAPPP! She's gone. Johnny grins, happy to be in love.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I do what I want, eh ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't think about it... go on instinct.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ace of spades appears, and the computer indicates "no match". Carl puts another card up, the jack of diamonds.</context>
      <utterance>Ace of spades.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Statistically speaking you should've accidentally guessed right by know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luck is not a factor. No one really knows why some people are sensitive and some aren't. Federal studies like this might provide a clue. The next card up is the nine of clubs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, A GIANT YELLOW FROG jumps onto the keyboard, fritzing the monitor. Johnny removes the blindfold.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't want to know what everyone was thinking. Four of spades.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny knows this frog, scratches him on the neck.</context>
      <utterance>Cyrano, you big yellow turd !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just wants attention. You don't play with him like you used to. Carl concentrates for a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cyrano's eyes widen. He hops off the table and up the stairs two at a time. Carl clears the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Go bug Mom, Cyrano.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you make him do that ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl, puts up more cards, Johnny misses them all.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be afraid. Can't do humans... yet. C'mon let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten of clubs. You still gonna sign up for Starside R&amp;D ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Who wouldn't want that ?</context>
      <utterance>Passport to the Universe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been thinking about applying for Federal Service, too. Fleet, maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father will never let you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm eighteen. It's my decision, I think I'd make a pretty good pilot. I've good great reflexes. You need that for maneuvering, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only 1 in 14 male applicants make it through stellar navigation. So what do you think your chances are ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight point... no, uh, seven...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you can't do those numbers, you haven't got a chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>and I don't think it'll work out for us if I'm not.</context>
      <utterance>All I know is Carmen's going to be a citizen,</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl puts a card up.</context>
      <utterance>Love... how excruciatingly pathetic. Now try and pay attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The computer indicates a match. Johnny peers around at the monitor. It is the Queen of hearts.</context>
      <utterance>Queen of hearts.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what do you know about that !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy bounces a JUMP SHOE to Johnny. The spring fires and vaults it high into the air. Johnny catches it, puts it on, smiles cocky at the TESLA GIANTS who suit up in red and gold.</context>
      <utterance>Tesla's tough. They tumble good and they hit HARD.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We tumble good, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander points. The SCOREBOARD shows TIGERS 19, GIANTS 20, three minutes and counting on the clock. Johnny grins.</context>
      <utterance>Time's running out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot can happen in three minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny takes the handoff, flips over a gauntlet of Giant guards. Zander hurls himself at Johnny, misses. Johnny scores. Zander tumbles into the crowd, loses a jump shoe.</context>
      <utterance>Hut... hut !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you alright ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm getting better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>21	EXT	SIDELINE - DAY - ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>finds his shoe, straps it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you doing later ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone is going to the dance. Aren't you ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander heads for the field. Carmen follows, interested.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It's my last night as acivilian. I ship out for Tereshkova tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A REFEREE blows his whistle at Zander, signalling impatiently.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to the Academy ? That's where I want to go. I'd love to talk to you abou that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm all ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you have to finish the game ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get any ideas. She's my girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny scowls at Zander, turns his head to look back at Carmen. She waves, smiling. The Giants pull ablitz.</context>
      <utterance>You can never be sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy slams Johnny upside his helmet with her forearm.</context>
      <utterance>Flip six, three hole. Rico ? Hey !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were drifting. Flip six, three hole. On one, got it ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They make fists and break.</context>
      <utterance>Just throw me the ball, Diz.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who said you could grow up so fast ? Last time I checked you were only five years old. You had such a bright little face...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny's FATHER enters carrying a FEDERAL SERVICE CATALOGUE.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, don't get mushy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This came for you today. I presume on your request.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot of my friends are doing Federal Service...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>You aren't thinking of applying...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you lost you lost your mind ? I'd rather take ten lashes in Public Square than see you ruin your life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny, people get hurt... people get killed in the Federal Service. If something happened to you I don't know what I would do...</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who gave you this idea ? It's that teacher. What's his name ? You know the one I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Rasczak.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rasczak... Silly name. There ought to be a law against using a school as a recruiting station !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sorta discourages you really.</context>
      <utterance>No, Mr. Rasczak doesn't do that at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, because you're going to Harvard, and that's the end of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm eighteen. It's my decision.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, is that how it is ?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can you guess what it is ?</context>
      <utterance>Wait you two. Dad and I have a surprise for you that will settle this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whad'ya think of that ?</context>
      <utterance>A trip to the Outer Rings.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow ! Santori and Zegema Beach, I've always wanted to go there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good good, then it's all settled.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A year at Harvard and you'll see this "Federal Service" is just menial training for inferior people so they can call themselves "citizens" and take airs for the rest of their lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute ! Carl is doing his Federal and he isn't inferior. He's the smartest kid at school !</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny puts on his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Carl's a fine boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what they teach at Harvard, but I think I'm pretty good enough the way I am !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny, please. Calm yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny stomps out, the transporter goes ZAPPP !</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's what you're saying ! You're saying that I'm not good enough the way I am now !</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you go and do that ? He was all ready to go Zegema Beach !</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Teenagers !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BAND LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights go down. Dizzy, dressed pretty, brightens when she sees Johnny standing alone near the dance floor.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, everybody, this is the last dance, so let's turn down the lights and make it a slow one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Rico, wanna dance ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, Diz, I promised Carmen...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy pulls him onto the floor, holds him close.</context>
      <utterance>Too bad for her if she's not around.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, it's sad... Most of us probably won't see each other again after tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still gonna play for Brazil ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like, unless Tokyo lets me start.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, anyone who gets you is lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy looks at Johnny meaningfully. He's distracted. Carmen crosses the room, stunning in her formal.</context>
      <utterance>How come we never got together ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't we just be friends, Diz ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, look, Diz...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess you gotta go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny heads for Carmen. Dizzy watches jealously as Carmen takes his hand. She looks around for someone to dance with. Carl, a nerd in a tux, waves shyly.</context>
      <utterance>You're the best.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it great to be in love ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I know if this is love ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wouldn't be so romantic if we weren't...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl and Dizzy dance by, Dizzy smiling bravely because Carl is a terrible dancer. Johnny goes in for the kiss again.</context>
      <utterance>Outa the way you two !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Romance is just a vestigial biological response to procreation...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny's confidence makes her smile. Johnny moves in to kiss her, but the music ends. Everyone applauds. The lights come up and people head for the doors. Johnny sees Rasczak.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, you're in love with me... You just dont know it yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, I want to talk to Mr. Rasczak.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny heads over to Rasczak.</context>
      <utterance>I'll meet you outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Rasczak ?</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Rico ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wanted to say thanks 'cause History and Moral Philosophy was the best class I had this year.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hope you learned something.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's not really my job to please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna join up, Mr. Rasczak. I think I have what it take to be a citizen.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good for you. Go find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What would you do if you were me ?</context>
      <utterance>Well, my parents are against it, and I know it's my choice, but I was wondering...</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Make your own choice, Rico.</context>
      <utterance>Figuring things out for yourself is the only freedom anyone really has. Use that freedom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny, this is Zander.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we know each other from the game. No hard feeling, eh, chum ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None at all... We won.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander takes back the wings and pins the to his tunic.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck at the academy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just got accepted to the Fleet Academy. Isn't that great ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean if he can get in, maybe I have a chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about ? We both know you're gonna be a pilot.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zander is going for pilot, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen pulls Johnny to a stop, looks him in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>You two have so much in common.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny Rico, you're jealous !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't help it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's nothing like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen smiles, leans in close to Johnny.</context>
      <utterance>I don't even know if you're my girl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you the boy for me ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss, tentatively, but the passion grows and they break apart, breathless.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna do it, Carmen. I'm gonna sign up for Federal Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Johnny...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone's looking... we shouldn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who cares ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right. Let's never stop...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without stopping, Johnny pulls Carmen into the flux. ZAPPP !</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you, there's a place for that !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, Carmen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her mouth on his and they melt together. The door flies open, and CARMEN'S DAD stands there.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carmen, it's late. Get inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen ducks inside. Her father looks Johnny over. He carries a terrible battle scar oon his face.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Dad. See you, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you around Carmen anymore. Get me ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe Carmen's gonna make her own decisions from now on, Mr. Ibanez. Carmen's Dad reddens. He'd like to punch Johnny out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARMEN'S DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carmen's gonna be a citizen. She don't need you and your rich family. The Federation'll give her everything she needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, leave him alone...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carmen's Dad slams the door in Johnny's face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RECRUITING SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fresh meat for the grinder, eh ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns in his chair to grab the forms. Johnny and his friends see that he is also missing both legs. The Recruiting Sergeant catches them looking, smiles even wider.</context>
      <utterance>That's us. Where do we sign ?</utterance>
   <speaker>RECRUITING SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he signs, Johnny looks at the campaign ribbons on the Recruiting Sergeant's chest. We hear MUSIC: "The Mobile Infantery Anthem" plays softly in honor of distant battles.</context>
      <utterance>Here and here and here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECRUITING SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the adventure of Federal Service. Follow the blue line.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A PSYCH OFFICER sits down across from each candidate.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is the part that hurts !</utterance>
   <speaker>PSYCH OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>questions. Please answer all questions truthfully. We'll know if you don't. Birthplace ?</context>
      <utterance>No talking please. I'm going to ask you some</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Psych Officer checks Johnny's response on a meter.</context>
      <utterance>Here in Buenos Aires.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PSYCH OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are your parents currently citizens ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PSYCH OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which do you think is more important, courage or confidence ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Courage, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>PSYCH OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>I want to be citizen because...</context>
      <utterance>Please complete this sentence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>well, because of my girl, sir.</context>
      <utterance>I want to be a citizen because...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm happy to tell you that you've been accepted for Federal Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow, that's great.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Major clucks his tongue as he highlights the last category on his list:</context>
      <utterance>Looks like you're quite an athlete. Boy, look at those reaction stats.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My job is to dertermine what you're best suited for.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be a pilot, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny swallows this. He knew it was coming. The Major deletes "Pilot" from the list, then several other items.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, son, no way. Your school records say you don't have the math skills.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns the monitor around and shows Johnny the list. The only thing left is MOBILE INFANTERY.</context>
      <utterance>That rules out the scientific and engineering applications, and I'm afraid we reserve non-military options for candidates who are frankly less able-bodied than you are, son...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like the only thing you're good for is cannon fodder. I'm putting you down for the Mobile Infantery.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHNNY ET AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...of my own free will, without promise, coercion, or inducement, after having been duly advised and warned of the meaning and consequence of this oath, do now enroll in the Federal Service of the Terran Federation for not less than two years and as much longer as may be required by the needs of the Service...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder where Carl is. You don't suppose...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Don rushes past, shamefaced, crying.</context>
      <utterance>Naw, I made it, Carl made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I guess he didn't...</context>
      <utterance>He was in the group with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Recruiting Sergeant is getting ready to go home. He's got legs now, and he takes a prosthetic arm from its case and snaps it on. He grins when he sees them staring.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh ! Don't make him feel worse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna go for pilot.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECRUITING SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny holds the door for Carmen and the Recruiting Sergeant. Suddenly Carl appears looking a little paler than usual.</context>
      <utterance>Good for you. We need every pilot we can get.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Carl, what's wrong ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get Starside R&amp;D ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well, everyone's a little impressed by this.</context>
      <utterance>I got Games &amp; Theory.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Games &amp; Theory ? That's Military Intelligence... Oh, Carl !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa ! Way to go, boy-yo !</utterance>
   <speaker>RECRUITING SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time we meet, I'll probably have to salute you. What about you, son ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Recruiting Sergeant beams, offers a prosthetic hand.</context>
      <utterance>Infantery, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECRUITING SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just what Johnny wanted to hear. They watch the old Sergeant walk away. MUSIC: "The Mobile Infantery Theme". Carmen takes Johnny and Carl by the arm as they walk.</context>
      <utterance>Well, good for you. The Mobile Infantery made me the man I am today.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's all make a vow. Let's swear we'll always be friends no matter what.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we're gonna be millions of light years away from each other, and chances are we'll never see each other again, but sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's gonna be so happy !</context>
      <utterance>I can't wait to tell my Dad I'm in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father's probably gonna kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll resign, and that's all there is to it. It might look bad, but if that's the worst you suffer...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't quit !</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, you will ! You're not going back. You're going to go on vacation !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny turns for the door. His father throws his last shot.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going on vacation ! I want to be acitizen ! It's my decision. I made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alright, THAT'S IT, YOU'RE...</context>
      <utterance>You walk out that door, you're cut off, young man... You understand me ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny, why won't you change your mind ? Does citizenship mean so much to you ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yeah, sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope so. I hope you don't ruin your life over some silly little girl who wants to look handsome in a uniform. Johnny's face reddens.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny turns on his heel, heads for the transporter. ZAPPP !</context>
      <utterance>Don't talk about my girl that way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're late.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the freight station, Carmen enters her Federal I.D. card and gets numbered tags for her bags.</context>
      <utterance>My Dad had to help me pack. Suddenly he's afraid he's never gonna see me again or something. It was sweet, but it took forever. Anyway, I guess I'm ready to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny loads them onto a conveyor belt.</context>
      <utterance>Me, too. I'm wearing everything I own.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor boy. I'm sorry your parents were so mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who cares ! The Federation'll give me everything I need for the next two years, right ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You talk to Carl ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen logs in, enters her destination: LUNA - TERESHKOVA FLEET ACADEMY. The tickets station spits out a pass.</context>
      <utterance>He left this morning. He couldn't say where.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen heads toward a bank of transporters. Johnny stops her, takes her by the arms.</context>
      <utterance>It's exciting, but it's scary, too isn't it. Going someplace new where you don't know anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna miss you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll miss you, too, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>P.A.</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outbound group 948A, Tereshkova, all sections, transporting at bank 5.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She scans her pass, but Johnny stops her again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Com'on, just say it. Try it on for size.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen kisses him, jumps into the transporter.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mean it ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZAPPP ! The last thing he sees are her beautiful eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I said it. Isn't that enough ? Don't forget to write !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From all over the known Galaxy, prospectice citizens work together to make a better tomorrow ! Would you like to know more ?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A murderer was captured and tried today. Sentence: DEATH. Tonight at six, all net, all channels. Would you like to know more ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Archival pictures of a captive two meter ARACHNID WARRIOR, multiple eyes, cutting mouthparts and claws. Wary SCIENTISTS keep their distance as it eats a COW.</context>
      <utterance>Disregarding Federal warnings, Mormon extremists established Port Joe Smith, a settlement of 300 on Tango Urilla, a system just inside the Arachnid Quarantine Zone.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now body parts litter the ruined streets of Port Joe Smith.</context>
      <utterance>Too late they realized tha Tango Urilla had already been chosen by other colonists -- Arachnids !</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The council asks future colonists to obey all official Federal warnings. Would you like to know more ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(then)</context>
      <utterance>I am your senior drill instructor, Career Sergeant Zim.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kitten Smith shake his head "no" , but he can't stifle himself.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think I'm funny ? Do I make you laugh ? Do you think I'm a comedian ?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry...!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you get me ?</context>
      <utterance>The first and last words out of your stinking holes will be "sir".</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, sorry...sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kitten Smith squints. Out in the distance, a tiny building. Zim smacks him on the leg with his baton.</context>
      <utterance>See the armory ? Run around it !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kitten Smith runs. Big CORPORAL BRONSKI, 28, takes out after him, laying a baton across his backside every time he slows.</context>
      <utterance>RUN, I SAID. Bronski, keep pace !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you get me ?</context>
      <utterance>You are now all brothers and sisters in the same family, my family, the Mobile Infantery. I will be your mother. I will be your father. If you do not please me I will throw you out of my family because I hate all slackers and negative hackers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY ET AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zim points at the little WHITE PICKET FENCE leading to a transporter near the front gate.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, yes, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anytime you think I'm being to tough, anytime you think I'm being unfair... QUIT ! Grab your gear and take a stroll down "Washout Lane". Get me ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY ET AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, yes, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Breckinridge, a big guy from a farm planet, steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>I wonder if there's a handful of guts in the whole bunch. Who thinks they've got what it takes to knock me down ?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRECKINRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zim crooks afinger at him. Breckinridge charges. Zim knocks him flat. Breckinridge holds his arm, twisted now.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I guess maybe I do, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You alright, Breckinridge ?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRECKINRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, yes, sir. It's my arm. I think it's broken, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MEDIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clean break... Doc'll have him back on active duty by tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shujumi steps up, assumes a fighting stance. Zim looks him over. There's not not much to him. Shujumi attacks Zim, counters his counter, dances out of range.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Who's next ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DJANA'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Zim attacks. Shujumi flip kicks Zim in the head.</context>
      <utterance>Lookit the little guy go !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's good alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet he makes squad leader.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The recruits check Ace out. Zim sweeps Shujumi's legs, puts a knee in the little man's throat. Shujumi passes out.</context>
      <utterance>He'll have to get past me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that all you got ? You hit like kitten, Smith ! This is a punch. WHAM ! Zim knocks Kitten Smith for a loop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will not like me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...to serve in my family.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zim yanks the knife out of the post.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I don't understands who needs a knife in a nuke fight anyway... All you gotta do is push a button, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ace obeys. Zim throws, sticks his hand to the post.</context>
      <utterance>Put your hand on the post, private.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zim pays no attention to Ace who remains stuck to the post. A recruit trots up. Johnny stares, surprised. It's Dizzy.</context>
      <utterance>The enemy cannot push a button if you disable his hand. MEDIC !</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, recruit Flores, reporting for duty , sir. She snaps Zim a salute and hands him her orders.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see you specifically requested transfer from Fort Cronkite to this training group... Dizzy grins self-consciously at Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I heard it was the best, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is the best... BUT WHAT MAKES YOU</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to disable Zim...!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Improper Attitude ! They'll kick you out for talking like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>DJANA'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They can kick you out for anything. Improper Conduct, Unsatisfactory Performance...</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ace cuts into the front off the mess line.</context>
      <utterance>Off you go down Washout Lane, bye-bye !</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, you either got what it takes or you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>DJANA'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon Ace, wait your turn !</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At ease, soldier. It's all the same muck.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. There could be a fight. Zim, standing nearby, watches with interest. Ace opens his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Better get in line like everyone else, Ace.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I guess you and me could be buddies.</context>
      <utterance>You got some guts for a rich kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What an honor...</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ace makes a big friendly show of trading places with Johnny.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, don't laugh. Everyone oughta have a friend like me !</utterance>
   <speaker>BRECKINRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now everyone's laughing, pushing Ace to the back of the line. Johnny has his grub. Dizzy comes up with her tray.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Ace, back off the line ! Bacl off the line !</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, amigo, come chow with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks, Diz.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your malfunction, Rico ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are. I joined up to get out on my own. And you had to tag along.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What ? You think I joined the Mobile Infantery because of you ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny turns away. Dizzy watches him go, hurt.</context>
      <utterance>You saying you didn't ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>squad leader, Rico ?</context>
      <utterance>What makes you think... you'll make...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something... I've got...you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You rich kids... are all the same !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come to a trap, prepare to leap.</context>
      <utterance>It isn't about rich... It's about who's best...!</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy jumps over them from behind. Johnny and Ace tumble into the mud. They watch, chagrined, as Dizzy reaches the end of the course effortlessly.</context>
      <utterance>Coming through !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, move it, you apes !</utterance>
   <speaker>57	INT	SHOWERS - NIGHT - DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>enters as the recruits scrub down.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all have one thing in common. We were all stupid enough to sign up for Mobile Infanterie. What's your excuse, Breckinridge ?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRECKINRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, my family is all farmers. I hate farming. Mobile Infantery's pure picnic by comparison.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the grow 'em big and dumb on the farm planet, eh ? Djana'd ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DJANA'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going in for politics. You gotta be a citizen for that. So here I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, keep it going... Katrina !</utterance>
   <speaker>KATRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna be a mom. It's easier to get a licence if you've served.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look for that.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going career... officer's training. That's why I wanna be squad leader.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanting it doesn't make you the best one for the job.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah ? I don't see anyone else here with the chops to lead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe you better look again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHUJUMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy dresses down. Johnny and all the other guys check her out. She has a fabulous body. Dizzy cathes Johnny looking. He turns his back as she steps into the shower next to him.</context>
      <utterance>Federation's gonna give me a scholarship when my hitch is up. I wanna be a neurologist, study brain chemisty and associated stimulus...</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your turn, Rico !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, who asked you to be so nosey ?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy uses her hand to divert the shower spray towards Johnny's crotch.</context>
      <utterance>Me, I got plans to be writer, and a writer's got a right to be nosey. Flores, you know Rico from Buenos Aires... What's his story ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, some say he turned his back on the family fortune to be a citizen, others say he did it for a girl... missed a spot there, bucko... which is funny because Johnny says I joined up to be with him, but why would I do that ? He doesn't even like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRECKINRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone look down at Johnny's crotch, laughing. Johnny blushes, grabs a towel and exits the shower.</context>
      <utterance>Don't look that way to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ace, Kitten Smith, Shujumi and Breckinridge dance around and moon the camera.</context>
      <utterance>I know it's not much, but it's home. Over there's my bunk where I dream about you every night...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny moves the camera away from the guys. Katrina walks by from the shower with Dizzy, mugs into frame.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, do you mind ?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's going on ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet it's that girl I was talking about... Her name's Carmen, I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE AND THE OTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carmen ! Ooh la la, Carmencita !</utterance>
   <speaker>KATRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Carmen !</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE AND THE OTHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The picture goes all screwy, comes up again on:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, where you going ? Come back...! He's getting awy... Grab him...!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The barracks lights go out. Taps plays over the public address. Johnny lowers his voice.</context>
      <utterance>Boot's pretty tough, and sometimes I think I won't make it, but then I imagine you're watching me, and that gives me someting... I try harder. Thanks to you, I think I might have a shot at squad leader.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh, I gotta pack it in. I hope you're having fun, hope you're careful. No training accidents for you, eh ?  I want to kiss you so badly. I want to feel you next to me, I- Behind him , someone begins to sing , badly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ace, the singer, and the other guys peer down from the transom over the door, giggling, delighted with themselves.</context>
      <utterance>I love you truly, so truly, dear...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our love will grow, dear, year by year...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The letter ends. Carmen smiles. A BALD CADET PILOT smacks her on the arm as she runs by in a sleek blue pressure suit.</context>
      <utterance>Bye ! Write me ! I'm gonna kill you guys !</utterance>
   <speaker>BALD CADET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grinning, Carmen grabs her duffel, takes off after her.</context>
      <utterance>Orbit in five, Ibanez ! First one there gets to fly !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LATE CADET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no, not Ibanez again, she's crazy !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On my mark, in three, two, one...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BALD CADET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geez, I thought I liked to fly fast !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points. Now visible from behind a host of smaller ships, STARSHIP ATHENA, of older design, but impressive.</context>
      <utterance>This is nothing. Today, I get to fly that !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pilot Trainee Ibanez reporting for duty, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Follow all instructions of you supervisor.</context>
      <utterance>Take the number one chair, Ibanez.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen turns for her station, but stops in her tracks. Her supervisor is Zander Barcalow, now a 2nd Lieutenant.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey ! What are you doing here ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen logs on. The ship recognizes her as a pilot trainee.</context>
      <utterance>I'm the guy who's gonna teach you to fly this crate.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Should I call you "sir" ?</context>
      <utterance>Assistant insructor... You must be some kind of a hot stick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only when I give you an order.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen and Zander go to work.</context>
      <utterance>Prepare for departure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's amazing, us running into each other like this. Maybe it's fate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe not. I heard about this crazy girl coming through the academy, solid math, a little wild on the stick, but a natural. When it turned out it was you, I made sure we'd run into each other...</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, take her out, Ibanez.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes are on carmen as she grabs the stick. The ship shudders under her hand. She winks at Zander.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In simulation, my supervisors could never keep up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Take'er out easy, cadet.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't simulation anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, sir. Vector ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen rocks the stick, and the view from the bridge spins smoothly away from the dense orbiting yards os Luna toward the outer system.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-five by five, roll seven. And don't exceed port speed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They revoke our flight status.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen jogs past lumbering freighters. Zander's impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I see... teamwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steady as she goes, number one. Prepare for warp. Number two, design for Jupiter orbit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Space appears to bend. Zander and Carmen share a smile. They blur together, becoming one, then: WHAM !</context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am. Star drive in three... two... one...</utterance>
   <speaker>66	EXT	LUNA - STARSHIP ATHENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>disappears in a flash of blinding light.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The object of this exercise is to capture your enemy's flag before your enemy captures yours. Bronski passes out Morita SmartRifles.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These weapons have been modified for this exercise. If your enemy hits you, your suit will fail. You will be unable to move. You will be as good as dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DJANA'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny, Kitten Smith, and Dizzy open fire from athicket as they pass. Djana'd and the others collapse as their suits fail, Djana'd laughing because playing at war seems funny.</context>
      <utterance>It's right over the next ridge... Only two guards.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tell us your plans or die !</context>
      <utterance>You are now prisoners of the Blue Team.</utterance>
   <speaker>DJANA'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no ! Name, rank, and mind your own business is all you get from me !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kitten Smith makes arun for the flag with a rifle team. Ace and Katrina open fire from two new hidden Red Team positions, taking Kitten and his team down with a cross fire.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going in ! Let's go !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, they're defended... no way in.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flip six, three hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny looks at the course in a new way, nods.</context>
      <utterance>High school... remember ? Run a flip six, three hole play, and you might score...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cover me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny tumbles open ground, vaults into the air. Dizzy takes out Breckinridge as he rises to fire. Johnny lands, knocks out Katrina, then Ace. He picks up Ace's fallen Morita.</context>
      <utterance>You got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, pal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rico, I'm making you sqaud leader !</context>
      <utterance>Smith, GO ! McIntire, GO ! Flores, GO !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, thank you, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny jumps, plummeting toward the earth.</context>
      <utterance>Don't stand there dumb... GO !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Next in line, Ace scowls.</context>
      <utterance>YEEEE-Haaaaaaaaaaaaa...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at him. Do you think anyone has ever been so pleased with himself ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zim hadda choose someone to be his brown nose, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny approaches Dizzy.</context>
      <utterance>I just want you guys to know that I'll never do anything that I haven't asked you to do first.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy smiles, shakes.</context>
      <utterance>Couldn't've done it without you, Diz. Friends ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bronski walks through with the mail.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure... friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRONSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny grabs the E-disk, pops it into his handcam. The Fleet Mail logo appears:</context>
      <utterance>Levy... Shujumi... Rico.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny's pals gather for a look. Carmen appears, dressed down to skivvies, in her quarters aboard starship Athena.</context>
      <utterance>Bet it's from my girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Johnny, I would've written sooner, but they've really got us going every moment here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeow, Rico, you don't deserve that !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhhh...!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny holds up his squad leader chevrons victoriously.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you're doing so well. If they haven't made you squad leader by now, I'm sure you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The image changes abrupltly. Now Carmen's wearing a trim blue flight suit. She stands the camera on Athena's gunnery deck. Outside , the rings of Saturn sparkle in bright solar light.</context>
      <utterance>All it takes is the love of a good woman...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny is stunned. All the other recruits suddenly seem to have something else to do.</context>
      <utterance>Look at that. Isn't it beautiful ? I had to show you. It's great to be out here on my own. I'm just not some little girl from Buenos Aires anymore. I'm gonna be a starship pilot, and I'm gonna see the universe...  And that's also the problem because I don't really want to get married, Johnny. I don't want to have kids. I want a command, a ship of my own, and you know, I don't think that's gonna leave a lot of room for you and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Fleet Mail logo appears again: END OF MESSAGE. Johnny shuts the handcam off. Ace puts a hand on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I know that's not what you wanted to hear... but I have to follow my heart. I'm sorry. I'm afraid you'll hate me, and I couldn't stand that. Write me, alright ? Write me, so I'll know that we'll always be friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny how they always want to be your friends after they kick your guts out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's what I deserve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whad'ya talkin about ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm a fool.</context>
      <utterance>I joined up for her. I wouldn't even be here if it wasn't for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny smiles in spite of himself.</context>
      <utterance>You made squad leader on your own, and, hey, you still got me to kick around.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny turns for the door, flipping the chevrons like a coin. Dizzy watches him leave. She'd so like to comfort him.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Ace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the Marauder's visual capabilities, all you have to do is look at something to hit it, so you will exercise EXTREME CARE on my firing line. Do you get me ?</utterance>
   <speaker>RECRUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, yes, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>are presently visible along a gauntlet of low walls, gullies, and three-story building facades.</context>
      <utterance>The live firing combat range is the closest simulation of actual combat we can provide. If you do not hit your target, it will shoot you... Fifty blackened AUTOMATED TARGET DRONES fitted with pulse guns</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Marauder power suit will prevent serious injury, but if you are hit, you will be non-operational and your team score will suffer accordingly. Rico, has each member of your squad completed a weapons safety check ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On a signal from Zim, the Live Fire Combat Range comes to life as the target drones take cover and disappear from view.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, yes, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfect score for this exercise is 300. B company came through last week with 285. I expect you to do better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The squad resumes ist advance. Breckinridge bangs on his helmet. There is something wrong with his "head up" display.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, no more screw ups. Ace takes point. Diz, you and Kitten Smith cover the flanks. Djana'd, you're rear guard. Move out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the problem ?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRECKINRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunno. Display's fritzed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DJANA'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lose another rifle, we're gonna mess up our score...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Breckinridge takes off helmet, hands it to Johnny. Djana'd turns on Breckinridge. Her "head up" zeroes him.</context>
      <utterance>Let me see.</utterance>
   <speaker>DJANA'D</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's when Djana'd trips on a loose stone. She fumbles her rifle and it discharges. The round tears the top of Breckinridge's head off. The recruits stare in horror.</context>
      <utterance>How come when something goes wrong, it's always you, Breckinridge ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zim arrives with Bronski on the bounce.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God... uh... MEDIC !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The recruits watch Johnny leave, stare aghast at their dead comrade. No one looks at Djana'd, who stands alone sobbing.</context>
      <utterance>Rico, you are relieved of squad command. Levy, McIntire you will escort private Rico to the C.O.'s Office.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rico, did you give the recruit permission to remove his helmet ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, yes, sir. Breckinridge reported a helmet malfunction, and I asked him to show it to me, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you rated to repair a Marauder power suit, Rico ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, no, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why did you order your man to remove his helmet during a live fire exercise ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I needed everyone in my squad operational, sir... I... I wanted to win, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, no, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you freely admit to the charges made against you ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zim looks out the window. Djana'd, dressed for travel, in civilian clothes, crying as she heads off down Washout Lane.</context>
      <utterance>Sir... I guess I do, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant, we've lost two recruits over this incident already... is there any possibility of salvaging this man ? Zim I believe so, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. We'll try administrative punishment. Until then you are confined to your quarters, Rico.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zim steps up to Johnny, offers him a red rubber mouthpiece.</context>
      <utterance>For incompetence of command, for failure to abide by safety regulations in a live fire exercise, for negligence which contributed to the death of a teammate...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bite on this. It helps. I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny takes it in his mouth. His tear away shirt is torn away. Johnny stands at the post alone. Corporal Bronski, a big man with an unhappy task, unrolls his whip.</context>
      <utterance>... recruit trainee John Rico is sentenced to administrative punishment. Ten lashes.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may carry out the sentence.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRONSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRONSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRONSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>CRACK ! Again. Dizzy flinches for Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRONSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CRACK ! Ace looks away.</context>
      <utterance>Three.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRONSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CRACK ! Zim watches without any apparent emotion.</context>
      <utterance>Four.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRONSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CRACK ! Johnny faints, sagging against his tether.</context>
      <utterance>Five.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. You read my mind. Third watch always seems to last forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He caresses her hair. She kisses his hand. Zander notices the plot map.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I don't know... Depends on who you are spending it with.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Profile's wrong... there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I replotted the course. It's more efficient this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three weeks aboard a starship and you know it all, huh ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander slides into his chair, runs a check.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, check it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I was talking to Captain, Deladier, and she said...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't change the subject. Am I right ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, whad'ya know...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mess with the boss. So what'd the captain say ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks we're good together.</context>
      <utterance>She got a command... and she thinks we oughta team up officially and crew for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander turns his chair so they are very close, moves a finger along her hand, up her arm and playfully around her breasts.</context>
      <utterance>You and me, huh ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen grabs him between his legs.</context>
      <utterance>I have a feeling about us. We're good together, way ahead of the curve in every department. I seem to be able to anticipate your needs. You know what I want...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander pulls her to him and they kiss passionately. She brteaks it off, gets serious for amoment.</context>
      <utterance>No, what do you want ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be part of the best flight team in the Fleet...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start to caress again when suddenly ALARMS sound. Captain Deladier appears on the hot screen, still waking up.</context>
      <utterance>Me, too... Day and Night-Cycle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Report.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, we are in the path of an unidentified object moving at near light speed... Carmen and Zander frantically check their displays.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like an... asteroid.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen and Zander see it through the front screens: A huge ASTEROID tumbles directly towards them at terrific speed.</context>
      <utterance>In this part of the system ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen breaks glass that reads EMERGENCY RETROS, arms the switch within and fires the rockets.</context>
      <utterance>Sweet Jesus...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd it come from ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trajectory indicates it came out of the Arachnid Quarantine Zone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Number 4, contact Fleet and tell 'em there's a loose asteroid headed their way.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMUNICATIONS OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Communications are down, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Engineering. Damage assessment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGINEERING OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Deladier notices Carmen staring at a monitor, stunned. A DEAD CAP TROOPER trails in the wreckage of the flight deck.</context>
      <utterance>Hull's compromised. We're lucky to be alive, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good work, Number 1. You'll do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, ma'am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It stinks, you goin.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't stay where I'm not wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they didn't want you, they woulda kicked you out, amigo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Corporal Bronski leans in, impassive.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, they humiliated me in front of everyone ! I'm just supposed to take it, huh ? Well, I'm not gonna, and I guess that proves I just can't cut it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRONSKI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nearby VU-PHONE lights up. The screen flashes: RINGING His mother appears when she picks up the other end.</context>
      <utterance>Your call's going through, Rico. Take it there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello... Oh, Johnny...!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The screen splits as Johnny's father activates an extension.</context>
      <utterance>Bill... pick up... it's Johnny ! You little rat. You haven't called, you haven't written. It's been so lonely here without you...</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny's mother makes a face to shut him up.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny ! Where's your uniform...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's up, son ?</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's just good to hear from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not really working out for me here, dad. I was thinking... I was hoping it would be alright if I came home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, of course you should come home immedietly !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've made a mess of things. I've been so stupid...</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk like that. Get yourself home as fast as you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll all have dinner. I'll fix your favorite.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sky in Buenos Aires seems to darken perceptively. Johnny's mother looks out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah ! We'll talk it out and have a good glass of wine ... and... well, we love you, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my, what's that ?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like rain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The transmission ends abruptly. A phone company logo appears:</context>
      <utterance>This time of the year...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VU-PHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny zips his duffel, hefts it gingerly over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Your transmission has been terminated due to atmospheric interference. Please try your call again later.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, see ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take the stroll down Washout Lane, you're only proving one thing, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that, Diz ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy turns on her heel and marches away.</context>
      <utterance>That you don't have what it takes to be acitizen !</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zim signs bitterly. The C.O. sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Now you, Sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The C.O. and Zim turn to other things. Johnny picks up his duffel and heads out the door.</context>
      <utterance>That's it, son. You can go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Kitten, what's going on ?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's war !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On screen, the smoldering ruins of what was once a huge city.</context>
      <utterance>... early estimates. Millions dead, a city in ruins...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, jeez, is that Geneva ?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddam bugs whacked us, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny is horrified. Dizzy is suddenly standing next to him.</context>
      <utterance>... Buenos Aires has been wiped of the Earth. Nothing lives in what was once called the Latin Paradise...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, Johnny, geez... It's home.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny sets his jaw, turns and runs for the C.O.'s office.</context>
      <utterance>The Federal Court met moments ago and voted unanimously for mobilization to destroy the Arachnid threat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The meteor derived from here, near Klendathu, in the Arachnid's home system...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I want combat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm serious, sir. I'll go anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it, Zim. We're gonna need you here. The only way you'll get a combat assignment is if you bust yourself to private. You get me ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir, I get you.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I do for you, Rico ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I wish to reconsider my request to drop out, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>C.O.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, son. I can't do it. You signed the 1240/A. It would be illegal.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zim picks up Johnny's 1240/A off the C.O.'s desk.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, i know it was wrong. I didn't learn from one mistake and I made another, sir.  Sir, my family... my whole family was in Buenos Aires, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that your signature, Rico ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, yes it is, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zim gives the C.O. a look. The C.O. shrugs, turns away, watching the news of the coming war. Zim tears up the 1240/A.</context>
      <utterance>Doesn't look like it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get outa here, private.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of the ashes of Buenos Aires comes first sorrow, then ANGER !</utterance>
   <speaker>ANGRY PERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only good bug is a dead bug !</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to know more ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SKY MARSHALL DIENES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>humankind ! We must meet the threat with our valor, our blood, with our very lives, to insure that human civilization, not insect, dominates this galaxy now and always. The council rises to its feet for a standing ovation.</context>
      <utterance>We are a generation commanded by fate to defend</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sky Marshall Dienes announces plans for an offensive against Klendathu, source of the bug meteor that destroyed Buenos Aires.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, shoot a nuke down a bug hole, lotta dead bugs, am I right ?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just hope it's not over before we get in it !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That guy's been in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you tell ?</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's hard and humorless, all wised up. Ace admires his LASER CUT TATTOOS. Dizzy eyes his skull and crossbone earring.</context>
      <utterance>The eyes. He's got the 1000 meters stare.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great scars.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like the jewelry. Hey, amigo, where can I get an earring like yours ?</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You don't see a lot of guys with three.</context>
      <utterance>Port Joe Smith, Outer Rings, Dantana... Every time I come back from a drop, my gunny gives me a bone. I got three now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waht's it like... combat ?</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess it's not so bad. I mean as long as you don't get any on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get any what on you ?</utterance>
   <speaker>VETERAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The veteran pays his tab and heads out.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you'll know when it happens. See you on the bounce.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say we all go to the laser parlor and get cut together.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I want with a scar ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>C'mon, everyone's doing it !</context>
      <utterance>What, your skin's too pretty ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Johnny looks up and sees Carmen. She lloks graet in uniform with the hat and the lieutenant's bars on her shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Johnny ! Johnny Rico !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny remembers himself, snaps to attention, salutes. Dizzy and the others follow suit. Carmen salutes back, sheepish.</context>
      <utterance>Carmen... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy, disgusted, turns back to Ace and Kitten Smith. Carmen tucks her hat under her arm. Her hair is very short.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... at ease. Guess I oughta lose the hat when I'm off duty, eh ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to your hair ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think ? Everyone did it when we got our wings. You don't like it, do you ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's alright, I guess. You hear from anyone made it out of B.A. alive ? Carmen shakes her head, sadly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's funny. Sometimes I forget. Then it hits me, and I can't stop crying.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I try just to be happy I'm still alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't look very happy to see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I be ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander leaves a group of FLEET OFFICERS to join them.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny... Life is so different from the way it was. One day you'll see what I did was best for both of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything coposetic, Lieutenant ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander puts his arm around Carmen, gives her a squeeze.</context>
      <utterance>Zander, you remember Johnny ? Zander and I are a flight team now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best in the Fleet !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny turns to leave.</context>
      <utterance>I get it. This is the part that's best for both of us. Don't do me anymore favors, eh ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny, wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny turns back to face Zander.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it, Carmen. The Mobile Infantery does a thankless, dirty job, so they naturally tend to be short-tempered, thoughtless and rude.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got something to say about the Mobile Infantery ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me. Wanna make something out of it, private ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone can see what's about to happen. A circle is forming, Fleet on one side, Mobile Infantery on the other.</context>
      <utterance>Not with an officer, no, sir. The M.I. doesn't mint stupid cap troopers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's disregaed rank... Everybody hear that ? Rank is not an issue here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander takes off his hat.</context>
      <utterance>Zander, please... Let's go !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHAM ! Johnny punches him right in the nose. Zander goes down, bleeding. Ace and Kitten Smith grab Johnny.</context>
      <utterance>It's alright. What's he gonna do ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander staggers to his feet, ready to fight, but Fleet Officers pull him back. Carmen looks at Johnny, the hate in his eye, the blood on his fist.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, easy there, buddy... Nice punch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen turns away, stung. Johnny immediately regrets. Dizzy, for her part, couldn't be happier.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's just a vestigal response to procreation... bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it, Johnny. Cap Troopers and Fleet weren't meant to mix !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy, Ace, and Kitten Smith awtch, grinning, passing a bottle. Ace pours booze directly into the fresh wound.</context>
      <utterance>It hurts...!</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, this hurts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They put their arms side by side. Each has a similiar scar: Lightning bolts on a shield and the words: DEATH FROM ABOVE.</context>
      <utterance>Well, here's to it ! We're gonna fightn, and we're gonna win !</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mobile Infantery rules !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Death to all bugs !</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get any on you !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone snaps to attention.</context>
      <utterance>Officer on deck !</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This does nothing to break the tension. Lt. Willy reassures.</context>
      <utterance>At ease. Alright... we got hot poop straight from the top: Willy's Wildcats is in with the first wave. Means more bugs for us to kill...</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are none.</context>
      <utterance>Now if you follow orders and remember your training, I guarantee you'll make it back alive. Any questions ?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The briefingplays on "head up" displays and the ready room screens. A captive BUG WARRIOR clicks and shrieks as FEDERAL SCIENTISTS torture it. The troopers cheer.</context>
      <utterance>Alright... next we got a little last minute briefing from Military Intelli-gence I think you're gonna like...</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The head scientists turns and speaks to camera. It's Carl. Johnny and Dizzy share an amazed grin, noticing a difference in their old friend, something that speaks of... authority.</context>
      <utterance>Everyday Federal scientists are looking for new ways to kill bugs and you can help...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl picks up apulse gun and blows one of the bugs legs off. The insect screams.</context>
      <utterance>To defeat the enemy, we must know the enemy. Take for instance your basic Arachnid warrior. Minimal IQ, armored, completely lethal. You can blow a limb off...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl fires again. The bug kicks and squeals as it dies. Carl tosses the pulse gun aside.</context>
      <utterance>... and it's still 86% combat effec-tive. But here's a tip: Aim for the nerve stem and put it down for good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>to divert meteors and aim them toward Earth. We need to know how they do this. If you encounter any plasma, report it immediately to your superior. Good luck and good hunting ! The briefing ends as klaxons sound.</context>
      <utterance>Now while you are out killing bugs, we want you to be our eyes and ears. The bugs use some kind of plasma burst</utterance>
   <speaker>P.A.</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the Captain speaking. All personnel prepare for drop.We are at D minus three and counting.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny and the other troopers climb into capsules on the port track. Dizzy gives him "thumbs up". The capsule seals as it moves with the others down the firing tube.</context>
      <utterance>Move out !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LT. WILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smash the entire area, kill anything that has more'n a couple legs , and don't any of you loafers come back aboard with unexpended bombs. Get me ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY ET AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRE CONTROL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sweat rolls down his face, hyperventilation... WHAM !</context>
      <utterance>Five seconds...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plasma, ma'am... from the planet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drop status ?</context>
      <utterance>Bug Batteries... According to Military Intelligence, it'll be random and light.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two more bursts of bug plasma streak past.</context>
      <utterance>Drop is 35% complete, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steady as she goes, Number 1.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>105	INT	CAPSULE - NIGHT - JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>takes in ENTRY DATA from the heads up display.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDANCE COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...surface in twenty-fivr seconds ...LZ has been identified ...beacon is in place...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone made amistake...!</context>
      <utterance>This isn't random or light.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out the front screens, a blast from below hits George Marshall amidships and it reels into Yamamoto. Both starships begin to burn.</context>
      <utterance>That's it, we're empty ma'am !</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen dodges past burning ships, avoids collision with Dauntless, and then KA-WHAM ! they're hit. Carmen flies out of her station and into CAMERA hard.</context>
      <utterance>Someone made a big goddam mistake ! Get us out of here, Number 1 !</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDANCE COMPUTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The chute pops. Across the sky, lit by outgoing bug plasma, he can see hundreds of cap troopers in ordered rows drifting down into the cloud layer. It's quiet in the clouds, then:</context>
      <utterance>...surface in fifteen seconds... deploying chute now...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where's the Sarge...?</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant's bought the farm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now comes a flood of WORKERS building ever advancing fortifications, and with them, hundreds of deadly ARACHNID WARRIORS.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't see him !</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here they come...!</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ace, what're we doing ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy and the others open fire simultanously. The whole area goes white hot in the magnesium flash of so many pulse cannons. Shujumi fires wildly at advancing insects.</context>
      <utterance>I uh... uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHUJUMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want some ? Here's some !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KATRINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the ground opens behind her and a huge (6 meters) TANKER BUG lumbers out of the ground, it's funnel-shaped snout extruding above multiple eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here !</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tanker bug sprays and hits Katrina. She screams, as her legs melt out from under her.</context>
      <utterance>Look out !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come to the rear lines where the Net Correspondent and his CAMERAMAN are doing live coverage of the invasion.</context>
      <utterance>It's a general retreat ! The boats are coming down.</utterance>
   <speaker>NET CORRESPONDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Correspondent is cut in half by a warrior. Johnny blows it away.</context>
      <utterance>We've just landed here on what cap troopers are calling the "Big K" with the 6th Mobile Infantery Division. It's an ugly planet, a bug planet, a planet hostile to life as we kow iGKKKKK !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cap troopers move out. Kitten Smith looks up as a purple beacon streaks acroos thr sky.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, let's go ! ON THE BOUNCE !</utterance>
   <speaker>KITTEN SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see the beacon...!</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hopper pounces on Kitten Smithm, and he goes down screaming.</context>
      <utterance>Retrieval !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Dizzy can't find Johnny, and soon she's lost in the smoke. Johnny looks down at the terrible hole in his leg where bright arterial blood gushes.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny ! JOHNNY ! WHERE ARE YOU ? JOHNNY ! Johnny...!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now two more Arachnid warriors close in on him through the enveloping smoke. He fires his pulse rifle empty, and dropping it, crawls desperately, dragging his useless leg.</context>
      <utterance>Medic... MEDIC...!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A third Arachnid warrior rears up in front of him, deadly jaws slashing down toward him, when suddenly it is blown to pieces in the blinding blast of a point-blank pulse cannon.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God... Oh, God, help me... please help me...!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Johnny reaches out. A STEEL HAND takes his, dragging him back as bugs attack. His rescuers's pulse cannon thunders overhead. Bug parts fly as insects swarm in for the kill.</context>
      <utterance>Take my hand !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICIAL VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Accepting responsibility for Klendathu, Sky Marshall Dienes resigns. His successor, Sky Marshall Tahat Meru, outlines her new strategy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKY MARSHALL MERU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can ill afford another Klendathu.</context>
      <utterance>Until we understand the bug better, we must proceed with caution...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen takes his hand. Zander kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>Give me hand, willya ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking. Maybe we should get married, Carmen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't thinking...you were dreaming !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we're gonna be a team, why not be a real team ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a war on. I want a command, I want my own ship, you do, too...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen lets his hand go and leaps through the hatch. Zander falls back onto the conveyer belt, finds himself eyeball-to-eyeball with a horribly maimed trooper, scrambles to get off.</context>
      <utterance>So who's got time to get married ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fleet encourages marriages among flight officers. You'd probably get a promotion out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not kidding. Marriage is -</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, funny there's almost no wounded at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen looks at the words at the Net terminal: WOULD YOU LIKE TO KNOW MORE ? She bites her lip, enters Johnny's name. In an instant, she has the news:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, bugs don't take prisoners.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears fill her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carmen...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rushes away. Zander looks at Johnny's name on the screen, shrugs, presses the ERASE button.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me...!</utterance>
   <speaker>119	INT	TICONDEROGA - CORRIDOR - ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>finds Carmen, sagging against a wall, weepimg.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Carmen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander puts an arm around her. She holds on tight.</context>
      <utterance>Please, I... Everybody's lost someone by now. This shouldn't be any different...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I... Oh, Zander, I'm a fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander kisses her hair. Tears roll down her face.</context>
      <utterance>You're upset, that's alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander holds Carmen as she sobs, feeling lucky.</context>
      <utterance>No, don't you see ? No one can wait for anything anymore... You're right... We should get married...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dizzy says you two knew this Rasczak character in Buenos Aires...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He was great.</context>
      <utterance>He was our teacher...</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, I hear he's a real nutbuster.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They size up the Roughnecks. There are scars, power prosthetics, and one, big SUGAR WATKINS, 26, wears a bug claw on a chain around his neck.</context>
      <utterance>The Roughnecks killed more bugs than any other outfit in 2nd Brigade... Only took 15% casualties on Big K.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seeing as how we're about all that's left of 1st Brigade, you'd have to call that an improvement.  You top kick ?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGAR WATKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding ? They always get killed. You want the job ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CORPORAL BIRDIE, 24, turns, gives Johnny the once over.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIRDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy looks her over. Not too big, but she's tough.</context>
      <utterance>I would. Nice earring.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you been besides Big K ?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIRDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outer rings. Zegema Beach.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always wanted to go to Zegema Beach.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGAR WATKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck. It's not there anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Birdie belts him, and Ace goes down.</context>
      <utterance>Is your Lieutenant as bad as they say ?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIRDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ace jumps up, ready to fight, but other Roughnecks block him.</context>
      <utterance>No one talks about the Lieutenant that way. He saved my life !</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGAR WATKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHER ROUGHNECKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny and Dizzy shrug. Ace's on his own.</context>
      <utterance>Same for me... me, too...</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like he is quite a guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SERGEANT GILLESPIE, 28, steps into the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLESPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone snaps to. Rasczak enters.</context>
      <utterance>Attention !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is for you new people. I only have two rules. Rule one, everyone fights. Rule two, no one quits. If you don't do your job, I'll kill you myself. Do you get me ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY, DIZZY AND ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points at Johnny's earring with his steel hand.</context>
      <utterance>We get you, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Welcome to the Roughnecks.</context>
      <utterance>Get rid of the jewelry. I hate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIRDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rasczak's Roughnecks ! The Roughnecks cheer. Rasczak smiles vaguely.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After Fleet glasses the planet, M.I. mops up.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. There's a new Sky Marshall and a new plan. We're gonna clean out the systems outlying Klendathu one planet at a time. Tomorrow we hit Tango Urilla.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rockets take out warriors. Bug guts go flying. Dizzy sets workers on fire. Johnnx and Ace step over burning bug carcasses to the rim of the hole and fire their gas rounds.</context>
      <utterance>There.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny drops an H.E. round, and they're in the air when the explosion collapses the entrance to the bug city.</context>
      <utterance>Fire in the hole !</utterance>
   <speaker>BIRDIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>WE could use some help...</context>
      <utterance>You new guys over there...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you've got a little bug problem, ma'am...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIRDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cao troopers let the bugs have it, but the insects keep coming, the living crawling over the dead, and now, trudging up out of the ground, comes a</context>
      <utterance>Stow it, trooper. Give it verything you've got !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasczak and Sugar Watkins pull Birdie to safety. Johnny fires a rocket into the hole he's made in the tanker bug's back, and jumps clear. KA-WHAP ! The big bug explodes.</context>
      <utterance>Sugar, in for pick up !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Roughnecks fire gas rockets into the bug hole. Johnny touches down beside Rasczak.</context>
      <utterance>Gas that hole and close it !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd you learn to do that, soldier ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uni High Tigers, sir. Don't you remember ? I was captain of the team.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasczak turns away, gives Birdie prosthetic thumps up as she is carried past to meet an arriving skimmer.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not interested in nostalgia, Rico, I need a corporal. You're it until you're dead or I find someone better.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy and Ace gather around Johnny, clap him on the back.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Birdie, your next arm comes with a factory guarantee !</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Way to go, amigo !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna need a squad leader.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. Big K taught me I ain't executive material.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about it, Diz ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tac Fighters reel by over head. WOMP ! Suddenly, BUG PLASMA shoots skyward from the flatlands below. Several Tac Fighters are blown out of the air. Flaming debris rains down.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like I'm your girl, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roughnecks head out on the bounce.</context>
      <utterance>Saddle up, Roughnecks. That's our trash !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny jumps the magnification on his "head up". Down in the pit, a giant translucent PLASMA BUG rears out of one of the subterranean tunnels that ring the battery.</context>
      <utterance>What kind of stinkin' bug is that ?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGAR WATKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny shakes his head. Swollen BREEDER BUGS gather around the plasma bug to inject it with their catalytic jelly.</context>
      <utterance>You never seen how they do it before ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The plasma bug writhes in pain and begins to swell, color changing from yellow to blue in accordance with some violent internal chemical reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Agghh ! It's making me sick...!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGAR WATKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WOMP ! The plasma bug explodes in its cauldron. A blast of bug plasma streaks past them towards the heavens. Now a new plasma bug crawls into the pit to begin the cycle anew.</context>
      <utterance>It's gonna pop !</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLESPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sergeant Gillespie points. A hole opens near the battery and dozens of warriors rampage out of the ground and up the cliff face toward the Roughneck position.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, look !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let's get some air support, eh ?</context>
      <utterance>We must be right over the colony.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLESPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasczak moves off down the line giving orders.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir ! Fleet, this is Roughneck patrol, over ...?</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Corporal, I want pulse cannons there and there ! Rifle teams, spread out along the ridge ! Sugar, bring up that flame thrower !</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLESPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fleet's pulling the battle group back to safe distance... They'd like us to knock out those batteries, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'd rather spend our lives than risk their ships. Who's got the nuke ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'd be me, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy activates a tactical nuke. It makes a distinctive HIGHPITCHED SQUEAL.</context>
      <utterance>Heat it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Roughnecks open fire. Bugs are blown to pieces but they keep climbing. A warrior breeches their line. Sugar Watkins torches it. The nuke's ready light flashes.</context>
      <utterance>Roughnecks, you may fire at will.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hot, sir !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GILLESPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now comes the part I hate the most.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that ?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLESPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We go down into the colony and make sure all the queens are dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SUGAR WATKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew the Lieutenant before the war... What was he like ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a teacher , kind of a know it all... Always had this little smile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SUGAR WATKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geez, I don't think I've ever seen him smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny joins Rasczak, Ace and Dizzy and they blow away several warriors guarding the entrance of a large chamber.</context>
      <utterance>Must fill your bottle up real quick when your wife and kids get smeared.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All dead except one, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill the bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny signals. Dizzy's pulse cannon rips open the dying queen. Thousands of wriggling premature bugs come spilling out. Horrified, knee-deep Roughnecks set them afire.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roughnecks cheer. Rasczak kicks open a CARGO MODULE. Beer kegs rool out. He kicks open a second module. Inside, musical instruments. Ace picks up a violin.</context>
      <utterance>Tango Urilla is now bug free. Means the Roughnecks have killed a helluva lotta bugs...!</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Habve some fun. That's an order !</context>
      <utterance>I expect the best, but I give the best.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, I don't do that anymore...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You used to dance...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said no. Want me to pull rank ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy heads back to the others. Johnny turns and finds Rasczak regarding him with an odd, sad smile.</context>
      <utterance>Well, excuse me, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Want some now ?</context>
      <utterance>Yopu asked me some advice once, Rico.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillespie appears.</context>
      <utterance>Never pass up a good thing, eh ?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLESPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasczak heads away. Johnny joins Dizzy.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant, Brigade's on the com...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Diz...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny takes her hand, bows implishly.</context>
      <utterance>What ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her out among the others and they begin to dance. Ace watches with a grin, puts some spirit in his fiddle.</context>
      <utterance>May I have the honor ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>INTELLIGENCE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At 0821 we received a distress call from Planet P, priority code, requesting reinforcement...</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought 4th brigade cleaned out P.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTELLIGENCE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Owen reported the eradication of a low generation colony a month ago. That's why MICOM wants onsite assessment.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Intelligence Officer reddens.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds more like some idiot at Military Intelligence Command wants to get me and my cap troopers killed...</utterance>
   <speaker>INTELLIGENCE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take your group down to P and have a look see. Leave the thinking to us, Lieutenant. That's not your job.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My job is to protect the lives of my soldiers so they can kill bugs, Major, and if you're walking me into a trap-</utterance>
   <speaker>INTELLIGENCE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bugs don't lay traps... They aren't intelligent ! Unlike you, they're stupid enough to follow orders !</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The Intelligence Officer disappears abruptly. A new hologram appears. Rasczak's jaw drops. It's his former student Carl Jenkins, now a Colonel, weary and pissed off.</context>
      <utterance>That'll be all, Major. Dismissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasczak recovers, salutes stiffly.</context>
      <utterance>This conference is over. Do your duty, Lieutenant. That's an order.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Corporal, the Roughnecks are moving out for Planet P immediately. Get yourself squared away and report to Gillespie for logistics.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy shows herself, grinning.</context>
      <utterance>Who's that with you ?</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasczak slams the door shut on them. They fall back into one anothers arms, laughing as they resume lovemaking.</context>
      <utterance>Report in ten minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Planet P ? What kind of name is that ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They ran out of names a long time ago in this part of the galaxy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GILLESPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>not even their transponder.</context>
      <utterance>I don't understand it, Lieutenant. It's not getting anything from 4th Brigade...</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep trying, Sergeant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy tosses her Morita to Rasczak. Gillespie writhes in the hopper's claws. Rasczak fires, killing Gillespie.</context>
      <utterance>Throw a rifle !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny and the others cover the Roughneck retreat as hoppers soar down on the flat lands from the canyon walls.</context>
      <utterance>I expext any one here to do the same for me... Rico, Watkins, Flores, Levy prepare for rear guard action. The rest of you make for 4th Brigade.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasczak turns away. Roughnecks engage in the sport of methodically killing the workers.</context>
      <utterance>Jeez, Command really humped the bunk on this one...</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We need retrieval.</context>
      <utterance>Rico, you're acting Sergeant now. My last Sergeant lost the com pack. Put together a search team and find the radio shack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Diz, see what you can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy goes to work. Rasczak checks the wound in the back of the dead major's head.</context>
      <utterance>I'm on it !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that look like to you, Rico ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like a bug was in his brain, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant, I think you're gonna wanna see this, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dirty bugs came in right when they were having chow !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then they hear a sound. Tap tap tap. Rasczak signals for quiet. Tap tap tap tap. It's coming from the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Gas that hole and seal it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Officer on the deck, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roughnecks prop him up. General Owen tries to talk, but no words come out. Rasczak bends down to listen.</context>
      <utterance>Pick up the general !</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out... you gotta get me out...!</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man grins, hugely relieved.</context>
      <utterance>General Owen, sir ?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>so where's the boat ?</context>
      <utterance>At ease, Lieutenant. Thank God for you, for all of you...this is grand...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GENERAL OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was forced to hide, of course. The security of the Federation in this theater of operations was at stake !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy lokks up from where she is working on the radio controls.</context>
      <utterance>Diz, what's with the uplink ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Workin on it...!</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>things ! Look here... They did it to Farley...! He points at the hole of the dead major's head.</context>
      <utterance>They get in your mind... they make you do</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The distress call... The bugs wanted us to rescue you...!</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasczak's lost interest in the general. He's on the com.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you can be sure of it ! They were biding their time... waiting for the most opportune moment !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To all Roughnecks, this is Rasczak. Prepare for attack. Repeat. We are going to be attacked...!</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasczak looks at General Owen with contempt.</context>
      <utterance>They weren't gonna do it to me. Oh no ! I know too many secrets !</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGAR WATKINS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>An explosion in the mess hall closes the bug hole.</context>
      <utterance>Fire in the hole !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GENERAL OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Roughnecks are shocked. They've never seen a general break down before. Lieutenant Rasczak slaps Owen hard.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God...! My soldiers...! All of my boys and girls...!</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up ! Your soldier's dead and you're not !</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know... I wish you'd shoot me...</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And it looks like Rasczak just might, but just then Ace touches down next to Johnny and Rasczak.</context>
      <utterance>I oughta !</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant, we got trouble !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Warm it all up ! Everything you got ! Levy, collect the big guns from the towers. Watkins, put General Owen with the wounded. Rico, where's my communications ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on, Diz ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Johnny runs for the communications room.</context>
      <utterance>I got power ! Gimme a minute !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have a minute !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What frequency ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All bands.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roughneck patrol to battle group...</context>
      <utterance>Roughneck patrol to battle group...</utterance>
   <speaker>RODGER YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We have Orion P-11 as clear !</context>
      <utterance>This is Rodger Young... What's going on down there ? We're taking plasma !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SHUT UP, SIR ! We need pick up now !</utterance>
   <speaker>RODGER YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your position ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Come down on this transmission !</context>
      <utterance>Landing zone is extremely hostile.</utterance>
   <speaker>RODGER YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>That's crazy !</context>
      <utterance>Inside 4th brigade compound ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny races out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Then I hope you have a crazy pilot ! Keep the line open, Dizzy !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Roughnecks stop firing as they run out of nukes.</context>
      <utterance>Boat coming down, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>ROUGHNECKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny scans the battlefield. Nukes have turned the surface into dark glass. Now, out of the smoke, come the bugs, steaming glass cracking beneath millions of marching feet.</context>
      <utterance>I'm empty...all nuked out... Me, too !</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, we musta killed a million already...!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sugar Watkins sees Genera Owen in the compound below, stumbling aimlessly among his dead soldiers.</context>
      <utterance>Not enough, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGAR WATKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General ! GENERAL, stay with the wounded... Sir, the general...!</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hoppers sweep into the compound. The Roughnecks open fire. General Owen make easy pickings for ones that get through.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, the hell with him...</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizzy arrives on thr bounce as the Roughnecks fall back into the compound. Bugs pile in over the walls. The circle affords them 360 degrees of kill zone.</context>
      <utterance>Fall back... form a circle ! If no living bug comes over that wall, we cannot be harmed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rico, Flores, Watkins, Levy ! We control the sky until retrieval !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY ET AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rasczak, Sugar Watkins, Johnny and Dizzy stand back-to-back in the center of the circle, sweeping the skies with the heavy guns from the towers. Hoppers are blown to pieces.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting low here, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>300 rounds and counting, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny looks up. A RETRIEVAL BOAT hurtles down through bursts of bug plasma, takes a grazing hit, rights itself with retros and lands within the circle. Roughnecks cheer, saved !</context>
      <utterance>Make every shot count !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant, secure the boat !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roughnecks move to protect the boat. The hatch blows open.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dead bugs ring the compound walls, forming ramps for living insect soldiers to enter the compound in greater numbers.</context>
      <utterance>Board the wounded !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The circle shrinks as Roughnecks fall back and board the boat. More and more bugs pile in over the compound walls.</context>
      <utterance>Move to retrieval on my command ! First group, now...!</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the ground collapses under Rasczak. He falls in to his waist, vomits blood as something chews on him from below.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, Flores ! Levy ! Rico...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ace and the others fire from the boat. Johnny and Dizzy fire at the ground around Rasczak. Rasczak stops screaming. They try to pull him free.</context>
      <utterance>Cover us, Ace !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hit your jets, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The compund wall collapses. A wave of bugs charges in.</context>
      <utterance>I can't My legs are gone... Get on the boat...</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rico, tell'em to glass this goddam planet. I've never seen so many bugs upstairs at the same time...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weakly, Rasczak picks up his pulse gun, checks the power.</context>
      <utterance>We're not leaving you here, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my farm. Get on the boat, NOW ! That's an order, Sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny and Dizzy run for the boat. Rasczak opens fire, picking his shots, but soon the bugs are all over him.</context>
      <utterance>Give'em hell, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>RASCZAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the boat, Dizzy turns to look back at Rasczak. A hopper swoops down on Dizzy, it's claws ripping into her abdomen.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon you sons of bitches ! There's no bug alive can kill a real mAAAAAAA !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bought the farm, didn't I, Johnny ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're gonna be alright, Diz !</utterance>
   <speaker>DIZZY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MEDICS push Johnny aside, go to work on Dizzy.</context>
      <utterance>It's alright 'cause I got to have you, Johnny...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The co-pilot turns around. It's Zander. His eyes narrow.</context>
      <utterance>Get on the com and tell Fleet to glass that rock...!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On whose authority, Corporal ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pilot turns around. It's Carmen.</context>
      <utterance>This would be mine, sir. Acting Sergeant John Rico. I've assumed command on this mission.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny...! I thought you were dead !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny leaves. Carmen punches up Fleet Command.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not, but alot of my soldiers are. Glass the planet !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rodger Young, this is inbound shuttle De Ruyter with an official request from the Mobile Infantery to bombard Planet P-11...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen sees Dizzy lying dead on the deck.</context>
      <utterance>Negative on your request. Fleet Command has the battle group on standby...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta choke on the mud and the blood and Fleet can't be bothered to spit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points out for a viewing port. Johnny looks. Fifteen battle groups, 100 ships strong, lay off Planet P, all of them dwarfed by the Sky Marshall's flagship, Buenos Aires.</context>
      <utterance>No, I think something's up. The Sky Marshall's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were KIA, Johnny...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was just a mix up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look so... I don't know, you look like you've really been in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen touches the scar over her eye.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to your eye ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost got knocked out of the sky over Big K.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it. It's kinda...you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A funeral.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That girl who died on the way up ...his girl ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you feel about him now ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Zander.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several INTELLIGENCE OFFICERS march into the bay.</context>
      <utterance>Dizzy bought the farm. She was my good friend, and friens are the best luck anyone gets... But in war, we must go on without our friends. We take with us their memory, and we are left to wonder if there is meaning in their death. Let me tell you what it is: Dizzy bough the farm so we can keep on fighting.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone snaps to attention. Colonel Carl Jenkins strides into the room. His eyes are hollow, and he looks grim. He returns Johnny's salute, nods to Carmen.</context>
      <utterance>Officer on deck !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please continue, Sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny nods to the GUNNERY CREW. They load Dizzy's body into a tube. Johnny steps back, salutes Dizzy. Everyone salutes.</context>
      <utterance>Dizzy wouldn't want our tears. She'd want us to remember her... with a vengeance. So go out and kill a bug for Dizzy. Kill as many as you can. You are her revenge, and every bug you kill honors her death.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Womb to tomb, cap trooper !</utterance>
   <speaker>ROUGHNECKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CREW CHIEF fires the tube. Out the viewports, A PULSE OF LIGHT disperses into space. The Roughnecks file out. Carl approaches. Carmen takes Johnny and Carl by the hand.</context>
      <utterance>Womb to tomb !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, look at this. The three of us back together again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you, Carl ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny, I'm sorry it had to be your unit on Planet P. That mission had a very low survival probability...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bugs laid a trap, didn't they ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elegant proof of intelligence, isn't it ? We thought there might be a brain on P.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew and you sent them anyway ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl sees the way Carmen is looking at him, like he's a bug.</context>
      <utterance>A colony has to reach a certain size before it produces a Brain... we think 300 generations. Woulda too expensive to launch an operation if there wasn't a Brain...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't approve. Well, too bad. We're in this for the species, boys and girls. It's simple numbers, they have more, and everyday I have to make decisions that send hundreds of people like you to their deaths.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl allows himself a tiny smile.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't they tell you, Colonel ? That's what cap troopres are good for.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hope you're ready for more. We're going back to P to capture that Brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Roughnecks are always ready, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Want the job ?</context>
      <utterance>I hear they need a new Lieutenant...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KLAXONS sound. Suddenly, everyone has someplace to go.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take it... until I get killed or you find someone better.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hope you get your Brain Bug, Carl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl turns abruptly and heads away. His entourage follows.</context>
      <utterance>It's good to see you two. It reminds me of the way things were before...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take care, wilya Johnny ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you on the bounce !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Lieutenant Barcalow ?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen bites her lip, takes first chair. Deladier feels bad for her, knows she's made a painful decision.</context>
      <utterance>He requested a combat assignment. There's always a need for experienced pilots on the ground. I had no choice but to let him go... He said you'd understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roughnecks fall in. Johnny steps into the room. There are many new and much younger faces.</context>
      <utterance>Officer on the deck !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you get me ?</context>
      <utterance>I only have two rules. Rule one, everyone fights. Rule two, no one quits. If you don't do your job, I'll kill you myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROUGHNECKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We get you, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who're all these kids ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got reinforced. Most of'em just got outa boot...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're the old men, Ace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll take this high ground. Lookouts there and therte and up there. If the bugs come upstairs in this neighbor-hood, we'll be the first to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it. Fleet tactical wants to know where they can deploy the skimmers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Roughnecks boo.</context>
      <utterance>Down there on the flats, eh ? Listen up, Roughnecks ! Our primary objective is to assist our friends from the Fleet...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A HERCULES CARGO BOAT hurtles out of the sky and lands on the high ground Johnny has intended forb his H.Q. Johnny scowls, marches over to the boat and confronts a FLEET OFFICER.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, cut it out. We will deploy from skimmers in teams of six. If the bugs open up a battery, we put it out of business. Any questions ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would'ya mind moving your boat ?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEET OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cargo bays open to deploy FLEET SKIMMERS. Zander jumps down to oversee the operation.</context>
      <utterance>Better talk to the boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're standing on my H.Q., Lieutenant !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You can have everything else, eh ?</context>
      <utterance>This is a Fleet-driven operation, son, and the Fleet thinks my boat will be safer on the high ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, in the distance, bug batteries open fire, not one but twenty. Zander and Johnny share a look of concern.</context>
      <utterance>You heard the Sky Marshall... Move it all down -</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rodger Young, prepare to receice outgoing fire...!  I'll take the first group.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saddle up, boys, that's our trash !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen dodges other starships, turns to her new number 2.</context>
      <utterance>Evasive action !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prepare for warp !</utterance>
   <speaker>NEW NUMBER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am ! Warp in 5... 4...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Rodger Young, we're going down... Repeat, this is Rodger Young, we're going down...!</utterance>
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ibanez...LET'S GO !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DELADIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me, Lieutenant ! That's an order !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way, ma'am !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your problem now, Lieutenant ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny's face falls.</context>
      <utterance>The Rodger Young just burned up...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander points. Far in the distance, a glowing pod plummets toward the planet. Johnny tracks it on his "head up".</context>
      <utterance>Any survivors ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is anyone receiving ?</context>
      <utterance>This is Lieutenant Carmen Ibanez.</utterance>
   <speaker>168	EXT	BASE CAMP - DAY - JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>grabs the handset from Ace.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Affirmative ! Carmen, this is Roughneck base camp... What is your present location ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've gotta go get her !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny knows it's true, swallows bitterly, turns away. That's when he sees it. Nearby, the ground shifts, a claw breaks through, a hole opens up and bugs boil up out of the ground.</context>
      <utterance>You know as well as I do she's probably already dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGAR WATKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn and see a second bug hole open up.</context>
      <utterance>Here they come !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're outa here. Lieutenant, get your men into the skimmers. This real estate's about to go buggy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The entire area underneath the base camp collapses to form a huge new canyon. The Hercules boat topples, crushing Skimmers and unfortunate Fleet personnnel.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, just calm down, I'm giving the orders here-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the dust, exposed bug tunnels can be seen in the canyon walls and piling out of them by the score, deadly Arachnid warriors. Johnny throws Zander a pulse cannon.</context>
      <utterance>Form a perimeter !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make yourself useful, fly boy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sugar Watkins tosses a bloody jump boot his way.</context>
      <utterance>Ace, get on the com. Tell Fleet we need retrieval... Sugar, salvage some armor and suit up Lieutenant Barcalow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ace points out a Tanker bug that's been brough up to the rim. Johnny sees another.</context>
      <utterance>Fleet Command says retrieval's no go. The battle group's at safe distance... and we got another problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like they're gonna hose us down... Johnny chews on this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright... Listen up, Roughnecks. We're gonna head west down through bug city, pick up any Rodger Young survivors we run across, and join A Company. Get me ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROUGHNECKS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander, awkward in a power suit, confronts Johnny.</context>
      <utterance>We get you, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think you're doing ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna save Carmen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would mean a comlete disregard for the mission objective. They hang you for that, Rico.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny and Zander stare each other down.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny starts for the gaping mouth of an exposed bug tunnel and the others fall in behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Move out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bug hunt !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Barcalow, save power, don't waste it on workers... Ace, tell Aardvark we're on our way...</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Warriors appear in the tunnel behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sugar, close the tunnel...!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUGAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sugar Watkins fires an H.E. round and seals the tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>Fire in the hole !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny makes an explosive sound. The Brain Bug slowly withdraws its palp.</context>
      <utterance>You know what this is...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny moves toward Carmen. The Brain Bug's multiple eyes track him. The warriors holding Carmen threaten. Johnny turns on the brain bug, his finger on the nuke's trigger.</context>
      <utterance>Sure you do... You're a big fat smart bug, aren't you ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Brain Bug clicks. The warriors back off. Carmen collapses. Johnny reaches for her.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take you with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chariot bugs move the Brain Bug down a hole. Workers seal the hole behind it with amazing speed. Johnny drags Carmen back toward the tunnel he entered from. The warriors charge.</context>
      <utterance>Take my hand !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny throws himself on top of Carmen as the Roughnecks burst into the chamber, guns blazing. The fight is furious, point blank, deadly to bug and Roughneck alike. Sugar Watkins screams as a warrior rips his arm off. Zander takes a claw through the gut.</context>
      <utterance>Roughnecks...NOW !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ace throws him a Morita. Johnny catches it, pumps three rounds into the bug's nerve stem. He struggles out from under the dead warrior. Every bug in the chamber is dead.</context>
      <utterance>Weapon !</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carmen throws her arms around Johnny.</context>
      <utterance>Are you hurt ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander takes this in. Carmen sees him, then his wound.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny...!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ace takes a look at his wound, makes a face.</context>
      <utterance>Zander...! Oh, you're hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander pushes him away, struggles to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Ah geez...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you walk ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Various components are gladly passed forward. Johnny and Ace help her putting it on.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get some armor on her, and the we'll get outa this stinkin bug hole !</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I was dead. Lucky for me you jokers showed up, eh ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't luck. Rico ignored the mission objective to rescue you...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it true ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now com'on, let's move out !</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, if I live through this, they'll probably hang me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tunnel floor drops out. FIVE ROUGHNECKS disappear into the hole. WARRIORS climb up into the tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>Up. We gotta be near A Company by now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How bad are you, pal ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny sees warriors coming up into the tunnel by the score.</context>
      <utterance>Been better, buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, we're gonna carry you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zander checks his pulse cannon's available power.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, I figureyou folks oughta get upstairs before it's too late... Gimmee the nuke.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be a hero...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny nods, hands him the nuke. Carmen sees what's happening.</context>
      <utterance>This is my farm. Now c'mon, give me what you got and get out of here...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zander, what are you doing ?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just giving you something to remember me by, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her and kisses her. Johnny drags Carmen away. Zander opens fire as the first warriors reach his position.</context>
      <utterance>Zander, no...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARMEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several of its delicate legs were apparently broken during the capture. Carl approaches it without fear, puts his hand on the thing.</context>
      <utterance>Look... they got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carl smiles in a cruel way.</context>
      <utterance>What's it thinking, Colonel ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Johnny and Carmen approach the General.</context>
      <utterance>It's afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I'd like to turn myself in. Dereliction of duty by an officer during wartime.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you freely admit to it ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is what this man says true, Lieutenant ?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
