<movie id="520" title="Star Wars Attack of the Clones">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN TYPHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ramp ;pwers. TWO NABOO GUARDS appear. SENATOR AMIDALA, ONE HANDMAIDEN (VERSE) and FOUR TROOPERS descend the ramp. AMIDALA is more beautiful now than she was ten years earlier when, as Queen, she was freeing her people from the yoke of the Trade Federation. The DIGNITARIES start to move forward. SENATOR AMIDALA reaches the foot of the ramp, when suddenly there is a blinding FLASH and a huge EXPLOSION. The DIGNITARIES and PILOTS are hurled to the ground as the starship is destroyed. Klaxons blare, alarms sound! CAPTAIN TYPHO and the TWO ESCORT PILOTS get up and run to where SENATOR AMIDALA lies dying. Beyond, ARTOO DETOO drops down from the Naboo Fighter and rolls toward the wreckage. The FEMALE ESCORT PILOT kneels by SENATOR AMIDALA and takes off her helmet, revealing SENATOR PADME AMIDALA.</context>
      <utterance>We made it. I guess I was wrong, there was no danger at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gathers up her decoy double in her arms. Cord's eyes are open. She looks up at her.</context>
      <utterance>Cord...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AMIDALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADM‰ lowers CORD‰ to the ground. She gets up and looks around at the devastation. There are tears in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No!... No!... No!...</utterance>
   <speaker>AMIDALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should not have come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN TYPHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amidala says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>M'Lady, you are still in danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN TYPHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns. They walk away. ARTOO lets out a small whimper and rolls off after them.</context>
      <utterance>This vote is very important. You did your duty and Cord did hers. Now come.  M'Lady, please!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAS AMEDDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everything quiets down. The AIDE disperses, and SUPREME CHANCELLOR PALPATINE steps to the podium.</context>
      <utterance>Order! We shall have order! The motion for the Republic to commission an army takes precedent, and that is what we will vote on at this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a shock silence in the vast arena.</context>
      <utterance>...My esteemed colleagues, excuse me... I have just received some tragic and disturbing news. Senator Amidala of the Naboo system... Has been assassinated!</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a moment of silence. ASK AAK, the SENATOR of MALASTARE, moves his pod into the centre of the arena.</context>
      <utterance>This grievous blow is especially personal to me. Before I became Chancellor, I served Amidala when she was Queen. She was a great leader who fought for justice, not only in this honourable assembly, but also on her home planet. She was so loved she could have been elected queen for life. She believed in public service, and she fervently believed in democracy. Her death is a great loss to us all. We will all mourn her as a relentless champion of freedom... and as a dear friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR ASK AAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A second pod moves into the centre of the area with DARSANA, the</context>
      <utterance>How many more Senators will die before this civil strife ends! We must confront these rebels now, and they need an army to do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>AMBASSADOR DARSANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Senator ORN FREE TAA swings forward in his pod.</context>
      <utterance>Why weren't the Jedi able to stop this assassination? We are no longer safe, under their protection.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORN FREE TAA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Republic needs more security now! Before it comes to war.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SENATORS yell pro and con. MAS AMEDDA tries to calm things down. SENATOR PADME AMIDALA, with CAPTAIN TYPHO, JAR JAR, and DORME, manoeuvre her pod into the centre of the vast arena.</context>
      <utterance>Must I remind the Senator from Malastare that negotiations are continuing with the separatists. Peace is our objective here... not war.</utterance>
   <speaker>AMIDALA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Senate goes quiet, then there is an outburst of cheering and applause.</context>
      <utterance>My noble colleagues, I concur with the Supreme Chancellor. At all costs, we do not want war!</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is with great surprise and joy the chair recognises the Senator from Naboo, Padm Amidala.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Many of the SENATORS boo and yell at SENATOR AMIDALA.</context>
      <utterance>Less than an hour ago, an assassination attempt was made against my life. One of my bodyguards and six others were ruthlessly and senselessly murdered. I was the target but, more importantly, I believe this security measure before you, was the target. I have led the opposition to build an army... but there is someone in this body who will stop at nothing to assure it's passage...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is sporadic yelling for and against her statements.</context>
      <utterance>I warn you, if you vote to create this army, war will follow. I have experienced the misery of war first-hand; I do not wish to do it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an undercurrent of booing... and groaning. SENATOR ORN FREE TAA moves his pod next to AMIDALA.</context>
      <utterance>Wake up, Senators... you must wake up! If you offer the separatists violence, they can only show us violence in return! Many will lose their lives. All will lose their freedom. This decision could very well destroy the very foundation of our great Republic. I pray you do not let fear push you into a disastrous decision. Vote down this security measure, which is nothing less than a declaration of war! Does anyone here want that? I cannot believe they do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORN FREE TAA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AMIDALA looks angry and frustrated. PALPATINE gives her a sympathetic look.</context>
      <utterance>My motion to defer the vote must be dealt with first. That is the rule of law.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Due to the lateness of the hour and the seriousness of this motion, we will take up these matters tomorrow. Until then, the Senate stands adjourned.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how much longer I can hold off the vote, my friends. More and more star systems are joining the separatists.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they do break away -</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I will not let that happen!</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if they do, you must realise there aren't enough Jedi to protect the Republic. We are keepers of the peace, not soldiers.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>YODA closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Master Yoda, do you think it will really come to war?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worse than war, I fear... Much worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you sense, Master?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A muted BUZZER SOUNDS. A hologram of an AIDE, DAR WAC, appears on the Chancellor's desk.</context>
      <utterance>Impossible to see ... The Dark Side clouds everything. But this I am sure of -  Do their duty the Jedi will.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAR WAC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The loyalist committee has arrived, my Lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all stand as SENATOR AMIDALA, CAPTAIN TYPHO, JAR JAR, MAS AMEDDA, DORME, and SENATORS BAIL ORGANA, HOROX RYYDER and ORN FREE TAA enter the office. YODA and MACE WINDU move to greet the SENATOR, YODA taps AMIDALA with his cane.</context>
      <utterance>Send them in.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With you the force is strong... young Senator. To see you alive brings warm feeling to my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Master Yoda. Do you have any idea who was behind the attack?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our intelligence points to disgruntled spice miners, on the moons of Naboo.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a stir of surprise.</context>
      <utterance>I don't wish to disagree but I think that Count Dooku was behind it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, M'Lady, Count Dooku was once a Jedi. He wouldn't assassinate anyone, it is not in his character.</utterance>
   <speaker>KI-ADI-MUNDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is a political idealist, not a murderer.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PALPATINE gets up, walks to the window, and looks out at the vast city.</context>
      <utterance>In dark times nothing is what it appears to be, but the fact remains Senator, in grave danger you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why would he kill you? To what end?</context>
      <utterance>Count Dooku has always avoided any kind of conflict. It appears he has no desire to start a war.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After gazing out of the window for several moments Palpatine turns to Mace.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but everything in my being tells me he was behind it...</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Master Jedi, may I suggest that the Senator be placed under the protection of your graces.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAIL ORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think that is a wise use of manpower during these stressful times?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chancellor, if I may comment, I do not believe the...</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..."situation is that serious." No, but I do, Senator.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chancellor, please! I don't want any more guards!</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PALPATINE nods to MACE WINDU, who nods back.</context>
      <utterance>I realise all too well that additional security might be disruptive for you, but perhaps someone you are familiar with... an old friend like... Master Kenobi...</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's possible. He has just returned from a Border dispute on Ansion.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must remember him, M'Lady... he watched over you during the blockade conflict.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not necessary, Chancellor.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AMIDALA sighs as the JEDI get up to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Do it for me, M'Lady, please. I will rest easier. We had a big scare today. The thought of losing you is unbearable.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>YODA leans into her ear.</context>
      <utterance>I will have Obi-Wan report to you immediately, M'Lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the JEDI leave the office, PALPATINE continues to pace behind his desk.</context>
      <utterance>Too little about yourself you worry, Senator, and too much about politics. Be mindful of your danger, Padm. Accept our help.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will not like this Republiv, that has stood for over a thousand years, be split in two</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Obi! Obi! Obi! Mesa sooo smilen to see'en yousa. Wahoooooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Good to see you, too, Jar Jar.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JAR JAR notices OBI-WAN'S APPRENTICE.</context>
      <utterance>Oops! Wheresa mesa manners? Excuse me, Master Obi-Wan. I completely forgot myself for a moment there. I have had to learn Diplodiaclect... speak it like a native now. Don't really see the point, actually, but members of the Senate seem to prefer it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and this, I take it, is your apprentice... Nooooooooo! Annie? Noooooooo! Little Bitty Annie?  Nooooooo! Yousa so biggen! Yiyiyiyyi! Annie!! Mesa no believen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JAR JAR grabs hold of ANAKIN and envelops him in a big hug.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Jar Jar.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annie! Annie! Yiyiyiyiyiyiiii!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME and TYPHO rise as OBI-WAN and ANAKIN stop before the SENATOR. OBI-WAN steps forward. ANAKIN stares at PADME. She glances at him.</context>
      <utterance>Lookie... lookie... Oops!... Oh, dear, I'm afraid I've forgotten myself again.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a great pleasure to see you again, M'Lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has been far too long Master Kenobi. I'm so glad our paths have crossed again... but I must warn you that I think your presence here is unnecessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves in front of ANAKIN</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure the Jedi Council have their reasons.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other for a long moment.</context>
      <utterance>Annie??  My goodness you've grown.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN looks disapprovingly at his apprentice. PADME laughs and shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>So have you... grown more beautiful, I mean... and much shorter... for a Senator, I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This embarrasses ANAKIN, and he looks down. OBI-WAN and CAPTAIN TYPHO smile.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Annie, you'll always be that little boy I knew on Tatooine.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our presence will be invisible, M'Lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN TYPHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am very grateful you are here, Master Kenobi. The situation is more dangerous than the Senator will admit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need more security, I need answers. I want to know who is trying to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're here to protect you Senator, not to start an investigation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's done it again. He bites his lip in frustration and shame. OBI-WAN gives ANAKIN a dirty look.</context>
      <utterance>We will find out who is trying to kill you Padm, I promise you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are not going to exceed our mandate, my young Padawan learner.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I meant in the interest of protecting her, Master, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are not going through this exercise again, Anakin. You will pay attention to my lead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What??!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why else do you think we were assigned to her, if not to find the killer? Protection is a job for local security... not Jedi. It's overkill, Master. Investigation is implied in our mandate.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will do as the Council has instructed, and you will learn your place, young one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone gives AMIDALA a slight bow as she and DORME leave the room.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps with merely your presence, the mysteries surrounding this threat will be revealed. Now if you will excuse me I will retire.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN TYPHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I know I feel a lot better having you here. I'll have an officer on every floor and I'll be at the command centre downstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Captain Typho leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Mesa busten wit happiness seein Yousa again, Annie. Deesa bad times, bombad times.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't even recognise me, Jar Jar. I thought about her every day since we parted... and she's forgotten me completely.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shesa happy. Happier den mesa see-en her in longo time.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now lets check the security here.</context>
      <utterance>Anakin, you're focusing on the Negative again. Be mindful of your thoughts. She was glad to see us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, my master.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why couldn't we see this attack on the Senator?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Masking the future, is this disturbance in the Force.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The propecy is coming true, the Dark Side is growing.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And only those who have turned to the Dark Side can sense the possibilities of the future. Only going through the Dark Side can we see.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you think they are behind this?</context>
      <utterance>It's been ten years, and the Sith still have no shown themselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Out there, they are. A certainty that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think Obi-Wan's apprentice will be able to bring balance to the Force?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a long silence as they walk away. Only footsteps are heard.</context>
      <utterance>Only if he chooses to follow his destiny.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Typho has more than enough men downstairs. No assassin will try that way. Any activity up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN checks a palm-sized view scanner he has pulled out of his utility belt. It shows a shot of ARTOO by the door, but no sign of PADME on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet as a tomb. I don't like just waiting here for something to happen to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She covered that camera. I don't think she liked me watching her.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is she thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She programmed Artoo to warn us if there's an intruder.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not an intruder I'm worried about. There are many other ways to kill a Senator.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but we also want to catch this assassin. Don't we, Master?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're using her as bait??</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trust me.</context>
      <utterance>It was her idea... No harm will come to her. I can sense everything going on in that room.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too risky... and your senses aren't that attuned, young apprentice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And yours are?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Possibly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't sleep well, anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because of your mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know why I keep dreaming About her now. I haven't seen her since I was little.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dreams pass in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>intoxicating.</context>
      <utterance>I'd rather dream of Padm. Just Being around her again is...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind your thoughts, Anakin, they betray you. You've made a commitment to the Jedi order... a commitment not easily broken... and don't forget she's a politician. They're not to be trusted.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not like the others in the Senate, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been my experience that Senators are only focused on pleasing those who fund their campaigns... and they are more than willing to forget the niceties of democracy to get those funds.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not another lecture, Master. Not on the economics of politics.... It's too early in the morning... and besides, you're generalising. The Chancellor doesn't appear to be corrupt.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Palpatine's a politician, I've observed that he is very clever at following the passions and prejudices of the Senators.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN looks stunned. He looks sharply at OBI-WAN</context>
      <utterance>I think he is a good man. My instincts are very positive about...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sense it, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="46">
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FINALLY, the DROID suffers a direct hit and blows up. OBI-WAN falls fifty stories, until a speeder drops down next to him, and he manages to grab onto the back end of the speeder and haul himself toward the cockpit. The JEDI struggles to climb into the passenger seat of the open speeder and sit down next to the driver, ANAKIN.</context>
      <utterance>I have a bad feeling about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was wacky! I almost lost you in the traffic.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What took you so long?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They zoom upward in hot pursuit of ZAM asshe fires out the open window at them with her laser pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you know, Master, I couldn't find a speeder I really liked, with an open cockpit... and with the right speed capabilities... and then you know I had to get a really gonzo color...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you'd spend as much time working on your saber skills as you do on your wit, young Padawan, you would rival Master Yoda as a swordsman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I already did.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As this conversation is going on, ANAKIN deftly moves in and out of the oncoming traffic, across lanes, between buildings, and miraculously through a construction site. ZAM WESELL continues firing at them.</context>
      <utterance>Only in your mind, my very young apprentice. Careful!! Hey, easy!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I forgot you don't like flying, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They barely miss a commuter train</context>
      <utterance>I don't mind flying... but what you're doing is suicide!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Master, you know I've been flying since before I could walk. I'm very good at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZAM WESSEL and the JEDI race through a line of cross-traffic made up of giant trucks. The speeders bank sideways as they slide around right-angle turns between buildings. ZAM races into a tram tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>Just slow down!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN zooms into the tunnel after ZAM. They see a tram coming at them. They brake, turn around, and race out, barely ahead of the charging commuter transport.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! Don't go in there!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I don't like it when you do that!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZAM WESSEL turns into oncoming traffic, deliberately trying to throw the JEDI off. Oncoming speeders swerve, trying to avoid ZAM and the JEDI. ZAM does a quick, tight loop-over and ends up behind the JEDI. She is now in a much better position to fire at them with her laser pistol. To avoid being hit by the laser bolts, ANAKIN slams on the brakes and moves alongside ZAM. She now fires point-blank at OBI-WAN.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Master. Don't worry, this guy's gonna kill himself any minute now!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? He's gonna blast me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN slides underneath Zam's speeder. They race along in traffic, one speeder right on top of the other. The BOUNTY HUNTER skims over the rooftops, causing ANAKIN to drop behind. ANAKIN goes through his gears, zooming around traffic. They race at high speed across a wide, flat surface of the city planet. A large spacecraft almost collides with them as it attempts to land. They round a corner and clip a flag, which gets caught on one of the front air scoops.</context>
      <utterance>Right - this isn't working.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was too close!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clear that!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What??</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN leans out of the speeder, then crawls out onto the front engine, pulling the flag free of the scoop. The speeder lurches forward with a surge of power.</context>
      <utterance>Clear the flag! We're losing power! Hurry!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whooooaaa! Don't do that! I don't like it when you do that!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They chase the BOUNTY HUNTER through a power refinery.</context>
      <utterance>So sorry, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Huge electrical bolts shoot between the buildings as the speeders pass.</context>
      <utterance>It's dangerous near those power couplings! Slow down! Don't go through there!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yiiii, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Master!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that was good...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZAM slides around a corner sideways, blocking an alley, firing point-blank as ANAKIN approaches.</context>
      <utterance>That was crazy!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh, damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN barely misses the BOUNTY HUNTER'S speeder as he dives under it, and through a small gap in the building hitting several pipes and going wildly out of control. ANAKIN struggles to regain control of the speeder, narrowly missing a crane, barely clipping a pair of giant struts. A giant gasball shoots up, causing ANAKIN to spin and bump a building, stalling the speeder.</context>
      <utterance>No, we can make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm crazy... I'm crazy... I'm crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it worked... we made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And you almost got us killed!</context>
      <utterance>It didn't work... we've stalled!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN works to get the speeder started. It quickly races to life.</context>
      <utterance>I think we're still alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was stupid!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could have made it...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, there is an ambush. Laser bolts fire everywhere. EXPLOSIONS surround them. They look up to see ZAM WESSEL take off.</context>
      <utterance>But you didn't!!! And now we've lost him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out of a cloud of smoke and ball of flames the JEDI tear after ZAM. They are smoking. OBI-WAN slaps out the small fire on the dashboard. ZAM goes up and down, through cross-traffic. There is a near miss as a speeder almost hits them. ZAM turns down and left between two buildings. ANAKIN pulls up and to the right</context>
      <utterance>No we didn’t...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?! He went down there, the other way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a shortcut... I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, ‘You think?’ What kind of shortcut?! He went completely the other way! You’ve lost him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Master, if we keep this chase going, that creep’s gonna end up deep fried. Personally, I’d very much like to find out who in the hell he is and who he’s working for...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN turns up a side street, zooming up several small passageways, then stops, hovering about fifty stories up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, so that’s why we’re going in the wrong direction.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you lost him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN looks around front and back. He spots something. He seems to start counting to himself as he watches something below approach.</context>
      <utterance>I’m deeply sorry, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN jumps out of the speeder. OBI-WAN looks down and sees Zam’s speeder about five stories below them cruising past. ANAKIN miraculously lands on top of the Bounty Hunter’s speeder. The speeder wobbles under the impact. ZAM looks up and realises what has happened. ZAM takes off, and ANAKIN slides to the back strut and almost slips off, but manages to hang on. ANAKIN works his way back to the speeder’s cockpit, just as ZAM stops suddenly, and ANAKIN flies forward to the left front fork. ZAM shoots at him with a laser pistol. There is a BLAST near ANAKIN'S hand, which breaks off a piece of the speeder. ANAKIN slides to the right fork of the speeder, where ZAM can’t reach him. He scrambles to the top, holding onto an air scoop. OBI-WAN has jumped into the driver’s seat of his speeder and is deftly gaining on the rogue speeder. The two speeders dive through oncoming traffic and then through cross traffic. Finally, ANAKIN is able to get hold of his lightsaber and starts to cut his way through the roof of the speeder. ZAM takes out her laser pistol and starts firing at the helpless JEDI, knocking the sword out of his hand. OBI-WAN races under the speeder and catches the Jedi weapon in the passenger’s seat. ANAKIN sticks his hand into the cockpit and, using the Force, pulls the gun out of ZAM’S hand. She grabs the Jedi’s hand, and they struggle for the weapon. It goes off, blowing a hole in the floor of the speeder. The speeder careens wildly out of control. ZAM struggles to pull the speeder out of it’s nose dive. OBI-WAN gets slowed down by traffic and loses sight of the Bounty Hunter’s speeder. Just as the dragster is about to nose dive into the ground, ZAM pulls it out, and it slides hard on the pavement in a shower of sparks. ANAKIN goes flying into the street.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me for a moment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anakin!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She went into that club, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN hands ANAKIN the lightsaber.</context>
      <utterance>Patience.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. Next time try not to lose it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN reaches for the lightsaber, but OBI-WAN holds it back.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Jedi's saber is his most precious possession.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for the lightsaber, OBI-WAN pulls it back.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He must keep it with him at all times.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This weapon is your life!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN finally holds out the lightsaber and ANAKIN grabs it.</context>
      <utterance>I've heard this lesson before...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, you haven't learned anything, Anakin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I try, Master.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I think you are going to be the death of me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say that Master... You're the closest thing I have to a father... I love you. I don't want to cause you pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why don't you listen to me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will. I'll do better, I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you see him him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he's a she...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN goes away.</context>
      <utterance>Then be extra careful...  Check it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going, Master?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN heads for the bar. ANAKIN blinks in surprise, then moves into the room, where ALIEN FACES look back at him with hostility, suspicion, and invitation as he moves among the tables. OBI-WAN arrives at the bar. He signals the BARMAN. CLOSE - Somewhere in the room a HAND moves to a pistol in its holster and unsnaps the safety catch. At the bar, a glass is placed in from of OBI-WAN. A drink is poured. He lifts the glass.</context>
      <utterance>To get a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAN SLEAZEBAGGANO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN looks at him. He moves his fingers slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Wanna buy some death sticks?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to sell me death- sticks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN moves his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to sell you death- sticks.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to go home and rethink your life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know who it was you were trying to kill?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAM WESSEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Senator from Naboo.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZAM glares at OBI-WAN.</context>
      <utterance>Who hired you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAM WESSEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was just a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell us!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAM WESSEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That Senator's gonna die soon anyway, and the next one won't make the same mistake I did...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This wound's going to need treatment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZAM glares hatefully.</context>
      <utterance>Who hired you? Tell us... tell us now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Representative Binks. I know I can count on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yousa betchen mesa bottums.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME kisses him on the cheek and gives him a hug. JAR JAR turns red.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, pardone-ay, Senator. I mean, I am honoured to accept this heavy burden. I take on this responsibility with deep humility tinged with an overwhelming pride.  It is not every day that I am called upon to...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a good friend, Jar Jar. I don't wish to hold you up. I'm sure you have a great deal to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JAR JAR bows and goes out. As he passes ANAKIN, he flashes a dazzling smile... PADME is in a very bad mood.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, M'lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not like this idea of hiding.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. Now that the Council has ordered an investigation, it won't take Master Obi-Wan long to find that bounty hunter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't worked for a year to defeat the "Military Creation Act" not to be here when its fate is decided.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes we have to let go of our pride and do what is requested of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pride?!? Annie, you're young, and you don't have a very firm grip on politics. I suggest you reserve your opinions for some other time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, M'lady. I was only trying to...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annie! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't call me that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annie...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've always called you that... it is your name, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Anakin. When you say Annie it's like I'm still a little boy... and I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME smiles at ANAKIN. He becomes a little shy.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Anakin. It's impossible to deny you've...  ...that you've grown up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Master Obi-Wan manages not to see it...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's the only way we grow.</context>
      <utterance>Mentors have a way of seeing more of our faults than we would like.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get me wrong... Obi-Wan is a great mentor. As wise as Master Yoda and as powerful as Master Windu. I am truly thankful to be his apprentice. Only... although I'm a Padawan learner, in some ways... a lot of ways... I'm ahead of him. I'm ready for the trials. I know I am! He knows it too. He believes I'm too unpredictable... Other Jedi my age have gone through the trials and made it... I know I started my training late... but he won't let me move on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That must be frustrating.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME cannot surpress a laugh. She shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>It's worse... he's overly critical. He never listens! He just doesn't understand! It's not fair!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... You sounded exactly like that little boy I once knew, when he didn't get his way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME just smiles at him. DORME laughs in the background.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not whining! I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say it to hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a brief silence. PADME comes over to ANAKIN.</context>
      <utterance>I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look into each other's eyes for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>Anakin...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't try to grow up too fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN looks deep into PADME'S eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I am grown up. You said it yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't look at me like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I can see what you're thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DORME is watching with concern.</context>
      <utterance>Ahh... so, you have Jedi powers too?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It makes me feel uncomfortable.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN backs away as PADME turns and goes back to her packing.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, M'lady.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN TYPHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be safe, m'lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Captain. Take good care of Dorme... the threat's on you two now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh, and PADME embraces her faithful handmaiden. DORME start to weep.</context>
      <utterance>He'll be safe with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not me, M'Lady. I worry about you. What if they realise I'm not you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DORME and PADME smile. ANAKIN frowns as OBI-WAN pulls him aside.</context>
      <utterance>Then my Jedi protector will have to prove how grown up he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anakin, you stay put on Naboo. Do not attract any attention. Do absolutely nothing without checking in with me or the Council.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will get to the bottom of this plot quickly, M'Lady. You'll be back here in no time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will be most grateful for your speed, Master Jedi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME gives DORME a last hug. ANAKIN picks up the luggage, and the TWO PEASANTS exit the speeder bus, where ARTOO is waiting for them.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May the Force be with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May the Force be with you, Master. They head off toward the giant Starfreighter.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suddenly, I'm afraid...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm kinda scared too. This is my first assignment on my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN and CAPTAIN TYPHO watch ANAKIN and PADME disappear into the vastness of the spaceport with ARTOO trundling along behind them.</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing to worry about... we have Artoo with us. The two laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope he doesn't try anything foolish.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN TYPHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd be more concerned about her doing something, than him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PK-4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN puts the dart onto the traym which retracts into the console. The DROID activates the system, and a screen lights up in from of OBI-WAN.</context>
      <utterance>Place the subject for analysis on the sensot tray, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a toxic dart. I need to know where it came from and who made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK-4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Diagrams and .... appear on the screem, scrolling past at great speed. OBI-WAN watches as the screen goes blank. They tray slides out.</context>
      <utterance>One moment, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>PK-4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you can see on your screen, subject weapon does not exist in any known culture. Markings cannot be identified. Probablt self-made by a warrior not associated with any known society.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me? Could you try again please?</utterance>
   <speaker>PK-4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN picks up the dart and looks at it, then looks to the DROID.</context>
      <utterance>Master Jedi, our records are very thorough. they cover eight percent of the galaxy. If I can't tell you where it came from, nobody can.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for your assistance! You may not be able to figure this out, but I think I know someone who might.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>SERVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARTOO slips tube into a tub of mush and sucks up a large quantity. With one of his little claw-arms, he grabs several chunks of something that looks like brown bread. A SERVER sees him.</context>
      <utterance>Keep moving! Keep moving!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOD SERVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARTOO takes one last big suck and heads away from the food line. The SERVER shouts after him angrily. The little droid moves past groups of eating or sleeping EMIGRANTS and comes to where ANAKIN is sound asleep. The young Jedi seems to be having a nightmare. He is very restless.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! No Droids!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is sweating. PADME leans over to wipe some of the sweat from his forehead. He wakes up with a start, then realises where he is. PADME simply looks at him. He stares back, somewhat confused. ARTOO fills up two bowls with mush.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, Mom, no...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN looks at PADME a little more closely, trying to see if he has revealed any of his secrets. She hands him a bowl of mush and bread.</context>
      <utterance>You seemed to be having a nightmare.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN looks into PADME'S eyes.</context>
      <utterance>We went into lightspeed a while ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME is a little unnerved by his intense stare.</context>
      <utterance>I look forward to seeing Naboo again. I've thought about it every day since I left. It's by far the most beautiful place I've ever seen...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were just a little boy then. It may not be as you remember it; time changes your perception.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think time has given me much more mature feelings to enhance my perception.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must be difficult having sworn your life to the Jedi... not being able to visit the places you like... or do the things you like...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or be with the people I love.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you allowed to love? I thought that was forbidden for a Jedi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Attachment is forbidden. Possession is forbidden. Compassion, which I would define as unconditional love, is central to a Jedi's life, so you might say we're encouraged to love.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have changed so much</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't changed a bit. You're exactly the way I remember you in my dreams. I doubt if Naboo has changed much either.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It hasn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN looks at PADME when he says this.</context>
      <utterance>I can't wait to breathe the sweet breeze that comes off the rolling hills. Whenever I try to visualise the Force, those hills are what I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an awkward moment.</context>
      <utterance>I love Naboo.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you dreaming about you mother earlier, weren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME gives ANAKIN a sympathetic look.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... I left Tatooine so long ago, my memory of her is fading. I don't want to lose it. Recently I've been seeing her in my dreams... vivid dreams... scary dreams. I worry about her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>HERMIONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HERMIONE'S eyes narrow.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for Dexter.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMIONE BAGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waddya want him for?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HERMIONE stares at OBI-WAN. There is a brief pause. Then she goes to the open serving hatch behind the counter.</context>
      <utterance>He's not in trouble. It's personal.</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMIONE BAGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steam billows out from the kitchen hatch behind the counter as a huge head pokes through.</context>
      <utterance>Someone to see ya, honey  A Jedi, by the looks of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEXTER JETTSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obi-Wan!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Dex.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEXTER JETTSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN sits in a booth.</context>
      <utterance>Take a seat! Be right with ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>HERMIONE BAGWA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want a cup of ardees?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HERMIONE moves off as the door to the counter opens and DEXTER JETTSTER appears. He is big - bald and sweaty, old and alien. Not someone to tangle with. He arrives, beaming hugely.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEXTER JETTSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, ol' buddy!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEXTER eases himself into the seat opposite OBI-WAN. He can just make it. HERMIONE sets two mugs of steaming ardees in from of them.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Dex.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEXTER JETTSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, my friend. What can I do for ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN places the dart on the table between them. DEX'S eyes widen. He puts down his mug.</context>
      <utterance>You can tell me what this is.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEXTER JETTSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEXTER picks up the dart delicately between his puffy fingers and peers at it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, whattaya know...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEXTER JETTSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't seen one of these since I was prospecting on Subterrel beyond the Outer Rim!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEXTER grins. He puts the dart down between them.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know where it came from?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEXTER JETTSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This baby belongs to them cloners. What you got here is a Kamino Kyberdart.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kamino Kyberdart... I wonder why it didn't show up in any analysis archive.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEXTER JETTSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's these funny little cuts on the side give it away... Those analysis droids you've got over there only focus on symbols, you know. I should think you Jedi would have more respect for the difference between knowledge and wisdom.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is it part of the Republic?</context>
      <utterance>Well, Dex, if droids could think, we wouldn't be here, would we?  Kamino... doesn't sound familiar.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEXTER JETTSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN then picks up the dart, holding it midway between them.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's beyond the Outer Rim. I'd say about twelve parsecs outside the Rishi Maze, toward the south. It should be easy to find, even for those droids in your archive to find. Those Kaminoans keep to themselves. They're cloners. Damned good ones, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cloners? Are they friendly?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEXTER JETTSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It depends.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dexter grins.</context>
      <utterance>On what, Dex?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEXTER JETTSTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>and how big your pocketbook is...</context>
      <utterance>On how good your manners are...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I grew up here, I don't think I'd ever leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I doubt that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, really. When I started my training, I was very homesick and very lonely. This city and my Mom were the only pleasant things I had to think about... The problem was, the more I thought about my Mom, the worse I felt. But I would feel better if I thought about the palace - the way it shimmers in the sunlight - the way the air always smells of flowers...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and the soft sound of the distant waterfalls. The first time I saw the Capital, I was very young... I'd never seen a waterfall before. I though they were so beautiful... I never dreamed one day I'd live in the palace.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, tell me, did you dream of power and politics when you were a little girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! That was the last thing I thought of. My dream was to help in the "Refugee Relief Movement." I never thought of running for elected office. But the more history I studied, the more I realised how much good politicians could do. So when I was eight, I joined the "Apprentice Legislators", then later on became a Senatorial advisor, with such a passion that, before I knew it, I was elected Queen. Partly because I scored so high on my education certificate, but for the most part it was my conviction that reform was possible. I wasn't the youngest Queen ever elected, but now that I think back on it, I'm not sure I was old enough. I'm not sure I was ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The people you served thought you did a good job. I heard they tried to amend the Constitution so you could stay in office.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Popular rule is not democracy, Annie. It gives the people what they want, not what they need. And, truthfully, I was relieved when my two terms were up. So were my parents. They worried About me during the blockade and couldn't wait for it all to be over. Actually, I was hoping to have a family by now... My sisters have the most amazing, wonderful kids... but when the Queen asked me to serve as Senator, I couldn't refuse her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I agree! I think the Republic needs you... I'm glad you chose to serve. I feel things are going to happen in our generation that will change the galaxy in profound ways.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN and PADME walk toward the palace. ARTOO continues to follow.</context>
      <utterance>I think so too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>QUEEN JAMILLIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been worried about you.  I'm so glad you're safe, Padm.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Your Highness. I only Wish I could have served you better by staying on Coruscant for the vote.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIO BIBBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Given the circumstances, Senator, you know it was the only decision Her Highness could have made.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN JAMILLIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many systems have joined Count Dooku and the separatists?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About two hundred. And more are leaving the Republic every day. If the Senate votes to create an army, I'm sure it's going to push us into a civil war.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIO BIBBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's unthinkable! There hasn't been a full-scale war since the formation of the Republic!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN JAMILLIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you see any way, through negotiations, to bring the separatists back into the Republic?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if they feel threatened. The separatists don't have an army, but if they are provoked, they will move to defend themselves. I'm sure of that. And with no time or money to build an army, my guess is they will turn to the Commerce Guilds or the Trade Federation for help.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN JAMILLIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The armies of commerce! Why has Nothing been done in the Senate to restrain them?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid that, despite the Chancellor's best efforts, there are still many bureaucrats, judges, and even Senators on the payrolls of the Guilds.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIO BIBBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's outrageous! After all of those hearings, and the four trials in the Supreme Court, Nute Gunray is still the Viceroy of the Trade Federation. Do those money mongers control everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN JAMILLIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, Counsellor, the courts were able to reduce the Federation's armies. That's a move in the right direction.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are rumours, Your Highness, that the Federation Army was not reduced as they were ordered.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Jedi have not been allowed to investigate. It would be to be too dangerous for the economy, we were told.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN JAMILLIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must keep our faith in the Republic. The day we stop believing democracy can work is the day we lose it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's pray that day never comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN JAMILLIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SIO BIBBLE signals. All the other ADVISORS and ATTENDANTS bow and leave the room.</context>
      <utterance>In the meantime, we must consider your own safety.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIO BIBBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your suggestion, Master Jedi?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anakin's not a Jedi yet, Counsellor. He's still a Padawan learner. I was thinking...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hold on a minute!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me! I was thinking I would stay in the Lake Country. There are some places up there that are very isolated.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SIO BIBBLE and QUEEN JAMILLIA exchange a look. Something is going on here.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?! I am in charge of security here, M'Lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annie, my life is at risk, and this is my home. I know it very well... that is why we're here. I think it would be wise for you to take advantage of my knowledge in this instance.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, M'Lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIO BIBBLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is right. The Lake Country is the most remote part of Naboo. Not many people and a clear view of the surrounding terrain.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN JAMILLIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN glares at PADME. Then QUEEN JAMILLIA gets up, and they all start to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Perfect. It's settled then.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN JAMILLIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME looks worred. They ALL exit down the main staircase.</context>
      <utterance>Padm, I had an audience with your father yesterday. I told him what was happening. He hopes you will visit your mother before you leave... your family's very worried about you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you call for assistance?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... yes, I did...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has a powerful face, doesn't he? He was one of the most brilliant Jedi I have had the privilege of knowing.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never understood why he quit. Only twenty Jedi have ever left the Order.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Lost Twenty... and Count Dooku was the most recent and the most painful. No one likes to talk about it. His leaving was a great loss to the Order.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, one might say, he was always a bit out of step with the decisions of the Council... much like your old Master, Qui-Gon Jinn.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOCASTA NU stares at the bust</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. They were alike in many ways. Very individual thinkers... idealists...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting... I'm still not sure I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm sure you didn't call me over here for a history lesson. Are you having a problem, Master Kenobi?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm trying to find a planet system called Kamino. It doesn't seem to show upon any of the archive charts.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOCASTA NU leans over OBI-WAN'S shoulder, looking at the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Kamino? It's not a system I'M familiar with... Let me see...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you have the right co-ordinates?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOCASTA NU taps the keyboard and frowns.</context>
      <utterance>According to my information, it should be in this quadrant somewhere... just south of the Rishi Maze.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No co-ordinates? It sounds like the kind of directions you'd get from a street tout... some old miner or Furbog trader.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All three actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure it exists?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN and JOCASTA NU studt the star map hologram.</context>
      <utterance>Let me do a gravitational scan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are some inconsistencies here. Maybe the planet you're looking for was destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't that be on record?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ought to be. Unless it was very recent.  I hate to say it, but it looks like the system you're searching for doesn't exist.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's impossible... perhaps the archives are incomplete.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCASTA NU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN stares at her, then looks back at the map.</context>
      <utterance>The archives are comprehensive and totally secure, my young Jedi. One thing you may be absolutely sure of - if an item does not appear in our records, it does not exist!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME starts forward; ANAKIN hangs back.</context>
      <utterance>There's my house!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Don't say you're shy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, there are shouts from two little girils, RYOO (age 6) and POOJA (age 4). They come running toward PADME.</context>
      <utterance>No, but I...</utterance>
   <speaker>RYOO &amp; POOJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aunt Padme!! Aunt Padme!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ryoo!! Pooja!! PADME scoops up RYOO and POOJA and hugs them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN and the GIRLS say hello shyly. Then:</context>
      <utterance>I'm so happy to see you! This is Anakin. Anakin, this is Ryoo, and this is Pooja.</utterance>
   <speaker>RYOO &amp; POOJA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they see the droid, they hug him. ARTOO WHISTLES and BEEPS. PADME laughs. ANAKIN and PADME go on toward the house. The GIRLS stay and play with ARTOO.</context>
      <utterance>Artoo!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>SOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SOLA puts the bowl down on the table, where ANAKIN, PADME and RUWEE NABERRIE (Padme's father) are coming into the room.</context>
      <utterance>They're eating over at Jev Narran's later, Mom. They just had a snack. They'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anakin, this is my sister, Sola.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Anakin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SOLA sits, as JOBAL NABERRIE (Padme's mother) comes in with a heaped bowl of steaming food.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOBAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just in time for dinner. I hope you're hungry, Anakin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's being polite, Mom. We're starving.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUWEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>EVERYONE sits and starts passing food.</context>
      <utterance>You came to the right place at the right time. Sit down, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOBAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME gives JOBAL a dirty look. RUWEE smiles as he watches.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, it's so good to see you safe. We were so worried.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUWEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOBAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I know... but I had to say it. Now it's done.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this is exciting! Do you know, Anakin, you're the first boyfriend my sister's ever brought home?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sola!! He isn't my boyfriend! He's a Jedi assigned by the Senate to protect me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bodyguard?! Oh, Padme! They didn't tell us it was that serious!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They nod.</context>
      <utterance>It's not, Mom, I promise.  Anyway, Anakin's a friend. I've known him for years. Remember that little boy who was with the Jedi during the blockade crisis?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He grew up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOBAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, when are you going to settle down? Haven't you had enough of that life? I certainly have!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, I'm not in any danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUWEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Yes... I'm afraid she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not much.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUWEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I wish I'd traveled more... but I must say, I'm happy here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Padme tells me you teach at the university?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUWEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, and before that, I was a builder. I also worked for the Refugee Relief Movement, when I was very young.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why haven't you told us about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's there to talk about? He's just a boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A boy? Have you seen the way he looks at you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sola - stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's obvious he has feelings for you. Are you saying, little baby sister, that you haven't noticed?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not your baby sister, Sola. Anakin and I are friends... our relationship is strictly professional.  Mom, would you tell her to stop it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe you haven't noticed the way he looks at you. I think you're afraid to.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOBAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sola's just concerned... we all are.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mom, you're impossible. What I'm doing is important.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOBAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've done your service, Padm. It's time you had a life of your own. You're missing so much!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RUWEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now tell me, son. How serious is this thing? How much danger is my daughter really in?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There have been two attempts on her life. Chances are there'll be more. My Master is tracking down the assassins. I'm sure he'll find out who they are. This situation, won't last long.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUWEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want anything to happen to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't either.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, this won't take long.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME goes on packing. ANAKIN looks around the room.</context>
      <utterance>I just want to get there before dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still live at home.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I move around so much, I've never had a place of my own. Official residences have no warmth. I feel good here. I feel at home.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN picks up a framed hologram.</context>
      <utterance>I never had a real home. Home was always where my Mom was.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hologram shows Padme at age seven or eight surrounded by forty or fifty little green creatures. She is holding one in her arms. They are all smiling hugely.</context>
      <utterance>Is this you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN picks up another hologram. It shows PADME at age ten or eleven. She is wearing official robes and standing between two robed legislators. Her expression is severe.</context>
      <utterance>That was when I went with the Relief Group to Shadda-Bi-Boran. Their sun was imploding, and the planet was dying. I was helping to relocate the children. See that little one I'm holding? His name was N'a-kee-tula, which means sweethear. He was so full of life,. All those kids were. I did everything I could to save him, but he died... they all did. They were never able to adapt... to live off their native planet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME pulls a face. ANAKIN grins. She continues packing. ANAKIN sets the two holograms down side by side - the beaming little girl, and the the stern, unsmiling adolescent.</context>
      <utterance>My first day as an Apprentice Legislator. Notice the difference?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CHILDREN take off their helmets and turn off their lightsabers.</context>
      <utterance>Don't think... feel... be as one with the Force. Help you, it will.  Younglings - enough! A visitor we have. Welcome him.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Master Obi-Wan Kenobi, meet the mighty Bear Clan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome, Master Obi-Wan!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am sorry to disturb you, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What help to you, can I be?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m looking for a planet described to me by an old friend. I trust him. But the system doesn’t show up on the archive maps.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The map reader is a small shaft with a hollow opening at the top. The CCHILDREN gather around it. OBI-WAN takes out a little glass ball and places it into the bowl. The window shades close darkening the room and the reader lights up, projecting the star map hologram into the room. The CHILDREN laugh. Some of them reach up to try and touch the nebulae and stars. OBI-WAN walks into the display.</context>
      <utterance>An interesting puzzle. Gather round the map reader, younglings. Master Obi-Wan has lost a planet. Find it, we will try...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is where it ought to be... but it isn’t. Gravity is pulling all the stars in this area inward to this spot. There should be a star here... but there isn’t.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a brief pause. Then a CHILD puts its hand up. YODA nods.</context>
      <utterance>Most interesting. Gravity’s silhouette remains, but the star and all its planets have disappeared. How can this be?</utterance>
   <speaker>JEDI CHILD JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because someone erased it from the archive memory.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s right! Yes! That’s what happened! Someone erased it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JEDI CHILD MAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN stares; YODA chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>If the planet blew up, the gravity would go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truly wonderful, the mind of a child is. Uncluttered. To the centre of the pull of gravity go, and find your planet you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Master Yoda who could have erased information from the archives? That’s impossible, isn’t it?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Much harder to answer, that question is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was in Level Three, we used to come here for school retreat. See that island? We used to swim there every day. I love the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME becomes aware that ANAKIN is looking at her.</context>
      <utterance>I do too. I guess it comes from growing up on a desert planet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...We used to lie on the sand and let the sun dry us... and try to guess the names of the birds singing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches her arm. PADME has become receptive to the way he looks at her but is nervous.</context>
      <utterance>I don’t like sand. It’s coarse and rough and irritating, and it gets everywhere. Not like here. Here everything’s soft... and smooth...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a very old man who lived on the island. He used to make glass out of sand - and vases and necklaces out of the glass. They were magical.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything here is magical.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>but it wasn’t.</context>
      <utterance>You could look into the glass and see the water. The way it ripples and moves. It looked so real...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look into each other's eyes. He touches her chin.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes, when you believe something to be real, it becomes real. Real enough, anyway...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to think if you looked too deeply into glass, you would lose yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN kisses PADME. She doesn't resist. She comes to her senses and pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>I think it's true...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shouldn't have done that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. When I'm around you, my mind is no longer my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>It's the situation... the stress...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the view.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be wary, this disturbance in the Force is growing stronger.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am concerned for my Padawan. He is not ready to be on his own.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Council is confident in this decision, Obi-Wan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has exceptional skills. The Council is confident in its decision, Obi-Wan. If the prophecy is true, he weill be the one to bring balance to the Force.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>But he still has much to learn. And his abilities have made him... well... arrogant. I realise now what you and Master Yoda knew from the beginning... the boy was too old to start the training and...</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something else?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Master, he should not have been given this assignment. I'm afraid Anakin won't be able to protect the Senator.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has a... an emotional connection with her. It's been there since he was boy. Now he's confused... distracted.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE-WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN climbs into the cockpit of the Starfighter.</context>
      <utterance>Obi-Wan, you must have faith that he will take the right path.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has Master Yoda gained any insight into whether or not this war will come about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probing the Dark Side is a dangerous process. He could be in seclusion for days... May the force be with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN looks up - wide-eyed innocence.</context>
      <utterance>You did that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME scowls at him. PADME jabs at the fruit - ANAKIN subtly moves his hand and it lifts up from the plate and hovers in front of her.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME laughs. ANAKIN laughs. She reaches out for the fruit - it loops.</context>
      <utterance>That! Now stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN moves his fingers. The fruit flies into his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Anakin!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN is pleased. He cuts the fruint into several pieces and sends one back to PADME. She bites it out of the air and laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not really supposed to do that... for fun, I mean. If Master Obi-Wan were here, he'd be very grumpy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I tell you something?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how can I tell you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should use your Jedi intuition.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't work around you. My mind is always a muddle... I can only think of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anakin, don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. The logs flame in the hearth.</context>
      <utterance>From the moment I met you, all those years ago, a day hasn't gone by when I haven't thought of you. And now that I'm close to you again, I'm in agony. The closer I get to you, the worse it gets. The thought of not being with you mskes my stomach turn over - my mouth goes dry. I feel dizzy. I can't breathe. I'm haunted by the kiss you should never have given me. My heart is beating, hoping that kiss will not become a scar. You are in my very soul, tormenting me. What can I do? I will do anything you ask...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you are suffering as much as I am, tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I can't. We can't. It's just not possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything's possible. Padme, please listen...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You listen. We live in a real world. Come back to it. You're studying to become a Jedi Knight. I'm a Senator. If you follow your thoughts through to conclusion, they will take us to a place we cannot go... regardless of the way we feel about each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you do feel something! There's an extraordinary connection between us. You can't deny that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>your future, for me.</context>
      <utterance>Annie, it doesn't make any difference. Jedi aren't allowed to marry. You swore an oath, remember? You'd be expelled from the Order. I will not let you give up your responsibilities...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was destined to be a Jedi. I don't think I could be anything else. But you are asking me to be rational. That is something I know I cannot do. I wish I could wish my feelings away... but I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is silence as they stare at the fire. ANAKIN is thinking.</context>
      <utterance>I am not going to give into this. I'm not going to throw my life away. I have more important things to do than fall in love.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>we could keep it a secret.</context>
      <utterance>It wouldn't have to be that way...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Then we'd be living a lie - one we couldn't keep even if we wanted to. Mt sister saw it. So did my mother. I couldn't do that. Could you, Anakin? Could you live like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...No, you're right. It would destroy us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TAUN WE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN wipes the rain from his face and blinks in surprise at a tall, pasty-white alien named TAUN WE. He has large, almond shaped eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to Tipoca City, Master Jedi.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAUN WE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything is ready. The Prime Minister expects you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm expected?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAUN WE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN masks his surprise as they move away along the corridor. Obi-Wan follows Taun We cautiously.</context>
      <utterance>Of course! He is anxious to see you. After all these years, we were beginning to think you weren't coming. Now please, this way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>TAUN WE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I present Lama Su, Prime Minister of Kamino... and this is Master Jedi...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obi-Wan Kenobi.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LAMA SU indicates a chair. OBI-WAN sits. TAUN WE hovers. The room is bathed in brilliant white light. The whole place is ultra high-tech.</context>
      <utterance>Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I trust you are going to enjoy your stay. We are most happy you have arrived at the best part of the season.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You make me feel most welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now to business. You will be delighted to hear we are on schedule. Two hundred thousand units are ready, with another million well on the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is... good news.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please tell your Master Sido-Dyas that we have every confidence his order will be met on time and in full. He is well, I hope?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Master - ?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jedi Master Sifo-Dyas. He's still a leading member of the Jedi Council, is he not?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes. Sido-Dyas.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be anxious to inspect the units for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why I'm here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you do... you just don't want to tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to use one of your Jedi mind tricks on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You are anything but weak-minded.</context>
      <utterance>They only work on the weak-minded.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right... his name was Palo. I was twelve. We were both in the Legislative Youth Program. He was a few years older then I... very cute... dark curly hair... dreamy eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>whatever happened to him?</context>
      <utterance>All right, I get the picture...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went on to become a Queen. He went on to become an artist.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he was the smart one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really don't like politicians, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like two or three, but I'm not really sure about one of them.  I don't think the system works.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would you have it work?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need a system where the politicians sit down and discuss the problems, agree what's in the best interests of all the people, and then do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is exactly what we do. The trouble is that people don't wlways agree. In fact, they hardly ever do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then they should be made to.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By whom? Who's going to make them?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone wise.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A mischievious little grin creeps across his face.</context>
      <utterance>That sounds an awful lot like a dictatorship to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME stares at ANAKIN. He looks back at her, straight-faced, and can't hold a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if it works...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're making fun of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On no, I'd be much too frightened to tease a Senator.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME picks up a piece of fruit and throws it at him. He catches it. PADME throws two more pieces of fruit, and ANAKIN catches them.</context>
      <utterance>You're so bad!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We modified their genetic structure to make them less independent than the original host. As a result they are totally obedient, taking any order without question.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was the original host?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bounty hunter called Jango Fett. We felt a Jedi would be the perfect choice, but Sido-Dyas hand- picked Jango Fett himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is this bounty hunter now?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, we keep him here. After a few hundred thousand clones, the genetic pattern starts to fade, so we take a fresh supply. He lives here, but he's free to come and go as he pleases.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apart from his pay, which is considerable, Fett demanded only one thing - an unaltered clone for himself. Curious isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unaltered?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pure genetic replication. No tampering with the structure to make it more docile... and no growth acceleration...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would like to meet this Jango Fett.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAUN WE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TAUN WE bows, and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>I would be most happy to arrange it, for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mentioned growth acceleration...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN looks at the BOY CLONES.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, it's essential. Otherwise, a mature clone would take a lifetime to grow. Now, we can do it in half the time. Those items you saw on the parade ground were started ten years ago, when Sido-dyas first placed the order, and they're already mature...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And these?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About five years ago.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're immensely superior to droids, capable of independent thought and action.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN gazes at the nearest embryos.</context>
      <utterance>I'd hoped you would be pleased.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, prime minister, when my Master Sido-dyas first contacted you, did he say the order was for... himself... or?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Himself? Of course not. This army is for the Republic?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Repubic?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are also very much agasint this Count Dooku and his seccessionist movement. We are proud to be of help to the Republic.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAUN WE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TAUN WE goes. The door slides closed behind him. OBI-WAN looks around, then moves swiftly to check the room over. Finally, satisfied, he takes out his comlink.</context>
      <utterance>I have arranged for you to meet Jango Fett in the morning. Sleep well.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arfour, Arfour...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I've never heard of a Jedi called Sido-Dyas, have you, Master?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Whoever placed that order was not a Jedi, I can assure you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a strong feeling that this bounty hunter is the assassin we're looking for.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who he is working for... discover that, you must.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The hologram switches off, and OBI-WAN fades away.</context>
      <utterance>I will, Master, and I will also find out more about this clone army... May The Force...</utterance>
   <speaker>WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A clone army! Ordered by someone in the Senate perhaps... Someone's out to start a war.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inform the chancellor of this, we must.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>YODA stares back at MACE WINDU, then slowly shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Who do you think this impostor Sido-Dyas, could be?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to disturb you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brief pause.</context>
      <utterance>Your presence is soothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had a nightmare again last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jedi don't have nightmares.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN'S opens his eyes and looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>I heard you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw my mother. I saw her as clearly as I see you now. She's suffering, Padme. She is in pain...They're killing her!  I know I'm disobeying my mandate to protect you, Senator. I know I will be punished and possibly thrown out of the Jedi Order, but I must go. I have to help her! I'm sorry, Padme. I don't have a choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annie, I told you I wouldn't let you give up your future for me. I'll go with you. That way you can continue to protect me, and you won't be disobeying your mandate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME smiles and takes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>What about Master Obi-wan?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess we won't tell him, will we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TAUN WE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a brief pause, then BOBA FETT nods.</context>
      <utterance>Boba, is your father here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TAUN WE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May we see him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBA FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another brief pause, then BOBA FETT steps aside, and TAUN WE and OBI-WAN go through.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>BOBA FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JANGO FETT comes in from the bedroom. He wears a jumpsuit. He is unshaven and mean looking, his face pitted with scars of old wounds. There are a couple of weird tattoos on his muscular forearms. He eyes OBI-WAN with suspicion.</context>
      <utterance>Dad! Taun We's here!</utterance>
   <speaker>TAUN WE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome back, Jango. Was your trip productive?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN and JANGO FETT size each other up. BOBA FETT studies both of them.</context>
      <utterance>Fairly.</utterance>
   <speaker>TAUN WE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Jedi Master, Obi-Wan Kenobi. He's come to check on our progress.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JANGO FETT'S eyes fix OBI-WAN coldly.</context>
      <utterance>That right?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You must be very proud.</context>
      <utterance>Your clones are very impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just a simple man, trying to make my way in the universe, Master Jedi.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN eyes the half-open bedroom door, through which a couple of pieces of body armour can be seen on the floor. JANGO FETT registers OBI-WAN'S look. He moves in front of him, blocking the view.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't we all?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever made your way as far into the interior as Coruscant?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once or twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Recently?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Possibly...</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you must know Master Sido- Dyas?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOBA FETT moves to close the bedroom door. JANGO FETT smiles thinly at OBI-WAN.</context>
      <utterance>Boba, close the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Master who?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sido-Dyas. Isn’t he the Jedi who hired you for this job?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never heard of him. I was recuited by a man called Darth Tyranus on one of the moons of Bogden.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No? I thought...</utterance>
   <speaker>TAUN WE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sido-Dyas told us to expect him. And he showed up just when your Jedi Master said he would. We have kept the Jedi’s involvement a secret until your arrival, just as your Master requested.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Curious...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you like your army?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems to me it's your army - being that they are all clones of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll do their job well, I'll guarantee that.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I look forward to seeing them in action. Thank you for your time, Jango.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN and TAUN WE go out. The door slides closed. JANGO FETT turns to his son. He is deep in thought.</context>
      <utterance>Always a pleasure to meet a Jedi.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Dad?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN and PADME get down. Sitting on a stool in front of the shop is WATTO. He is using a small electronic screwdriver on a fiddly DROID. THREE PIT DROIDS are chattering away and are trying to help him, but they seem only to make him madder.</context>
      <utterance>Wait, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not that one - that one!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Watto.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WATTO turns to the chattering PIT DROIDS.</context>
      <utterance>I said excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PIT DROIDS snap into their storage position.</context>
      <utterance>Shut down.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WATTO drops the screwdriver and curses loudly in Huttese</context>
      <utterance>What? I don't know you... What can I do for you? You look like a Jedi. Whatever it is... I didn't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN takes the fiddly piece of equipment and starts to play with it. WATTO blinks in surprise.</context>
      <utterance>Let me help you with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WATTO looks at him suspiciously. He stares at PADME, then back to ANAKIN.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for Shmi Skywalker.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the fiddly piece of equipment in Anakin's hands WHIRS into life. WATTO blinks at it.</context>
      <utterance>Annie?? Little Annie?? Naaaah!!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WATTO gives ANAKIN a big hug.</context>
      <utterance>You are Annie! It is you! You little womp rat.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure sprouted Weehoo! A Jedi! Waddya know? Hey, maybe you couldda help wit some daedbeats who owe...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother...</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. Shmi... she's not mine no more. I sold her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sold her...</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Years ago. Sorry, Anne, but you know, business is business. Sold her to a moisture farmer named Lars. Least I think it was Lars. Believe it or not, I heard he freed her and married her. Can ya beat that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know where they are?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long way from here... someplace over on the other side of Mos Eisley, I think...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN'S grim look means business; WATTO gets the hint quickly.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATTO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN and WATTO go into the shop.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... sure... absolutely. Let's go look in my records.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAMA SU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell your Council the first battalions are ready. And remind them that if they need more troops, we will need time to grow them.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't forget.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening. May I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Threepio?</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my... oh, my! Master Anakin! My goodness, I can hardly believe it! And this must be Miss Padme.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Threepio.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've come to see my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, dear! I'm so terribly sorry, Master Annie.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Threepio, what's happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we'd better go inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OWEN LARS and BERU WHITESUN come out into the courtyard.</context>
      <utterance>Master Lars - Master Owen! Somebody to see you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Anakin Skywalker. I'm here looking for my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Owen Lars... I guess I'm your step-brother.  This is my girlfriend, Beru.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Padme.</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a feeling you might show up some day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is my mother here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIEGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLIEGG LARS swings from the house on a small floating chair. One of his legs is heavily bandaged; the other is missing. He balances awkwardly and puts out a hand.</context>
      <utterance>No, she's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIEGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cliegg Lars. Shmi is my wife... Come on inside. We have a lot to talk about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CLIEGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLIEGG grimaces, easing his throbbing leg.</context>
      <utterance>Your mother had gone out early, like she always did, to pick mushrooms that grow on the vaporatos. From the tracks, she was about halfway when they took her. Those Tuskens walk like men, but they're vicious, mindless monsters. Thirty of us went out after her. Four of us came back. Three more are still out there looking. I'd be with them, only... I just couldn't ride any more... until I heal.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIEGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Then ANAKIN stands up.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't the way I wanted to meet you, son. This isn't how your mother and I planned it. I don't want to give up on her, but she's been gone a month. There's little hope she's lasted this long.</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To find my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Annie!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLIEGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's daed, son. Accept it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN turns abruptly.</context>
      <utterance>I can feel her pain, and I will find her. I know she's alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are going to have to stay here. These are good people, Padme. You'll be safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take my speeder bike.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME hugs him. ANAKIN walks over to Owen's speeder bike, which is standing close by.</context>
      <utterance>Anakin...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I trust you'll watch over her, Owen.</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN swings onto the bike. The engine fires.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN takes off across the desert. PADME watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>I won't be long.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JANGO FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JANGO FETT guides he ship around the asteroids. Suddenly:</context>
      <utterance>Nearly there, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBA FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the view screen, Obi-Wan's ship appears, chasing after them. JANGO FETT grabs the controls. They are thrown around as the ship plummets to try to lose OBI-WAN.</context>
      <utterance>Dad, look!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ship goes into a power-climb. A GREAT SPACE DDOGFIGHT ensues between OBI-WAN and JANGO FETT.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOBA FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad! Watch out!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN OBI-WAN'S COCKPIT, his skill is pushed to the limit as he throws the ship from side to side, avoiding great rocks. Then a huge asteroid tumbles across his path. There seem no way he can avoid it. OBI-WAN fires a couple of aerial torpedoes. They streak toward the asteroid. IN JANGO'S COCKPIT, they see the huge explosion as Obi-Wan's ship appears to smash into the asteroid.</context>
      <utterance>Stay calm, son. We'll be fine. That Jedi won't be able to follow us through this. But Obi-Wan ship dives into the asteroid belt after them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBA FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got him! Yeahhhhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOBA FETT laughs. Jango Fett's ship emerges from the asteroid belt and heads down toward the planet of Geonosis.</context>
      <utterance>We won't see him again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THREEPIO is parked in a corner.</context>
      <utterance>Please don't leave us, Miss Padme. These people need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not leaving, Threepio. I just can't sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's no in-between.</context>
      <utterance>That's something I cannot relate to. As a Protocol Droid, I'm either active or inactive.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess you're lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you really think so..? I suppose I shouldn't expect...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not happy here?</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>well, it's embarrassing.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm not unhappy... and my masters here ar so kind I wouldn't wish to trouuble them, it's just... being like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Being like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naked. If you pardon the expression. You see, when Master Annie made me, he never quite found the time to give me any outer covering. It's so humiliating. How would you like it if you had to go around with all your circuits showing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I wouldn't like it at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME looks thoughtfully at a pile of spare parts and bits of metal and tools.</context>
      <utterance>Of course you wouldn't. Nobody would. It's simply not protocol.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we can do something about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. Only Master Annie...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? They seem to have a box of old coverings here.</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME picks up a piece of metal and holds it against him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh? How observant of you, Miss Padme. Of course, I'm just not mechanically minded... if you see what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>here...</context>
      <utterance>Let's see, if we put this...</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooooh! That's tickles.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hold still, please.</context>
      <utterance>You'll have to be quiet, Threepio.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SHMI'S eyelids flutter - and barely open. They are caked with blood.</context>
      <utterance>Mom... Mom... Mom...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SHMI'S eyes focus slowly. ANAKIN gives a little choking gasp.</context>
      <utterance>Annie...? Is it you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m here, Mom. You’re safe. Hang on. I’m going to get you out of here...</utterance>
   <speaker>SHMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m so glad... to see you, Annie... Now... I am complete...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everything’s going to be fine.</context>
      <utterance>Just stay with me, Mom. I’m going to make you well again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHMI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SHMI dies. ANAKIN draws her to his breast. There is silence for a moment. ANAKIN lifts his head, listening for a moment, then he sits on the floor of the Tusken hut, cradling his dead mother in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>You look so handsome. My son... my grown-up son. I’m so proud of you, Annie... so proud... I missed you so much... I love...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Starships from the Trade Federation and the Commerce Guilds are taking deliveries of battle droids from the foundries on Geonosis.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAIL ORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's outrageous! The treaty forbids the Trade Federation from building up an army. What are they doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The droid foundry seems to be working at full capacity. I am going to go down and investigate. I will bring Jango Fett back home for interrogation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those Geonosian foundries are part of the Techno Union. We will call in their representatives and ask them a few very pointed questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One more thing. Jango mentioned he was recruited by someone named Darth Tyranus. Any idea who that might be?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the forename Darth, a Sith he must be.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our missing apprentice. They are playing their hand at last.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe he could be the mysterious Sido-Dyas, who made the deal for the clone army?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps too many pieces are missing from this puzzle, there are.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful, Obi-Wan. This investigation is becoming less than routine. Do you need help?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hologram of OBI-WAN fades off. PALPATINE stares at the spot where the hologram was in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>Let me see if I can figure out what's going on first.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAIL ORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Commerce Guilds are preparing for war... there can be no doubt of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Count Dooku must have made a treaty with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must stop them soon before they're fully ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR ASK AAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The debate is over, we need that clone army now!</utterance>
   <speaker>BAIL ORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mas Amedda, who had been silent up until now suddenly speaks up.</context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately, the debate is not over. The Senate will never be able to approve the use of that army before the separatists attack.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAS AMEDDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a crisis! If the Senate votes the Chancellor emergency powers, he could approve the use of the army in a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MACE WINDU and YODA look at one another.</context>
      <utterance>Please, please, I don't wish to have emergency powers. That's too extreme a solution. It's akin to a dictatorship. We must rely on the Jedi. Master Yoda, how many are available to go to Geonosis?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two Hundred,... less or more.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAIL ORGANA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With all due respect for the Jedi Order, two hundred will be no match for hundreds of thousands of battle droids.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patience. We should wait for Obi- Wan to report back. We don't know that Count Dooku has made a treaty with the Corporate Alliance, it's speculation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR ASK AAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we must prepare for the worst. I'm going to propose a motion granting emergency powers to the Chancellor at the next session. We must not wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of the question, Senator! You and I are too closely aligned. The issue will become partisan and debates will begin. The proposal must come from a neutral source.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAS AMEDDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JAR JAR steps forward from the back of the group.</context>
      <utterance>If only Senator Amidala were here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Supreme Chancellor... my august colleagues, I would be proud to propose the motion in question. This is a grave situation, and I'm sure Senator Amidala, and the Queen of Naboo would agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR ASK AAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Then PALPATINE sighs deeply.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Representative Binks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If called upon, I will serve. But it will be the saddest day of my life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME stands back. OWEN is with her. They look at THREEPIO. He isn't the golden figure we know because PADME has had to use whatever stuff she could findin the garage. He is multi-coloured in several textures, but he is complete.</context>
      <utterance>There!</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um. How do I look?</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great! You look perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THREEPIO drops his hand and bows formally.</context>
      <utterance>Perfect? Oh, Miss Padme, I'm so happy!  Oh, pardon me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He forgets formality and hugs her. PADME hugs him back, laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!</utterance>
   <speaker>OWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Padme, I think he should be yours from now on... I know that is what my Mom would want.</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then suddenly, from outside:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, my!</utterance>
   <speaker>BERU</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come topside, everybody! He's back! He's back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hologram cuts off. ANAKIN jumps up, agitated.</context>
      <utterance>...Alliance have pledged their armies to Count Dooku and are forming an... Wait!... ah... attack... I don't... make it... aaaggghhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going after him!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought the first thing he said was to retransmit his message to Coruscant.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you're right, you're right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That is your priority.</context>
      <utterance>We will deal with Count Dooku. The most important thing for you, Anakin, is to stay where you are. Protect the Senator at all costs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hologram switches off. PADME is looking at the readout on the ship's control panel.</context>
      <utterance>Understood, Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME starts to hit buttons and flick switches. ANAKIN puts a hand over hers, stopping her. She stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>They'll never get there in time to save him. They have to come half way across the galaxy. Look, Geonosis is less than a parsec away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he's still alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annie, are you just going to sit here and let him die?? He's your friend... your mentor...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...He's like my father, but you heard Master Windu. He gave me strict orders to stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME pulls her hand free and flicks more switches. The engines fire.</context>
      <utterance>He gave you strict orders to protect me...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN grins and takes the controls.</context>
      <utterance>...and I'm going to save Obi-Wan. So if you plan to protect me, you will have to come along.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All of the JEDI COUNCIL nod their approval.</context>
      <utterance>The longer we wait, the stronger Dooku's armies become. We cannot wait for the Senate to make up its mind about granting the Chancellor emergency powers, in order to be able to use that clone army... We have the authority to go now. We must go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agreed, Master Windu. Two hundred Jedi send. Enough, let's hope they are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MAS AMEDDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, the uproar dies.</context>
      <utterance>Order! Order!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amid the conflicting storm of CHEERS AND BOOS, JAR JAR, with TWO GUNGAN AIDES, floats on his pod to the middle of the vast space. He looks at PALPATINE nervously. PALPATINE nods. JAR JAR clears his throat.</context>
      <utterance>In the regrettable absence of Senator Amidala, the chair recognises Senior Representative of Naboo, Jar Jar Binks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter. Jeers. JAR JAR blushes.</context>
      <utterance>Senators, dellow felagates...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAS AMEDDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Comparative quiet. JAR JAR grips the edge of the podium.</context>
      <utterance>Order! The Senate will accord the Representative the courtesy of a hearing!</utterance>
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uproar. JAR JAR looks a little sheepish.</context>
      <utterance>In response to the direct threat to the Republic from the Confederacy of Independent Systems, I propose that the Senate gives immediate emergency powers to the Supreme Chancellor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who can deny these are exceptional times? Exceptional times demand exceptional measures! Exceptional measures demand exceptional men!</utterance>
   <speaker>ORN FREE TAA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SHOUTS of agreement.</context>
      <utterance>We won't support a dictator.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAR JAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brief silence, then a rolling wave of APPLAUSE. JAR JAR beams and bows. PALPATINE rises.</context>
      <utterance>That is the sentiment every one of us agrees with! And when the shadow of war has dispersed and the bright day of liberty has dawned once again, the power we now give to the Supreme Chancellor will be gladly, and swiftly returned. Out ancient liberties will be restored to us, burnished even more brightly than before!</utterance>
   <speaker>PALPATINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is with great reluctance that I have agreed to this calling. I love democracy... I love the Republic. The fact that this crisis is demanding I be given absolute power to tule over you is evident. But I am mild by nature and have no desire to destroy the democratic process. The power you give me I will lay down when this crisis has abated, I promise you. And all I ask in return is when my current term of office is over, you allow me to reture and live out my life in peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAS AMEDDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We shall proceed to the vote. All those in favor of granting emergency powers to the Supreme Chancellor, signal ate at this time... those opposed?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN gets up and goes over to her.</context>
      <utterance>To find Obi-Wan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her arm.</context>
      <utterance>No! You're not!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go of me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's too dangerous.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not letting you go out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my job to protect you. I said it's too dangerous. You're not going, and that's final!</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME storms out of the cockpit of the Naboo Starfighter. ANAKIN stands scratching his head, then follows. ARTOO BEEPS and WHISTLES.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you give me orders, Annie! I'm a Senator of the Galactic Republic. You have no authority to contain me, restrain me, or direct me! You remember your place, young man.  Now you can come along and protect me or stay here. It's up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARTOO WHISTLES a plaintive sigh.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it is, Artoo. Most confusing. One moment they're generating a pleasant mutual attraction and the next, waves of violent hostility. Even though I'm programmed to understand them, I doubt if I ever shall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWENTY WINGED GEONOSIANS carrying weapons alight on the flagstones in front of them. The GEONOSIANS part, and COUNT DOOKU appears. He bows courteously.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senator Amidala, I've heard so much about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Count Dooku, I assume.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm delighted to meet you at last. We have a great deal to discuss, Senator. I hope you can keep your young Jedi under control.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry he's housebroken.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are holding a Jedi Knight, Obi- Wan Kenobi. I am formally requesting you turn him over to me, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COUNT DOOKU smiles.</context>
      <utterance>He has been convicted of espionage, Senator, and will be executed. In just a few hours, I believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You can't do that.</context>
      <utterance>He is an officer of the Republic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN grabs his lightsaber but doesn't turn it on.</context>
      <utterance>We don't recognise the Republic here, Senator. But if Naboo were to join our Alliance, I could easily hear your plea for clemency.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I don't join your rebellion, I assume this Jedi with me will also die?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wish to make you to join our cause against your will, Senator, but you are a rational, honest representative of your people and I assume you want to do what's in their best interest. Aren't you fed up with the corruption, the bureaucrats, the hypocrisy of it all?.. Aren't you? Be honest, Senator.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ideals are still alive, Count, even if the institution is failing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You believe in the same ideals we believe in! The same ideals we are striving to make prominent.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If what you say is true, you should stay in the Republic and help Chancellor Palpatine put things right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Chancellor means well, M'Lady but he is incompetent. He has promised to cut the bureaucracy, but the bureaucrats are stronger than ever, no? Senator, the Republic cannot be fixed. It is time to start over. The democratic process in the Republic is a sham, a shell game played on the voters. It will not be long before the cult of greed, called the Republic, will lose even the pretext of democracy and freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I cannot believe that. I will not forsake all I have honoured and worked for and betray the Republic. I know of your treaties with the Trade Federation, the Commerce Guilds, and the others, Count. What is happening here is not government that has been bought out by business... it's business becoming government!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you willing to betray your Jedi friends? Without your co-operation I can do nothing to stop their execution.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is to happen to me? Am I to be executed also?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JANGO FETT moves over to ANAKIN.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't think of such an offence. But, there are individuals who have a strong interest in your demise, M'lady. It has nothing to do with politics, I'm afraid. It's purely personal, and they have already paid great sums to have you assassinated. I'm sure they will push hard to have you included in the executions. I'm sorry but if you are not going to co-operate, I must turn you over to the Geonosians for justice. I've done all I can for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANGO FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take that weapon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may cause a lot of bloodshed, my young Jedi, but you will not escape.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN hands his lightsaber over to JANGO FETT.</context>
      <utterance>Anakin...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SUN RIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have been charged and found guilty of Espionage.</utterance>
   <speaker>POGGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have anything to say before your sentence is carried out?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>POGGLE laughs. COUNT DOOKU simply smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You are committing an act of war, Archduke. I hope you are prepared for the consequences.</utterance>
   <speaker>POGGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We build weapons, Senator... that is our business! Of course we're prepared!</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTE GUNRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get on with it. Carry out the sentence. I want to see her suffer.</utterance>
   <speaker>POGGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FOUR GUARDS take hold of PADME and ANAKIN. They are escorted out of the chamber to the sounds of chuckling.</context>
      <utterance>Your other Jedi friend is waiting for you, Senator. Take them to the arena!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not afraid to die. I've been dying a little bit each day since you came back into my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That it would destroy our lives...</context>
      <utterance>You love me?! I thought we decided not to fall in love. That we would be forced to live a lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME leans toward ANAKIN. By straining hard, it is just possible for their lips to meet. They kiss.</context>
      <utterance>I think our lives are about to be destroyed anyway. My love for you is a puzzle, Annie, for which I have no answers. I can't control it... and now I don't care. I truly, deeply love you, and before we die I want you to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DRIVER cracks his whip over the ORRAY harnessed between the shafts. The cart jerks forward. Suddenly, there isa HUGE ROAR and blinding sunlight as they emerge into the arena</context>
      <utterance>I have no desire to be cured of this love either. Long or short, I vow to spend the rest of my life with you. They kiss again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was beginning to wonder if you had gotten my message.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I retransmitted it as you requested, Master. Then we decided to come and rescue you.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their arms are pulled high above their heads, and the cart drives away. There is another ROAR as POGGLE THE LESSER, COUNT DOOKU, NUTE GUNRAY, THE FETTS and DIGNITARIES arrive in the archducal box and take their places.</context>
      <utterance>It looks like you're going a good job so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUN RIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd ROARS and CHEERS. In the box, POGGLE THE LESSER rises. The crowd becomes quiet.</context>
      <utterance>The felons before you have been convicted of espionage against the Sovereign System of Geonosis. Their sentence of death is to be carried out in this public arena henceforth.</utterance>
   <speaker>POGGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd goes wild.</context>
      <utterance>Let the executions begin!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From different gates around the arena, THREE MONSTERS are driven in. One is a REEK (bull-like), one is a NEXU (lion-like), and one is an ACKLAY (a kind of dino-lobster). They are driven in by PICADORS carrying long spears and riding ORRAYS. The PICADORS poke the MONSTERS toward the center, then retire to the perimeter. The MONSTERS toss their heads, looking around, ROARING or SCREECHING. Then they catch sight of the THREE CAPTIVES and start moving toward them.</context>
      <utterance>I have a bad feeling about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take the one the left. I'll take the one on the right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADME has turned around and is pulling herself up by the chain to the top of the post. Within a moment, she is standing on top of it, trying to pull the chain free.</context>
      <utterance>What about Padme?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The REEK charges ANAKIN. He jumps up, and the beast hits the post hard. ANAKIN lands onto its back, wrapping part of his chain around its horn. The REEK backs off, shaking its head angrily, which tears the chain from the post OBI-WAN ducks around the post as the ACKLAY charges. It knocks the post flat, sending OBI-WAN sprawling. The ACKLAY crunches the post between its claws, freeing the chain. OBI-WAN leaps up and runs towards ONE of the PICADORS. The ACKLAY taks off after him. The NEXU arrives at PADME'S post and rears on its hind legs. One top, PADME struggles to tear the chain free. The NEXU ROARS, displaying wicked, dripping fangs. In the archducal box, NUTE GUNRAY beams and rubs his hands. In the arena, OBI-WAN runs at the PICADOR. The ORRAY rears up. OBI-WAN grabs the PICADOR'S long spear and pole vaults over him. The chasing ACKLAY smashes into the ORRAY. It goes down. The PICADOR tumbles onto the sand, where he is grabbed by the ACKLAY and crunched. ANAKIN's REEK starts to buck. It charges around the arena with ANAKIN hanging on for dear life. He whirls the free length of chain around his head and casts it into the REEK's mouth. Its jaws clamp hard on the chain. ANAKIN yanks hard on the chain, turning the REEK, beginning to ride it. The NEXU's claws dig deep into the post. The cat-like creature reaches the top of the post and takes a swipe at PADME. She turns and the claw barely catches her shirt ripping it off, leaving superficial claw marks across her back. She hits the creature with her chain and it backs off down the pole. Then, PADME jumps off the post into the air. She swings around on the chain and whacks the beast hard on the head with both her feet. It tumbles back onto the sand. In the archducal box:</context>
      <utterance>It looks like she's already on top of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTE GUNRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the arena, OBI-WAN runs out from behind the fallen ORRAY and throws the spear at the ACKLAY, hitting it in the neck. It lets out a terrible SCREECH and turns on him. The NEXU springs up and makes to leap up at PADME again. She finally manages to work the chain loose. ANAKIN comes charging up on the REEK.</context>
      <utterance>Foul!! She can't do that... shoot her or something!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure! Well, sort of.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The NEXU springs. PADME leaps from the top of the post to land on the REEK in front of ANAKIN. He hauls her upright. The REEK charges away, around the arena. The NEXU bounds after it. The REEK passes the wounded ACKLAY. The NEXU smells the blood and turns aside to attack the ACKLAY. The TWO MONSTERS fight. The crowd GROANS and BOOS. In the archducal box, NUTE GUNRAY turns angrily to COUNT DOOKU.</context>
      <utterance>Jump!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTE GUNRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COUNT DOOKU motions for the bounty hunter to ptay put. BOBA FETT is enjoying the spectacle.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't how it's supposed to be! Jango, finish her off.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN runs and jumps on the back of the REEK behind ANAKIN. Across the arena, the NEXU, having chewed up the ACKLAY, starts to advance toward them.</context>
      <utterance>Patiece, Viceroy... she will die. Maybe this is the way it's supposed to end.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ARTOO BEEPS and WHISTLES.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, it has been rather a long time. Do you suppose something's happened to them?</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Danger? Oh no, I shouldn't think so. It looks a very dull planet to me. They should be back shortly. Just stop worrying, Artoo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Master Windu, how pleasant of you to join us. You're just in time for the moment of truth. I would think these two new boys of yours could use a little more training.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MACE WINDU signals, and at stategic places around the arena there are sudden flashes of light as about ONE HUNDRED JEDI switch on their lightsabers. The crowd is suddenly silent. COUNT DOOKU'S lips curl in slight amusement.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry to disappoint you, Dooku. This party's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brave, but stupid, my old Jedi friend. You're impossibly outnumbered.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COUNT DOOKU looks around the great theater. His smile grows.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. One Jedi has to be worth a hundred Geonosians.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MACE WINDU draws his lightsaber, JANGO FETT draws his guns and fires at MACE WINDU, who deflects the shots. JANGO FETT and MACE WINDU jump into the arena, where they fight. BOBA FETT wacthes his Dad and the Jedi Master fight. The battle beginss. GEONOSIANS fly away everywhere. DROIDS fire at JEDI, who deflect the bolts and cult down the DROIDS. The GEONOSIAN TROOPS fire ray guns that are more difficult for the JEDI to deflect. The REEK and the NEXU are spooked by the battle. The REEK bucks the riders off its back and stampedes around the arena, trampling DROIDS and JEDI that have moved into its path. PADME picks up a discarded pistol and joins the fight. SEVERAL JEDI run to the center of the arena and toss lightsabers to OBI-WAN and ANAKIN. Among the crowd, JEDI cut down swaths of GEONOSIANS and DROIDS. On the sand, JEDI fight, attacking DROIDS. OBI0WAN and ANAKIN swing their lightsabers, cutting DROIDS in half. PADME blasts away at DROIDS and GEONOSIANS.</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't the Geonosians I was thinking about. How well do you think one Jedi will hold up against a thousand battle droids? COUNT DOOKU signals. THOUSANDS OF DROIDS start to pour into all parts of the arena.</utterance>
   <speaker>C-3PO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't hear anything.  You're scaring me! Stop imagining things!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone's got to - shut down - these droids.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry! It's being - taken care of!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PLO KOON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, there is a harsh BEEPING SOUND. All the DROIDS on the Starship and all the DROIDS in the arena start fighting again! KI-ADI-MUNDI stares in disbelief and dismay.</context>
      <utterance>We've done it! Now we have a chance!</utterance>
   <speaker>KI-ADI-MUNDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The system's off but they're still active. That's a new feature. They are independent of the control system.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Master Windu!</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have fought gallantly. Worthy of recognition in the history archives of the Jedi Order. Now it is finished.  Surrender - and your lives will be spared.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will not be hostages for you to barter with Dooku.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DROIDS raise their weapons. ANAKIN and PADME clasps hands tightly. COUNT DOOKU raises his hand to give the order to fire. PADME looks up suddenlt and whispers to ANAKIN.</context>
      <utterance>Then, I'm sorry, old friend. You will have to be destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PADME</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Above, six Gunships are descending fast through the open area in the arena ceiling. They land in a cluster around the handful of JEDI. CLONE TROOPERS spill out and start firing at the DROIDS. There is a hellstorm of laserfire that bounces off the laser shields created by the Gunships. YODA appears at the door of one of the Gunships.</context>
      <utterance>Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SURVIVING JEDI dash to the Gunships and scramble in. MACE WINDU hangs on tight as the Gunship, firing all its weapons, rises out of the arena up and over the topmost rim.</context>
      <utterance>Come on - hurry! Hurry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the other side of the Gunship, they see a Geonosian Speeder racing past. In the open cockpit is the unmistakable figure of COUNT DOOKU.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on! Look over there...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PILOT starts to comply, but... there is a HUGE BLASTS, the ship lurches on its side, and PADME tumbles out.</context>
      <utterance>It's Dooku, go after him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN stares down in horror as PADME hits thr ground below.</context>
      <utterance>Padme!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put the ship down! Down!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Forget her. We have to go after Dooku.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No we're not!! Land this ship!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Below, PADME hauls herself to her feet and waves for them to go after DOOKU.</context>
      <utterance>Don't let your personal feelings get in the way. We've got a job to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care!.. Go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN stares out to see PADME rescued by CLONE TROOPERS.</context>
      <utterance>Anakin! She's all right! Look.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the ground, PADME looks up at Gunship 2 as it speeds away after Count Dooku. OBI-WAN and ANAKIN follow the speeder to a Geonosian tower. The speeder decsends rapidly; the Gunship follows. Count Dooku's speeder parks outside the tower; the Gunship parks next to it. OBI-WAN and ANAKIN leap down and run inside the tower.</context>
      <utterance>Follow that speeder!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>DROID CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COUNT DOOKU turns as OBI-WAN and ANAKIN run in through the hanger doors. They draw their lightsabers. The DROIDS raise their weapons.</context>
      <utterance>Your Excellency!</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DROIDS lower their weapons and back off to the walls. COUNT DOOKU looks at OBI-WAN and ANAKIN with slight amusement.</context>
      <utterance>That won't be necessary, Captain. Stand down. And leave them to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We move in together - you slowly on the...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm taking him now!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anakin, no!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANAKIN charges across the open space at COUNT DOOKU, who smiles faintly, watching him come. ANAKIN raises his lightsaber. At the last moment, COUNT DOOKU thrusts out an arm, and ANAKIN is lifted up, hurled across the room, and slammed into the opposite wall. He slumps to the foot of the wall, semi-conscious. COUNT DOOKU moves toward OBI-WAN</context>
      <utterance>You'll pay for all the Jedi you've killed today, Dooku.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kenobi, isn't it? As you can see, my Jedi powers are far beyond yours. Now, back down.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN lifts his lightsaber. COUNT DOOKU smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COUNT DOOKU draws his lightsaber. He and OBI-WAN start to circle each other.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, but if I must.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have spent the last ten years learning to use the power of the Dark Side. It gives me infinitely greater power.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN comes in fast, swinging at COUNT DOOKU'S head. DOOKU parries the cut easily. As they fight, it quickly becomes clear that DOOKU is the complete swordsman - elegant, graceful, classical - a master of the old style.</context>
      <utterance>You will have to prove it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COUNT DOOKU parried another cut.</context>
      <utterance>Grand Master Kenobi, you disappoint me. Yoda holds you in such high esteem.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COUNT DOOKU thrusts. OBI-WAN steps back quickly, panting for breath.</context>
      <utterance>Surely you can do better...?  No, I'm surprised. Has Jedi swordsmanship degenerated so quickly, or are you trying to make fun of me?  Which is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN takes a deep breath, gets a fresh grip on his lightsaber and comes in again. For a moment, he drives COUNT DOOKU back. Then Dooku's superior skill begins to tell again, and he forces OBI-WAN to retreat. COUNT DOOKU increases the tempo of his attack. OBI-WAN is pushed to the limit to defend himself. DOOKU presses. His lightsaber flashes. OBI-WAN is wounded in the shoulder, then the thigh. He stumbles back against the wall, trips, and falls. His lightsaber goes skittering across the floor. COUNT DOOKU raises his lightsaber. OBI-WAN looks up helplessly. Dooku's lightsaber flashes down and CLASHES against - Anakin's lightsaber! COUNT DOOKU and ANAKIN stare eyeball to eyeball.</context>
      <utterance>come, come, Master Kenobi. Put me out of my misery.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's brave of you, boy - but foolish. I would have thought you'd have learnt your lesson.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And ANAKIN charges at COUNT DOOKU. The force of his attack catches the Count slightly off balance. Anakin's lightsaber flashes. COUNT DOOKU draws back, putting a hand to his arm. He takes the hand away and looks at the smear of blood whee Anakin has nicked him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a slow learner.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have unusual powers, young Padawan. But not enought to save you this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANAKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't bet on it!</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN uses the Force to catch his lightsaber and he tosses it to ANAKIN. With TWO LIGHTSABERS, ANAKIN attacks. COUNT DOOKU parries and ripostes. It is no contest. ANAKIN is driven back against the wall. He loses one lightsaber. Finally COUNT DOOKU, in one flashing move, sends Anakin's arm, cut at the elbow, flying still gripping his lightsaber. ANAKIN drops to the ground in agony. COUNT DOOKU draws himself up to deliver the coup de grace. Suddenly, the great doors slide open. The DROIDS turn fast, raising their weapons. Through the thick smoke, emerges the heroic figure of YODA. He stops on the smoke-filled threashold, FOUR DROIDS lined up on either side of him, guns pointed. Before the DROIDS can get off a shot, YODA raises his hand, and the DROIDS are flung against the far walls and crash to the floor in heaps of smoking metal. Silence. COUNT DOOKU steps away from ANAKIN to face the Jedi Grand Master. His lightsaber whirls in a formal salute.</context>
      <utterance>Anakin!</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>YODA draws a miniature lightsaber out of his cane. He salutes formally.</context>
      <utterance>Master Yoda. At last we shall know who is the most powerful.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COUNT DOOKU charges across the space at YODA. He rains down blows upon the tiny figure. YODA doesn't budge an inch. For the first part of the contest, he parries every cut and thrust that Dooku aims. Nothing the great swordsman tries gets through. His energy drains. His strokes become feebler, slower. YODA attacks! He flies forward. COUNT DOOKU is forced to retreat. Wprds are insufficient to describe the range and skill of Yoda's speed and swordplay. His lightsaber his a humming blur of light. Count Dooku's lightsaber is sent cartwheeling from his hand. He staggers back, gasping and spent, against the control panel. YODA jumps onto DOOKU'S shoulders, and is about to drive the lightsaber into the top of the Count's head.</context>
      <utterance>Count Dooku. No interest in contests, do I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The end for you, Count, this is.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COUNT DOOKU raises his arms and knocks YODA off his shoulders and then, with all his might, he uses the Force to pull on one of the cranes in the hanger. It comes crashing down on OBI-WAN and ANAKIN. But in the blink of and eye, YODA is under the crane, holding it up, using the Force. YODA closes his eyes and concentrates. ANAKIN is unconscious, and OBI0WAN tries toget out from under the crane. The fallen crane trembles and starts to life. Behind it, the sound of the Sail Ship's engines are heard starting up. YODA concentrates harder. Slowly, the crane rises. The SOUND OF THE ENGINES increases. YODA exerts every scrap of his powers. The crane lifts clear of ANAKIN and is thrown to the ground. DOOKU'S Sail Ship takes off. OBI-WAN and ANAKIN struggle to the exhausted YODA, but it's too late. The Sail Ship rises into the air and flies away. PADM‰ and a CLONE CAPTAIN with about TEN TROOPERS appear in the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>...Not yet...</utterance>
   <speaker>PADM‰</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PADM‰ runs too him and throws her arms around him. ANAKIN is barely able to stand up. The CLONE CAPTAIN marches up to YODA, stops, and salutes smartly.</context>
      <utterance>Anakin!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLONE CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>YODA looks at him and sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Resistance is at an end, General. What are your orders ?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Force is with us, my Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARTH SIDIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome home, Lord Tyranus. You have done well.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT DOOKU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The war has begun.</context>
      <utterance>I bring you good news, my Lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>DARTH SIDIOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent.  Everything is going as planned.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MACE WINDU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is your apprentice?</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are standing, looking out through the tall windows at the great plaza below. YODA sits in his chair.</context>
      <utterance>On his way back to Naboo. He is escorting Senator Amidala home.</utterance>
   <speaker>OBI-WAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must admit without the clones, it would not have been a victory.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OBI-WAN turns and looks at the sad little Jedi sitting in the Council Chamber. Apart from KI-ADI-MUNDI and PLO KOON, who is wounded, the Chamber is empty.</context>
      <utterance>Victory? Victory, you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not victory, a defeat, it was... Master Obi-Wan. Begun, the Clone War has!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
