<movie id="521" title="Star Wars The Empire Strikes Back">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE EMPIRE STRIKES BACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Written by</utterance>
   <speaker>THE EMPIRE STRIKES BACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lawrence Kasdan and Leigh Brackett</utterance>
   <speaker>THE EMPIRE STRIKES BACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From a story by George Lucas</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a little static a familiar voice is heard.</context>
      <utterance>Echo Three to Echo Seven. Han, old buddy, do you read me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loud and clear, kid. What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I finished my circle. I don't pick up any life readings.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There isn't enough life on this ice cube to fill a space cruiser. The sensors are placed, I'm going back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke clicks off his transmitter and reins back on his nervous lizard. He pats the beast on the head to calm it.</context>
      <utterance>Right. I'll see you shortly. There's a meteorite that hit the ground near here. I want to check it out. It won't take long.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke takes a small device from his belt and starts to adjust it when suddenly a large shadow falls over him from behind. He hears a monstrous howl and turns to see an eleven-foot-tall shape towering over him. It is a Wampa Ice Creature, lunging at him ferociously.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, steady girl. What's the matter? You smell something?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke grabs for his pistol, but is hit flat in the face by a huge white claw. He falls unconscious into the snow and in a moment the terrified screams of the Tauntaun are cut short by the horrible snap of a neck being broken. The Wampa Ice Creature grabs Luke by one ankle and drags him away across the frozen plain.</context>
      <utterance>Aaargh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Wookiee grumbles a reply.</context>
      <utterance>Chewie!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewbacca puts his mask back on and returns to his welding as Han leaves.</context>
      <utterance>All right, don't lose your temper. I'll come right back and give you a hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Solo?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sign of life out there, General. The sensors are in place. You'll know if anything comes around.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commander Skywalker reported in yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He's checking out a meteorite that hit near him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking a deep breath, Han blurts out what is on his mind.</context>
      <utterance>With all the meteor activity in this system, it's going to be difficult to spot approaching ships.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Princess Leia, standing at a console nearby, is dressed in a short white combat jacket and pants. Her hair is braided across her head in a Nordic fashion. She overhears their conversation and seems somewhat distressed.</context>
      <utterance>General, I've got to leave. I can't stay anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to hear that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's a price on my head. If I don't pay off Jabba the Hut, I'm a dead man.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A death mark's not an easy thing to live with. You're a good fighter, Solo. I hate to lose you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to Leia as Rieekan moves away.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, General.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Your Highness, I guess this is it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia is angry. Han sees she has no warmth to offer him. He shakes his head and adopts a sarcastic tone.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han walks away into the quiet corridor adjoining the command center. Leia stews a moment, then hurries after him.</context>
      <utterance>Well, don't get all mushy on me. So long, Princess.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han stops in the corridor and turns to face Leia.</context>
      <utterance>Han!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Your Highnessness?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you decided to stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the bounty hunter we ran into on Ord Mantell changed my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Han, we need you!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, what about you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need? I don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You probably don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what precisely am I supposed to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on! You want me to stay because of the way you feel about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're a natural leader...</context>
      <utterance>Yes. You're a great help to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia stares at him, understanding, then laughs.</context>
      <utterance>No! That's not it. Come on. Aahhh - uh huh! Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're imagining things.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I? Then why are you following me? Afraid I was going to leave without giving you a goodbye kiss?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd just as soon kiss a Wookiee.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angrily, Han strides down the corridor as Leia stares after him.</context>
      <utterance>I can arrange that. You could use a good kiss!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo beeps a stream of protesting whistles.</context>
      <utterance>Don't try to blame me. I didn't ask you to turn on the thermal heater. I merely commented that it was freezing in the princess' chamber. But it's supposed to be freezing. How are we going to dry out all her clothes? I really don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, switch off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie grumbles in irritation.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you take this apart now? I'm trying to get us out of here and you pull both of these.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put them back together right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Might I have a word with you, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's Princess Leia, sir. She's been trying to get you on the communicator.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I turned it off. I don't want to talk to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well, Princess Leia is wondering about Master Luke. He hasn't come back yet. She doesn't know where he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know where he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody knows where he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han glances at the fading light at the entrance of the ice cave as night slowly begins to fall on the planet.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, "nobody knows"?</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han jumps down off the lift, as Threepio follows him.</context>
      <utterance>Well, uh, you see...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deck Officer. Deck Officer!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han abruptly puts his hand over Threepio's mouth as the deck officer approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir. Might I inqu...</utterance>
   <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know where Commander Skywalker is?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't seen him. It's possible he came in through the south entrance.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's possible? Why don't you go find out? It's getting dark out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The deck officer leaves hurriedly, as Han takes his hand off Threepio's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir. Might I inquire what's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impossible man. Come along, Artoo, let's find Princess Leia. Between ourselves, I think Master Luke is in considerable danger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He might have forgotten to check in.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, Commander Skywalker hasn't come in through the south entrance.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not likely. Are the speeders ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet. We're having some trouble adapting them to the cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we'll have to go out on Tauntauns.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, the temperature's dropping too rapidly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. And my friends out in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han pushes through the troops and mounts a Tauntaun.</context>
      <utterance>I'll cover sector twelve. Have com-control set screen alpha.</utterance>
   <speaker>DECK OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Tauntaun'll freeze before you reach the first marker.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han maneuvers his mount out of the cave and races into the dark bitter night.</context>
      <utterance>Then I'll see you in hell!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo beeps, long and low.</context>
      <utterance>You must come along now, Artoo. There's really nothing more we can do. And my joints are freezing up.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Threepio turns to go back inside the main hangar as Artoo mournfully keeps his vigil.</context>
      <utterance>Don't say thing like that! Of course we'll see Master Luke again. He'll be quite all right, you'll see.  Stupid little short-circuit. He'll be quite all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, all the patrols are in. There's still no contact from Skywalker or Solo.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia nods an acknowledgment, but she is lost in thought.</context>
      <utterance>Mistress Leia, Artoo says he's been quite unable to pick up any signals, although he does admit that his own range is far too weak to abandon all hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>DERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to the lieutenant.</context>
      <utterance>Your Highness, there's nothing more we can do tonight. The shield doors must be closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close the doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lieutenant walks away. Chewie lets out a long, mournful howl, somewhat like a coyote. At the same moment, Artoo begins a complex series of efficient beeps.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia stands praying to herself as the huge metal doors slam across the entrance of the ice cave. The loud booms echo throughout the huge cavern. Chewie lets out another suffering howl.</context>
      <utterance>Artoo says the chances of survival are seven hundred seventy-five... to one.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, Artoo has been known to make mistakes... from time to time. Oh, dear, oh, dear. Don't worry about Master Luke. I'm sure he'll be all right. He's quite clever, you know... for a human being.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke... Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will go to the Dagobah system.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dagobah system?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The image of Ben fades, revealing a lone Tauntaun rider approaching from the windswept horizon.</context>
      <utterance>There you will learn from Yoda, the Jedi Master who instructed me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han pulls up and leaps off his mount. He hurries to his snow-covered friend, cradling him in his arms. Han's Tauntaun lets out a low, pitiful bellow. But Han's concern is with Luke, and he shakes him urgently.</context>
      <utterance>Ben... Ben. Luke drops into unconsciousness.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke doesn't respond. Han begins frantically rubbing and slapping Luke's unconscious face. As he starts to lift the youth, Han hears a rasping sound behind him. He turns, just in time to see his Tauntaun stagger and then fall over into the snow. Han carries Luke to the moaning beast. Then, with a final groan, the Tauntaun expires.</context>
      <utterance>Luke! Luke! Don't do this, Luke. Come on, give me a sign here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes Luke's inert form against the belly of the dead beast.</context>
      <utterance>Not much time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben... Ben...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang on, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han ignites Luke's saber and cuts the beast from head to toe. He quickly tosses it's steaming innards into the snow, then lifts Luke's inert form and stuffs him inside the carcass.</context>
      <utterance>Dagobah system...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whew...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dagobah...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This may smell bad, kid...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yoda...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wind has picked up considerably, making it difficult to move. Han removes a pack from the dead creature's back, taking out a shelter container. He begins to set up what can only be a pitiful protection against a bitter Hoth night.</context>
      <utterance>...but it will keep you warm... til I get the shelter built.  Ooh... I thought they smelled bad on the outside!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZEV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a sharp crackle of static, then a faint voice.</context>
      <utterance>This is Rogue Two. this is Rogue Two. Captain Solo, so you copy? Commander Skywalker, do you copy? This is Rogue Two.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning. Nice of you guys to drop by.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZEV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Echo Base... this is Rogue Two. I found them. Repeat, I found them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo beeps his good wishes.</context>
      <utterance>Master Luke, sir, it's so good to see you fully functional again.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han and Chewie make their entrance. The Wookiee growls a greeting.</context>
      <utterance>Artoo expresses his relief, also.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you feeling, kid? You don't look so bad to me. In fact, you look strong enough to pull the ears off a Gundark.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han turns as Leia enters the room. He looks at her with a big, devilish grin.</context>
      <utterance>That's two you owe me, junior.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well your Worship, looks like you managed to keep me around for a little while longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had nothing to do with it. General Rieekan thinks it's dangerous for any ships to leave the system until we've activated the energy shield.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a good story. I think you just can't bear to let a gorgeous guy like me out of your sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie is amused; he laughs in his manner. Han, enjoying himself, regards Chewie good-humoredly.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know where you get your delusions, laser brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke sparks to this; he looks at Leia.</context>
      <utterance>Laugh it up, fuzzball. But you didn't see us alone in the south passage.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia is flushed, eyes darting between Luke and Han.</context>
      <utterance>She expressed her true feelings for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My...! Why, you stuck up,... half- witted... scruffy-looking ...nerf- herder!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia looks vulnerable for a moment, then the mask falls again, and she focuses on Luke.</context>
      <utterance>Who's scruffy-looking?  I must have hit pretty close to the mark to get her all riled up like that, huh, kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that she leans over and kisses Luke on the lips. Then she turns on her heel and walks out, leaving everyone in the room slightly dumbstruck. With some smugness, Luke puts his hands behind his head and grins. Suddenly, in the distance, the muffled sound of an alarm is heard.</context>
      <utterance>Why, I guess you don't know everything about women yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voice repeats the order and Han, Chewie, Artoo, and Threepio hurry out of the room, bidding farewell to Luke.</context>
      <utterance>Headquarters personnel, report to command center.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse us, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group hurries over to Rieekan.</context>
      <utterance>Princess... we have a visitor.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've picked up something outside the base in zone twelve, moving east.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR CONTROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's metal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it couldn't be one of those creatures that attacked Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could be a speeder, one of ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR CONTROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Threepio steps up to the control panel and listens intently to the strange signal.</context>
      <utterance>No. Wait - there's something very weak coming through.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The transmission ends in static.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I am fluent in six million forms of communication. This signal is not used by the Alliance. It could be an Imperial code.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't friendly, whatever it is. Come on, Chewie, let's check it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Send Rogues Ten and Eleven to station three-eight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Afraid there's not much left.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Droid of some kind. I didn't hit it that hard. It must have had a self-destruct.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An Imperial probe droid.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a good bet the Empire knows we're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd better start the evacuation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Admiral.</utterance>
   <speaker>OZZEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Captain</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we've got something, sir. The report is only a fragment from a probe droid in the Hoth system, but it's the best lead we've had.</utterance>
   <speaker>OZZEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have thousands of probe droids searching the galaxy. I want proof, not leads!</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The visuals indicate life readings.</utterance>
   <speaker>OZZEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could mean anything. If we followed every lead...</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vader moves to a large screen showing an image of the Rebel snow base. Rebel speeders can be seen approaching the base in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>But, sir, the Hoth system is supposed to be devoid of human forms.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You found something?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it. The Rebels are there.</utterance>
   <speaker>OZZEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My lord, there are so many uncharted settlements. It could be smugglers, it could be...</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is the system. And I'm sure Skywalker is with them. Set your course for the Hoth system. General Veers, prepare you men.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REBEL CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Groups seven and ten will stay behind to fly the speeders. As soon as each transport is loaded, evacuation control will give clearance for immediate launch.</utterance>
   <speaker>REBEL FIGHTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MEDICAL DROID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, it will take quite a while to evacuate the T-forty- sevens.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, forget the heavy equipment. There's plenty of time to get the smaller modules on the transports.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEDICAL DROID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take care, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Luke pats Chewie on the arm, Chewie puts his arms around Luke and gives him a tight hug. Han is discussing the lifter with a repair droid when he sees Luke.</context>
      <utterance>Chewie, take care of yourself, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, kid.  There's got to be a reason for it. Check it at the other end. Wait a second.  You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke smiles, then waves at his friend and walks on. After a few steps, he stops and looks back. Han glances up and the two exchange a silent communication, each wishing the other safety, happiness - many things, all difficult to verbalize.</context>
      <utterance>You, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CONTROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General, there's a fleet of Star Destroyers coming out of hyperspace in sector four.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rieekan exits hurriedly.</context>
      <utterance>Reroute all power to the energy shield. We've got to hold them till all transports are away. Prepare for ground assault.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, General?</utterance>
   <speaker>VEERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My lord, the fleet has moves out of light-speed. Com-Scan has detected an energy field protecting an area around the sixth planet of the Hoth system. The field is strong enough to deflect any bombardment.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Rebels are alerted to our presence. Admiral Ozzel came out of light-speed too close to the system.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He felt surprise was wiser...</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is as clumsy as he is stupid. General, prepare your troops for a surface attack.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Veers turns smartly and leaves as Vader activates a large viewscreen showing the bridge of his mighty ship. Admiral Ozzel appears on the viewscreen, standing slightly in front of Captain Piett.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>OZZEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord Vader, the fleet has moved out of light-speed, and we're preparing to... Aaagh!</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Piett steps forward, as the admiral moves away, slightly confused, touching his throat as it begins to constrict painfully.</context>
      <utterance>You have failed me for the last time, Admiral. Captain Piett.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make ready to land out troops beyond the energy shield and deploy the fleet so that nothing gets off that system. You are in command now, Admiral Piett.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Piett's pleasure about his unexpected promotion is not an unmixed emotion. He glances warily at the struggling Admiral Ozzel who, with a final choke, stumbles and falls in a lifeless heap before him.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Lord Vader.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All troop carriers will assemble at the north entrance. The heavy transport ships will leave as soon as they're loaded. Only two fighter escorts per ship. The energy shield can only be opened for a short time, so you'll have to stay very close to your transports.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two fighters against a Star Destroyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ion cannon will fire several shots to make sure that any enemy ships will be out of your flight path. When you've gotten past the energy shield, proceed directly to the rendezvous point. Understood?</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>DERLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pilots hurry away.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Everyone to your stations. Let's go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CONTROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, Rebel ships are coming into our sector.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Our first catch of the day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone cheers at the announcement, which echoes through the hangar. Luke turns and walks on, heading toward his snowspeeder. His gunner, Dack, a fresh-faced, eager kid, is glad to see him. They climb in.</context>
      <utterance>The first transport is away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feeling all right, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like new, Dack. How about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now I feel like I could take on the whole Empire myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what you mean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRENCH OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have spotted Imperial walkers!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONTROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imperial walkers on the north ridge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, boys, keep tight now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke, I have no approach vector. I'm not set.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steady, Dack. Attack pattern delta. Go now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns his speeder and heads directly at one of the walkers, flying toward its towering legs. The horizon twists as the speeder banks between the legs.</context>
      <utterance>All right, I'm coming in.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hobbie, you still with me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the horizon, another walker moves up past Luke's cockpit window, twisting out of sight as Luke banks and starts another run.</context>
      <utterance>That armor's too strong for blasters.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dack is at the gunner's controls.</context>
      <utterance>Rogue Group, use your harpoons and tow cables. Go for the legs. It might be our only chance of stopping them.  All right, stand by, Dack.</utterance>
   <speaker>DACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke, we've got a malfunction in fire control. I'll have to cut in the auxiliary.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barely keeping his seat in the tumbling ship, Dack struggles to set up his harpoon gun. Luke swings his speeder around and heads toward an oncoming walker. Laser bolts and flak fill the air, creating a deadly obstacle course for the tiny craft.</context>
      <utterance>Just hang on. Hang on, Dack. Get ready to fire that tow cable.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Copy, Rogue Leader</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wedge, I've lost my gunner. You'll have to make this shot. I'll cover for you. Set your harpoon. Follow me on the next pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming around, Rogue Leader.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One more pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming around. Once more.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JANSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wedge swings the speeder between the legs of the giant walker.</context>
      <utterance>Once more.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cable out! Let her go!</utterance>
   <speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Detach cable.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think we can protect two transports at a time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's risky, but we can't hold out much longer. We have no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIEEKAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Launch patrols.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evacuate remaining ground staff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In another area of the hangar, Threepio watches as Artoo is raised up into Luke's X-wing fighter.</context>
      <utterance>No, no! No! This one goes there, that one goes there. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Artoo, you take good care of Master Luke now, understand? And ... do take good care of yourself. Oh, dear, oh, dear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZEV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Set for position three.  Steady.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay tight and low.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia nods. She is surprised to see him.</context>
      <utterance>You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you still here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard the command center had been hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got your clearance to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I'll leave. First I'm going to get you to your ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Highness, we must take this last transport. It's our only hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A blast rocks the command center, throwing Threepio backward into Han's arms.</context>
      <utterance>Send all troops in sector twelve to the south slope to protect the fighters.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imperial troops have entered the base.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on... that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia looks exhausted. Han grabs her and starts to lead her out. As Han, Leia, and Threepio run out of the command center, the code signal can be heard echoing off the corridor walls.</context>
      <utterance>Give the evacuation code signal. And get to your transports!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD CONTROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>K-one-zero... all troops disengage.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! Wait for me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Begin retreat!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Troops flee from the battle, the ground exploding around them.</context>
      <utterance>Fall back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VEERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Distance to power generators?</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Veers reaches for the electrorangefinder and lines up the main generator.</context>
      <utterance>One-seven, decimal two-eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>VEERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Target. Maximum fire power.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han and Leia turn and race down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Transport, this is Solo. Better take off - I can't get to you. I'll get the princess out on the Falcon.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... but... but... where are you going? Uh... come back!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door to the hangar closes in his face.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! Wait for me! Wait! Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quickly, the door reopens as Han reaches out and pulls the golden droid through.</context>
      <utterance>How typical.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up, goldenrod, or you're going to be a permanent resident!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! Wait!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Wookiee barks a negative reply.</context>
      <utterance>How's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would it helped if I got out and pushed?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Threepio clanks into the hold.</context>
      <utterance>It might.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han gives the gold robot a devastating look.</context>
      <utterance>Captain Solo, Captain Solo... sir, might I suggest that you...</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can wait.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This bucket of bolts is never going to get us past that blockade.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han and Leia look out the cockpit window and see a squad of stormtroopers rushing into the far side of the hangar. Quickly, Han straps himself into the pilot's seat and Leia into the navigator's chair.</context>
      <utterance>This baby's got a few surprises left in her, sweetheart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A laser hits the window near Chewie as he is settling into his chair. Letting out a loud whelp, Chewie quickly pulls back on the controls and the first stage of engine fire can be heard. Han flashes a big grin at Leia.</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Come on! Switch over. Let's hope we don't have a burnout.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han looks at Chewie.</context>
      <utterance>Someday you're going to be wrong, and I hope I'm there to see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The roar of the Falcon's main engines blasts out everything as the ice- cave wall rushes by outside the cockpit window.</context>
      <utterance>Punch it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From his ship, Luke sees Wedge in his own X-wing, preparing for takeoff.</context>
      <utterance>Artoo! Get her ready for takeoff.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke smiles and nods at Wedge, then lowers himself into the cockpit of his X-wing while Artoo waits in the cubbyhole, beeping impatiently.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck, Luke. See you at the rendezvous.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The canopy over the X-wing lowers and snaps shut.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Artoo. We're going, we're going.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo beeps once again.</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing wrong, Artoo. I'm just setting a new course.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo utters a soft, carefully phrased steam of whistles.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Artoo?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little droid lets out a defeated whimper. Luke smiles, and continues on his course.</context>
      <utterance>That's all right. I'd like to keep it on manual control for a while.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw them! I saw them!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saw what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Threepio bumps and bangs his way into the cockpit.</context>
      <utterance>Star Destroyers, two of them, coming right at us.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, sir! Might I suggest...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie barks a reply as he readjusts an overhead switch.</context>
      <utterance>Shut him up or shut him down!  Check the deflector shield!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, great. Well, we can still outmaneuver them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prepare to make the jump to light- speed.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The buffeting of lasers becomes louder and stronger.</context>
      <utterance>But, sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're getting closer!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Expectantly, they look out the cockpit window as stars do not go into hyperspace, but just sit there. Han and Chewie look at each other and are thrown into an acute state of concern.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? Watch this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han tries again. Still nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Watch what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we're in trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I may say so, sir, I noticed earlier that the hyperdrive motivator has been damaged. It's impossible to go to light-speed!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The explosions become heavier.</context>
      <utterance>We're in trouble!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie hurries over to the pit and places the tools on the edge.</context>
      <utterance>Horizontal boosters...!  Alluvial dampers...! Well that's not it.  Bring me the hydrospanners!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a loud thump hits the side of the Falcon, causing it to lurch radically. Chewie barks. The tools fall into the pit on top of Han.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know how we're going to get out of this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More turbulence rocks the ship.</context>
      <utterance>Oww! Chewie!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was no laser blast! Something hit us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Han, get up here!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han climbs out of the hold like a shot. Both he and Chewie run out of the hold and toward the cockpit.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Chewie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han changes places with Leia who has been at the controls, and Chewie gets into his chair. Han works his controls as a chunk of rock crosses in front of the ship.</context>
      <utterance>Asteroids!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no! Chewie, set two-seven- one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? You're not actually going into an asteroid field?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another asteroid thumps against the ship and Leia winces at the jolt.</context>
      <utterance>They'd be crazy to follow us, wouldn't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to do this to impress me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, the possibility of successfully navigating an asteroid field is approximately three thousand, seven hundred and twenty to one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never tell me the odds!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you wanted to be around when I made a mistake; well, this could be it, sweetheart.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group watches as more asteroids race by outside the window.</context>
      <utterance>I take it back. We're going to get pulverized if we stay out here much longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to argue with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pulverized?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going in closer to one of those big ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Closer?</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewbacca barks the same word, only louder.</context>
      <utterance>Closer?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han notices something on his main scope and nudges his faithful Wookiee, pointing.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is suicide!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There. That looks pretty good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What looks pretty good?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That'll do nicely.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out the cockpit window, they see that they are skimming the surface of the enormous asteroid and nearing a large crater.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, ma'am, but where are we going?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you know what you're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, me too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo beeps a hopeful inquiry.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, that's it. Dagobah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo beeps, this time a slightly worried question.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not going to change my mind about this.  I'm not picking up any cities or technology. Massive life-form readings, though. There's something alive down there...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm sure it's perfectly safe for droids.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo lets out a short beep. As Luke moves along the nose, Artoo loses his balance and disappears with a splash into the boggy lake.</context>
      <utterance>No, Artoo, you stay put. I'll have a look around.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke kneels and leans over the plane looking for Artoo, but the water is still and reveals no sign of the little droid.</context>
      <utterance>Artoo?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A small periscope breaks the surface of the water and a gurgly beep is heard. The periscope starts to move to shore. Relieved, Luke starts running along the nose of the fighter to its tip.</context>
      <utterance>Artoo! Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The outline of the shore is now more than ten feet away. Luke jumps off the plane into the water, scrambles up to the shore, and turns to look for Artoo. The periscope still steadily moves toward shore.</context>
      <utterance>Artoo! You be more careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, through the thick fog layer, a dark shape appears, moving toward the little droid. The dark, sinuous bog beast dives beneath the swampy water, making a loud clunk against Artoo's metal hull. The droid disappears from sight, uttering a pathetic electronic scream. Holding his ignited lightsaber before him, Luke wades a few feet into the murky pool, looking for any sign of his little friend.</context>
      <utterance>Artoo - that way!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The black surface is still as death itself... until a few bubbles begin to appear. Then, phheewaat!! The runt-size robot is spit out of the water, makes a graceful arc, and comes crashing down into a patch of soft gray moss.</context>
      <utterance>Artoo!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke helps Artoo to his feet and begins wiping the mud and roots from his round metal body. Artoo responds with feeble, soggy beeps.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no! Are you all right? Come on. You're lucky you don't taste very good. Anything broken?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Luke glances around at the spooky swamp jungle that surrounds him, Artoo ejects a stream of muddy water from one of his cranial ports.</context>
      <utterance>If you're saying coming here was a bad idea, I'm beginning to agree with you. Oh, Artoo, what are we doing here? It's like... something out of a dream, or, I don't know. Maybe I'm just going crazy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Admiral?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our ships have sighted the Millennium Falcon, lord. But... it has entered an asteroid field and we cannot risk...</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Asteroids do not concern me, Admiral. I want that ship and not excuses.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, lord.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to shut down everything but the emergency power systems.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I'm almost afraid to ask, but... does that include shutting me down, too? Chewie barks "yes". But Han thinks otherwise.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the ship lurches, causing all the loose items in the cockpit to go flying. Chewie howls.</context>
      <utterance>No, I need you to talk to the Falcon, find out what's wrong with the hyperdrive.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, it's quite possible this asteroid is not entirely stable.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not entirely stable? I'm glad you're here to tell us these things. Chewie, take the professor in the back and plug him into the hyperdrive.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sliding door closes behind the indignant Threepio as Chewie and he move back to the hold. Suddenly, the ship lurches again, throwing Leia across the cabin into Han's arms. Then, abruptly, the motion stops as suddenly as it started. With some surprise, Han and Leia realize they are in each other's arms.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! Sometimes I just don't understand human behavior. After all, I'm only trying to do my job in the most...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let go.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sshh!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia flushes, averting her eyes. She's not exactly fighting to get free. But, of course, Han blows it...</context>
      <utterance>Let go, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The anger rises in Leia.</context>
      <utterance>Don't get excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, being held by you isn't quite enough to get me excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han grins quickly wickedly at Leia as he turns and exits through the door. Leia's confused emotions show clearly on her lovely face.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sweetheart. We haven't got time for anything else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The droid whistles his appreciation. Luke then opens a container of processed food and sits before the thermal heater.</context>
      <utterance>Ready for some power? Okay. Let's see now. Put that in there. There you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nervously, he looks around at the foreboding jungle.</context>
      <utterance>Now all I have to do is find this Yoda... if he even exists.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still... there's something familiar about this place. I feel like... I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke jumps out of his skin. Artoo screeches in terror. The young warrior grabs for his lightsaber as he spins around, looking for the speaker. Mysteriously standing right in front of Luke is a strange, bluish creature, not more than two feet tall. The wizened little thing is dressed in rags. It motions toward Luke's sword.</context>
      <utterance>Feel like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like we're being watched!</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After some hesitation, Luke puts away his weapon, although he really doesn't understand why. Artoo watches with interest.</context>
      <utterance>Away with your weapon! I mean you no harm.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am wondering, why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little creature laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Looking? Found someone, you have, I would say, hmmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help you I can. Yes, mmmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. I'm looking for a great warrior.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With the aid of a walking stick, the tiny stranger moves over to one of the cases of supplies. He begins to rummage around. Artoo moves to the edge of the case - standing almost eye level to the creature who is carelessly handling the supplies - and squeaks his disapproval. Their tiny visitor pick up the container of food Luke was eating from and takes a bite.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh! A great warrior.  Wars not make one great.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The creature spits out the bite he has taken. He makes a face.</context>
      <utterance>Put that down. Hey! That's my dinner!</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flips the container in Luke's direction and reaches into one of Luke's supply cases.</context>
      <utterance>How you get so big, eating food of this kind?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, friend, we didn't mean to land in that puddle, and if we could get our ship out, we would, but we can't, so why don't you just...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you could have broken this. Don't do that. Ohhh... you're making a mess. Hey, give me that!</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clutching its treasure, the creature backs away from Luke, drawing closer to Artoo. As Luke and the creature argue, one of Artoo's little arms slowly moves out toward the power lamp, completely unnoticed by the creature.</context>
      <utterance>Mine! Or I will help you not.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want your help. I want my lamp back. I'll need it to get out of this slimy mudhole.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo grabs hold of the lamp and the two little figures are immediately engaged in a tug-of-war over it. Artoo beeps a few angry, "Give me thats."</context>
      <utterance>Mudhole? Slimy? My home this is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, ah, ah!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Artoo, let him have it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine! Mine!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Artoo!</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The creature lets go with one hand and pokes Artoo lightly with one finger. Artoo reacts with a startled squeal, and lets go.</context>
      <utterance>Mine!</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now will you move along, little fella? We're got a lot of work to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! No, no! Stay and help you, I will.  Find your friend, hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not looking for a friend. I'm looking for a Jedi Master.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oohhh. Jedi Master. Yoda. You seek Yoda.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, the creature scurries out of the clearing, laughing merrily. Luke stares after him. All he sees is the faint light from the small power lamp moving through the fog. Luke makes his decision and starts after the creature.</context>
      <utterance>Mmm. Take you to him, I will.  Yes, yes. But now, we must eat. Come. Good food. Come.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo, very upset, whistles a blue streak of protest.</context>
      <utterance>Come, come.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo beeps even more frantically. But as Luke disappears from view, the worried little droid grows quieter, and utters a soft electronic sigh.</context>
      <utterance>Stay here and watch after the camp, Artoo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han enters the hold area and kneels on the floor near the control box.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, where is Artoo when I need him?</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I don't know where your ship learned to communicate, but it has the most peculiar dialect. I believe, sir, it says that the power coupling on the negative axis has been polarized. I'm afraid you'll have to replace it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands a wire coil up to Chewie who is working near the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Well, of course I'll have to replace it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie brings his head back through the trap door in the ceiling and whines. Han glances back at Threepio, then speaks quietly to Chewie so only he can hear.</context>
      <utterance>Here! And Chewie...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Your Worship, I'm only trying to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han hears a new tone in her voice. He watches her pull on the lever.</context>
      <utterance>Would you please stop calling me that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, Leia.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you make it so difficult sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lets go of the lever and rubs her sore hand.</context>
      <utterance>I do, I really do. You could be a little nicer, though.  Come on, admit it. Sometimes you think I'm all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Occasionally...  ... when you aren't acting like a scoundrel.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, Han takes her hand and starts to massage it.</context>
      <utterance>Scoundrel? Scoundrel? I like the sound of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia is flushes, confused.</context>
      <utterance>Stop what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop that! My hands are dirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My hands are dirty, too. What are you afraid of?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han looks at her with a piercing look. He's never looked more handsome, more dashing, more confident. He reaches out slowly and takes Leia's hand again from where it is resting on a console. He draws it toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Afraid?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're trembling.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then with an irresistible combination of physical strength and emotional power, the space pirate begins to draw Leia toward him... very slowly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not trembling.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia is now very close to Han and as she speaks, her voice becomes an excited whisper, a tone completely in opposition to her words.</context>
      <utterance>You like me because I'm a scoundrel. There aren't enough scoundrels in your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I happen to like nice men.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a nice man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her now, with slow, hot lips. He takes his time, as though he had forever, bending her body backward. She has never been kissed like this before, and it almost makes her faint. When he stops, she regains her breath and tries to work up some indignation, but finds it hard to talk. Suddenly, Threepio appears in the doorway, speaking excitedly.</context>
      <utterance>No, you're not. You're...</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han turns slowly, icily, from their embrace.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, sir! I've isolated the reverse power flux coupling.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moment spoiled, Han marches out after Threepio.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you're perfectly welcome, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NEEDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and that, Lord Vader, was the last time they appeared in any of our scopes. Considering the amount of damage we've sustained, they must have been destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Imperial star captains fade out one by one as Vader turns to Admiral Piett.</context>
      <utterance>No, Captain, they're alive. I want every ship available to sweep the asteroid field until they are found.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord Vader.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The admiral is scared, his face white as a sheet.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Admiral, what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Emperor commands you make contact with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Move the ship out of the asteroid field so that we can send a clear transmission.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, my lord.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is thy bidding, my master?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is a great disturbance in the Force.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have felt it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a new enemy - Luke Skywalker.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, my master.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He could destroy us.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just a boy. Obi-Wan can no longer help him.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Force is strong with him. The son of Skywalker must not become a Jedi.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he could be turned, he would become a powerful ally.</utterance>
   <speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes. He would be a great asset. Can it be done?</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vader kneels. The supreme Emperor passes a hand over the crouched Lord of the Sith and fades away.</context>
      <utterance>He will join us or die, my master.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm sure it's delicious. I just don't understand why we can't see Yoda now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moving with some difficulty in the cramped quarters, Luke sits down near the fire and serves himself from the pot. Tasting the unfamiliar concoction, he is pleasantly surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Patience! For the Jedi it is time to eat as well. Eat, eat. Hot. Good food, hm? Good, hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far away is Yoda? Will it take us long to get there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not far. Yoda not far. Patience. Soon you will be with him.  Rootleaf, I cook. Why wish you become Jedi? Hm?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mostly because of my father, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREATURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, your father. Powerful Jedi was he, powerful Jedi, mmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The creature turns away from Luke and speaks to a third party.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on. How could you know my father? You don't even know who I am.  Oh, I don't know what I'm doing here. We're wasting our time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He will learn patience.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm. Much anger in him, like his father.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was I any different when you taught me?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hah. He is not ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trying to see Ben, Luke starts to get up but hits his head on the low ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Yoda! I am ready. I... Ben! I can be a Jedi. Ben, tell him I'm ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke looks down. He knows it is true.</context>
      <utterance>Ready, are you? What know you of ready? For eight hundred years have I trained Jedi. My own counsel will I keep on who is to be trained! A Jedi must have the deepest commitment, the most serious mind.  This one a long time have I watched. All his life has he looked away... to the future, to the horizon. Never his mind on where he was. Hmm? What he was doing. Hmph. Adventure. Heh! Excitement. Heh! A Jedi craves not these things.  You are reckless!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So was I, if you'll remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke thinks he detects a subtle softening in Yoda's voice.</context>
      <utterance>He is too old. Yes, too old to begin the training.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yoda turns his piercing gaze on Luke, as though the Jedi Master's huge eyes could somehow determine how much the boy had learned. After a long moment, the little Jedi turns toward where he alone sees Ben.</context>
      <utterance>But I've learned so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will he finished what he begins?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't fail you - I'm not afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you will be. You will be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, if I may venture an opinion...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia rushes into the cabin just as Han drops the final floor panel into place.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not really interested in your opinion, Threepio.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she speaks, there comes a sharp banging on the hull. Chewie looks up and barks anxiously.</context>
      <utterance>Outside, in the cave.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There it is. Listen! Listen!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Chewie grab their breath masks off a rack and hurry out. Leia follows.</context>
      <utterance>I just got this bucket back together. I'm not going to let something tear it apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I'm going with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it might be better if I stay here and guard the ship.  Oh, no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han kneels and studies the ground, then attempts to study the outline of the cave.</context>
      <utterance>This ground sure feels strange. It doesn't feel like rock at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's an awful lot of moisture in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I have a bad feeling about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie barks through his face mask, and points toward the ship's cockpit. A five-foot-long shape can be seen moving across the top of the Falcon. The leathery creature lets out a screech as Han blasts it with a laser bolt.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The black shape tumbles off the spaceship and onto the ground in front of the princess. Han bends down to investigate the dead creature.</context>
      <utterance>Watch out!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's what I thought. Mynock. Chewie, check the rest of the ship, make sure there aren't any more attached. They're chewing on the power cables.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mynocks?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, a swarm of the ugly creatures swoops through the air. Leia puts her arms over her head to protect herself as she runs toward the ship. Chewie shoos another Mynock away with his blaster. Several of the batlike creatures flap their wings loudly against the cockpit window of the Falcon. Inside, Threepio shudders at their presence.</context>
      <utterance>Go on inside. We'll clean them off if there are any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han looks around the strange, dripping cave.</context>
      <utterance>Ohhh! Go away! Go away! Beastly little thing. Shoo! Shoo!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He unholsters his blaster and fires at the far side of the huge cave. The cavern begins to shake and the ground starts to buckle. Chewie barks and moves for the ship, followed closely by Leia and Han. The large wings of the Mynocks flap past them as they protect their faces and run up the platform.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Wookiee heads for the cockpit as Han, followed by Threepio, rushes to the hold area and checks the scopes on the control panel. Leia hurries after.</context>
      <utterance>All right, Chewie, let's get out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han rushes past her and heads for the cockpit.</context>
      <utterance>The Empire is still out there. I don't think it's wise to...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that he is gone. The main engines of the Falcon begin to whine. Leia races after him, bouncing around in the shaking ship.</context>
      <utterance>No time to discuss this in committee.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not a committee!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't make the jump to light- speed in this asteroid field...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the ship begins to move forward, Chewie barks. He notices something out the window ahead. Threepio sees it too.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down, sweetheart. We're taking off!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a row of jagged white stalagmites and stalactites can be seen surrounding the entrance. And as the Falcon moves forward, the entrance to the cave grows ever smaller. Han pulls hard on the throttle, sending his ship surging forward.</context>
      <utterance>I see it, I see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're doomed!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cave is collapsing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is no cave.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia's mouth drops open . She sees that the rocks of the cave entrance are not rocks at all, but giant teeth, quickly closing around the tiny ship. Chewie howls.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run! Yes. A Jedi's strength flows from the Force. But beware of the dark side. Anger... fear... aggression. The dark side of the Force are they. Easily they flow, quick to join you in a fight. If once you start down the dark path, forever will it dominate your destiny, consume you it will, as it did Obi-Wan's apprentice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vader. Is the dark side stronger?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... no... no. Quicker, easier, more seductive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how am I to know the good side from the bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will know. When you are calm, at peace. Passive. A Jedi uses the Force for knowledge and defense, never for attack.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But tell me why I can't...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yoda sits on a large root, poking his Gimer Stick into the dirt.</context>
      <utterance>There's something not right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel cold, death.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That place... is strong with the dark side of the Force. A domain of evil it is. In you must go.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke looks warily between the tree and Yoda. He starts to strap on his weapon belt.</context>
      <utterance>Only what you take with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke gives the tree a long look, than shakes his head "no." Yoda shrugs. Luke reaches up to brush aside some hanging vines and enters the tree.</context>
      <utterance>Your weapons... you will not need them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bounty hunters. We don't need that scum.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST CONTROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A second controller interrupts.</context>
      <utterance>Those Rebels won't escape us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND CONTROLLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, we have a priority signal from the Star Destroyer Avenger.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group standing before Vader is a bizarre array of galactic fortune hunters There is Bossk, a slimy, tentacled monster with two huge, bloodshot eyes in a soft baggy face; Zuckuss and Dengar, two battle- scarred, mangy human types; IG-88, a battered, tarnished chrome war droid; and Boba Fett, a man in a weapon-covered armored space suit.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... there will be a substantial reward for the one who finds the Millennium Falcon. You are free to use any methods necessary, but I want them alive. No disintegrations.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBA FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, Admiral Piett approaches Vader in a rush of excitement.</context>
      <utterance>As you wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord Vader! My lord, we have them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han pulls back on the hyperspace throttle and - nothing happens. Flak bursts continue to rock the ship.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here. Ready for light-speed? One... two... three!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie is very angry and starts to growl and bark at his friend and captain. Again, Han desperately pulls back on the throttle.</context>
      <utterance>It's not fair!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie puts his head in his hands, whining.</context>
      <utterance>The transfer circuits are working. It's not my fault!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No light-speed?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not my fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han pauses for a moment, makes a decision, and pulls back on a lever.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, we just lost the main rear deflector shield. One more direct hit on the back quarter and we're done for.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie barks in puzzlement.</context>
      <utterance>Turn her around.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said turn her around! I'm going to put all power in the front shield.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to attack them?!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, the odds of surviving a direct assault on an Imperial Star Destroyer...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NEEDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Needa and his men duck as the Falcon nears the bridge window. At the last minute, the Falcon veers off and out of sight. All is quiet.</context>
      <utterance>They're moving to attack position! Shields up!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEEDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Track them. They may come around for another pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACKING OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Needa, the ship no longer appears on our scopes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEEDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They can't have disappeared. No ship that small has a cloaking device.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACKING OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's no trace of them, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMUNICATIONS OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain, Lord Vader demands an update on the pursuit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEEDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get a shuttle ready. I shall assume full responsibility for losing them, and apologize to Lord Vader. Meanwhile, continue to scan the area.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMUNICATIONS OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Captain Needa.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yoda taps Luke's leg. Quickly, Luke lifts one hand from the ground. His body wavers, but he maintains his balance. Artoo, standing nearby, is whistling and beeping frantically.</context>
      <utterance>Use the Force. Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke concentrates on trying to lift the top rock. It rises a few feet, shaking under the strain. But, distracted by Artoo's frantic beeping, Luke loses his balance and finally collapses. Yoda jumps clear.</context>
      <utterance>Now... the stone. Feel it.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annoyed at the disturbance, Luke looks over at Artoo, who is rocking urgently back and forth in front of him. Artoo waddles closer to Luke, chirping wildly, then scoots over the edge of the swamp. Catching on, Luke rushes to the water's edge. The X-wing fighter has sunk, and only the tip of its nose shows above the lake's surface.</context>
      <utterance>Concentrate!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yoda stamps his foot in irritation.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no. We'll never get it out now.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke looks uncertainly out at the ship.</context>
      <utterance>So certain are you. Always with you it cannot be done. Hear you nothing that I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Master, moving stones around is one thing. This is totally different.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! No different! Only different in your mind. You must unlearn what you have learned.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, I'll give it a try.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke closes his eyes and concentrates on thinking the ship out. Slowly, the X-wing's nose begins to rise above the water. It hovers for a moment and then slides back, disappearing once again.</context>
      <utterance>No! Try not. Do. Or do not. There is no try.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. It's too big.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Size matters not. Look at me. Judge me by my size, do you? Hm? Mmmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And well you should not. For my ally in the Force. And a powerful ally it is. Life creates it, makes it grow. Its energy surrounds us and binds us. Luminous beings are we...  ... not this crude matter.  You must feel the Force around you.  Here, between you... me... the tree... the rock... everywhere! Yes, even between this land and that ship!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't... I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke shakes his head, bewildered.</context>
      <utterance>That is why you fail.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clutching desperately at his throat, Captain Needa slumps down, then falls over on his back, at the feet of Darth Vader. Two stormtroopers pick up the lifeless body and carry it quickly away as Admiral Piett and two of his captains hurry up to the Dark Lord.</context>
      <utterance>Apology accepted, Captain Needa.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord Vader, our ships have completed their scan of the area and found nothing. If the Millennium Falcon went into light- speed, it'll be on the other side of the galaxy by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alert all commands. Calculate every possible destination along their last know trajectory.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, my lord. We'll find them.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vader exits as the admiral turns to an aide, a little more uneasy than when he arrived.</context>
      <utterance>Don't fail me again, Admiral.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alert all commands. Deploy the fleet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why doesn't anyone listen to me?</context>
      <utterance>Captain Solo, this time you have gone too far.  No, I will not be quiet, Chewbacca.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie barks, struggles from his seat, and climbs out of the cabin.</context>
      <utterance>The fleet is beginning to break up. Go back and stand by the manual release for the landing claw.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia reaches over and shuts off Threepio, mid-sentence.</context>
      <utterance>I really don't see how that is going to help. Surrender is a perfectly acceptable alternative in extreme circumstances. The Empire may be gracious enough...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you have in mind for your next move?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if they follow standard Imperial procedure, they'll dump their garbage before they go to light-speed, then we just float away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then what?</context>
      <utterance>With the rest of the garbage.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we've got to find a safe port somewhere around here. Got any ideas?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Where are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Anoat system.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anoat system. There's not much there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to a computer mapscreen on the control panel. Leia slips out of her chair and moves next to the handsome pilot. Small light points representing several systems flash by on the computer screen.</context>
      <utterance>No. Well, wait. This is interesting. Lando.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lando system?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lando's not a system, he's a man. Lando Calrissian. He's a card player, gambler, scoundrel. You'd like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bespin. It's pretty far, but I think we can make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A mining colony?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, a Tibanna gas mine. Lando conned somebody out of it. We go back a long way, Lando and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you trust him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie barks over the intercom. Han quickly changes his readouts and stretches to look out the cockpit window.</context>
      <utterance>No. But he has no love for the Empire, I can tell you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han leans back in his chair and gives Leia an invisible smile. She thinks for a moment, shakes her head; a grin creeps across her face and she gives him a quick kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Here we go, Chewie. Stand by. Detach!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do have your moments. Not many, but you have them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke suddenly becomes distressed.</context>
      <utterance>Concentrate... feel the Force flow. Yes. Good. Calm, yes. Through the Force, things you will see. Other places. The future... the past. Old friends long gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two packing boxes and Artoo fall to the ground with a crash, then Luke himself tumbles over.</context>
      <utterance>Han! Leia!</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm. Control, control. You must learn control.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw... I saw a city in the clouds.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm. Friends you have there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were in pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is the future you see.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yoda closes his eyes and lowers his head.</context>
      <utterance>Future? Will they die?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Difficult to see. Always in motion is the future.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to go to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke is stopped cold by Yoda's words. Gloom shrouds him as he nods his head sadly.</context>
      <utterance>Decide you must how to serve them best. If you leave now, help them you could. But you would destroy all for which they have fought and suffered.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More flak bursts outside the cockpit window and rattles the ship's interior. Leia looks worried.</context>
      <utterance>No, I don't have a landing permit. I'm trying to reach Lando Calrissian.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Wait a minute! Let me explain.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCOM VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will not deviate from your present course.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rather touchy, aren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie barks and growls at his boss.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you knew this person.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that was a long time ago. I'm sure he's forgotten about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCOM VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Permission granted to land on Platform Three-two-seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angry, Han snaps off the intercom. Chewie looks at him and grunts. Han turns to the worried princess and her droid.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia doesn't look convinced.</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing to worry about. We go way back, Lando and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's worried?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. No one to meet us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what would you like?</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they did let us land.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, don't worry. Everything's going to be fine. Trust me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lando moves threateningly toward Han. Suddenly, he throws his arms around his startled, long-lost friend and embraces him.</context>
      <utterance>Why, you slimy, double-crossing, no-good swindler! You've got a lot of guts coming here, after what you pulled. Han points to himself innocently, mouthing, "Me?"</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two old friends embrace, laughing and chuckling.</context>
      <utterance>How you doing, you old pirate? So good to see you! I never thought I'd catch up with you again. Where you been?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he seems very friendly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... very friendly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh... repairs. I thought you could help me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you done to my ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie growls a reserved greeting. Lando suddenly notices the princess and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Your ship? Hey, remember, you lost her to me fair and square.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello. What have we here? Welcome. I'm Lando Calrissian. I'm the administrator of this facility. And who might you be?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leia.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lando bows before Leia and kisses her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome, Leia.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han takes Leia by the hand and steers her away from Lando.</context>
      <utterance>All right, all right, you old smoothie.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Threepio can finish his self-introduction, Lando has turned to follow Han and Leia, who are walking toward the city.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, sir. I am See-Threepio, human-cyborg relations. My facilities are at your...</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lando, his aide, Lobot, and Han lead the way across the bridge, followed by Threepio, Chewie and Leia.</context>
      <utterance>Well, really!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with the Falcon?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hyperdrive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get my people to work on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lando turns to Leia.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, that ship saved my life quite a few times. She's the fastest hunk of junk in the galaxy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the gas mine? Is it paying off for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, not as well as I'd like. We're a small outpost and not very self-sufficient. And I've had supply problems of every kind. I've had labor difficulties...  What's so funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lando is reflective. He looks at Han a moment.</context>
      <utterance>You. Listen to you - you sound like a businessman, a responsible leader. Who'd have thought that, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, seeing you sure brings back a few things.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han and Lando laugh together, and the group moves on through the corridor. The lagging Threepio passes a Threepio-type silver droid who is coming out of a door.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm responsible these days. It's the price you pay for being successful.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! Nice to see a familiar face.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>E chu ta!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Threepio stops, watching the silver droid move away. Then he hears the muffled beeping and whistling of an R2 unit coming from within the room.</context>
      <utterance>How rude!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Threepio walks through the doorway to the main room. He looks in.</context>
      <utterance>That sounds like an R2 unit in there. I wonder if...</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello? How interesting. Oh, my.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A laser bolt to Threepio's chest sends him flying in twenty directions. Smoldering mechanical arms and legs bounce off the walls as the door whooshes closed behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm terribly sorry. I... I didn't mean to intrude. No, no, please don't get up. No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke! You must complete the training.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't keep the vision out of my head. They're my friends. I've got to help them.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must not go!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Han and Leia will die if I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke looks toward the voice in amazement. Ben has materialized as a real, slightly shimmering image near Yoda. The power of his presence stops Luke.</context>
      <utterance>You don't know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even Yoda cannot see their fate.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I can help them! I feel the Force!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you cannot control it. This is a dangerous time for you, when you will be tempted by the dark side of the Force.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes. To Obi-Wan you listen. The cave. Remember your failure at the cave!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I've learned so much since then. Master Yoda, I promise to return and finish what I've begun. You have my word.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is you and your abilities the Emperor wants. that is why your friends are made to suffer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that is why I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke, I don't want to lose you to the Emperor the way I lost Vader.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stopped they must be. On this all depends. Only a fully trained Jedi Knight with the Force as his ally will conquer Vader and his Emperor. If you end your training now, if you choose the quick and easy path, as Vader did, you will become an agent of evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patience.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And sacrifice Han and Leia?</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke is in great anguish. He struggles with the dilemma, a battle raging in his mind.</context>
      <utterance>If you honor what they fight for ... yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you choose to face Vader, you will do it alone. I cannot interfere.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo whistles a happy reply.</context>
      <utterance>I understand.  Artoo, fire up the converters.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke nods and climbs into his ship.</context>
      <utterance>Luke, don't give in to hate - that leads to the dark side.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strong is Vader. Mind what you have learned. Save you it can.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo closes the cockpit. Ben and Yoda stand watching as the roar of the engines and the wind engulf them.</context>
      <utterance>I will. And I'll return. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Told you, I did. Reckless is he. Now matters are worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That boy is our last hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>YODA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. There is another.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ship is almost finished. Two or Three more things and we're in great shape.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han takes Leia by the shoulders and gently kisses her forehead.</context>
      <utterance>The sooner the better. Something's wrong here. No one has seen or knows anything about Threepio. He's been gone too long to have gotten lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax. I'll talk to Lando and see what I can find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't trust Lando.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't trust him, either. But he is my friend. Besides, we'll soon be gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not speaking, Han considers her words and gazes at her troubled face.</context>
      <utterance>And then you're as good as gone, aren't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie sets the case on a table, grunting and groaning an explanation.</context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where? Found him in a junk pile?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The giant Wookiee studies the array of robot parts. He looks at the princess and shrugs sadly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, what a mess. Chewie, do you think you can repair him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lando's got people who can fix him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a buzz and the door slides open, revealing Lando.</context>
      <utterance>No, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. Am I interrupting anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look absolutely beautiful. You truly belong here with us among the clouds.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han looks at Lando suspiciously, but Chewie barks at the mention of food and licks his lips.</context>
      <utterance>Will you join me for a little refreshment?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia takes Lando's proffered arm, and the group turns to go. Lando spots Threepio's remains.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone's invited, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han and Leia exchange a quick glance.</context>
      <utterance>Having trouble with you droid?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han and Leia move arm-in-arm through the door, followed by Lando and Chewie. The door slides closed behind them.</context>
      <utterance>No. No problem. Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you see, since we're a small operation, we don't fall into the... uh... jurisdiction of the Empire.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're part of the mining guild then?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The group walks into another corridor and heads for a huge doorway at the far end.</context>
      <utterance>No, not actually. Our operation is small enough not to be noticed... which is advantageous for everybody since our customers are anxious to avoid attracting attention to themselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you afraid the Empire's going to find out about this little operation and shut you down?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's always been a danger looming like a shadow over everything we've built here. But things have developed that will insure security. I've just made a deal that will keep the Empire out of here forever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han gives Lando a mean look.</context>
      <utterance>We would be honored if you would join us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had no choice. They arrived right before you did. I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo whistles another worried inquiry.</context>
      <utterance>No, Threepio's with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just hang on. We're almost there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie looks at Threepio in bewilderment, then scratches his furry head. He gets an idea and adjusts some connections, whereupon Threepio immediately begins speaking normally.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmm. Oh, my. Uh, I, uh - Take this off! I, uh, don't mean to intrude here. I, don't, no, no, no... Please don't get up. No!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh, no! I've been shot!</context>
      <utterance>Stormtroopers? Here? We're in danger. I must tell the others.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord Vader.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han's screams filter through the torture room door.</context>
      <utterance>You may take Captain Solo to Jabba the Hut after I have Skywalker.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBA FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's no good to me dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He will not be permanently damaged.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord Vader, what about Leia and the Wookiee?</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must never again leave this city.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was never a condition of our agreement, nor was giving Han to this bounty hunter!</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you think you're being treated unfairly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vader turns and sweeps into the elevator with Boba Fett. Lando walks swiftly down another corridor, muttering to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Good. It would be unfortunate if I had to leave a garrison here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This deal's getting worse all the time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Threepio is cut off in mid-sentence as Chewie angrily deactivates a circuit and the droid shuts down. The Wookiee smells something and sits up. The door to the chamber slides open and a ragged Han Solo is shoved into the room by two stormtroopers. Barking his concern, the huge Wookiee gives Han a big hug. Han is very pale, with dark circles under his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, that's very good. I like that. Oh! Something's not right because now I can't see. Wait. Wait! Oh, my! what have you done? I'm backwards, you stupid furball. Only an overgrown mophead like you would be stupid enough...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie helps Han to a platform and then turns as the door slides open revealing Leia. She, too, looks a little worse for wear. The troopers push her into the cell, and the door slides closed. She moves to Han, who is lying on the platform, and kneels next to him, gently stroking his head.</context>
      <utterance>I feel terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are they doing this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cell door slides open. Lando and two of his guards enter.</context>
      <utterance>They never even asked me any questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lando.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of here, Lando!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up and listen! Vader has agreed to turn Leia and Chewie over to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll have to stay here, but at least they'll be safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Han?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vader's giving him to the bounty hunter.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vader wants us all dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't want you at all. He's after somebody called Skywalker.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia's mind is racing.</context>
      <utterance>Lord Vader has set a trap for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we're the bait.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han's rage peaks.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he's on his way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han hauls off and punches Lando. The two friends are instantly engaged in a frantic close-quarters fight. The guards hit Han with their rifle butts and he flies across the room. Chewie growls and starts for the guards. They point their laser weapons at the giant Wookiee, but Lando stops them.</context>
      <utterance>Perfect. You fixed us all pretty good, didn't you?  My friend!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop! I've done all I can. I'm sorry I couldn't do better, but I have my own problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lando and the guards leave. Han wipes the blood from his chin as Leia and Chewie help him up.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you're a real hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You certainly have a way with people.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An Imperial soldier appears.</context>
      <utterance>This facility is crude, but it should be adequate to freeze Skywalker for his journey to the Emperor.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMPERIAL SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>X-wing class.</context>
      <utterance>Lord Vader, ship approaching.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldier bows and leaves the chamber.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Monitor Skywalker and allow him to land.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord Vader, we only use this facility for carbon freezing. If you put him in there, it might kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lando's face registers dismay.</context>
      <utterance>I do not want the Emperor's prize damaged. We will test it... on Captain Solo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If only you had attached my legs, I wouldn't be in this ridiculous position. Now, remember, Chewbacca, you have a responsibility to me, so don't do anything foolish.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on... buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Boba Fett moves away from the group to Darth Vader.</context>
      <utterance>You're being put into carbon freeze.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOBA FETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if he doesn't survive? He's worth a lot to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Realizing what is about to happen, Chewie lets out a wild howl and attacks the stormtroopers surrounding Han. Within seconds, other Imperial reinforcements join the scuffle, clubbing the giant Wookiee with their laser weapons. From the instant of Chewie's first move, Threepio begins to scream in panic while he tries to protect himself with his one arm.</context>
      <utterance>The Empire will compensate you if he dies. Put him in!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stormtroopers are about to bash Chewie in the face.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no! No, no, no! Stop, Chewbacca, stop...!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop, Chewie, stop! Do you hear me? Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han breaks away from his captors. Vader nods to the guards to let him go and the pirate breaks up the fight.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, stop, please! I'm not ready to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han gives the Wookiee a stern look.</context>
      <utterance>Chewie! Chewie, this won't help me. Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Han winks at the Wookiee, who wails a doleful farewell. In a flash the guards have slipped binders on Chewbacca, who is too distraught to protest. Han turns to Princess Leia. They look sorrowfully at one another, then Han moves toward her and gives her a final, passionate kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Save your strength. There'll be another time. The princess - you have to take care of her. You hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears roll down Leia's face as she watches the dashing pirate walk to the hydraulic platform. Han looks one final time at his friends - and then, suddenly, the platform drops. Chewie howls. Leia turns away in agony. Lando winces in sorrow; it makes a life-changing impression on him. Instantly, fiery liquid begins to pour down in a shower of sparks and fluid as great as any steel furnace. Holding Leia, Chewie half-turns away from the sight, giving Threepio a view of the procedure.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie is in no mood for technical discussion; he gives the droid an angry glance and bark. A huge mechanical tong lifts the steaming metal-encased space pirate out of the vat and stands him on the platform. Some Ugnaughts rush over and push the block over onto the platform. They slide the coffinlike structure to the block and lift the metal block, placing it inside. They then attach an electronic box onto the structure and step away. Lando kneels and adjusts some knobs, measuring the heat. He shakes his head in relief.</context>
      <utterance>What... what's going on? Turn round, Chewbacca, I can't see. Oh... they've encased him in carbonite. He should be quite well-protected - if he survives the freezing process, that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Calrissian, did he survive?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vader turns to Boba Fett.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, he's alive. And in perfect hibernation.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reset the chamber for Skywalker.</context>
      <utterance>He's all yours bounty hunter.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMPERIAL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skywalker has just landed, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. See to it that he finds his way here. Calrissian, take the princess and the Wookiee to my ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said they'd be left in the city under my supervision.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lando's hand instinctively goes to his throat as he turns to Leia, Chewie, and Threepio.</context>
      <utterance>I am altering the deal. Pray I don't alter it any further.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Lando's guards quickly march the stormtroopers away, Lando begins to undo Chewie's binding.</context>
      <utterance>Well done. Hold them in the security tower - and keep it quiet. Move.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're getting out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie turns on Lando and starts to choke him.</context>
      <utterance>I knew all along it had to be a mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lando tries to free himself from Chewie.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think that after what you did to Han we're going to trust you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie barks ferociously.</context>
      <utterance>I had no choice...</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? Trust him, trust him!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so we understand, don't we, Chewie? He had no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just trying to help...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't need any of your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>H-a-a-a...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sounds like Han.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's still a chance to save Han... I mean, at the East Platform...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie finally releases Lando, who fights to get his breath back.</context>
      <utterance>Chewie.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm terribly sorry about all this. After all, he's only a Wookiee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie turns around to see the stubby droid, causing Threepio to be spun out of sight of his friend.</context>
      <utterance>Artoo! Artoo! Where have you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whistling frantically to Threepio, Artoo scoots along with the racing group.</context>
      <utterance>Turn around, you wooly...!  Hurry, hurry! We're trying to save Han from the bounty hunter!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, at least your still in one piece! Look what happened to me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have learned much, young one.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vader makes two quick moves, hooking Luke's sword out of his hand and sending it flying. Another lightning move at Luke's feet forces the youth to jump back to protect himself. Losing his balance, Luke rolls down the stairs to the circular carbon-freezing platform. There he sprawls on the floor, surprised and shaken. Just in time he looks up to see Vader, like a giant black bird, flying right at him. Luke rolls away as Vader lands. Crouching, Luke keeps his gaze steadily on his enemy.</context>
      <utterance>You'll find I'm full of surprises.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your destiny lies with me, Skywalker. Obi-Wan knew this to be true.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind Luke the hydraulic elevator cover has opened noiselessly. All the while, Luke slowly, cautiously moves back, away from the Dark Lord. Suddenly, Vader attacks so forcefully that Luke loses his balance and falls back into the opening. There is a rumble, and in an instant freezing steam rises to obscure Vader's vision. Vader turns aside and deactivates his sword.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the steam behind Vader something blurs upward. Liquid metal begins to pour into the pit. Vader turns around - and then looks up. He sees Luke, who has leaped fifteen feet straight up and who now hangs from some hoses on the carbonite outlet.</context>
      <utterance>All to easy. Perhaps you are not as strong as the Emperor thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke jumps down to the platform where he is separated from Vader by the steaming carbonite pit. He raises his hand. His sword, which had fallen on another part of the platform, swiftly jumps into his outstretched hand and is instantly ignited. Vader immediately lights his sword as well.</context>
      <utterance>Impressive... most impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke is more cautious, controlling his anger. He begins to retreat as Vader goads him on. As Luke takes a defensive position, he realizes he has been foolhardy. A quick sword exchange and Luke forces Vader back. Another exchange and Vader retreats. Luke presses forward.</context>
      <utterance>Obi-Wan has taught you well. You have controlled your fear... now release your anger.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Breathing hard, Luke jumps in the air, turning a somersault over Vader. He lands on the floor and slashes at Vader as the room continues to fill up with steam. Vader retreats before Luke's skillful sword. Vader blocks the sword, but looses his balance and falls into the outer rim of pipes. The energy Luke has used to stop Vader has brought him to the point of collapse. Luke moves to the edge and looks down, but sees no sign of Vader. He then deactivates his sword, hooks it on his belt, and lowers himself into the pit.</context>
      <utterance>Only your hatred can destroy me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The security codes has been changed!</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Threepio points to a computer socket on the control panel. Artoo beeps and scoots toward it. Lando meanwhile has connected up to the panel's intercom.</context>
      <utterance>Artoo, you can tell the computer to override the security system.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo takes off a computer cover and sticks his computer arm into the socket. Suddenly, a short beep turns into a wild scream. Artoo's circuits light up, his head spins wildly, and smoke begins to seep out underneath him. Quickly, Chewie pulls him away.</context>
      <utterance>Attention! This is Lando Calrissian. The Empire has takes control of the city. I advise everyone to leave before more Imperial troops arrive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lando, Leia, Artoo, and Chewie flee down the corridor. As he scoots along with them, Artoo sends some angry beeps Threepio's way.</context>
      <utterance>This way.</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't blame me. I'm an interpreter. I'm not supposed to know a power socket from a computer terminal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie starts up the ship. The giant engines begin to whine as Lando and Leia race up the ramp under a hail of laser fire.</context>
      <utterance>Ouch! Oh! Ah! That hurt. Bend down, you thoughtless... Ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leia! Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke answers by rolling sideways and thrusting his sword at Vader so viciously that he nicks Vader on the shoulder. The black armor sparks and smokes and Vader seems to be hurt, but immediately recovers. Luke backs off along the narrow end of the gantry as Vader comes at him, slashing at the young Jedi with his sword. Luke makes a quick move around the instrument complex attached to the end of the gantry. Vader's sword comes slashing down, cutting the complex loose; it begins to fall, then is caught by the rising wind and blown upward. Luke glances at the instrument complex floating away. At that instant, Vader's sword comes down across Luke's right forearm, cutting off his hand and sending his sword flying. In great pain, Luke squeezes his forearm under his left armpit and moves back along the gantry to its extreme end. Vader follows. The wind subsides. Luke holds on. There is nowhere else to go.</context>
      <utterance>You are beaten. It is useless to resist. Don't let yourself be destroyed as Obi-Wan did.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no escape. Don't make me destroy you. You do not yet realize your importance. You have only begun to discover your power. Join me and I will complete your training. With our combined strength, we can end this destructive conflict and bring order to the galaxy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll never join you!</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you only knew the power of the dark side. Obi-Wan never told you what happened to your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He told me enough! It was you who killed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shocked, Luke looks at Vader in utter disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>No. I am your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No. That's not true! That's impossible!</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Search your feelings. You know it to be true.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! No! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vader puts away his sword and holds his hand out to Luke. A calm comes over Luke, and he makes a decision. In the next instant he steps off the gantry platform into space. The Dark Lord looks over the platform and sees Luke falling far below. The wind begins to blow at Vader's cape and the torrent finally forces him back, away from the edge. The wind soon fades and the wounded Jedi begins to drop fast, unable to grab onto anything to break his fall.</context>
      <utterance>Luke. You can destroy the Emperor. He has foreseen this. It is your destiny. Join me, and together we can rule the galaxy as father and son. Come with me. It is the only way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke tries to pull himself up on the weather vane but slips back down. He hooks one of his legs around the fragile instruments. All the while, a powerful current of air rushes out at him from the exhaust pipe.</context>
      <utterance>Ben... Ben, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an ominous cracking sound from the base of the weather vane and a piece breaks off, falling into the clouds far below.</context>
      <utterance>Ben. Leia!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hear me! Leia!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie growls in surprise.</context>
      <utterance>Luke... We've got to go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know where Luke is.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie barks in agreement with Lando.</context>
      <utterance>But what about those fighter?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chewie, just do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie turns on Lando, the newcomer, with an ominous growl.</context>
      <utterance>But what about Vader?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, all right, all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, someone's up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lando rushes out of the cockpit.</context>
      <utterance>It's Luke. Chewie, slow down. Slow down and we'll get under him. Lando, open the top hatch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lando?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Leia.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leia helps Luke from the cockpit as another huge blast rocks the ship.</context>
      <utterance>All right, Chewie. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Star Destroyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Chewie. Ready for light-speed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another explosion rocks the ship. Leia notices as a green light on the panel next to her flashes on.</context>
      <utterance>If your people fixed the hyperdrive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie barks in agreement.</context>
      <utterance>All the coordinates are set. It's now or never.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Wookiee shrugs and pulls back on the light-speed throttle. The sound of the ion engine changes...it is winding up. Faces are tense, expectant. But nothing happens, and the engine goes off. Chewie lets out a frustrated howl. The flak still violently rocks the ship.</context>
      <utterance>Punch it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie gets up from his chair and starts out of the cockpit. He gives Lando and angry shove as he storms past him.</context>
      <utterance>They told me they fixed it. I trusted them to fix it. It's not my fault!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll be in range of our tractor beam in moments, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did your men deactivate the hyperdrive on the Millennium Falcon?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>VADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Prepare the boarding party and set your weapons for stun.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, my lord.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo beeps in response.</context>
      <utterance>Noisy brute. Why don't we just go into light-speed?</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Artoo whistles knowingly.</context>
      <utterance>We can't? How would you know the hyperdrive is deactivated?</utterance>
   <speaker>THREEPIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie is in the pit. He is trying to loosen something with an enormous wrench. Frustrated, he uses the wrench like a club and hits the panel...</context>
      <utterance>The city's central computer told you? Artoo-Detoo, you know better than to trust a strange computer. Ouch! Pay attention to what you're doing!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke, we're ready for takeoff.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck, Lando</utterance>
   <speaker>LANDO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we find Jabba the Hut and that bounty hunter, we'll contact you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chewie's wail comes over the comlink.</context>
      <utterance>Chewie, I'll be waiting for your signal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke looks down at his hand. A metalized type of bandage has been wrapped around his wrist. The medical droid makes some adjustments in a tiny electronic unit, then pricks each one of Luke's fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Take care, you two. May the Force be with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke wriggles his fingers, makes a fist, and relaxes it. His hand is completely functional. He gets up and walks over to Leia. There is a new bond between them, a new understanding. Leia is thinking about Han; Luke is thinking about his uncertain and newly complicated future. Together they stand at the large window of the medical center looking out on the Rebel Star Cruiser and a dense, luminous galaxy swirling in space. Luke puts his arm around Leia. The droids stand next to them, and Threepio moves closer to Artoo putting his arm on him. The group watches as the Millennium Falcon moves into view, makes a turn, and zooms away into space.</context>
      <utterance>Ow!</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
