<movie id="525" title="Stepmom">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room looks like a 6 (but I'm almost 7) year old exploded. Posters of MAGICIANS on all the walls. Rachel darts about the room mismatching the clothes she forgot to arrange the night before.</context>
      <utterance>Ben! You overslept again damn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LUMP under the cover doesn't move.</context>
      <utterance>Get Up Get Up Get Up!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No movement. Rachel tugs the sleeve of a shirt hanging on a chair, and out comes a magician's bouquet of FLOWERS.</context>
      <utterance>Ben you're late. I'm serious. I'm wearing a very serious face. Don't make me start counting ONE...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She RIPS the covers off and a blow-up DINOSAUR sleeps in Ben's place.</context>
      <utterance>Don't make me say three I'm about to say three.  Three!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WHITE BUNNY saunters across her toes. Rachel SCREAMS -- then gathers her wits and searches under the bed -- under the bureau -- she opens the closet doors and shoving clothes aside.</context>
      <utterance>Ben I'm not kidding around. You make yourself appear this instant!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unseen by Rachel, six-year-old BEN sits, perched on the highest closet shelf, knees under his chin, holding his breath. His eyes gleeful as Rachel frantically closes the closet door.</context>
      <utterance>You might think this is funny but this is actually NOT funny.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You forgot to wash my purple shirt. I told you a hundred times it was Purple Day at school today.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't forget. I was up all night thinking about it and I concluded you're too special to look like everyone else.  Orange Red. That's your color. Few can carry it off. Now please. Help me find your brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lost Ben?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(big breath)</context>
      <utterance>Of course not. Does he look lost to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I told you. I like apple butter not butter butter.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never mind. I'll just eat my lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm almost done making it.  Alright Ben --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him a bowl of sugared cereal -- puts two spoonfuls of instant coffee in Barney cup, and sticks it under the faucet.</context>
      <utterance>Fine! Eat in the cupboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Cocoa Puffs on Top -- Fruit Loops on the bottom.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel grabs the bowl, turn it UPSIDE DOWN on the table reversing the order of the cereal. She SWEEPS it back in the bowl and quickly hands it back to him, the phone RINGS THROUGHOUT...</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You touched it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then have a donut --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright starve.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna beep daddy at work.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's badgering a witness. Eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you told us to starve.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel runs around absentmindedly loading out leftover pizza, Hoho's, and Chips. She glances at the clock again -- 8:00.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?...Duncan...The Ad Agency's already there?...I'm out the door...  Ben! Knock it off!  It's gonna go beautifully...  Damn it Ben --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You swore. You owe me a quarter. Did you remember my egg carton? I told you I needed my egg carton for seed planting today.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel takes the eggs from the fridge, and dumps them -- accidentally missing the sink. They SHATTER onto the floor. She hands the empty carton to Annabelle.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely Duncan I'm on top of everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...EGGzactly. I'm putting on my coat --  We are late. We are seriously late. Which means Mister Ben we've got to get you dressed --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben races away but Rachel LUNGES And CATCHES him. He wiggles in her arms as she struggles to change his clothes. Just as she gets his bottoms off she drops his clothes in the pile of gooey eggs when we hear a loud KNOCKING at the kitchen door. Holding a half naked Ben in her arms, Rachel looks up at... JACKIE HARRISON. An immaculately dressed, intimidatingly intel- ligent, utterly beautiful woman staring at her with extreme disapproval.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE AND BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle and Ben RACE into their mother's arms like little angels. Jackie shoots a fiercely protective glare at Rachel. They LOCK eyes. Enough wattage to light up all of Manhattan.</context>
      <utterance>Mommy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...it's really not so bad Annabelle -- Red and Blue make purple.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you don't, but if you had, chrom- atically you</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if by rote, they hold out their lunches. One is a plastic Vons bag and the other a crumpled Macy's bag. She collects them and hands Ben and Annabelle two brightly colored lunch bags.</context>
      <utterance>I noticed a whopping pile of laundry sitting on the washer -- perhaps Rachel's underpants are in there -- Now where are your lunches?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annabelle sucked her thumb last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And SLUGS him.</context>
      <utterance>I NEVER do that, you ALWAYS lie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Those were all words. I hate the planet Uranus. Hate.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have lava.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lava's hateable. I never thought of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate overly ripe bananas -- they make me want to throw up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent point.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate wax lips and red ants and pretzels without salt...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie nods sagely. Pulls up next to a school playground.</context>
      <utterance>I hate the crayon Burnt Sienna and people who spit when they walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They bump foreheads and elbows. Ben runs toward the kindergarten playground; Jackie watches concerned as Annabelle climbs the steps. The only orangey red dot in a sea of purple.</context>
      <utterance>I hate to say goodbye. Eskimo Kiss.  Russian Orthodox Wedding Kiss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cooper, back the fill off I don't have enough shadow...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got a fruit loop in your hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You say that like I don't know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I once threw an entire bowl of jello on my stepmother's head --</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when did that pass?</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DUNCAN SAMUELS -- Rachel's boss, an elegant, edgy, Englishman interrupts them.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, never. They'll always hate you. There's a gene for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations. Only forty minutes late. You're handling this promotion really well Rachel.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Duncan backs off, charmed by her ballsiness. The music BLARES just then, and a penguin JUTS forward and NIPS the model. The FLASH of the camera. We FREEZE for a second, seeing the photo Rachel just took. An Avedonesque portrait of a model being GOOSED by a penguin COLLIDING with a maitre'd who SPILLS his tray and the penguins seem to be POINTING and LAUGHING uproariously. It's an inspired photo.</context>
      <utterance>Duncan. My work is everything to me. This'll never happen again. Now stand back -- this session's gonna make you remember why you hired me even though I wouldn't sleep with you -- Cooper let's get these penguins dancing --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>MRS. FRANKLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke's beeper beeps. He ignores it; focuses on Mr. Franklin.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. and Mrs. Harrison, while change is exhilarating for adults, it can be quite challenging for a child.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>we were talking about change.</context>
      <utterance>I won't get that...It's fine. Change.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. FRANKLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fact that you two are remarrying obviously has Annabelle overjoyed...  And she's very excited about your move to Switzerland.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly -- a long bell rings -- Jackie STANDS UP, startled.</context>
      <utterance>She said we're getting remarried?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. FRANKLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only a fire drill. My concern is that Annabelle seems apathetic towards her work knowing she's leaving before the end of the semester.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Franklin we're not --</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Planning on getting --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remarried. There is no move.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. FRANKLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke's beeper BEEPS again. They talk right over Mrs. Franklin...</context>
      <utterance>Really? Well then my concern for --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you don't really seem here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here. I've got a case where they're this close to sequestering the jury but have I answered the goddamn thing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something's up wi...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cuts a look at Mrs. Franklin.</context>
      <utterance>You think I didn't get that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And reaches. Does it for him.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse him. He never learned how to turn the darn thing off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. FRANKLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long pause. Then suddenly they both start speaking AT ONCE.</context>
      <utterance>I'm wondering if there's anything going on at home that could be intensifying Annabelle's need to create this fantasy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been with someone for quite some time, and didn't feel it was appropriate for her to move in too quickly. But after a lot of thought and careful discussion with her -- and the kids I might add -- she moved in last month.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since our divorce Luke has seen a number of different women in three short years and without a lot of warning for the kids, he's now living with a woman half his age --</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rachel's not half my age.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not discussing your age.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we're not discussing Rachel's age either.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They want to be with you Luke, they go to your house to be with their father.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie, they come to be part of my life. Rachel is part of that life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. FRANKLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Harrison, I hear you talking about your life, your needs, but are you really in touch with what Annabelle needs?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This man would walk thru fire for Annabelle, gladly, any day of the week.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Napalm.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except for last Thursday when Rachel forgot to pick them up --</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie, she was five minutes late --</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. FRANKLIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm wondering if Annabelle is responding to the underlying hostility that exists between Rachel and Mrs. Harrison...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course she's responding to it. You think it's easy for any of us? You think it's easy for Jackie to watch her kids being looked after by someone who has half the experience she does? Of course she's going to be hostile, irrational, and defensive.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Franklin doesn't quite know what to say. The bell RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you Luke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you Mrs. Franklin. Jackie?  This has been very valuable for us. And I'll have a serious talk with Annabelle tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Wednesday night. She's at my house. I'll talk to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call from work. We can have a conference call.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they're out the door. You can hear the fight as it echoes down the elementary school hallway.</context>
      <utterance>You tried that last week and we were on hold forty-five minutes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ask me that counselor's making a mountain out of a molehill...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm worried.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luke, I need to switch next Friday for Thursday, so why don't you take the weekend...  ...that way you'll be there, and I'll pick up Monday, Tuesday, and Wednesday.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. But I wanted to take the kids to work with me on Wednesday so I'll take Wednesday, and you can pick up that Thursday, Friday after soccer, and Saturday before riding.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if on automatic pilot they move in to kiss each other goodbye then stop. Each takes a step back. 15 years of hellos and goodbyes. A beat. A wave. They head their separate ways.</context>
      <utterance>Good...Well...Take care.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say that. Why would I say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well Daddy and I were thinking that sometimes people tell a story about what they wish would happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want that to happen. Why would I want that to happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you're telling your teachers and your friends --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mass hysteria.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you're upset that Rachel moved in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not upset. Why would I be upset?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look if the truth is you don't feel like talking about this right now that's fine. But don't look me in the eye with a big smile on your face and lie to me. Cause there are only so many lies you're allowed to tell before it starts showing on your face. You wind up looking like... She stops. It's just too horrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like who?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben enters in white gloves and Jackie's scarf.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he's not president anymore, so why be petty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie picks a card.</context>
      <utterance>Pick a card. Any card.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It just slipped out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens when he loves Rachel more than us?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That will never happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll bet daddy's mad at me now.</context>
      <utterance>Never say never you always say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Queen of diamonds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven of clubs. Nobody's mad we just want to talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna call him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle RUNS out of the room. Jackie watches her sadly. Ben hits Jackie hard with his magic wand.</context>
      <utterance>Annabelle, daddy and I will always be there. That's one time always is always. You can call him after dinner but...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poof! You're happy now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben finds himself alone in the kitchen. He hits himself on the head, hard. Poof! He begins to serve himself dinner. Alone.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you Ben.  Annabelle!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, if they're going to</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke is thinking of something. She's watching that.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it wasn't a reduction like you do it! Boiling down half a ton of bones...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The way you cook. If you could make love, I'd marry you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh. I mention marriage, all of a sudden...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to spoil our supper...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd rather spoil our walk home.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Okay, what?</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, it's cheaper.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just found out I have to go to Boston to get a deposition. I might not be back until Saturday.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'll have to order in?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have the kids this weekend, so...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances over...</context>
      <utterance>Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it was</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a babysitter -- I mean...you're working...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can take them to work with me -- I can shift things around --</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't need to. I don't expect you to handle them yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maybe she's right. Because he doesn't say anything.</context>
      <utterance>Can't handle them myself is what you mean. Can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't trust me to be alone with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I trust you of course I do but --</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But? But what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm sorry.</context>
      <utterance>But you're not good at this. Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He loves her. But this problem is real.</context>
      <utterance>I know how responsible, caring adults parent children. I'm bribe 'em. But 'em a dog or something. Maybe a Doberman.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. I know they hate me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't hate you --</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what you're telling them is keep hating her -- keep up the good work --</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's telling them to hate you --</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Look in your ex-wife's eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's complicated for Jackie. It's complicated for me...You don't have kids -- you don't understand --</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh right...So it's just complicated for you and Jackie -- for me it's pretty simple cause I just don't understand...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you don't. And I'm not gonna screw with my kids heads right now --</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've reached their building. As they enter...</context>
      <utterance>You know I don't need another person in this family making me feel like an idiot...your ex-wife's doing a bang up job and I have to face it every Tuesday and Thursday and every other goddamn weekend and I just don't know how the hell you were married to her for so goddamn long! Jesus what did you see in her? I don't get it -- I just don't get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a great mother.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around -- completely exhausted. It's late. Annabelle is video taping the dog pee. Ben's in the kitchen talking to himself. He pours and sprinkles, working intently on a MAGIC POTION.</context>
      <utterance>Aw George...not again... who wants to help clean up this time?  Annabelle?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben ZAPS the magic potion theatrically with his fingertips.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you make that face when you talk to me?  And that voice you use...you think I'm deaf or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, okay? Let's not fi...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch me! I'm</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She races upstairs. Rachel follows. So does Ben. And George.</context>
      <utterance>I have to work on my video project! Don't follow me! I can put myself to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me --</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annabelle let's get something clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to listen to you! You're not my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves the room SLAMMING the door behind her. Takes a breath, turns, and walks back in.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God for that!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I meant and perhaps I didn't say it well was you have a great mom. You don't need another one. But when you're at this house --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my daddy's house --</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my house too!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is my room so get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Rachel throws open the door. Ben stands there innocently.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made you some cocoa. See?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel leads Ben to his room. With Rachel safe out of sight, Annabelle takes the puppy into her arms and cuddles it.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you Ben. That was so sweet of you.  Goodnight Annabelle. Sweet dreams.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the great green room there was a telephone and a red balloon...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's the good kind.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't you going to drink your cocoa?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight moon, goodnight hush, goodnight mush, goodnight goodnight goodnight Gracie -- Goodnight Ben!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben's eyes are glued to her. She lays down next to him, yawns.</context>
      <utterance>No! You're cheating -- you have to start from the beginning and you have to read the whole thing I can't sleep otherwise.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the great green room there was a telephone and a red balloon...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And a picture of the cow jumping over the moon...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben reads until Rachel's asleep. He looks at her in AWE.</context>
      <utterance>That's nice Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response. Rachel's really asleep. He lifts her head. It flops down! In HORROR he jumps off the bed and with a quick look back, races from the room, and... ...DARTS down the hallway, BUMPING into walls -- He LEAPS inside Annabelle's room, SLAMMING the door behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Rachel! Rachel!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben! What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben and Annabelle gape at one another, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>I killed her!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's missed her sunrise Groom'n Ride.</context>
      <utterance>How do you hold down a job? It's 8:10. You were supposed to be here at 7:00.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Friday, her riding lesson is on Tuesdays.  I got it right here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every Tuesday except the 3rd Tuesday of the month when it's switched to Friday except in April when she rides on Thursday. It's not that hard. Didn't you have a mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I please have a cup of coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have any coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this? The Betty Ford Center?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle RUSHES past her. Ben saunters off after his sister. Jackie turns to Rachel, accusingly.</context>
      <utterance>Annabelle, how's your video rep...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened with Annabelle? Has nothing I said gotten through to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you could back off just a little bit --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie's edge sharpened by Rachel's unease.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Look, I want to talk to you about...well...Luke said to ask you...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And...?</context>
      <utterance>See, the place where I can connect with Annabelle is my photography. Because she loves video and all...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's been talking about this little editing machine, it's only...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...a ridiculously Forgiveness? For what, exactly?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much time have you got? Let's start with this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone in our family takes showers.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure that didn't upset her.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The air is thick with tension.</context>
      <utterance>I was in there in him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you or Luke talk to her about it afterwards?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I thought it might be uncomfortable for her --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean for you. A 10-year-old girl is coping with the fact that her father is never coming back to live with his family. She sees her father naked with another woman for the first time. And you think it's best for her if every- one pretends it didn't happen?  This isn't going to work out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're damn right. I'm gonna sick of your imperious bullshit. I never said I was Betty Fucking Crocker. If every time life hits her in the face you want to have a 12 hour talk every third Friday or the month -- go ahead! I have a life!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh and I don't because I have a children?! The problem is you're too self-involved to ever be a mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe the problem is your kids. Maybe they're spoiled, coddled brats!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's not on the schedule!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie turns away, storming out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>You got to hell!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah Ah Ah! You owe me a quarter --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Ladies, the secrets to a great pie is the crust. And the secret to a great flaky pie crust comes from less flour and more...what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ice cold water.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel watches from a corner.</context>
      <utterance>That's my girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blueberry pie must be topped with vanilla Haagan Daz and/or creme fraiche...now the secret to a great creme fraiche is...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL THE GIRLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Orange peel!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...which also is the secret to...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL THE GIRLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>French toast!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off his apron and walks toward Rachel as the girls file out...</context>
      <utterance>Now don't forget to teach your fathers that. Next week...apple brown betty!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't even know what she's talking about.</context>
      <utterance>She said no.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks down.</context>
      <utterance>The editing machine. I mean, Annabelle would have really loved it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eyes down. Choosing her words.</context>
      <utterance>It would have been great for us, so obviously, Jackie just...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks up.</context>
      <utterance>She's really a difficult person...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An afterthought...</context>
      <utterance>Best thing ever happened to you was her throwing you out on your butt.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes and kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>Not that I have a personal stake in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get ready. To get really mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh. Annabelle's video report has been switched again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I sold my body to Satan to clear Friday at two o'clo...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have the kids. Next weekend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the evil part is. I am</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Pause. PULL BACK to see...</context>
      <utterance>Hi, it's the trophy bimbo. Annabelle's teacher called, and her video report is being moved up to 8:30 tomorrow. Sorry to deprive your step aerobics class of their role model.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>...BEN, looming over the hardware. Fingers poised above the buttons, and he...</context>
      <utterance>Anyway. I'm sorry I lost my temper the other day. And I'm sure you are, too, so...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>...strikes! Playing all the keys at once. Like chords on a baby grand.</context>
      <utterance>...no, apology necessa...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TAMARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The class OOOOOS, WHISTLES. Annabelle flushes, but she clearly likes it. Brad grins a Redford grin her way. And through the back door BURSTS... ...a harried, disheveled JACKIE. Still in workout clothes. As on screen...</context>
      <utterance>Well, first off, Annabelle. I'd give half of it. To you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The screen goes BLACK. The class, teacher and especially Luke ERUPT with APPLAUSE. So does Jackie, who has locked eyes across the room with her mortally-wounded abandoned daughter. Then Jackie's eyes CUT TO... ...Rachel, a deer in headlights. Death by Army ants would be too kind.</context>
      <utterance>There you have it. Now ask yourself ...what would YOU do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Machines do not EAT message.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Said with bottomless pride.</context>
      <utterance>Of all the lead vegetable...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And nothing. And</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're WHERE?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the Big Apple Circus, it's the only big top I know. I said I'd get 'em back tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie,</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me. Another machine ate</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think twice. Before you</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The timing was off -- I need this light.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we're hungry -- and I have to pick up my costume for the pageant! It starts at seven!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LATER...Annabelle asleep on the bench. Rachel stands over her, a canary on her finger.</context>
      <utterance>It's only one o'clock...Why don't you get another Fudgesicle -- I'll be done soon -- really soon. Annabelle and Ben. Rolling their eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lunch time Sleeping Beauty. Where's Ben? Is he in the bathroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...I feel like I'm gonna throw up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if he's kidnapped?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Panicked, she grabs Annabelle's hand.</context>
      <utterance>He's not kidnapped he's -- he's just hiding -- he's just -- BENNNN? GODDAMMIT!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel. Starting to believe it.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch me! You bring bad luck!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the corner of the tower we see GEORGE staring up at her. But Ben is NOWHERE to be found.</context>
      <utterance>Ben! Ben we're here! BEN!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel once more. Her life flashing before her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>He's gone forever and I'm gonna miss the pageant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben! Oh my Ben! Are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew where I was all the time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke elbows her with an &quot;We're in an Elementary School&quot; elbow.</context>
      <utterance>Jackie? I am so sorry about today I really fucked up royalty. When you called Luke I was so goddamn relieved --</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie lifts Ben onto her lap, holding him tightly. She turns and faces Rachel, claws bared.</context>
      <utterance>No I did -- I know I did -- I screwed up. I feel like such an asshole...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights go down. They sit pretending the other is not there. On stage -- The class is dressed as the harvest PRODUCE. Annabelle is the CORN. Each FOOD DISH steps forward and introduces itself. Annabelle rehearing her line over and over.</context>
      <utterance>Shhhhhh!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside her costume, her breathing is sharp. She stands very straight, very bold. A brazen ear of corn. She steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Hello! I am Maze. But you can call me Corn. Hello! I am...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel POPS UP next to the stage with her huge PROFESSIONAL CAMERA and giant flash. Her camera FLASHES three times, quickly. After each flash, we see the picture for a split second, Annabelle. A TERRIFIED ear of corn. A LOST ear of corn.</context>
      <utterance>Hello! I am...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the audience, Jackie is willing her daughter a recovery. Sees instead, a completely DEVASTATED ear of corn.</context>
      <utterance>Um...I'm...I'm...Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs offstage amidst laughter and applause. Luke looks over at Jackie but she and Ben have already left their seats.</context>
      <utterance>Oh forget it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate her. I really hate her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There you are!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to cry. Ben's lip quivers, his eyes well up.</context>
      <utterance>Don't take my picture!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annabelle doesn't really want to talk to you right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I didn't mean to break your concentration. I thought it would be a nice moment to rememb...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A TURKEY approaches.</context>
      <utterance>I don't ever want to remember this!</utterance>
   <speaker>TURKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're taking a picture of the Produce, we need the Corn. C'mon Annabelle.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben takes Annabelle's hand. When they are gone...</context>
      <utterance>See? No one's laughing at you. Your friends want you to join them, Anna- belle. Corn is a very important part of the Harvest Produce. Now Ben, walk your sister over to the Yams.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie, if I thought for one moment...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You listen carefully because I am only going to say this once. That woman has nothing more to do with my children.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our children.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you realize what could have hap- pened to your son today? How lucky we are the police found him before some lunatic did? He could have been...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he hasn't. He wandered off. I know it's terrifying. I can imagine how you felt when that call came -- But it happens.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie, you've made mistakes -- We all make mistakes --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna wait around to see the next one. I'm not gonna watch my kids fall through the cracks of this arrangement. I'm seeing a lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie stop. We promised we never go there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've broken a lot of promises, haven't we Luke?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you taking this out on him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rache, get out of th...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't done</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A court</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guinevere, Godiva, I sense enemy sol...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she canters off, blood in her eye. Alone now with his mom, Ben has something serious on his mind.</context>
      <utterance>I'll ride ahead. Nelson, protect the Queen...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy? It's not Rachel's fault I ran away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's your fault. It's her fault for not watching over my precious son, as if it were her priority. Which means, the most important job.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rachel's job is she works.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben, mommies work too. They work very hard. Mommy works harder as a mom than she did when she was working. I just don't get paid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does Rachel make a lot of money?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People like Rachel who only think about themselves often do make a lot of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she's pretty, Mommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...if you like big hair...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Jackie. Stunned. Her lips part for an answer. But she hasn't got one.</context>
      <utterance>If you want me to hate her I will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the end of his rope. She walks down to him.</context>
      <utterance>You know, you can come inside the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. Well...</context>
      <utterance>Did you see the lawyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Called him. We set an ap...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So vulnerable. The air comes out of her. We see how much she still cares for this man.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're saying, don't make the kids a football, don't put them through a war. But I'm doing this for their well-being.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Staring. At each other.</context>
      <utterance>Partly. But partly, you're mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know the kids aren't really in danger. This is about Rachel, and you're right, I'm disappointed in her learning curve, and...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out. Takes her hands.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm supposed to care.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>About me, yeh. Like I care about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shrugs. Looks saddened by that.</context>
      <utterance>Like you cared about me three years ago?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has to tell her...</context>
      <utterance>Forget I said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't want to lose her. And I will</context>
      <utterance>This thing with Rache. I need this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice tried to be tough. But the tension showed through.</context>
      <utterance>One last chance, don't make me regret it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A last look. She walks slowly. Back toward the house.</context>
      <utterance>...or you will, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stops.</context>
      <utterance>...no, no, that is not possible. You must have the wrong little gir...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...because Annabelle's mother client arriving at exac...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. I was just doin' my nails.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie turns, suddenly focusing...</context>
      <utterance>Your paper went off during the procedure. Do you want the number?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait...what time is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, sea salt and vinegar, I</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks up. Eyes desperate.</context>
      <utterance>Now could she just... forget me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, that's something</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mom had to...help a friend with this...emergency? And she called me. And we switched days. Then, I got stuck on my shoot, and...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie's eyes come back to focus. Hmmn?</context>
      <utterance>Are you worried about your friend? With the emergency?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she smiles. Real carefree. So Annabelle smiles back.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm waiting on some news, that's all. Say. Can I ask you why you never asked me something you probably asked Daddy anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More brushing. Gentler, slower strokes.</context>
      <utterance>You can try.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy was washing Rachel. In the shower. What did you think that was about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh.</context>
      <utterance>Sex. Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, not exactly s...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Does she mean what Jackie thinks she means?</context>
      <utterance>Why does Rachel scream?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scream.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. Again.</context>
      <utterance>During sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would you know sh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her mother laughs. Encouraged...</context>
      <utterance>I live. In the same country.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God oh God Oh God oh God oh God Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...why do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie moves around. Leans to stare in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Because it feels really incredibly good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why are you asking me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The look holds. Almost a bittersweet smile plays on Jackie's lips. She leans to kiss her daughter's head.</context>
      <utterance>I like talking about it. At least, to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same here, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie enters, leaving the door wide OPEN.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on! Don't let the light...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. Look, I'm not real comfortable being here, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>I don't recall inviting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unreadable faces. What are they feeling?</context>
      <utterance>I overhead what you told Annabelle. The lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a snoop.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't need you to take the blame for me, I'm quite...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Jackie. Finds that interesting.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't do it for you. Believe me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She already hates me. You've seen to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not terribly good at taking care of h...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need practice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Straight to her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I did it for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing friendly about it. But Jackie hasn't come seeking friendship.</context>
      <utterance>Poor kid has to believe in someone. Even if it's you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have an appointment this after- noon. I need someone to take them to the park.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hard looks. All around.</context>
      <utterance>What? And have Federal agents jump out of the bushes with court orders? How many years do you get in this state for giving second-rate care to minors?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>However many. It's not enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm already on thin ice. Yesterday, I actually thought my boss was going to fire me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But neither of them wants her to. A Mexican Standoff. Until Jackie empties her huge purse on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Fine, forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bandaids for cuts. Bandaids for new shoe blisters. Packet of Wash n Dri's. Kleenex. Sugar free lollipops, potty seat covers for public restrooms...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not just bring the whole toilet?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben likes to be read to. Do you know Dr. Seuss...?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not personally.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This silences Rachel. Jackie hands her a Post It.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have a word limit you need to hit every day or can I finish?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Here's their schedule for this after- noon. I'll meet you at the park at five. All I ask is that they're alive when I get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And scoops up the parenting paraphernalia.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And walks out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sweetest smile she's got. Which is pretty good.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Samuels? Forgive the intrusion, I'm Jacqueline Harrison, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For your generosity.</context>
      <utterance>...well, I just wanted to thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gener...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Confides...</context>
      <utterance>...my daughter had a terrible emergency yesterday. My husband and I couldn't be reached, and...your Ms. Kelly came to Annabelle's rescue.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakes her hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'd hate to think what might have happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An amazing smile.</context>
      <utterance>She told me that you were so suppor- tive, even at great inconvenience to your business, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's wonderful to see a successful man. With that sense of priorities.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...under the circumstances...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Backing out the door...</context>
      <utterance>If I can ever repay your kindness. It would be my great pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The client is beaming.</context>
      <utterance>...and your Ms. Kelly? A remarkable young woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spread. That is</context>
      <utterance>I don't even know what that means.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The air comes out of Jackie. In a thin, slow, precise stream. Everything, her very breath. Under complete control.</context>
      <utterance>The other time. Was a year ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Silence. Jackie's eyes stay on her folded, still, hands.</context>
      <utterance>That was a tiny lump in the breast. We radiated, we thought we had it all. We were hopeful. But there were no guarantees.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL BACK to see the small, neatly kept office. DR. SWEIKERT is 50, slender, elegant, kind. The doctor you want when you're dying. Jackie looks up to her.</context>
      <utterance>But we can beat it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People beat it, don't they? All the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. SWEIKERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie swallows. The confirmation of hope has allowed some of the fear to show.</context>
      <utterance>Every day. More and more.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we'll...radiate some more?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. SWEIKERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A blow. Jackie absorbs this.</context>
      <utterance>At first. Then, after awhile, some chemo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's necessary, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. SWEIKERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie nods. Staring at the woman. Then, to break the spell...</context>
      <utterance>Let's take our best shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor smiles. Jackie looks at her watch...</context>
      <utterance>I guess a no-hair day beats a bad-hair day.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to get dressed. My ex-husband has asked me to dinner. God knows why, he was very mysteri...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. SWEIKERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A flash of the anger flickers.</context>
      <utterance>Have you still never told him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would his worry? Or my children's worry. Or anyone's worry. Help the sit...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. SWEIKERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That brings a silence. A shading of defiance to Jackie's features.</context>
      <utterance>Sooner than later. You really need to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hold the look.</context>
      <utterance>You don't burden others needlessly. That's how I was raised, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. SWEIKERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe at dinner tonight. Think about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Throughout, Annabelle is trying on Jackie's jewelry, making a pest of herself. Jackie fights against rising irritation.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you going to a French restaurant?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it's quiet. And he wants to talk. Alise -- Once he saws you in half, it's bedtime...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you gonna talk about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably you -- your brother -- school -- The solar system...The usual...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why are you putting on mascara?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a little tired and it's just a pick-me-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you only wore mascara when you and Daddy went on romantic dates...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well Daddy and I are just friends now, and that's no reason not to wear mascara...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or blush. You look pale.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie feels her heart beginning to race. They lock eyes for a moment. He unconsciously begins to eat off her plate. He eats her chicken, and in the dance they've done a thousand times -- she reaches for his uneaten vegetables. The WAITER approaches.</context>
      <utterance>...Maybe you don't think three years is enough for a person to change but...things are different now Jackie. I'm different.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't correct the waiter.</context>
      <utterance>Would you and your wife prefer still or sparkling water?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's amazing in it.</context>
      <utterance>Annabelle showed me the new dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes lock for a moment. Here it comes...</context>
      <utterance>Getting so beautiful...she looks more like you every day.  Jackie...I've really given this a lot of thought. A great deal of thought...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna marry Rachel. I know you don't think much of her but she's a special person -- she really is. And I love her. This is a bridge we never wanted to cross but it's not helping her or the kids if I don't really commit to that. Jackie stares at him stonefaced.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't think a phone call was appropriate...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shifts in his chair. Wants this to sound as authentic as he feels it...</context>
      <utterance>Tell me exactly how you're different from three years ago? The music sounds kind of the same from where I'm sitting.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I grew up, a little. I'm ready for a life that's built around commitm...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter returns with a bottle of red wine. It's horribly quiet as he pours. Waits, obtrusively.</context>
      <utterance>Just not to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, it's fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to taste it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter leaves, taking his attitude with him. Luke sighs...</context>
      <utterance>Can we please have less service, here?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going to be hard for the kids when I tell them...I'd like you to be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To make it easier for them or you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a huge moment in their life --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't be an 'us' just when you want to. You can't play that card when it's convenient.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>WE are over.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On this, Jackie looks down at her hands.</context>
      <utterance>WE'RE still their parents for the next hundred years.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're still going to have to be dealing with me -- with us. We should tell them together.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You think this is going to help the kids then you do it. You're on your own.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The great thing about life is that things keep changing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember when Mommy and Daddy got divorced?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON ANNABELLE -- Behind the video camera -- Where's this headed?</context>
      <utterance>And we all went through that together? ON Ben. OH MY GOD. He knew it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben LEAPS up from the couch and FLIES into Jackie's arms.</context>
      <utterance>Well things are going to change again...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie looks at Luke. Annabelle ZOOMS IN on their faces.</context>
      <utterance>I knew it! I knew it! I knew you guys were getting back together!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No they're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She ZOOMS in on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Annabelle put down that camera.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put down that goddamn camera!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You owe me a quarter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look she's upset --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I'm not. I don't care. Why should I care? I mean nobody asked me when you got divorced. Nobody asked me if I wanted a new mother. Nobody even asked me if I like her. If you guys don't care about our family staying together, why sh...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy and I tried hard. We really did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben runs out of the room. Luke follows him.</context>
      <utterance>No you didn't! All you guys did was name call! I heard you! You didn't even try and use your words!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm disappearing. I'm almost invisible...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>nothing will ever change that.</context>
      <utterance>I'll find you wherever you go...my magic boy...I'm still your daddy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answers. Jackie looks at this daughter she loves so much. Pats the seat beside her...</context>
      <utterance>Annabelle...Rachel's not taking my place as your mother -- it's just Daddy's chance to be happy again. Isn't that what we all want for each other?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something in the softening of the tone changes the atmosphere in the room. More real. More like equals.</context>
      <utterance>Come. Sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't you? Annabelle nods, cautiously.</context>
      <utterance>Life is full of hard things. And we can't always have what we want, you know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we do have a choice. To make it better. Instead of worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like how?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle's stare is hard and questioning. She didn't expect this.</context>
      <utterance>Like seeing the good side of Rachel. So she'll see the good side of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I'm looking ahead. And you know what I see...? Annabelle doesn't. But she sure is listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Strokes her baby's hair.</context>
      <utterance>Time will come. When we all need to be there. For each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That happens. To families.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her mother's eyes cloud with feeling. A murmured...</context>
      <utterance>I'll be there for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm counting on it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God. Are you serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so...What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hold each other for a long time.</context>
      <utterance>I think so too...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's forever you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay...Is that the good thing or the bad thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grins.</context>
      <utterance>Because I can't hurt anyone like this ever again.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rache, it may take time.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's eight, ten years? Hell, you'll still be ambulatory. I think. She's counting on her fingers. He kisses her.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her incredible smile. Filling even Luke with confidence.</context>
      <utterance>It's inevitable. Look, I was defensive, I was insecure. I was afraid to love first.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sudden horrific CRASHING sound. The breakage of the breakable. Their look holds.</context>
      <utterance>But I'm not anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD on Luke's light smile. Maybe this</context>
      <utterance>I'll get this. A quick kiss. And she's gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you real mad?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes to his bed. Sits down.</context>
      <utterance>How could I be? We learned some magic...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. She leans toward him...</context>
      <utterance>I made all the pieces disappear.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses his forehead. Very sweetly.</context>
      <utterance>And you learned...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...to make that</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh. Put that away, hon, your mom w... The door OPENS. Jackie is dressed for riding.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry I'm late, I got lost dropping Ben off at Kevin's.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel blinks. Is she on the right planet?</context>
      <utterance>It's okay, it's twenty minutes. The horse'll be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uh-oh. The kid holds it up.</context>
      <utterance>Mom, look what Rache got me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not to wear around, or any- thing, I'm</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Who's that for?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid WHIRLS around. Really?</context>
      <utterance>Well. It's for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle starts to unwrap the present with Christmas-morning-care. Jackie looks at the glitter gloss...</context>
      <utterance>Just because. Just because I love you. Go ahead...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I just...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. At least it's not an editing machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And stops. Because the paper has come off. A giant deluxe model beginner's VIDEO EDITOR. Annabelle is STUNNED silent. So's Rachel.</context>
      <utterance>No way. I told her two, three years, maybe, for such an expens...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And JUMPS into Jackie's arms, CRUSHING her with the hug mothers live for.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mommy...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope it's the right kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's like still a kid, herself.</context>
      <utterance>...I mean, she knows all the music, and pop stars, and clothes and stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a big sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks to see if her mom is okay hearing...</context>
      <utterance>She knows every neat junk food place.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually. She's kind of cool, when you get to know her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle studies her mom's profile.</context>
      <utterance>I bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And don't tell her I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Secret's safe with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rache says I have to eat big spaghetti.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nurse enters, and Jackie shoots her with a wave of her fingers.</context>
      <utterance>And many meatballs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be up to your armpits in meatballs, I'm flying them in from Sweden.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She loves this kid so much.</context>
      <utterance>Is that like Luigi's?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like Canada. Only smaller.</context>
      <utterance>Not a lot, sweetie. It's a country.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the feeling comes straight to her eyes. She can't fight it.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm somewhere, thinking of you. And meatballs. And you know what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, you do. Being magic. Then you know I've got a flu bug, and I turn green and barf profusely when I even think about food. So, all the more meatballs for you. But you know what.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daddy didn't cook it, she did.</context>
      <utterance>I did. Do I have to eat lamb?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs. And she can hear that. And her eyes fill. And she murmurs...</context>
      <utterance>Do me a favor? Eat it, and then give me a secret report, okay? Pay particular attention to whether it's chewy and if it tastes more like chocolate or soup.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A silence. And for a heartbeat, the fear. Did he hear it in my voice? But no...</context>
      <utterance>Hey, that's a world-class laugh you got there. Can I all you sometime? If I fell blue.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now she's crying. But she can't. She can't. Gains control for a whispered...</context>
      <utterance>Sure. You got my number.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That I do. Always will.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sniffles...</context>
      <utterance>Mom...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine, ba...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>See her relief. Secret still safe.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow? Can I have one butterscotch pudding for dessert?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's crestfallen.</context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can only have two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy, if your real name's Jackie and I call you mommy; and Rachel's real name's Rachel...Then when I see her do I say hi Stepmommy? And if my name's Ben, how come you don't call me son?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frustrated, Ben CLIMBS OUT of the cart and trails behind Jackie. He reaches for an apple off the BOTTOM of a huge display of Red Delicious, and the whole thing comes TUMBLING DOWN. Shaken, she looks around for Ben. He's gone.</context>
      <utterance>Thursday's fine...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just one second...he's...he's...</context>
      <utterance>I looked away for one second...</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How would you describe him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's my son! He looks like his father! His name is Ben -- he answers to Harry --</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The manager POINTS to the frozen food bin. There, lying on his back atop dwindling stores of Breyer's ice cream...is Ben. Hands and beaming face PRESSED to the underside of the glass. Jackie does the only reasonable thing...</context>
      <utterance>Is he wearing a red shirt?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Enough of a non-sequitur to make everybody blink, before Jackie YANKS him, roughly and tenderly, from the bin. She CRUSHES him in a violent, desperate hug...</context>
      <utterance>Nope. I got my warm t-shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You found me cause I'm your</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the bleachers, Jackie sits alone with Rachel. They are having a coaching session of their own. Rachel points down to the field, where... ...Annabelle pushes her hair over her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Alright my Little Warriors, remain calm; trust that the ball will find you; remember they're your opponent not your enemies -- Not kick MAJOR butt!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie casts a sidelong glance at Rachel. Decides to tell her...</context>
      <utterance>She's gonna trip over her own feet, if she doesn't get her hair out of her eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel looks over. Really? Jackie decides to share more. Reading Rachel's reaction to...</context>
      <utterance>Pushing her hair over her eyes. Means she's avoiding a confrontation.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Rachel listens she's unconsciously twisting her hair.</context>
      <utterance>If she's twirling it, she's playing something out in her mind. If she's stopped combing it, she might be depressed...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about obsessively picking her split ends?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anxiety.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last week when she chopped her Barbie's bangs all to hell --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was angry at herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jackie?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie gives her the trace of a smile.</context>
      <utterance>When I twisted hair like this it means I'm intimidated by you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks back down at the game. Rachel watching her profile. Finally...</context>
      <utterance>I'll keep it in mind, and use it against you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feeling all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Things. Rachel doesn't know. Blurts...</context>
      <utterance>Not great. Plus, I've got things on my mind. You know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie snorts a laugh. In spite of herself.</context>
      <utterance>Are you...seeing someone?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, that</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Jackie still hasn't turned. Eyes glued to Annabelle, racing around with determination.</context>
      <utterance>Wowie. How wonderful!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sighs. Boy, this is tough. Tries for matter-of-fact...</context>
      <utterance>Well, I could do most of it from home. But, while I'm working it out with the head editor, I'd need to...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sometimes, overnight.</context>
      <utterance>...make some trips into the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie nods. Appreciates that. But she</context>
      <utterance>Hey, any help you need, we'll cover.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little strange. Particularly the hardness of Jackie's eyes. Rachel watching her. Something's up.</context>
      <utterance>Let's...hold up for a bit. It may not happen. Our secret, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can still go to Tucker's party, right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...for Christmas, okay? Every magician needs a white dove, a real one, they do!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We'll talk to Mom and Dad...</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's a long way off, sweetie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unseen by the two, Luke grins. Then, Ben snuggles into Rachel's arms and kisses her. Jackie stares.</context>
      <utterance>Dad! You can talk him into anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'In the still...still of the ni-ight...I held you... held you so ti-ight'...take it, man...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doo-wop-doo-doo,</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He give her a goofy give-me-a-break FACE. She twists the corner of a smile.</context>
      <utterance>It is. It's about time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a charmer, you'll see. In fifty years, the kids'll love her ten percent as much as they love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now they're smiling at each other. In the old way. A nice moment for them.</context>
      <utterance>Stop. You're making me insecure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And we notice. It does look different.</context>
      <utterance>You changed your hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's temporary.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her look holds. An odd extra beat.</context>
      <utterance>It's good. You're not pulling a mid-life crisis on us, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances back through the doorway...</context>
      <utterance>Not the term I'd use.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want us to take him tonight? Give you some private time with Annab....</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never stand between that kid and a meatball.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yet another spaghetti night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pats him on the shoulder...</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, better I should forcefeed him burnt lamb and...couscous, was it she made him? Boy, kids go wild for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And breezes by him into the room. Ben wheels to see her...</context>
      <utterance>I'll drop him at Tucker's party Saturday, if one of you guys can pick him up. I have to go into the City.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He really thinks.  Actually...</context>
      <utterance>You know what happens to spaghetti when it waits around for you too long?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pray. We never find out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm here to pick up Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does Jackie know this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm doing it behind her back.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where is she?</context>
      <utterance>In seven years Jackie's never missed one of Tucker's parties.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've got a shoot at three...</context>
      <utterance>Something came up. C'mon Ben!</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel eyes the MOUND OF PRESENTS yet to be opened. DISSOLVE TO... FORTY-FIVE MINUTES LATER...Rachel, in a pointed party hat, sits schmushed on the couch in between all the other MOTHERS. A black jeans stranger in a strange peach land. She eyes that mound of presents. Not even a dent. She pulls out her cell phone, moves towards the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Tucker hasn't penned Ben's present yet -- it won't be too much longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A piece of CAKE FLIES through the air and LANDS on Rachel.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Cooper...pull a number 64 steel blue gel on the back light...yeah I'm on my way but...</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben won't let go of Tucker's presents. Tucker tries to take it. Ben is adamant. Rachel reaches for him, tousling his hair.</context>
      <utterance>Now Ben, let Tucker play with his Batcave...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mothers are all too aware of Rachel on the phone. Two kids shoot water guns -- Rachel gets drenched. Ben pulls at the toys...</context>
      <utterance>Hey Benjy boy -- chill.  He's there already? No I don't want to talk to him -- Duncan? How are you...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want it!</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben and Tucker fight for it -- the mothers all LOOK TO RACHEL.</context>
      <utterance>Ben I know you're angry and confused but it's Tucker's birthday party.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Duncan I'm aware of that - Goddamn it Ben! Let go of it. NOW! He stares at her. It looks like he's gonna let go -- On the mothers -- impressed, not to mention surprised. When Ben suddenly HURLS the toy onto the floor SHATTERING IT! A horrible SILENCE falls over the room. Broken only by the sound of Duncan SCREAMING from inside the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Ben --</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN IN PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel takes Ben and leads him into another room.</context>
      <utterance>Rachel...This is a big bloody account -- If you don't show up in five minutes...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She SLAMS the phone SHUT. Hands it to Ben.</context>
      <utterance>Ben I'm sorry. It's been a hard day. Now would you do us both a favor and take this phone and...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Okay. He SHOVES it down the front of his pants. The peach moms are taken aback. Rachel nods, you got it. Delighted, Ben turns, scampers off, as... ...his pants start RINGING. He stops dead. Looks down at them. Still RINGING. He turns around and waddles delicately back to Rachel, as if he's carrying nitro in his shorts. She holds out her hand...</context>
      <utterance>...make it disappear.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Breaks out the geiger counter, the man is</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT throughout: a starchy, powerful, crisply intellectual SENIOR EDITOR, in her early fifties and her Jil Sander outfit. The East Side below her window.</context>
      <utterance>...just that her daughter left a science book somewhere at her house, and I need t...</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Ms. Harrison is</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss, I</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. If Jackie Harrison were coming back to the editorial staff, I would be frankly delighted. And I. Would be the first. To know. Silence. In the midst of hysterical children.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you for your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR EDITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Rachel's line. Is dead.</context>
      <utterance>Don't mention it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OPENS the door. Enters the empty home. Walks slowly, self- consciously, down the hallway. Kitchen, kids' rooms...</context>
      <utterance>What the hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And stops. At the doorway of the master bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Now, if I were a science book, where would I...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And goes straight to Jackie's desk. Starts rummaging through the incredibly neat stack of papers...</context>
      <utterance>Who am I kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The open appointment book. Today's date. Just says, NEW YORK. Nothing more. Opens a drawer. Stapler, clips, neatly-stacked stationery. Opens the bottom drawer, and... ...stops. She pulls out...AIRLINE TICKETS. Opens the folder. Continental Airlines. Newark to San Francisco. And tucked inside... ...a fax, neatly folded. Rachel opens it. The letterhead says, NORTH POINT PRESS, 134 Sutter Street, San Francisco, California. CHARLENE DRUMMOND, Editor.</context>
      <utterance>Great, I'm leaving prints.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD on Rachel. Trying to put this together.</context>
      <utterance>Jackie. Can't wait to see you here. I know you're anxious. But it's going to work out wonderfully, I promise. Til then. Charlie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="47">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And before she can sit...</context>
      <utterance>Okay, what is this? If you want to dump Luke on me, no sale. You're stuck with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie FREEZES. To stone. No one says anything. Two hearts beating at red-line.</context>
      <utterance>I know your secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know wh...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>My what? Jackie leans forward. Her hands resting on the back of the chair she never sat in.</context>
      <utterance>I was looking for Annabelle's book, and I found your tickets. And the note. From your new boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not working at Random House, I talked to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You WHAT?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Jackie has to laugh. Cold. Bitter.</context>
      <utterance>You're taking the kids. And moving to San Francisco.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you've never liked me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't flatter yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I know checking into your life was inexcusable...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody likes a snoop.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the air comes out of this young woman. so vulnerable, so real.</context>
      <utterance>But I came here to...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And at this. A look of intense interest crosses Jackie's face. Really?</context>
      <utterance>...to beg you. Not to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd have thought this was the answer to your prayers. Lose the witch, and her two brats, in one swoop. Problems solved. Rachel is clearly distraught. This is no act.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie thinking. Reading this girl's face.</context>
      <utterance>You can't take Luke's children away from him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bi-coastal parenting. Happens every day. Luke gets the kids every other summer, every other holiday, it's not ideal, but people make it work, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Jackie straightens. Cocks her head.</context>
      <utterance>We can't live like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I hear the word...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah.</context>
      <utterance>Luke. Can't live like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then let him talks to me. We don't need you to solve our prob...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Rachel's eyes. Fill with tears. She hates that. Jackie won't take her off the hook. Stands waiting, until...</context>
      <utterance>...it's my problem, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As...my kids too.</context>
      <utterance>I got used to...thinking of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel lifts her chin. Defiant and tender at once.</context>
      <utterance>Really. By what right? Six months of part-time screw-ups?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now it's Jackie's eyes. That begin to fill. And she hates that even more.</context>
      <utterance>No right at all. I just love them.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An odd, almost defiant look. Jackie reaches up to her own head, and... ...slowly, holding eye contact all the way, she slips the wig from her head. Her scalp covered by the partial regrowth that chemo- therapy has left her. You can hear Rachel's GASP clear to Kansas.</context>
      <utterance>You're a moron, kid. You guessed the wrong secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel's lips part. But no sound comes.</context>
      <utterance>Charlie Drummond used to be a colleague at Random House. I'm crashing at her place, while I take some new protein injections my oncologist recommended. I can only get them in San Francisco.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life's a trade-off. You get cancer, your hair falls out, but you do get to smoke dope.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid so painfully sincere.</context>
      <utterance>You're not dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel can't find her breath. She is clearly the worse off of the two, in this moment. Then she starts to nod...</context>
      <utterance>No such luck. I'm beating the shit out of this. Pardon my French.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell would you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That leaves a silence.</context>
      <utterance>How would you know I've got cancer!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And cigarettes. I smoke, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Comes forward. Stalks her.</context>
      <utterance>And you. Love my kids. How fucking touching.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They came out of my body!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have given them more</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And staring in Rachel's eyes, Jackie's fierceness fades.</context>
      <utterance>Ironic, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the air comes out. Her heart as naked as her skull.</context>
      <utterance>Ironic, that I'm gonna need you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The look holds. And holds.</context>
      <utterance>To be a little less. Undeserving.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And turns, goes to the door. Turns back.</context>
      <utterance>Drink your tea while I go vomit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And gone. Hear her footsteps. Climbing stairs. Rachel lifts her cup. Looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>You love my kids, that's a start.  We'll work on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then tastes it. Makes a face.</context>
      <utterance>This is very good tea!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one smiles at the irony. Not much to smile about.</context>
      <utterance>I thought a phone call was inappropriate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He loos up. She studies the pain.</context>
      <utterance>I could have taken you to that restaurant, but it would have been a waste of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I wouldn't know what to say. If it were you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to win this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears fill his eyes. None in hers.</context>
      <utterance>Walk in the park. And thanks for the 'we'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie swallows. Tries a smile that doesn't get halfway there. Looks down.</context>
      <utterance>You're not alone in this. You're not alone. Jesus, you're not alone, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens next?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks straight in his eyes. We don't need the bullshit. Not us.</context>
      <utterance>I live or I die.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She thinks. A barely perceptible nod.</context>
      <utterance>Tell the kids together?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On that one. She has to smile.</context>
      <utterance>Want Rache someplace else?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My compliments. On your learning curve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's up? Who's marrying who this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's happy. Jackie reaches and shuts OFF Annabelle's camera. And the directness in her gaze keeps the child from complaining.</context>
      <utterance>Mommy's marrying Rache!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy's sick, guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have the WORST flu since...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't. Someone else does.</context>
      <utterance>I have cancer. Do you know what that is?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is your bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the anger in her eyes isn't for Ben. She is glaring. At her mom.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up. She's going to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Straight. As if to an equal, an adult.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, I'm getting better already.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a lot of treatments, and they weren't any fun, but the tests show the cancer got smaller.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle cuts him an angry look. He's on her shit list, too.</context>
      <utterance>A lot smaller.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm still sick, but I'm better.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know how scared</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We make mistakes. And we forgive each other. Because we love each other, very m...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Rache? It's Thursday, we get to be with Rache!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd rather be with Mommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do NOT run out on your moth...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YOU'RE WORSE THAN</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I think you should tell him you changed your mi...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's still watching. It's a French-language comedy. She can feel his eyes on her. Never turns...</context>
      <utterance>It's no biggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just an assignment.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Anna Sui, you should be doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's still never looked at him. He can see she's getting irritat- ed. He says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Are you hungry? You could make us something?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her hair and flinches slightly. Tries to pretend it's because she's concentrating on the movie.</context>
      <utterance>It's two solid months, around the clock, Jackie needs some cover- age, you're in a trial, what are we talking about? There'll be other assignments.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're my kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great, wallow in guilt, you</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From across the room. Jackie stares at her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry you're sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't hear you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They grin at each other. Like equals. Jackie picks up the remote, cuts OFF the sound. And when Ben turns to her...</context>
      <utterance>...I'm not deaf, y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the still...still of the ni-ight...I held you...held you so ti-ight...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Rache's song!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wow? Really? You bet. Annabelle chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>Sugar. I was slow dancing to that song before Rachel was even born.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie shakes her head. Pulls down the covers, pulls up her t-shirt...</context>
      <utterance>You think she's the Queen of Cool?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The butterfly. Just below her navel. Ben has seen this before, of course. Touches it, with his small hand.</context>
      <utterance>Does she have a tattoo?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wouldn't know. I saw her in the shower!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben looks to his sister. For the verdict. Annabelle shakes her head. Nope.</context>
      <utterance>And...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is only the Princess of Cool. Mommy is the Queen!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A new word, apparently.</context>
      <utterance>She is but an arriviste.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle nods. You betcha.</context>
      <utterance>A newcomer. She's still got a thing or two to learn.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bumps head gently with Ben.</context>
      <utterance>I held you...held you so ti-ight...  You sing lead, you've got the voice...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as they doo-wop the back-up...</context>
      <utterance>The stud and I will doo-wop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>promise I'll never...Let you go...</context>
      <utterance>For I love...lo-ove you soooo...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE/JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the still of the ni-ight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Small world.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To prove it, she balances the cookies on her thighs, and produces a notebook. Looks around, and in a conspiratorial near-whisper...</context>
      <utterance>Luke's depo ran late. I promised I'd take notes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I have to tell you something in confidence...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a cross-dresser.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Does a Groucho eyebrow move.</context>
      <utterance>That. And. Annabelle is over her head. With Brad 'The Dreamboat' Kovitsky.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She hasn't mentioned this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie is hurt. Covers...</context>
      <utterance>She was afraid you'd make a big deal out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moi?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel breathless and happy. Jackie attentive.</context>
      <utterance>Toi. They've been 'going out' for two weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you may know, 'going out' in the six grade doesn't mean shit. They don't actually</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway. He walks up to her on lunch yard today. And tells her... publicly...that they're 'breaking up.' Jackie's mouth drops.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my God.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Which is the whole</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you said...?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh.</context>
      <utterance>Beats me. Ask your mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leans closer. Whispers...</context>
      <utterance>So she's gonna. Tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't fuck this up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, did you really think you'd meet someone at</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's Thursd...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ms. Flannery is twisted.</context>
      <utterance>A debate. Man's inhumanity to woman. He's pro women. I'm con.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could help with the debate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually. I could only help him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every time I'm on the lunch yard, and he's with twelve of his retarded dorkface little adoring out-crowd henchmen...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't like his friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...they all yell 'There goes the Virgin Queen' or the 'Ice Princess', or some</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not with my mouth open.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle's eyes well up. She covers by concentrating all the harder.</context>
      <utterance>Good girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do you do wh...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I call him a fartface or a pervert, or something equally lame.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And on this. Annabelle looks up.</context>
      <utterance>You have to ignore him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not even there. You don't see him, you don't hear him, you're just too much of a woman to bother with little boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie shakes her head. Nope.</context>
      <utterance>This is a joke, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kid blinks.</context>
      <utterance>All he wants is the attention. When he can't get to you, he'll try harder for a little while. Then, he'll give up. It'll be no fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takes Mom back a bit. Enough for her daughter to notice.</context>
      <utterance>You think Rache would do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie shrugs. Maybe. Annabelle studies her.</context>
      <utterance>It's just she's younger. Maybe she remembers how to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This'll work, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle takes heart from her mom's confidence. Nods, with her trademark determination.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many devilled eggs can you eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie surveys the table.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sudden BANGING on the screen door. They turn to see... ...a breathless six-year-old TUCKER through the screen. The birthday boy at the recent party.</context>
      <utterance>We can always go to the store, if w...</utterance>
   <speaker>TUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Harrison...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tucker, is something wr...</utterance>
   <speaker>TUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How tall is your tree? The really, really, really, REALLY big...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uh.</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>TUCKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How bad would it hurt? If you fell off the top?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An enormous CRANE moves through the sky. Jackie holds tightly onto JESSICA, a diminutive five-foot-tall Firewoman, as they soar skyward towards Ben. A slightly condescending tone to...</context>
      <utterance>Don't move! SMASH CUT TO LATER, as...</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patronized the wrong gal. In a crisis.</context>
      <utterance>That's quite a grip you have there Ma'am. Do we have an issue with heights?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care if you're a dwarf, so long as you do your job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JESSICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma'am, my arm's going numb, maybe you could loosen your grip just a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's absolutely out of the question.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>JESSICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben tries to climb a little higher -- Branches SNAP.</context>
      <utterance>Hello Ben. Your mother says you're real good at disappearing --</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben! Mommy's so glad to see you -- Now stop climbing!  Ben listen to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I have to get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where Ben?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben where do you have to get to?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie's heart breaks, unable to speak.</context>
      <utterance>Heaven. I have to tell him he's made a mistake. He should take Grammy Martha first. Or Grandpa Norman.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben. God doesn't like visitors.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does this twenty times a day.</context>
      <utterance>Ask her, she's a heroic Fireperson.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jessica begins to crawl out to him on the limb.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeh. It's in our official manual.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>between heaven and earth.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, Ben. That's why Firemen have giant ladders and climb up and down poles. They're like... messengers... carrier pigeons...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good cause we need to hurry. My mom doesn't have very much time left.</utterance>
   <speaker>JESSICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you know what we should do? We should go to the Fire Station together and ring the firebell to get God's attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben opens his arms, teeters, and Jessica HAS him. She reaches him out, and... ...HANDS him to Jackie, alone in the cherry-picker. Jackie GRASPS Ben, pulling him FIERCELY to her arms in a death grip. From down below, the kids CHEER. The worst is over. HOLD on Jackie, clutching her baby for dear life. Knowing it isn't.</context>
      <utterance>Cause it's an emergency.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A slow ragged breath.</context>
      <utterance>God...I will do anything...I will go through any amount of pain you give me. If you'll just let me see them grow up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves the room soundlessly. Ben stirs.</context>
      <utterance>Is that asking so damn much?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annabelle...wake up honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom? What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie sits on the edge of the bed, stroking Annabelle's head.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing sweetheart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle's puzzled look. Why would you do that?</context>
      <utterance>I got Ginny Weintraub to come stay with Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you like to go someplace special with me? Right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She KICKS the horse forward and they HEAD OFF toward the rolling hills in the distance. Jackie and Annabelle ride faster and faster along the trail. Jackie has one arm firmly around Annabelle's waist and controls the horse with the other. Jackie closes her eyes for a moment, allowing the wind to wash over her. The smells and sounds of the night seem to free her, give her strength. Annabelle relaxes against her mother and giggles with delight. Jackie soon joins her, and the sounds of their laughter break the silence of the night. They come to a stop at the crest of a small hill and we now see the tears on Jackie's face. Annabelle can't see, and stares out at the moonlit valley before them.</context>
      <utterance>Hold tight, sweetheart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle snuggles back. Happy.</context>
      <utterance>I'm never, never going to forget this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie kisses the top of her baby's head.</context>
      <utterance>Never say never.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're old enough to learn the loophole.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>OPEN UP.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So he does. Gives her a sweet hug.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He enters behind her. SCOOPS his body in the air.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Remember me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen up. That's a pretty big love you're givin' my best girl, pard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen sideways.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, gorgeous, where's Big Mama? No answer. Annabelle worried about something.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She still packing for her trip?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I not in front of the menfolk.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle frowns at Mom's name. Rachel strokes her. Heads down the hall... Knocks at the open door to Jackie's bedroom, where Jackie is calmly, meticulously, laying out things beside her large open suitcase. She waves Rachel in, and keeps working.</context>
      <utterance>We'll talk. I'll go check on Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bulky sweaters. Wool things.</context>
      <utterance>It's gonna be cool, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel and we have a better angle now. Jackie looks awful. Drawn, weak, masking pain with obvious courage.</context>
      <utterance>I can never figure weather. Last trip, I made all the wrong choices.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel sits on the edge of the bed. Jackie turns away, goes to her open chest of drawers.</context>
      <utterance>Bad day?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even her voice is carefully under control. Awkward, Rachel looks around the room. A stack of photo albums, scrapbooks, open. Works in progress.</context>
      <utterance>Can't complain.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I look at the pictures?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So quiet, we can hear a clock TICKING nearby. Rachel's gaze returns to the bulky sweaters. Holds there.</context>
      <utterance>It's a mess, right now. That's my project when I get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like you obviously figured out.</context>
      <utterance>See, I'm not going to Houston, after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two women nodding, in a calm, matter-of-fact way. As if discussing recipes.</context>
      <utterance>There's this clinic in Montreal. We've studied their process, we like their success rate...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>They combine some compounds that have been getting results in France, with vitamin injections. Seems to activate the chemo...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. Hopeful.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel swallows. She's out of words.</context>
      <utterance>It's promising, this one. We're upbeat.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really look like shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>together. Mentally tough.</context>
      <utterance>You look sick. But you look...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shrug. The first bitterness to seep through.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, that's bull. I'm going for serene, they say some actually get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits, unceremoniously, right on the floor. Pantomimes a smoke. Rachel goes into her bag.</context>
      <utterance>Prob'ly low percentage on mothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You try to center on the big issues, y'know. What it's all about. What this whole trip has meant. But then, the really big issues keep swamping y...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tosses Jackie a pack. Matches next.</context>
      <utterance>Brad Kovitsky.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel's eyebrows head north.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have any pot, I s'pose?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The primo stuff is great for pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think my 'primo shit' got left in my 'bellbottoms.' Jackie lighting up. Deep soulful drag.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reading Rachel's face. Who is already wincing.</context>
      <utterance>So. She ignores this little Kovitsky punk, takes the high moral ground...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's relentless. A major asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you said...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. Rachel tries to hide her disappointment.</context>
      <utterance>What else? Keep on keepin' on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Half a beat. Rachel shakes her head, nope.</context>
      <utterance>She has to stick with it. Have the patience, the guts, to ignore the pain. You disagree?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. You oughta know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She is entering, peeling off her jacket. Tired as hell.</context>
      <utterance>God, sorry I'm so late...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duncan is doing his Himmler imitation on this gig. I got yelled at for quitting at really sorry look...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wow. They lock eyes in the bond of 'what are we gonna do?'</context>
      <utterance>I've got a morning plane to Boston for the depo. Back Sunday night.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses Ben's head, Luke's mouth, that one lingering a little. Then, down the hall to... ...the kitchen. Annabelle sits with her homework stacked, untouched. Staring out the dark window. Clearly, this is worse than death.</context>
      <utterance>I made that paella you liked. It's on the stove.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle TURNS like a hunted animal...</context>
      <utterance>Lemme guess. A bad hair day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She told me to</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told her if she pulled</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Keep RINGING. Rachel checks her watch. Shit.</context>
      <utterance>Specially not in this family.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Annabelle BREAKS LOOSE from Rachel's arms and BOLTS out of the room. Rachel watching in despair. Lifts the phone on the sixth ring...</context>
      <utterance>Nine o'clock. That could be your mom from Montreal. Now you need t...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT throughout: Jackie in a hospital gown. At the window of her room, rain pouring down on Montreal.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. How's the vitamins up there? Having big fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eat your heart out. Is Annabelle there?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, she's...I'll get you Ben first, it's past his bedti...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>How's she doing with Brad?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I say one thing? I mean, the</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yah? Well, even the best mom in the world, the smartest, the wisest, whatever. Needs to know when to find a Plan B. Cos Plan A is not and will n...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annabelle, I know you miss your mother. So why don't you say hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you say hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annabelle pick up the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annabelle pick up the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't bother me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't bother me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think this is funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think this is funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I think it's ugly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just a</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When they</context>
      <utterance>You know when girls grow into women?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT throughout: Jackie at her clinic window. Cellular at her ear.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Mom. How are you feeling? As Rachel leaves, silently, we...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darling, I've been thinking about our little Brad problem? And I think it's time we move to Plan B...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cannot straight up to that little jerk...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And bring my knees up, real hard, yeh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nodding to herself. Knows this is right.</context>
      <utterance>No, that never solves anything. You talk like the big girl you are. About what you feel. And how he's hurt you. You know? You tell the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You use your words.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And starts WALKING OFF down the tunnel. Duncan looks at his watch, then JUMPS up, TEARS after Rachel, GRABBING her arm, SPINNING her around, he faces... ...someone ready for this.</context>
      <utterance>I love you guys. You're animals!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's 1:45, I told you there's no one to pick up Annab...</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're not</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her glare says do NOT fuck with me. The mother lion look we've seen on Jackie.</context>
      <utterance>We don't KNOW if you've got it, we haven't SEEN it yet! Now go back and FINISH!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which part of no don't you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I will</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're making a career decision here, I would strongly sugg...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duncan. I've got an</utterance>
   <speaker>DUNCAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do that, I won't let you!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no, this is a job that's hard to</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, baby, I'm so sor...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>IT'S NOT YOUR</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And wraps her arms around the girl...</context>
      <utterance>That's because men can be scum, your precious father excepted, may you live to find one like him, it is damn hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now is that little prick still here, because if he is, I'm gonna rip his fucking heart out!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, his mother's always on time. Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Mom says anger never, never</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle stops crying. This is what she has prayed for.</context>
      <utterance>If I tell you what to do. Can we cut a deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leans close...</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow is Friday, your mom comes home. You tell her you did what she said. It didn't work yet. But you're gonna talk to Brad again on Monday.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, baby. You're gonna use</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nope. None.</context>
      <utterance>Does he have zitz? We can call him Pizza Face.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help me here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh. He thinks his nose is too big. But it's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Big ears, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shows how.</context>
      <utterance>No. But they stand out, a little. Like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel stands up. Walks in circle, thinking. Comes back. Strikes a pose.</context>
      <utterance>Done. He's a dead man.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finger STABS out...</context>
      <utterance>Monday lunch, you walk up with attitude, you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey,</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. It's an incredibly disgusting, and not remotely sexy thing, that they described in a movie I'd never let you go to. But it's real. Does he have an older brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In high school.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll be impressed. The clincher is, you walk away, then whip around... Like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The guy</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've had the worst day. Till now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FLIGHT ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie GRIPS the wheel, STOPPING them. Stares, frozen, as across the way...three faces stare back.</context>
      <utterance>We'll get your bags, and the taxis are just...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Jackie LEAPS out of the wheelchair, RUNS across the distance, runs to SCOOP her babies in her arms...</context>
      <utterance>Surprise?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle laughs. Ben covers Jackie with kisses. Rachel watches. From the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>It's a miracle! I can walk!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. These are good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She know he did. Looks across the room at Rachel. No more words.</context>
      <utterance>I helped.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie sighs. Smiles down at him.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go to the park!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a lot of medicine in me, sweetie. And I'm a little wobbly for driving or running ar...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie absorbs that. And all it portends.</context>
      <utterance>Rache can do that part.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hon, maybe your mom would like t...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>...go to the park. In the worst way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, with Rachel driving. That's how we'll go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie doesn't answer for a beat. Almost as if she hasn't heard.</context>
      <utterance>Serene. You're getting the hang of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Serene means you accept.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watching the world of moms and kids. Who are not terrified.</context>
      <utterance>Part of me hasn't quit yet. And the other part is still pretty outraged.  When it's not terrified.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking. Do I know you well enough to really chew you out?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie turns to her. Diamond laser glare...</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you lost your</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do what you've worked your whole life to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was just a job, there'll be plenty of others.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you?</context>
      <utterance>You mean, after I'm dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you haven't quit on you, I'm sure as hell not gonna. I just mean, I'm juggling a lot right n...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juggle it! Move the darkroom into your house. You've got that room downstairs with the treadmill Luke never uses anyway. Don't lose your confidence. Don't lose your edge.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the same choice you made.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reading Rachel's face.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I made the choice that was right for me. And I don't regret it. But even for me, there were days when I felt so lost, so invis- ible. And then I'd hate myself for the kids not being enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you, huh? The car pools, he measles, the PTA. It's not gonna be enough for you in the long run. You have to think long term.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to spend time with them when I'm not rushing or on the phone or tired or...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They</context>
      <utterance>That's motherhood. That's the job, with or without a career. I'm telling you the biggest gift you can give them is your happiness.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Glances over.</context>
      <utterance>That's the bottom line, isn't it? I can't make a mistake. Because it'll screw your kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My advice to you? Don't die.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel's eyes move across Jackie's face. Then, out to Ben, on the distant swings.</context>
      <utterance>Feeling the pressure?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last time</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watches Rachel nodding, absorbing.</context>
      <utterance>Ben was born in two hours, went right to my breast and camped there for three days. Always with this...mischievous look...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somehow, his blanket always looked like a cape, even the nurse said that. He</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watches the feeling well in Rachel's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Took 28 hours. She just wasn't sure about entering this world.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel nods. It fits.</context>
      <utterance>The doctor wanted to go in and get her, but I knew she'd come in her own time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. A murmur...</context>
      <utterance>That's who she is. Don't let anybody rush her.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel settles back. Her eyes now locked away somewhere private.</context>
      <utterance>I'll keep that in mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rache smiles. That Jackie sensed something.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks over. Decides whether to ask...</context>
      <utterance>It's not about the kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That thing you said before. Pushing the guy sleeping next to you away. Because of what you gave up for motherhood...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what he told you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A trace of edge to Jackie's smile. But no real anger.</context>
      <utterance>He won't discuss it. Just calls it history.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking. Looking.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he got that part right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An urgency in that.</context>
      <utterance>So what's the part he got wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got all day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a great surpri...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And from her face. She means every word.</context>
      <utterance>Hold your applause. We're not having fun, here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Great. Just what she wants to hear.</context>
      <utterance>Is Jack okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah. A beat. To assess the damage.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeh, she was cracking me up. Dishing details of her sordid little divorce.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hey...</context>
      <utterance>And you freaked. A little.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like to make sure. That your past. And my future. Are real different.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they will be.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs. Jesus.</context>
      <utterance>Imagine my relief. So what's for dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why in the world would she t...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Liked it so much, you took another.</context>
      <utterance>You took a fishing trip with the boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I needed some time away.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...while she watched the kids. Then, you booked this flat in Paris for your family's summer. But she said...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It did. People are passing them. They do not notice.</context>
      <utterance>'...the kids have camp. Their friends are here. Over there, I'll just be shopping in a language I don't even know. My life, and the kids' lives, aren't here to service your mid-life crisis.' Did it go like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She called it a fight. The fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around. People are moving on. Toward their drinks, their dinners, their lives.</context>
      <utterance>What do you call it? You told her you had doubts.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we go sit somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And takes out her cigarettes. Her fingers fumble slightly. It isn't the cold.</context>
      <utterance>Let me put it this way. Hell, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told her I loved her.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By way of saying you were unhappy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Restless.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. 'Things are so confusing for me, Jack. Our life feels too comfortable, too safe, too predict- able. It's a partnership, it's juggling schedules. When I think of playing that out, every day, for the rest of my life...' Dead at his eyes. And he nods. Once.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'...I don't know if I can make it.' That's what I said. But I didn't leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pulls out her box of matches.</context>
      <utterance>No, she threw you out. What a difficult woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So now I get to wait... A single match...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the first sign. The first</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, here's ugly. 'I love</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not us.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his hands on her, gently. But she flinches. So the hands come away.</context>
      <utterance>Because you've changed so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I can't. She searches the lovelight in his eyes. As if she could weigh it.</context>
      <utterance>You want me to show you the future. Well, I can't darlin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is only a hope.</context>
      <utterance>We make our lives, one step at a time. We do the best we can. The truth about the future? A promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about the promises we make to our kids? About</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takes a step back. Only one. But it registers.</context>
      <utterance>You got one less for dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you goin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nods, to herself.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna get me a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she walks off. Slow.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm gonna drink it alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really didn't have to come, you know. I'd have brought them straight t...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who in the world</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Across the way, the boy leans, kisses Annabelle sweetly on the cheek. Waves to her. Peddles off. In distance, kids are dying. Annabelle pretends not to know that. Just walks casually toward us, but as she approaches, she can't help breaking into a RUN, straight... ...into RACHEL'S ARMS.</context>
      <utterance>He looks familiar. Did he do a Calvin Klein ad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It workeditworkedit</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we're going to have a fight, you and I.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm going to win.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No anger in Jackie at this moment. The ferocity of that mother lion. The strongest face we'll ever see.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be too sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is 'snowballing'?</context>
      <utterance>Now, 'limp dick', I know. What.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter, I didn't tell h...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because there'll be, oh, 20 or 30 mothers phoning me in the next hour or so. And they'll b...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie on the prowl around this swing. Stalking her prey.</context>
      <utterance>Give 'em my number.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually. They'll want Annabelle's mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking bad at the PTA?</context>
      <utterance>Is that what you're worried about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are defending what you did?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not quite what Jackie expected.</context>
      <utterance>Right down to the ground. Let's get to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You put filth in my child's mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had her lie about that... that fancy-boy model!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie cannot even</context>
      <utterance>Worked. Like a charm. believe this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was beaten, and bloodied, and it was going to go on, uni...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Straightening her spine...</context>
      <utterance>So you became the hero. And I became the schmuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You taught my child that I am some limp dick</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe real growth.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's what parenting is</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've turned her into you. And I may not get another chance. To turn her back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thinks. Really thinks. Wants so much to say this right.</context>
      <utterance>All year long, I've been watching how you do this. The worries, the sacri- fices, the signals you give them...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks up. Straight to her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>And I admire you. More than you'll ever believe. And yet...this... thing...has been growing. Inside me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And so she stands up. The swing shimmies in her wake.</context>
      <utterance>For better or worse. I'm not you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sets the beer down. Stabs out her smoke.</context>
      <utterance>I can't live my life channeling the One True Mom after you're gone. I can't do it. I can't do it. I can't. Do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And walks off, slowly. Across the yard.</context>
      <utterance>We have to deal with that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>See him now. Standing awkwardly, against the side of a stall.</context>
      <utterance>It was like telling her...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>See the horse, still steaming. Standing patiently.</context>
      <utterance>...that I didn't love her anymore...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Circling the horse now, we see Annabelle's back. She is slowly brushing out the sweat mark. Where the saddle used to be. Her movements are stiff, mechanical. The soft voice continues...</context>
      <utterance>...if I could be sure I'd always stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Our ANGLE CIRCLING to see at last Annabelle's face...</context>
      <utterance>She said, 'This thing you call a partnership. The schedules, the chores, all the things we have to work out...'</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The tears that stand in her eyes. The set line of her small mouth.</context>
      <utterance>'...for the kids.'</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'...that's the life I dreamed of. And it's all I ever wanted it to be.' She swallows. Because she will not cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Annabelle says nothing. She drops to her knees. Begins to clean out one of her horse's hooves with a metal pick. The only sound against the stillness. And her father watches. His heart pounding.</context>
      <utterance>That's the kind of person your mom is. She's the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to her. The sound of his feet on the straw.</context>
      <utterance>I complained a lot, baby. We couldn't travel, we'd lost our privacy, our chance to do things on the spur of the moment. To live for...ourselves. The way we'd started out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crouches down. Very close to his child.</context>
      <utterance>And she said. Sounds like you'd be happier. If the kids weren't around.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle stops working. Turns her faces away.</context>
      <utterance>I said. I love them more than anything. But sometimes... I do miss what I've lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So he leans closer.</context>
      <utterance>She said she could never feel that way, not for one single second.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. He's staring at the back of her head.</context>
      <utterance>She didn't want to be with someone. Who could.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, this horse smells really bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At least she can talk. If only just above a whisper.</context>
      <utterance>There's worse things.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. She doesn't look at him.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know why I never told you all this before?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Waiting to hear...</context>
      <utterance>Sure. You wanted me to blame her. Instead of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hears honesty. And heartbreak. It makes her turn...</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets lost. Looking in those eyes.</context>
      <utterance>How come you're telling me now?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to be wrong anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swallows hard. Her eyes moving over his face.</context>
      <utterance>I want to say I'm sorry, because I am. And let you hate me. If you have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head very slightly. And her eyes water.</context>
      <utterance>See that feeling? Where you feel two different things at once? That's a grown-up thing. It's not a lot of fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>Know why your mom never told you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hardest thing. He's ever had to say...</context>
      <utterance>She knew that you and her were so...solid. Nothing could rock that. But she didn't want to risk...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...your hating me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cos she loves you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cos she loves</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The way he says this. Makes her ask...</context>
      <utterance>There's going to come a moment. When she'll really need you to give that back. And you're just the girl that can do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches. First time. Strokes her hair.</context>
      <utterance>Now do I know when?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That moment will come. And your heart is going to whisper, 'here it is' Winds his fingers. Around her hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares in his eyes. And dead straight.</context>
      <utterance>And you'll come through.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Okay, he nods. That's a plan.</context>
      <utterance>If I miss it, daddy? You clue me in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="43">
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for coming out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie stares evenly. Her chin rests across the back of her knuckles. She looks tired, but okay. Fueled by adrenaline.</context>
      <utterance>Neutral ground. What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress appears. Rachel too locked into the moment to notice. So...</context>
      <utterance>Luke called. He says you're checking out. Of the Heartbreak Hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She likes a Stolie, no ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the woman leaves...</context>
      <utterance>Double.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this about? Because we fought?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Signs.</context>
      <utterance>Don't flatter yourself.  I always liked that line.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love Luke, I love the children. But there is more to life than even love...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, there isn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie unblinking. Focused, strong.</context>
      <utterance>And I have looked down the road. At what my life will be. And I can't handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Then...</context>
      <utterance>What do you see? Down that road.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never wanted to be a mom. Then, sharing it with you was one thing. Carrying it alone, the rest of my life...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Stolie arrives. They wait a beat. The waitress disappears.</context>
      <utterance>Is scary. But you want it. Gimme some truth here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's the Jack Kennedy Syndrome, huh? You die young, you always look golden. Perfect. The memory kind of burnishes the image, and...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, a wuss like me? The stiff who wouldn't help her own daughter fight back?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That sits there. In its sincerity.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I was wrong on that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And so does that. Tears are forming in Rachel's eyes. Here, in this public place.</context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe you weren't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Look, when I said I couldn't channel you. That didn't mean I wouldn't give my right arm to do just that.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie waits. Thinks.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I don't want to be looking over my shoulder. Every day for twenty years. Knowing someone else would have done it right. The way I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The way she said that. Something weighty behind it. So Rachel reaches into her purse.</context>
      <utterance>Trade you a smoke. For a secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel's hand freezes. In mid-course.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I lost Ben awhile back? In a supermarket.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're lying.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lost him. I was panicked.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are lying, you never lost that kid for 4</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben never mentioned it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He only remembers I</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Passing the cigarettes over.</context>
      <utterance>Uh. You hate my guts?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yes we were.</context>
      <utterance>We were competing. Even then.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pulls out a smoke. Offers the pack...</context>
      <utterance>Instead of being partners. Watch- ing each other's back. Seeing things were covered.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not scared</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I have that you don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything. You're...the Earth Mother incarnate...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the hip and fresh.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ride with Annabelle...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll learn.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know every story, every wound, every memory, their whole life's</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel stunned. By the simplicity of it all. Slowly, she leans to accept Jackie's flame.</context>
      <utterance>You. Have their future.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you get it? You look down the road to her wedding. You're in the room alone with her, fitting her veil, fluffing her dress. Telling her no woman was</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hand trembles as she takes a drag.</context>
      <utterance>And mine is. She won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie raises her glass.</context>
      <utterance>Now that's enough fear for either one of us to kill the other. And no jury in the world would convict.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holds it forward. In a toast.</context>
      <utterance>We're guilty, girl. Of being human. And we can't forgive ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And slowly, Rachel lifts her own glass. CLICKS it with Jackie's.</context>
      <utterance>But I forgive you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't rush me. I'm deciding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackie licks her lips. Pretty dry. Rachel takes a cotton lemon swab from the nightstand. Tenderly, cleans Jackie's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, gorgeous. Time for the presents?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Edna says you short-changed your last meds. You can do presents and be comfortable at the same time, y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few minutes.</context>
      <utterance>Just want to be a little sharper. For a few minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Some things to say. To the kids, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel can't really bear this.</context>
      <utterance>Then, bring in the presents. We'll have big fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, there's nothing you have to say. Because they know your heart. You don't have t...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Staring at each other. Then Rachel reaches her arms around Jackie, and as gently as she can manage, lifts her to a full sitting position.</context>
      <utterance>Just sit me up. Nice and tall. Bring Benjamin first.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rachel brings the big book. Lays it on the bed. And goes. Jackie begins to turn the pages. Her life with these children passing before her eyes. No tears. No smile. Just full attention. Fingertips touch the one she was looking for, as... The door OPENS. Ben, hesitant, enters alone. His mother's face is fine and strong and smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Scrapbook.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find the bird cage?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rache says it's from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben nods. Okay, I won't. She glances to the scrapbook...</context>
      <utterance>Well, don't make him disappear before I see him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And forgetting his uneasiness, he runs over, climbs ONTO the bed. Jackie doesn't wince, doesn't even blink. Nothing for his memory bank but smiles. He looks at the photo... ...Jackie holding a spunky newborn.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. Really staring at it.</context>
      <utterance>That's you and me. Our first photo as a couple.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches to hold his face in her hand. Stares in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Did you know I was good-looking right away?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. Her smile is right there.</context>
      <utterance>You dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes brighten. The sadness pushed aside.</context>
      <utterance>The secret of it. That only magicians. Can ever understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, when we die. Our body goes away. Our body. But</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you can still see him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is so fucking hard. But her eyes stay dry.</context>
      <utterance>Half. Of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dying. Is where the</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Does it? And Ben smiles. He is inside the secret.</context>
      <utterance>Just because you can't see it. Doesn't. Mean. It's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The world.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right here. Right here. Inside the magician. Shhhh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I talk to you? When you're there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always. Always. And you won't hear a voice. But in</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. They do.</context>
      <utterance>No, it isn't. Because it isn't everything. And we want every- thing, don't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But God does let us keep the</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He answers. With a kiss.</context>
      <utterance>It's worth a lot. Will you keep it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle looks straight to her dad. There is a moment, a silence, that no one else could ever understand. She leans to him and whispers...</context>
      <utterance>Your turn. It wasn't bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes water. He takes her in his arms. Whispers close to her ear, only the words...</context>
      <utterance>Here it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at hi. Fear gone, filled with resolve. Gives him a kiss. Rises, to... ...follow Rachel down the hall. Rache wraps an arm around her big girl. No words, except a murmured...</context>
      <utterance>Here it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Voice cracking. She's not as good at it as this girl's mother.</context>
      <utterance>You can do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the door. Open it, and...</context>
      <utterance>You can do anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to say goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Annabelle looks up. Tears on her face.</context>
      <utterance>Don't. Take me with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grown up.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God. I got to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Annabelle climbs onto the bed. Their hands never stop touching each other. Saying I love you.</context>
      <utterance>Let me be the judge of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anything.</context>
      <utterance>There's an amazing thing when a woman has a daughter. One day you look up, and you see...a sister. Someone. You can say. Anything to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Things like that. Annabelle is beginning to lose it now. So Jackie says only...</context>
      <utterance>I wrote a whole lot of letters. To each of you. And the envelope says when to open it. Like, which birthday. Or...when you get your driver's permit. First time you see Rome. Things like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep Ben's for awhile, okay? Until he's old enough to not open them all at once.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until he's old enough to read. Tears on Annabelle's face. Her mom wonders...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you afraid for me? Where I'm going.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be. I'm going. Where we all go. Now how can that be bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll miss you so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, yes it is.</context>
      <utterance>Good. That's very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you're grown-up enough to know. Is that people. Can do</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Said with such absolute assurance.</context>
      <utterance>When you're in trouble. Have me there. When you fall in love. Have me there. You can.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annabelle swallows hard.</context>
      <utterance>That's how we go on, you know. Forever. Because someone takes us along.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A straight question. It needs an answer.</context>
      <utterance>On your wedding night. When your babies are born. I want to be there. Will you take me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNABELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sigh. A shared smile.</context>
      <utterance>Always, always. Always.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You.</context>
      <utterance>You made my life wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hold. On Annabelle.</context>
      <utterance>Take that with you, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Only...</context>
      <utterance>See, I told you I'd do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hand reaches out. A finger absently traces the edge of the wood. It seems a gesture of unconscious affection.</context>
      <utterance>Only. Now I don't know what to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A slight smile. Here's where the love shows.</context>
      <utterance>You'd have written it down, so you wouldn't blow it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nods slightly. Maybe we should. She takes a step back now, to a waiting chair. Sits. Her hands folded in her lap. Thinks.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should change places.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More.</context>
      <utterance>Well. We were less than friends, I guess. And more.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No apology there. It's just the truth.</context>
      <utterance>We were never...girlfriends, we never dished. That wasn't. What we had.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sad little shrug.</context>
      <utterance>We had some battles, man, they were...world class, huh?  And I don't regret a one of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thinking. Of how much more she'll miss.</context>
      <utterance>I miss them.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crosses her arms. Lost in the moment.</context>
      <utterance>We've got our secrets, we have. And I'll keep 'em if you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice wavers. But the eyes are dry.</context>
      <utterance>But I wish we had one more night. In that little bar, remember? Remember that toast? Sure, you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A murmur...</context>
      <utterance>Know what? I forgive me, too. See? You're the magician.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's what she came to say. CROSSFADE TO...</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, partner, I've got your back. We're covered.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BEST MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody shouts THE BRIDE. Everybody drinks champagne. And the bride stands up. In her white gown. In her hand, an envelope. She goes to the mike, and waits for the raucous cheers, the calls of SPEECH!, to die down. Leans to the mike. Flushed and happy. And, oddly, nervous.</context>
      <utterance>...so TO THE BRIDE! Thank GOD she's more than he deserves!</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>not for me.</context>
      <utterance>Now I know the tradition, so this isn't a toast. At least...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks down the table at her children. Dressed to kill. Enjoying the party.</context>
      <utterance>The guest list is 114. But we all know there's one more here, tonight. Because...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right? Right.</context>
      <utterance>...my two sidekicks there always bring her along. Wherever they go.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Jackie and I were sitting around. On New Year's Eve. And she said, 'You're not gonna talk at my funeral, are you?' And now. It is quiet indeed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I said, 'I've never been to a funeral. I'm not sure I'll know how to act...' Her sweet smile. Keeps the mood right.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nods to herself. Fights back the feeling of that moment.</context>
      <utterance>'...but I'll prob'ly sneak into where you are. Just before it's over...'</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is laughter in this room. Gentle, loving.</context>
      <utterance>'...say something. Just to you. Get the last word in, when you can't talk back.'</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So she says, 'No way.' Holds up the envelope. Holds it tight.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And slowly, Luke begins to CLAP. And others join. And when it stops...</context>
      <utterance>She wrote this. She sealed it up, I didn't see it. She made me promise to read it. At the wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No way in hell.</context>
      <utterance>I told her she'd better make it dirty, or make it funny. Because... no way...on my wedding...</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>APPLAUSE. They are loving it.</context>
      <utterance>...could she make me cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The band plays an impromptu FLOURISH. Rachel begins to carefully tear open the envelope...</context>
      <utterance>She says, 'It's a deal'.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The world watches her sway, watches her eyes fill as she stares at the small card in her hand. She can't believe this...</context>
      <utterance>Now, if it's too raunchy, we may have to excuse the kids... SHOUTS from everyone, ESPECIALLY the children. She has it open. She looks at it. And everything. Stops.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tears are welling. Everyone SCREAMS for her to read it. She leans to the mike, shaking her head...</context>
      <utterance>You promised.</utterance>
   <speaker>RACHEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The place goes happily UP FOR GRABS. A joyful RIOT of demand. Tears STREAMING now, Rachel fumbles to pull up her white beaded bag. As she puts the card inside, we alone can read the words...</context>
      <utterance>It's...no big thing, really... it's just...five words, it's...</utterance>
   <speaker>MY BABIES.  ARE SO LUCKY.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>HOLD on this. And...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
