<movie id="532" title="Sunset Blvd">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The buzzer SOUNDS again. Gillis gets up and opens the door. Two men wearing hats stand outside one of them carrying a briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NO. 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joseph C. Gillis?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men ease into the room. No. 1 hands Gillis a business card.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>NO. 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've come for the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What car?</utterance>
   <speaker>NO. 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1946 Plymouth convertible. Calif- ornia license 97 N 567.</utterance>
   <speaker>NO. 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the keys?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I give you the keys?</utterance>
   <speaker>NO. 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Come on -- the keys.</context>
      <utterance>Because the company's played ball with you long enough. Because you're three payments behind. And because we've got a Court order.</utterance>
   <speaker>NO. 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or do you want us to jack it up and haul it away?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax, fans. The car isn't here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NO. 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that So?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He took it up to Palm Springs.</context>
      <utterance>I lent it to a friend of mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NO. 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had to get away for his health, I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't believe me? Look in the garage.</utterance>
   <speaker>NO. 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure we believe you, only now we want you to believe us. That car better be back here by noon tomorrow, or there's going to be fireworks.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men leave. Gillis GILLIS' VOICE stands pondering beside Well, I needed about two the door for a moment. hundred and ninety dollars Then he walks to the and I needed it real center of the room and, quick, or I'd lose my car. with his back to the It wasn't in Palm Springs CAMERA, slips into a and it wasn't in the pair of gray slacks. garage. I was way ahead There is a metallic of the finance company. noise as some loose change and keys drop from the trouser pockets. As Gillis bends over to pick them up, we see that he has dropped the car keys, identifiable be- cause of a rabbit's foot and a miniature license plate attached to the key-ring. Gillis pockets the keys and as he starts to put on a shirt</context>
      <utterance>You say the cutest things.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="43">
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Gillis. You've got five minutes. What's your story about?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about a ball player, a rookie shortstop that's batting 347. The poor kid was once mixed up in a hold- up. But he's trying to go straight -- except there's a bunch of gamblers who won't let him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So they tell the kid to throw the World Series, or else, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A secretary enters, carrying a glass or milk. She opens a drawer and takes out a bottle of pills for Sheldrake.</context>
      <utterance>More or less. Only for the end I've got a gimmick that's real good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a title?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bases Loaded. There's a 4O-page outline.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the Readers' Department and see what they have on Bases Loaded. The secretary exits. Sheldrake takes a pill and washes it down with some milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens and Betty Schaefer enters -- a clean- cut, nice looking girl of 21, with a bright, alert manner. Dressed in tweed skirt, Brooks sweater and pearls, and carrying a folder of papers. She puts them on Sheldrake's desk, not noticing Gillis, who stands near the door.</context>
      <utterance>They're pretty hot about it over at Twentieth, but I think Zanuck's all wet. Can you see Ty Power as a GILLIS  shortstop? You've got the best man for it right here on this lot. Alan Ladd. Good change of pace for Alan Ladd. There's another thing: it's pretty simple to shoot. Lot of outdoor stuff. Bet you could make the whole thing for under a million. And there's a great little part for Bill Demarest. One of the trainers, an oldtime player who got beaned and goes out of his head sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Sheldrake. On that Bases Loaded. I covered it with a 2-page synopsis.  But I wouldn't bother.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's from hunger.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing for Ladd?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a rehash of something that wasn't very good to begin with.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty turns towards Gillis, embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you'll be glad to meet Mr. Gillis. He wrote it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Miss Kramer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Schaefer. Betty Schaefer. And right now I wish I could crawl into a hole and pull it in after me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I could be of any help...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I found it flat and banal.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Mr. Gillis, but I just don't think it's any good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dostoosvsky?</context>
      <utterance>Exactly what kind of material do you recommend? James Joyce?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name dropper.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just think pictures should say a little something.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you're one of the message kids. Just a story won't do. You'd have turned down Gone With the Wind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that was me. I said, Who wants to see a Civil War picture?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps the reason I hated Bases Loaded is that I knew your name. I'd always heard you had some talent.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was last year. This year I'm trying to earn a living.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you take Plot 27-A, make it glossy, make it slick --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carefull Those are dirty words! You sound like a bunch of New York critics. Thank you, Miss Schaefer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Mr. Gillis.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye. Next time I'll write The Naked and the Dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, seems like Zanuck's got himself a baseball picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Sheldrake, I don't want you to think I thought this was going to win any Academy Award.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, we're always looking for a Betty Hutton. Do you see it as a Betty Hutton?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frankly, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now wait a minute. If we made it a girls' softball team, put in a few numbers. Might make a cute musical: It Happened in the Bull Pen -- the story of a Woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You trying to be funny? -- because I'm all out of laughs. I'm over a barrel and I need a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, Gillis. If something should come along -</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Along is no good. I need it now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't got a thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any kind of assignment. Additional Dialogue.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing, Gillis. Not even if you were a relative.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Mr. Sheldrake, could you let me have three hundred bucks yourself, as a personal loan?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHELDRAKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could I? Gillis, last year some- body talked me into buying a ranch in the valley. So I borrowed money from the bank so I could pay for the ranch. This year I had to mortgage the ranch so I could keep up my life insurance so I could borrow on the insurance so I could pay my income tax. Now if Dewey had been elected -</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Mr. Sheldrake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SKOLSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis looks around. At the fountain sits Skolsky, drinking a cup of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Gillis.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Skolsky.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKOLSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got anything for the column?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Just sold an original for a hundred grand. The Life of the Warner Brothers. Starring the Ritz Brothers. Playing opposite the Andrew Sisters.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKOLSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis walks out.</context>
      <utterance>But don't get me wrong -- I love Hollywood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MORINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you need three hundred dollars? Of course, I could give you three hundred dollars. Only I'm not going to.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sinks his putt and walks toward the next tee, Gillis following him.</context>
      <utterance>Gillis, get this through your head. I'm not just your agent. It's not the ten per cent. I'm your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that about your being my friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you know the finest things in the world have been written on an empty stomach? Once a talent like yours gets into that Mocambo- Romanoff rut, you're through.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget Romanoff's. It's the car I'm talking about. If I lose my car it's like having my legs out off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greatest thing that could happen to you. Now you'll have to sit behind that typewriter. Now you'll have to write.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I need three hundred dollars.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think I've been doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORINO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe what you need is another agent. He bends down to tee up his ball. Gillis turns away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis enters the shot.</context>
      <utterance>In here!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I had a blow-out. I thought --</context>
      <utterance>I just put my car in the garage.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is authority in the gesture of his white- gloved hand as he motions Gillis inside.</context>
      <utterance>Go on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, maybe I'd better take my car --</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Automatically, Gillis wipes his feet on an enormous shabby cocoanut mat.</context>
      <utterance>Wipe your feet!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are not dressed properly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dressed for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Max! Have him come up, Max!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up the stairs!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suppose you listen just for a minute -</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame is waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis enters.</context>
      <utterance>For me? Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you need help with the coffin call me. The oddity of the situation has caught Gillis' imagination. He climbs the stairs with a kind of morbid fascination. At the top he stops, undecided, then turns to the right and is stopped by</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis swings around. Norma Desmond stands down the corridor next to a doorway from which emerges a flickering light. She is a little woman. There is a curious style, a great sense of high voltage about her. She is dress- ed in black house pyjamas and black high-heeled pumps. Around her throat there is a leopard-pat- terned scarf, and wound around her head a turban of the same material. Her skin is very pale, and she is wearing dark glasses.</context>
      <utterance>This way!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In here. I put him on my massage table in front of the fire. He always liked fires and poking at them with a stick. Gillis enters the SHOT and she leads him into</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've made up my mind we'll bury him in the garden. Any city laws against that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up the shawl to make up her mind about the color. From under the shawl flops down a dead arm. Gillis stares and recoils a little. It is like a child's arm, only black and hairy.</context>
      <utterance>I don't care anyway. I want the coffin to be white. And I want it specially lined with satin. White, or deep pink.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis edges closer and glances down. Under the shawl he sees the sad, bearded face of a dead chimpanzee. Norma drops back the shawl.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe red. bright flaming red. Gay. Let's make it gay.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much will it be? I warn you - don't give me a fancy price just because I'm rich.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lady. you've got the wrong man. For the first time. Norma really looks at him through her dark glasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I thought this was an empty house.</context>
      <utterance>I had some trouble with my car. Flat tire. I pulled into your garage till I could get a spare.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is not. Get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, and I'm sorry you lost your friend, and I don't think red is the right color.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Wait a minute -- haven't I seen you -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or shall I call my servant?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know your face. You're Norma Desmond. You used to be in pictures. You used to be big.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am big. It's the pictures that got small.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew there was something wrong with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're dead. They're finished. There was a time when this busi- ness had the eyes of the whole wide world. But that wasn't good enough. Oh, nol They wanted the ears of the world, too. So they opened their big mouths, and out came talk, talk, talk...</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's where the popcorn business comes in. You buy yourself a bag and plug up your ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at them in the front offices -- the master minds! They took the idols and smashed them. The Fairbankses and the Chaplins and the Gilberts and the Valentinos. And who have they got now? Some nobodies -- a lot of pale little frogs croaking pish-poshl</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get sore at me. I'm not an executive. I'm just a writer.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are! Writing words, words! You've made a rope of words and strangled this businessl But there is a microphone right there to catch the last gurgles, and Technicolor to photograph the red, swollen tongue!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ssh! You'll wake up that monkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis starts down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time I'll bring my autograph album along, or maybe a hunk of cement and ask for your footprints. He is halfway down the staircase when he is stopped by</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a minute, you!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a writer, you said.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma starts down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you or aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that's what it says on my driver's license.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you have written pictures, haven't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma has reached him at the bottom of the staircase.</context>
      <utterance>Sure have. The last one I wrote was about cattle rustlers. Before they were through with it, the whole thing played on a torpedo boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leads him into</context>
      <utterance>I want to ask you something. Come in here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="56">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The wind gets in that blasted pipe organ. I ought to have it taken out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma has led him to the card tables which stand side by side near a window. They are piled high with papers scrawled in a large, uncertain hand.</context>
      <utterance>Or teach it a better tune.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long is a movie script these days? I mean, how many pages?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends on what it is -- a Donald Duck or Joan or Arc.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is to be a very important picture. I have written it myself. Took me years.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like enough for six impor- tant pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the story or Salome. I think I'll have DeMille direct it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've made a lot of pictures together.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you'll play Salome?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who else ?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only asking. I did't know you were planning a comeback.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate that word. It is a return. A return to the millions of people who have never forgiven me for deserting the screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fair enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Salome -- what a woman! What a part! The Princess in love with a Holy man. She dances the Dance of the Seven Veils. He rejects her, so she demands his head on a golden tray, kissing his cold, dead lips.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll love it in Pomona.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They will love it every place.  Read it. Read the scene just before she has him killed!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now? Never let another writer read your stuff. He may steal it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not afraid. Read it! NORMA   Max! Max!  Sit down. Is there enough light?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max has entered.</context>
      <utterance>I've got twenty-twenty vision.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring something to drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. Norma turns to Gillis again.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is compulsion in her voice. Gillis looks at her GILLIS' VOICE and starts slowly Well. I had no pressing reading. engagement, and she'd men- tioned something to drink.. Max comes in, wheeling Sometimes it's interesting a wicker tea wagon on to see just how bad bad which are two bottles o writing can be. This prom- f champagne and two ised to go the limit. I red Venetian glasses, wondered what a handwriting a box of zwieback and expert would make of that a jar of caviar. Norma childish scrawl of hers. sits on her feet. deep Max wheeled in some champagne in a chair, a gold ring and some caviar. Later, I on her forefinger with found out that Max was the a clip which holds a only other person in that cigarette. She gets up grim Sunset castle, and I and forces on Gillis found out a few other things another batch of script, about him... As for her, she goes back to her chair. sat coiled up like a watch spring, her cigarette clamped in a curious holder... I could sense her eyes on me from behind those dark glasses, defying me not to like what I read, or maybe begging me in her own proud way to like it. It meant so much to her...</context>
      <utterance>I said sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is fascinating.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's a little long and maybe there are some repetitions... but you're not a professional writer.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wrote that with my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you did. That's what makes it great. What it needs is a little more dialogue.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for? I can say anything I want with my eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It certainly could use a pair of shears and a blue pencil.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will not have it butchered.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not. But it ought to be organized. Just an editing job. You can find somebody.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who? I'd have to have somebody I can trust. When were you born -- I mean, what sign of the zodiac?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What month?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>December twenty-first.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You can trust them.</context>
      <utterance>Sagittarius. I like Sagittarians.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to do this work.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? I'm busy. Just finished one script. I'm due on another assignment.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I get five hundred a week.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I'm pretty expensive.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll make it worth your while.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't worry about money.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'd better take the rest of the script home and read it -</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no. I couldn't let it out of my house. You'll have to finish it here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's getting kind of late --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you married, Mr. -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name is Gillis. I'm single.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you live?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hollywood. The Alto Nido Apart- ments.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something wrong with your car, you said.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There sure is.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma takes off her glasses.</context>
      <utterance>I'll come early tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonsense. There's room over the garage. Max will take you there...Max!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made your bed this afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.  How did you know I was going to stay, this afternoon? Max doesn't answer. He walks across to the bed, screws a bulb in the open socket above it. The light goes on, revealing:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This room has not been used for a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max gives him an enigmatic look.</context>
      <utterance>It will never make house Beautiful. I guess it's O.K. for one night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is the bathroom. I put in soap and a toothbrush.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.  Say, she's quite a character, that Norma Desmond.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was the greatest. You wouldn't know. You are too young. In one week she got seventeen thousand fan letters. Men would bribe her mani- curist to get clippings from her fingernails. There was a Maharajah who came all the way from Hyderabad to get one of her stockings. Later, he strangled himself with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sure turned into an interesting driveway.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>looks after him, hangs cuckoo, too. A stroke maybe. his coat over a chair, Come to think of it, the walks over to the win- whole place seemed to have dow, pulls down the been stricken with a kind of rickety Venetian blind. creeping paralysis, out of As he does so, he looks beat with the rest of the down at: world, crumbling apart in slow motion ...</context>
      <utterance>He goes out. Gillis I pegged him as slightly</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you -- Max -- whatever -your- name-is -- what are my things doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm talking to you. My clothes and things are up in the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naturally. I brought them myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that so!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you so upset? Is there anything missing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma Desmond's shadow moves into the shaft of light.</context>
      <utterance>Who said you could? Who asked you to?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the couch by the fireplace reclines Norma Desmond, dressed in a negligee. She rises.</context>
      <utterance>I did. Gillis looks around.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know why you should be so upset. Stop that playing, Max.  It seemed like a good idea -- if we are to work together.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm supposed to fix up your script. There's nothing in the deal about my staying here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll like it here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the invitation, but I have my own apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't work in an apartment where you owe three months' rent.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all taken care of. It's all paid for.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm used to paying my own bills.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You proud boy, why didn't you tell me you were having difficulties.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. We'll deduct it from my salary.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, now, don't let's be small about such matters. We won't keep books.  Go on, unpack Mr. Gillis' things.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unpack nothing. I didn't say I was staying.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you want this job or don't you?</context>
      <utterance>Suppose you make up your mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a scene I cut out.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What scene?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The one where you go to the slave market. You can cut right to the scene where John the Baptist -</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut away from me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They don't want that any more.</context>
      <utterance>Honestly, it's a little old hat.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't? Then why do they still write me fan letters every day. Why do they beg me for my photo- graphs? Because they want to see me, me, me! Norma Desmond.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the page from his typewriter. As he does so he glances over towards Norma.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>graphs which she is sign- sleepwalker-- he may fall ing. On the long table and break his neck.That's in the living room is a it -- she was still gallery of photographs sleepwalking along the in various frames -- all giddy heights of a lost Norma Desmond. On the career --plain crazy piano more photographs. when it came to that one Above the piano an oil subject: her celluloid portrait of her. On the self, the great Norma highboy beside him still Desmond. How could She more photographs. breathe in that house, so crowded with Norma DISSOLVE TO: Desmonds? More Norma Desmond and still more Norma Desmond.</context>
      <utterance>On the table in front I didn't argue with her. of her are the photo- You don't yell at a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a sudden flareup she jumps to her feet and stands in the flickering beam of light.</context>
      <utterance>Still wonderful, isn't it? And no dialogue. We didn't need dialogue. We had faces. There just aren't any faces like that any more. Well, maybe one -- Garbo.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll be up there again. So help me!</context>
      <utterance>Those idiot producers! Those imbeciles! Haven't they got any eyes? Have they forgotten what a star looks like? I'll show them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some men are here. They asked for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I told them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They found your car in the garage. They are going to tow it away. Gillis doesn't know what to do. From offstage comes:</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis dumps the cigarette butts into the cold fire- place, crosses to the bridge table, puts the ashtray down, leans over and speaks into Norma's ear.</context>
      <utterance>The ashtray, Joe dear! Can we have the ashtray?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to talk to you for a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now, my dear. I'm playing three no trump.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've come for my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Now I've forgotten how many spades are out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need some money right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you wait till I'm dummy?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis stands frustrated, hideously embarrassed by the stares of the waxworks. He turns away and hurries to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Please!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what is it? Where's the fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've lost my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...and I thought it was a matter of life and death.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is to me. That's why I came to this house. That's why I took this job -- ghost writing!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE CAMERA HAS PANNED over to the garage and FOCUSES on the dirty Isotta-Fraschini on its blocks.</context>
      <utterance>Now you're being silly. We don't need two cars. We have a car. And not one of thuse cheap new things made of chromium and spit. An Isotta-Fraschini. Have you ever heard of Isotta-Fraschinis? All hand-made. Cost me twenty-eight thousand dollars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ABOVE SUNSET</speaker>
      <mode>DAY</mode>
      <context>dressed as usual except So Max got that old bus for a chauffeurfs cap. down off its blocks and polished it up. She'd take me for rides in the B-22 INSIDE THE CAR hills above Sunset. Gillis sits beside Norma, The whole thing was up- who is wearing a smart holstered in leopard tailleur and her eternal skin, and had one of sun glasses. Gillis those car phones, all wears his sport jacket- gold-plated. flannel trousers-moccasin combinatIon. He sits uncomfortably. Norma is studying him.</context>
      <utterance>Max is at the wheel, GILLIS' VOICE</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a dreadful shirt you're wearing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with It?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well, go there !</context>
      <utterance>Nothing, if you work in a fill- ing station. And I'm getting rather bored with that sport jacket, and those same baggy pants.  Max, what's a good men's shop in town? The very best...</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need any clothes, and I certainly don't want you buy- ing them for --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By this time Max has made a U-turn.</context>
      <utterance>Why begrudge me a little fun? I just want you to look nice, my stray little boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The salesman leaves.</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing like gray flannel with a chalk stripe.  This one single-breasted, of course.  Now we need a topcoat. Let's see what you have in camel's hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about some evening clothes?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need a tuxedo.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you do. A tuxedo and tails.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tails. That's ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll need them for parties. You'll need them for New Year's Eve.  Where are your evening clothes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads her off. The other salesman arrives with a selection of topcoats.</context>
      <utterance>This way, Madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here are some camel hairs, but I'd like you just to feel this one. It's Vicuna. Of course, it's a little more expensive.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A camel's hair will do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As long as the lady is paying for it, why not take the Vicuna?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose room was this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slightly embarrassed, Gillis picks up his toilet kit with razor, toothbrushes, soap, etc., and starts towards the bathroom, pausing en route at a rain- splattered window.</context>
      <utterance>It was the room of the husband. Or of the husbands, I should say. Madame has been married three times.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He proceeds towards the half-opened door leading to the bathroom. Something strikes his attention and he stops. As in the door to the room above the garage, this lock, too, has been gouged out.</context>
      <utterance>I guess this is the one you can see Catalina from. Only this isn't the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's this with the door? There isn't any lock.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the entrance door of the room, and to another door.</context>
      <utterance>There are no locks anywhere in this house.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The doctor suggested it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame's doctor. She has moments of melancholy. There have been some suicide attempts.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to be very careful. No sleeping pills, no razor blades. We shut off the gas in her bed- room.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She still gets those fan letters.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Her career? She got enough out of it. She's not forgotten.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't look too closely at the postmarks.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You send them. Is that it, Max?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd better press your evening clothes, sir. You have not for- gotten Madame's New Year's party.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I haven't. I suppose all the waxworks are coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max leaves. Gillis comes out of the bathroom, picks up his shirts, goes over to a closet, opens it. As he does so one of the doors without a lock swings slightly open. Gillis looks through the half-open door and sees.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, sir. Madame made the arrangements.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>HOUSE</speaker>
      <mode>NIGHT</mode>
      <context>stairs in his tailcoat It was at her New Year's adjusting the handkerchief party that I found out in his pocket. He obviously how she felt about me. feels a little uneasy in Maybe I'd been an idiot this outfit. From below not to have sensed it comes a tango of the Twen- was coming - that sad, ties. played by a small embarrassing revelation. orchestra. Gillis stops in the archway leading to the big room and looks around. C-6 THE BIG ROOM has been deco- rated for the occasion with laurel garlands. Dozens of candles in all the sconces and candelabra are ablaze. Their flickering flames are reflected in the waxed sur= face of the tile floor. There is a buffet, with buckets of champagne and caviar on ice. In one corner on a little platform banked with palms. a four-piece orchestra is playing. At the buffet are Max and Norma. She is drinking a glass of champagne. She is wearing a diamonte evening dress. very high style. with long black gloves and a headdress of paradise feathers. Her eyes fall on Gillis. She puts down the glass of champagne. picks up a gardenia boutonniere and moves toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Gillis is coming down the GILLIS' VOICE</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joe, you look absolutely divine. Turn around!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis makes a slow 36O-degree turn.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She indicates the V from his shoulders to his hips.</context>
      <utterance>Perfect. Wonderful shoulders. And I love that line.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All padding. Don't let it fool you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the gardenia on his lapel.</context>
      <utterance>Come here!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, to me dressing up was always just putting on my dark blue suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nice big pearls.</context>
      <utterance>I don't like those studs they've sent. I want you to have pearls.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, I'm not going to wear ear- rings, I can tell you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leads him over to the buffet.</context>
      <utterance>Cute. Let's have some drinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't we wait for the others?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach the buffet. Max is ready with two glasses of champagne. Norma hands Gillis a glass.</context>
      <utterance>Careful, it's slippery. I had it waxed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drink.</context>
      <utterance>Here's to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens her arms.</context>
      <utterance>You know, this floor used to be wood but I had it changed. Valentino said there is nothing like tiles for a tango.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not on the same floor with Valentino!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start to tango. After a moment --</context>
      <utterance>Just follow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't bend back like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma pulls the paradise feathers from her hair and tosses them away.</context>
      <utterance>It's those feathers. They tickle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a quarter past ten. What time are they supposed to get here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The other guests?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are no other guests. We don't want to share this night with other people. This is for you and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand some rich guy bought up all the tickets for a perfor- mance at the Metropolitan and sat there listening to La Traviata, all by himself. He was afraid of catching cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold me tighter.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come midnight, how about blind- folding the orchestra and smash- ing champagne glasses on Max's head?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think this is all very funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it funny that I'm in love with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They dance on. Gillis is acutely embarrassed. THE CAMERA SLOWLY PULLS BACK, PANS past the faces of the musicians, who play on with a rather overe- mphasized lack of interest. Finally it winds up on Max, behind the buffet. He stands watching Gillis, a faint trace of pity in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in love with you. Don't you know that? I've been in love with you all along.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>NORMA.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a wonderful next year it's going to be. What fun we're going to have. I'II fill the pool for you. Or I'll open my house in Malibu, and you can have the whole ocean. Or I'll buy you a boat and we'll sail to Hawaii.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it. You aren't going to buy me anything more.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis opens the box. It contains a matched gold cigarette case and lighter.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be silly.  Here. I was going to give it to you at midniglht.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis snaps open the case. Engraved inside the cover is: TO JOE FROM NORMA, and two bars of music.</context>
      <utterance>Read what's inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are the notes?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Mad about the boy."</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norma, I can't take it. You've bought me enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I've got a million dollars.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up. I'm rich. I'm richer than all this new Hollywood trash.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I own three blocks downtown. I have oil in Bakersfield -- pumping, pumping, pumping. What's it for but to buy us anything we want.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises.</context>
      <utterance>Cut out that us business.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What right do you have to take me for granted?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What right? Do you want me to tell you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has it ever occurred that I may have a life of my own? That there may be some girl I'm crazy about?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who? Some car hop, or a dress extra?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? What I'm trying to say is that I'm all wrong for you. You want a Valentino -- somebody with polo ponies -- a big shot --</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis doesn't answer. Norma slaps his face and rushes from the room and upstairs. Gillis stands paralyzed, the slap burning his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>What you're trying to say is that you don't want me to love you. Is that it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="49">
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what do you know ! Joe Gillis !</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Artie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where have you been keeping that gorgeous face of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a deep freeze.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis greets some of the kids by name as he and Artie push their way into the room.</context>
      <utterance>I almost reported you to the Bureau of Missing Persons.  Fans, you all know Joe Gillis, the well-known screen writer, opium smuggler and Black Dahlia suspect.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me your coat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let it ride for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to stay, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was the general idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Artie starts peeling the coat off Gillis. Its texture takes his breath away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has taken the coat. He looks at Gillis standing there in tails.</context>
      <utterance>What is this - mink?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Judas E. Priest, who did you borrow that from? Adolphe Menjou?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis stands embarrassed While Artie rolls up the Vicuna coat and tucks it above the books on a book- shelf.</context>
      <utterance>Close, but no cigar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, you're not really smuggling opium these days, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two make their way toward the punch bowl. It's a little like running the gauntlet for Gillis. There are whistles and 'stares of astonishlnent at his tails. When they reach the punch bowl, Artie picks up a half-filled glass and fills it.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the bar?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good party.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fake the rest.</context>
      <utterance>The greatest. They call me the Elsa Maxwell of the assistant directors.  Hey, easy on the punch bowl. Budget only calls for three drinks per extra.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Artie, can I stick around here for a while?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, this'll go on all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, could you put me up for a couple of weeks?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It just so happens we have a vacancy on the couch.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs his finger across the decollete back of a girl standing in a group next them.</context>
      <utterance>I'll have the bell-hop take care of your luggage.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just register here. The girl turns around. She is Betty Schaefer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Gillis.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis looks at her a little puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>You know each other?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me help you. Betty Schaeter, Sheldrake's office.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Bases Loaded.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. This is the woman I love. What's going on? Who was loaded?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. She's just a fan for my literary output.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurt feelings department.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About that luggage. Where's the phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis squeezes his way through groups of people to the telephone, which is next to an open door leading to the bathroom. The phone is busy. A girl sits listening to it, giggling wildly. Another girl beside her is laughing too. They are apparently sharing a conversation with some man on the other end of the wire. The telephone passes from hand to hand. Gillis watches impatiently, then</context>
      <utterance>Over by the Rainbow Room.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl just nods, going on with her chattering. Gillis stands waiting, and Betty Schaefer comes up with his glass.</context>
      <utterance>When youlre through with that thing, can I have it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You forgot this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been hoping to run into you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for? To recover that knife you stuck in my back?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I felt a little guilty, so I got out some of your old stories.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, you sweet kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>something with a window.</context>
      <utterance>There's one called....Window...</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dark Windows. How did you like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is too much racket for her.</context>
      <utterance>Except for about six pages. You've got a flashback there ...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there someplace we can talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They squeeze their way towards the bathroom, past Artie.</context>
      <utterance>How about the Rainbow Room?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said you could have my couch. I didn't say you could have my girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She and Gillis go through the open door into</context>
      <utterance>This is shop talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now if I got you correctly, there was a short stretch of my fiction you found worthy of notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The flashback in the courtroom, when she tells about being a school teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a teacher like that once.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe that's why it's good. It's true, it's moving. Now why don't you use that character...</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who wants true? Who wants moving?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drop that attitude. Here's some- thing really worth while.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maybe there's some paper around.</context>
      <utterance>Want me to start right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm serious. I've got a few ideas.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got some ideas myself. One of them being this is New Year's Eve. How about living it up a little?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As for instance?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well....</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could make some paper boats and have a regatta. Or should we just turn on the shower?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about capturing the kitchen and barricading the door?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hungry? After twelve years in the Burmese jungle. I am starving, Lady Agatha -- starving for a white shoulder --</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the girls who was on the phone comes to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Phillip, you're mad!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can have the phone now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirsting for the coolness of your lips -</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Phillip, no. We must be strong. You're still wearing the uniform of the Coldstream Guards! Furthermore, you can have the phone now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>O.K.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I find I'm terribly afraid of losing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't.  I'll get us a refill of this awful stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be waiting for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With a wildly beating heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Life can be beautiful!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I want you to do me a favor.</context>
      <utterance>Max? This is Mr. Gillis.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I cannot talk now.</context>
      <utterance>I am sorry, Mr. Gillis.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up the dead receiver, stands numb with shock. Betty elbows her way up to him, carrying the two punch glasses filled again.</context>
      <utterance>Max ! Max !</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis looks up at her. Without a word he pushes her aside so that she spills the drink. He makes his way through the guests to the Vicuna coat, pulls it from the shelf, some books tumbling with it, and rushes towards the door and out. Betty stands look- ing after him, completely bewildered.</context>
      <utterance>I just got the recipe: take two packages of cough drops, dissolve in one gallon of lukewarm grape juice --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis starts to push past Max. Max grabs his arm.</context>
      <utterance>She is upstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis goes into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful. Do not race up the stairs. The musicians must not know what has happened.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of a silly thing was that to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To fall in love with you -- that was the idiotic thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sure would have made attractive headlines: Great Star Kills Her- self for Unknown Writer.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts one bandaged forearm over her eyes, sobbing. Gillis walks slowly over to the mantelpiece, stands there for awhile.</context>
      <utterance>Great stars have great pride.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away. Go to that girl of yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I was making that up because I thought the whole thing was a mistake. I didn't want to hurt you. You've been good to me. You're the only person in this stinking town that has been good to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just say thank you and go, go, go --</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not until you promise to act like a sensible human being.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis stands looking at her helplessly.</context>
      <utterance>I'll do it again, I'll do it again, I'll do it again!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma continues to sob. Gillis goes to the bed, puts his arms on her shoulders and turns her around.</context>
      <utterance>Happy New Year.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma looks at him, tears in her eyes. Slowly she enfolds him in her bandaged arms.</context>
      <utterance>Happy New Year.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>Happy New Year. darling.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D-1b MAX, AT THE PHONE</context>
      <utterance>Is this Crestview 5-1733? ... I'm sorry to bother you again, but I've confirmed the number. I must speak to Mr. Gillis.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D-1c BETTY ON THE PHONE</context>
      <utterance>He is not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D-1d MAX ON THE PHONE</context>
      <utterance>Where can I reach him? Maybe somebody else in the house could tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up. From off comes:</context>
      <utterance>Nobody here can give you any information. You will please not call again.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is a sunny day. The garden is in somewhat better shape. The old house looks less unkept. The pool is filled. Norma sits on a wicker chaise longue, her face shielded by an enormous straw hat, her eyes by dark glasses. Gillis, in bathing trunks, is on a rubber mattress in the pool. Max comes to the entrance door.</context>
      <utterance>Who was it, Max? What is it? D-1e PATIO, NORMA'S HOUSE</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to turn back.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing, Madame. Somebody Inqu- iring about a stray dog. We must have a number very similar to the pound.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. I want you to get out the car. You're going to take the script over to Paramount and deliver it to Mr. De Mille in person.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really going to send it to De Mille?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She indicates a typewritten letter she is holding. NORMA (Cont'd) The chart from my astrologer. She read deMille's horoscope. She read mine.</context>
      <utterance>This is the right day.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she read the script?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the towel around his sholders and starts drying him.</context>
      <utterance>DeMille is Leo. I'm Scorpio. Mars has been transmitting Jupiter for weeks. Today is the day of greatest conjuction. Now turn around. Let me dry you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you realize, Norma, that scripts don't sell on astrologers' charts.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not just selling the script. I'm selling me. DeMille always said I was his greatest star.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did he say it, Norma?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>So he said it quite a few years ago. So what? I never looked better in my life. Do you know why? Because I've never been as happy in my life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That idiot. He forgot to fill my cigarette case.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have one of mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're awful. They make me cough.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull up at the drugstore, will you, Max.  I'll get you some.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a dollar bill from her purse and gives it to him.</context>
      <utterance>You're a darling.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl opens the glass showcase to locate the fancy brand. From OFF comes</context>
      <utterance>Give me a pack of those Turkish cigarettes -- Melachrinos.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis turns.</context>
      <utterance>Stick 'em up, Gillis, or I'll let you have it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Artie. Good evening, Miss Schaefer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know how glad I am to see youl</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walking out on the mob. What's the big idea?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about New Year's. Would you believe me if I said I had to be with a sick friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone in the formal set, no doubt, with a ten-carat kidney stone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it, Artie, will you?  Where have you been keeping your- self? I've got the most wonderful news for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't been keeping myself at all. Not lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called your agent. I called the Screen Writers Guild. Finally your old apartment gave me some Crestview number. There was always somebody with an accent growling at me. You were not there. You were not to be spoken to. They never heard of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that so? What's the wonderful news?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheldrake likes that angle about the teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What teacher?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dark Windows. I got him all hopped up about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He thinks it could be made into something.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Into what? A lampshade?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Into something for Barbara Stan- wyck. They have a commitment with Barbara Stanwyck.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless you'd rather have Sarah Bernhardt.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is on the level. Sheldrake really went for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O.K. Where's the cash?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It needs work.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the story? I bluffed it out with a few notions of my own. It's really just a springboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was afraid of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got twenty pages of notes. I've got a pretty good character for the man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you write in plenty of back- ground action, so they'll need an extra assistant director?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Artie.  Now if we could sit down for two weeks and get a story.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Miss Schaefer, but I've given up writing on spec.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell you this is half sold.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max has appeared in the door.</context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact. I've given up writing altogether.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Gillis, if you please.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Right with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get those studs. Get those cuff-links.</context>
      <utterance>The accent! I've got it: this guy is in the pay of a foreign government.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to run along. Thanks any- way for your interest in my career.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not your career -- it's mine. I kind of hoped to get in on this deal. I don't want to be a reader all my life. I want to write.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry if I crossed you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure have.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves.</context>
      <utterance>So long.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Babe, it's like that producer says: In life, you've got to take the bitter with the sour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What on earth, darling? It took you hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ran into some people I knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are my cigarettes?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He realizes he's forgotten them, takes the dollar and hands it back to her.</context>
      <utterance>Where are your...?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norma, you're smoking too much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She climbs on it, pantomimes timidity, an attempted dive, then jumps off. Gillis lolls on a couch, watching the performance, very bored.</context>
      <utterance>This is a rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can still see myself in the line: Bebe Daniels, Marie Prevost, Mabel Normand ... Mabel was always stepping on my feet ...What's the matter with you, darling? Why are you so glum?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing is the matter. I'm having a great time. Show me some more.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Give me this. I need it for a moustache. Now close your eyes. She runs out of the GILLIS' VOICE picture. Gillis has Something was the matter, closed his eyes. all right. I was thinking THE CAMERA MOVES to about that girl of Artie's, his face. that Miss Schaefer. She was so like all us writers when we first hit Holly- wood -- itching with am- bition, panting to get your names up there: Screenplay by. Original Story by. Hmph! Audiences don't know somebody sits down and writes a picture. They think the actors make it up as they go along.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma has equipped herselr with a derby hat, a cane, and blacked in a small moustache. She goes into a little Chaplin routine. While she is doing it, the telephone rings. After a moment Max comes to the living room door.</context>
      <utterance>Open your eyes. Gillis opens his eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame is wanted on the telephone.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know better than to interrupt me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paramount is calling.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paramount studios.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, now do you belive me? I told you deMille would jump at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is not Mr. deMille in person. It is someone by the name or Gordon Cole. He says it's very important.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly it's important. It's important enough for Mr. deMille to call me personally. The idea of having an assistant call me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I myself was surprised at Mr. de Mille's manners.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say that I'm busy, and hang up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bows and exits.</context>
      <utterance>Very good, Madam.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His greatest successes.</context>
      <utterance>How do you like that? We've made twelve pictures together.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe deMille is shooting.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that trick! He wants to belittle me. He's trying to get my price down. I've waited twenty years for this call. Now Mr. deMille can wait till I'm good and ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DRIVING DOWN MELROSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>with a veil, a daring About three days later she hat, a suit so stunning was good and ready. In- only she would venture credible as it may seem, to wear it. THE CAMERA there had been some more PULLS BACK. Beside her of those calls from sits Gillis in the glen Paramount. So she put on plaid suit. Max is about half a pound of driving. makeup, fixed it up with a veil, and set forth to see deMille in person. Norma is examining her face in the mirror of her vanity. Max, while driving, sees her in the rear view mirror.</context>
      <utterance>She is in full makeup, GILLIS' VOICE</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you will pardon me, Madame. The shadow over the left eye is not quite balanced.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a handkerchief, she corrects it.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Max.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>YOUNG POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold that noise!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To see Mr. de Mille. Open the gate.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. deMille is shooting. You got an appointment?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No appointment is necessary. I am bringing Norma Desmond.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma has rolled down the window on her side. She calls to the old policeman.</context>
      <utterance>Norma Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jonesy! Come here, Jonesy!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How have you been, Miss Desmond?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?  Why, if it isn't Miss Desmond!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, Jonesy. Now open that gate.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They can't drive on the lot without a pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They fling open the gate.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Desmond can. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stage eighteen, Miss Desmond.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>goes to wall phone beside the gate, dials a number.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Jonesy. And teach your friend some manners. Tell him without me he wouldn't have any job, because without me there wouldn't be any Paramount Studio.  Go on. They drive through the gates. The old policeman</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norma Desmond coming in to see Mr. deMille.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>STAGE HAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norma Desmond is coming to see Mr. deMille. The second assistant walks  to the first assistant. 2nd ASSISTANT Norma Desmond coming in to see Mr. deMille. The first assistant  hurries to the set. Sitting with his back toward us is C.B. himself. He is rehearsing a scene with Hedy Lamarr.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>C. B. turns his head.</context>
      <utterance>Norma Desmond is coming in to see you, Mr. deMille.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norma Desmond? lst ASSISTANT She must be a million years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate to think where that puts me. I could be her father.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By this time de Mille is on his feet.</context>
      <utterance>I'm terribly sorry, Mr. de Mille.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must be about that appalling script of hers. What can I say to her? What can I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can tell her you're all tied up in the projection room. I can give her the brush ...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isn't that enough?</context>
      <utterance>Listen, thirty million fans have given her the brush.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to --</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you didn't. You didn't know Norma Desmond as a plucky little girl of seventeen, with more courage and wit and heart than ever came together in one youngster.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear she was a terror to work with.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves, accompanied by his entourage.</context>
      <utterance>She got to be. A dozen press agents working overtime can do terrible things to the human spirit.  Hold everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you want to come along, darling?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Good luck.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. It's your script. It's your show.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She presses his hand against her cheek, descends from the car and walks toward -</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, darling.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DE MILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, young fellow.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has reached him. They embrace.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. deMille.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I was dancing on a table.</context>
      <utterance>Last time I saw you was someplace very gay. I remember waving to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE MILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads her into</context>
      <utterance>Lots of people were. Lindbergh had just landed in Paris. Come on in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>DE MILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norma, I want to apologize for not calling you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd better. I'm very angry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE MILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pretty busy, as you can see...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's no excuse. You read the script, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE MILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you could have picked up the phone yourself instead of leaving it to one of your assistants.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE MILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What assistant?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't play innocent. Somebody named Gordon Cole.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE MILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gordon Cole?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if you hadn't been pretty darned interested in that script, he wouldn't have tried to get me on the phone ten times.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE MILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks onto the set, accompanied by his assistants.</context>
      <utterance>Gordon Cole... Look, Norma, I'm in the middle of a rehearsal.  Make yourself comfortable.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE MILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me Gordon Cole on the phone. Meanwhile, Norma starts to sit, sees the name MISS LAMARR on the chair and with a look of distaste changes and sits on the one marked C.B. DE MILLE. From somewhere comes</utterance>
   <speaker>A VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around her.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Miss Desmond! Miss Desmond!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up here! Norma looks up at the scaffolding. On the scaffold stands one of the electricians, next to his light.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELECTRICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's met It's Hog-eyel Norma waves at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hog-eye points his light at her.</context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOG-EYE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The beam of the lamp moves toward Norma. It hits her. She sits bathed in light. A couple of old costume extras recognize her.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get a look at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXTRAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They rush over and start wringing her hand. Into the shot comes a middle-aged hairdresser.</context>
      <utterance>Say, it's Norma! Norma Desmond!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAIRDRESSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some elderly electricians and stagehands move in.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Miss Desmond. It's Bessie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>DE MILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma hasn't heard a word.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Norma ...  I got hold of Gordon Cole.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see them? Did you see how they came?</utterance>
   <speaker>DE MILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly he realizes that she is crying. She takes the handkerchief from his pocket and puts it over her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You know, crazy things happen in this business. I hope you haven't lost your sense of humor ...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, Norma?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I just didn't realize what it would be like to come back to the old studio. I had no idea how I'd missed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've missed you too, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll be working again, won't we, Chief? We'll make our greatest picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I want to talk to you about.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a good script, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's got a lot of good things. Of course, it would be an expensive picture...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care about the money. I just want to work again. You don't know what it means to know that you want me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing would thrill me more -- if it were possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The first assistant comes up.</context>
      <utterance>But remember, darling -- I don't work before ten in the morning, and never after 4:30 in the afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're ready with the shot, Mr. deMille.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll pardon me, Norma? Why don't you just sit and watch?  O.K. Here we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Roll 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scene starts.</context>
      <utterance>Action!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see those offices there, Mr. Gillis? They used to be her dressing room, The whole row.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That didn't leave much for Wallace Reid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words "Readers' Department" have registered on Gillis' mind. He gets out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>He had a great big bungalow on wheels. I had the upstairs. See where it says 'Readers' Department'? I remember my walls were covered with black patent leather...</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses the street towards the green staircase leading to the second floor. Meanwhile, two prop men walking down the street come into the SHOT.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be with you in a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST PROP MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, that's the comic car Cole was talking about!  Do you mind if we look inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away. Go away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just so you don't think I'm a complete swine -- if there's anything in Dark Windows you can use, take it. It's all yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves the book and the apple aside and points at the free space on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Well, for heaven's sake!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis sits on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Have a chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean it. It's no good to me anyway. Help yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you get a hundred thousand for it, you buy me a box of chocolate creams. If you get an Oscar, I get the left foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I'd take you up on that in a minute. I'm just not good enough to do it all by myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about all those ideas you had?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See if they make sense. To begin with, I think you should throw out all that psychological stuff -- exploring a killer's sick mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Psychopaths sell like hotcakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This story is about teachers -- their threadbare lives, their struggles. Here are people doing the most important job in the world, and they have to wprry about getting enough money to re-sole their shoes. To me it can be as exciting as any chase, any gunplay.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From below comes the SOUND of the Isotta's horn.</context>
      <utterance>Now I see her teaching day classes while he teaches night school. The first time they meet ...</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, if you don't mind, I haven't got time to listen to the whole plot ...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make it short.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. It's your baby now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not good enough to write it alone. We'll have to do it together.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm all tied up. I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't we work in the evenings? Six o'clock in the morning? This next month I'm completely at your disposal. Artie is out of town.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What has Artie to do with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're engaged.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good for you. You've got yourself the best guy in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so. They're on location in Arizona, shooting a Western. I'm free every evening, every week- end. If you want, we could work at your place.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is another honk: from down below.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody can be that busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's out.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Betty, It can't be done.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're tough, all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're on your own. Stop being chicken-hearted and write that story.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honest to goodness, I hate you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And don't make it too dreary. How about this for a situation: she teaches daytimes. He teaches at night. Right? They don't even know each other, but they share the same room. It's cheaper that way. As a matter of fact, they sleep in the same bed -- in shifts, of oourse.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding? Because I think it's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do I.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Came on back. Let me show you where it fits in. She reaches in a drawer for her notes on Dark Windows.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty picks up the apple and is about to throw it after him.</context>
      <utterance>So long.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you --</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And here's a title: AN APPLE FOR</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, Max?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just found out why all those tele- phone calls. It is not Miss Desmond they want. It is the car they want to rent.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max has seen something off.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With his head he indicates</context>
      <utterance>Ssh...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DE MILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, young fellow. We'll see what we can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not worried. Everything will be fine. The old team together. Nothing can stop us. She turns and walks out of the shot. De Mille stands for a second watching her, then turns to his assistant.</utterance>
   <speaker>DE MILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get Gordon Cole. Tell him to forget about her car. He can find another old car. I'll buy him five old cars, if necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn back into Stage 18.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. De Mille.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did it go?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an exchange of looks between Max and Gillis.</context>
      <utterance>It couldn't have gone better. It's practically set. Of course, he has to finish this picture first, but mine will be his next.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He must be quite a guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'a a shrewd old fox. He can smell box office. Only I'm going to outfox him a litt1e. This isn't going to be C. B. deMille's Salome. It's going to be Norma Desmond's Salome, a Norma Desmond Production, starring Norma Desmond...Home, Max.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he says the words, he and Gillis exchange a glance in the rear view mirror.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Miss Desmond.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the slit in the door there is a suggestion of Norma.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Norma.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't turn around. Keep your eyes on the book.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma pushes the door open and comes in.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Norma.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just came to say good night. I don't want you to see me -- I'm not very attractive.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've lost half a pound since Tuesday.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was a little worried about the line of my throat. This woman has done wonders with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd better get to bed yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'll read a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You went out last night, didn't you, Joe?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you say that?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just happen to know it. I had a nightmare and I screamed for you. You weren't here. Where were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went for a walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you didn't. You took the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, I drove to the beach. Norma, you don't want me to feel I'm locked up in this house?</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not, Joe. It's just that I don't want to be left alone. Not now, while I'm under this terrible strain. My nerves are being torn apart. All I ask is for you to be a little patient and a little kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't done anything, Norma.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bends and kisses the top of his head.</context>
      <utterance>Of course you haven't. I wouldn't let you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes into her room, shutting the door behind her. Gillis puts his book down and looks at her door.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, my darling.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>PARAMOUNT</speaker>
      <mode>NIGHT</mode>
      <context>BOOM MOVES FORWARD to the only So we'd started two lights. They are the door working on it, the and window of Betty Schaefer's two of us. Nights, cubicle. Betty sits at the when the studio was desk, typing. Gillis, his deserted, up in her coat off, his shirt-sleeves little cubby-hole rolled up, j.s pacing the floor, of an office. discussing the construction of a sentence. The discussion at a stalemate, Betty suggests some coffee. Gillis agrees. From the electric plate on the shelf beside her, Betty takes a glass coffee machine. Gillis seats himself in her chair and starts typing. Betty opens the door and comes out on the balcony to fill the coffee machine from the water cooler stand- ing beside the door.</context>
      <utterance>Start on a LONG SHOT. THE GILLIS' VOICE</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves back into the room.</context>
      <utterance>I got the funniest letter from Artie. It's rained every day since they got to Arizona. They re-wrote the whole picture for rain and shot half of it. Now the sun is out. Nobody knows when they'll get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's good about it? I miss him something fierce.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean this is good dialogue along in here. It'll play.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Especially with lots of music underneath, drowning it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you sometimes hate yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He resumes typing. Betty puts the water on. She picks up a pack of cigarettes on the desk, finds it's empty and throws it away, sees Gillis' open gold cigarette case and lighter on the table by the couch. Betty reaches for a cigarette. The inscription en- graved inside the case catches her eye. It reads:</context>
      <utterance>Constantly. No, in all serious- ness, it's really good. It's fun writing again. I'm happy here, honest I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Norma?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's who?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I don't usually read private cigarette cases.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that. It's from a friend of mine. A middle-aged lady, very foolish and very generous.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll say. This is solid gold.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gave her some advice on an idiotic script.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's that old familiar story, you help a timid little soul across a crowded street. She turns out to be a multimillionaire and leaves you all her money.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the trouble with you readers. You know all the plots. Now suppose you proof-read page ten while the water boils.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this street. All card- board, all hollow, all phoney. All done with mirrors. I like it better than any street in the world. Maybe because I used to play here when I was a kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were you -- a child actress?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was born just two blocks from this studio. Right on Lemon Grove Avenue. Father was head elec- trician here till he died. Mother still works in Wardrobe.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Second generation, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Third. Grandma did stunt work for Pearl White. I come from a picture family. Naturally they took it for granted I was to become a great star. So I had ten years of dramatic lessons, diction, dancing. Then the studio made a test. Well, they didn't like my nose -- it slanted this way a little. I went to a doctor and had it fixed. They made more tests, and they were crazy about my nose -- only they didn't like my acting.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice job.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should be. It cost three hundred dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saddest thing I ever heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now I'm a reader...</context>
      <utterance>Not at all. It taught me a little sense. I got me a job in the mail room, worked up to the Stenographic.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come clean, Betty. At night you weep for those lost closeups, those gala openings...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's really more fun.</context>
      <utterance>Not once. What's wrong with being on the other side of the cameras?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I will now kiss that nose of yours.</context>
      <utterance>Three cheers for Betty Schaefer!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis kisses her nose. As he stands there, his face close to hers -</context>
      <utterance>If you please.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I say you smell real special.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must be my new shampoo.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's no shampoo. It'smore like a pile of freehly laundred hand- kerchiefs, like a brand new auto- mobile. How old are you anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-two.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start walking in the direction of the office.</context>
      <utterance>That's it -- there's nothing like being twenty-two. Now may I suggest that if we're ever to finish this story you keep at least two feet away from me ... Now back to the typewriter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Max? Want to wash the car, or are you doing a little spying in your off hours?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be very careful as you cross the patio. Madame may be watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Will that do it?</context>
      <utterance>How about my going up the kitchen stairs and undressing in the dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis goes every night...</context>
      <utterance>I'm not inquiring where Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you? I'm writing a script and I'm dying to finish it, no matter what.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just that I'm very worried about Madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you are. And we're not help- ing her any, feeding her lies and more lies. Getting herself ready for a pioture ... What happens when she finds out?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She never will. That is my job. It has been for a long time. You must understand I discovered her when she was eighteen. I made her a star. I cannot let her be destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You made her a star?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I directed all her early pictures. There were three young directors who showed promise in those days: D.W. Grirrith, C.B. deMille, and Max von Mayerling.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And she's turned you into a servant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was I who asked to come back, humiliating as it may seem. I could have gone on witn my career, only I found everything unendur- able arter she divorced me. You see, I was her rirst husband.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's the matter... Betty, wake up!  Why are you staring at me like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was I? I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What is it, Betty?</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something came up. I don't want to talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty gets up.</context>
      <utterance>What is it you've heard. Come on, let's have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty doesn't answer, walks out on</context>
      <utterance>Is it about me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betty, there's no use running out on it. Let's face it, what- ever it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nothing. I got a telegram from Artie.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Artie. What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants me to come on to Arizona. He says it only oosts two dollars to get married there. It would kind of save us a honeymoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty stands crying silently.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you? We can finish the script by Thursday.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop crying. You're getting married. That's what you've always wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want it now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? Don't you love Artie?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I love him. I always will. I'm just not in love with him any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a moment's pause before he takes her in his arms. THE CAMERA MOVES AWAY.</context>
      <utterance>You did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betty, here's that weird-sounding woman again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this anyway?  This is Betty Schaefer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During the latter part of her call, the doors from Gillis' room have been pushed open and Gillis has walked towards her. Suddenly Norma senses his pre- sence and turns around. The telephone freezes in her hand. She tries to hang it up. Very calmly Gillis takes the receiver from her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Schaefer, I'm trying to do you a favor. I'm trying to spare you a great deal of misery. Of course you may be too young to even suspect there are men of his sort... NORMA  I don't know what he's told you, but he does not live with relatives, nor with friends, in the usual sense of the word. Ask him ... Ask him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is Joe.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, Betty, ask me again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joe, where are you? What's this all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or maybe it would be a better idea if you came over and saw it for yourself. The address is 10086</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't hate me, Joe. I did it because I need you. I need you as I never needed you. Look at me. Look at my hands, look at my face, look under my eyes. How can I go back to work if I'm wasting away under this torment? You don't know what I've been through these last weeks. I got myself a revolver. You don't believe me, but I did, I did! I stood in front of that mirror, only I couldn't make myself. It wouldn't be NORMA  fair to all those people who are waiting to see me back on the screen. I can't disappoint them. Only, if I'm to work, I need sleep, I need quiet, I need you! Don't just stand there hating me! Shout at me, strike me! But don't hate me, Joe. Don't you hear me, Joe?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I hear you. And I wish you'd keep still so I can hear the doorbell when she rings it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>E-29    INT. COUPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Connie is looking at the house numbers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty turns the car into the driveway of Norma's place, stops at the entrance steps. Betty gets out.</context>
      <utterance>Here's ten thousand seventy-nine, Betty. It must be over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betty, let me come along with you. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shuts the door of the car and goes up the steps.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'll be all right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is the sound of footsteps below and the ringing of a doorbell. Gillis rises.</context>
      <utterance>I love you, Joe. I love you, Joe. I love you, Joe. I love you, Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without a word, he leaves the room. Norma raises herself on the bed, reaching for a black negligee lying at the foot of it. As she does so, she dis- lodges her pillow a little, revealing a revolver hidden beneath it.</context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do, Joe?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>GILLIS' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right, Max. I'll take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands back as Gillis opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Betty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know why I'm so scared, Joe. Is it something awful?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty enters. As he leads her into the living room, Gillis puts his arm around her shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Come on in, Betty,</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentino used to dance here.</context>
      <utterance>Ever been in one of these old Hollywood palazzos? That's from when they were making eighteen thou- sand a week, and no taxes. Careful of these tiles, they're slippery.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is where you live?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have reached</context>
      <utterance>Whose house is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just look around. There's a lot of her spread about. If you don't remember the face, you must have heard the name of Norma Desmond.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was Norma Desmond on the phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want something to drink? There's always champagne on ice, and plenty of caviar.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did she call me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the rope, showing the projection screen under the picture.</context>
      <utterance>Jealous. Ever see so much junk? She had the ceiling brought from Portugal. Look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her own movie theatre.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What about Norma Desmond?</context>
      <utterance>I didn't come here to see a house.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Can you figure it out yourself?</context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to tell you. This is an enormous place. Eight master bedrooms. A sunken tub in every bathroom. There's a bowling alley in the cellar. It's lonely here, so she got herself a companion. A very simple set-up: An older woman who is well-to-do. A younger man who is not doing too well ...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. I'll give you a few more clues.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let's get out of here.</context>
      <utterance>No, no! I haven't heard any of this. I never got those telephone calls. I've never been in this house ... Get your things together.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All my things? All the eighteen suits, all the custom-made shoes and the eighteen dozen shirts, and the cuff-links and the platinum key- chains, and the cigarette cases?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on where? Back to a one-room apartment that I can't pay for? Back to a story that may sell and very possibly will not?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you love me, Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, sweetie -- be practical. l've got a good thing here. A long-term contract with no options. I like it that way. Maybe it's not very admirable. Well, you and Artie can be admirable.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joe, I can't look at you any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betty turns from him, to hide the fact that she is crying.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody asked you to.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads her in the direction of the door.</context>
      <utterance>All right, baby. This way out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to take his hand to kiss it as he passes. He doesn't stop. Norma catches his coat. Gillis moves right on into his room. Norma lies on the floor looking after him. She crawls toward a con- sole, pulls herself up by it, starts towards Gillis' door, passes a mirror, realizes how she looks, moves back to the mirror and takes the patches off her face and does a hasty job of removing the cream with her handkerchief, readjusts her expression to a poor travesty of a smile and goes to the door of Gillis' room.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Joe -- thank you, Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>May I come in? I've stopped cry- ing. I'm all right again. Joe, tell me you're not cross -- tell me everything is just as it was, Joe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing, Joe? What are you doing? You're not leaving me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am, Norma.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're not.  Max! Max!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>wrist watch, the platinum key-chain and the tie clip.</context>
      <utterance>Max is a good idea. He can help with my luggage.  Thanks for letting me wear the handsome wardrobe. And thanks for the use of all the trinkets. He takes the cigarette case and throws it on the chaise longue. Then he throws the lighter, the</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rest of the jewelry is in the top drawer.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's yours, Joe. I gave it to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'd take it in a second, Norma -- only it's a little too dressy for sitting behind the copy desk in Dayton, Ohio.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are nothing. You can have anything you want if you'll only stay. What is it you want -- money?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norma, you'd be throwing it away. I don't qualify for the job, not any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do this! Max! Max! ... I can't face life without you, and I'm not afraid to die, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's between you and yourself, Norma.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rushes into her room. Gillis closes the suitcase calmly, notices that he is still wearing some cuff- links Norma gave him, takes them off. Norma reappears in the door, carrying the revolver.</context>
      <utterance>You think I made that up about the gun...</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, you didn't believe me!.. Now I suppose you don't think I have the courage!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. sure -- if it would make a good scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't care. do you? But hundreds of thousands of people will carel</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During the preceding. Max has entered. He stands listening, paralyzed.</context>
      <utterance>Wake up, Norma. You'd be killing yourself to an empty house. The audience left twenty years ago. Now face it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lie! They still want me!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What about De Mille?</context>
      <utterance>What about the studio?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The studio wanted to rent your car.</context>
      <utterance>He was trying to spare your feelings.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanted what?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>De Mille didn't have the heart to tell you. None of us has had the heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lie! They want me, they want me! I get letters every day!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell her, Max. Come on, do her that favor. Tell her there isn't going to be any picture -- there aren't any fan letters, except the ones you write yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That isn't true! Max?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Madame is the greatest star of them all... I will take Mr. Gillis' bags.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard him. I'm a star!</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Norma, grow up. You're a woman of fifty. There's nothing tragic about being fifty - not unless you try to be twenty-five.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the greatest star of them all.</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye. Norma.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gillis picks up the typewriter and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>No one leaves a star. That makes one a star.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not leaving me!</utterance>
   <speaker>E-40    STAIRCASE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gillis descending with the typewriter.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is the SOUND OF A SHOT. The glass of the front door is shattered. Gillis at the door opens it and walks out, without looking back. Down the staircase rushes Norma. a disordered wild- ness in the way she moves.</context>
      <utterance>Joe! ...Joe!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hurries after Gillis.</context>
      <utterance>You're not leaving me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shoots twice in rapid succession. Gillis drops the typewriter. The shots have swung him around. He is now facing Norma. She shoots him. This shot hits him in the belly. He doubles up, instinctively backs away from her, plummets into the lit pool. Up the stone steps from the garage rushes Max. He sees the situation, hurries towards Norma, who stands exultant in the strange light from the pool.</context>
      <utterance>You're not leaving me!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stars are ageless, aren't they?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coroner's office? ... I want to speak to the Coroner ... Who's on this phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS HOPPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE CAMERA PANS TO ANOTHER PART OF THE BEDROOM, where Norma sits at a mirror, staring at herself blankly. Firing questions at her are the Captain of the Holmby Hills Division and the L.A. Homicide Squad. Max stands by faithfully.</context>
      <utterance>I am! Now get off, this is more important ... Times City Desk? Hedda Hopper speaking. I'm talking from the bedroom of Norma Desmond. Don't bother with a rewrite man, take this direct. Ready? -- As day breaks over the murder house, Norma Desmond, famed star of yesteryear, is in a state of complete mental shock ...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMBY HILLS CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do not deny having killed this man, Miss Desmond?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD OF HOMICIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just answer me that.</context>
      <utterance>Did you intend to kill him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMBY HILLS CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it a sudden quarrel? Had there been any trouble between you before?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD OF HOMICIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it was a quarrel, how come you had the gun right there?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMBY HILLS CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy -- where did you meet him for the first time? Where did he come from? Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD OF HOMICIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he have a wife? Did he had a girl friend? Did you know them?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMBY HILLS CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had he been trying to blackmail you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HEAD OF HOMICIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Were you in fear of bodily injury?</context>
      <utterance>Did the deceased ever threaten you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMBY HILLS CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hate him? Had you ever thought of doing something like this before?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD OF HOMICIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A police lieutenant has entered, goes to the Head of Homicide.</context>
      <utterance>Was theft involved? Did you catch him trying to steal something, or find he had stolen something?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The newsreel guys have arrived with the cameras.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD OF HOMICIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A word has pierced the mists that surround Norma.</context>
      <utterance>Tell them to go fly a kite. This is no time for cameras.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cameras? ...What is it, Max?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cameras have arrived, Madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Max flashes a look at the Head of Homicide.</context>
      <utterance>They have? Thank you, Max. Tell Mr. DeMille I will be on the set at once.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD OF HOMICIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please ...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMBY HILLS CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's one way to get her down stairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD OF HOMICIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. And let's have the car right outside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the stairway comes a murnur. They look up. Norma has emerged from the bedroom and comes to the head of the stairs. There are golden spangles in her hair and in her hand she carries a golden scarf. The police clear a path for her to descend. Press cameras flash at her every step. Max stands at the cameras.</context>
      <utterance>Is everything set up, gentlemen? Are the lights ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is everything set up, gentlemen?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAMERAMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The portable lights flare up and illuminate the staircase.</context>
      <utterance>Just about.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are the lights ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND CAMERA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All set.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Are you ready, Norma?</context>
      <utterance>Quiet, everybody! Lights!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is the scene? Where am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the staircase of the palace.</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm ready.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, yes. They're below, waiting for the Princess ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Norma arranges the golden GILLIS' VOICE scarf ebout her and proudy So they were grinding starts to descend the stair- after all, those cam- case. The cameras grind. eras. Life, which can Everyone watches in awe. be strangely merciful, had taken pity on Norma Desmond. The dream she had clung to so des- perately had enfolded her... At the foot of the stairs Norma stops, moved.</context>
      <utterance>All right.  Camera!  Action!</utterance>
   <speaker>NORMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't go on with the scene. I'm too happy. Do you mind, Mr. DeMille, if I say a few words? Thank you. I just want to tell you how happy I am to be back in the studio making a picture again. You don't know how much I've missed all of you. And I promise you I'll never desert you again, because after "Salome" we'll make another picture, and another and another. You see, this is my life. It always will be. There's nothing else - just us and the cameras and those wonderful people out there in the dark... All right, Mr. DeMille, I'm ready for my closeup.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
