<movie id="534" title="Superbad">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was doing research last night, for next year, and I think I'm gonna go with Bang Bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one's Bang Bus?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The one where they bang the chicks on the bus. Thirteen bucks a month. Total access, live Web Cam feed. The works. It'll be like I'm on the bus, banging them myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That stuff's bullshit, they're all faking it. And plus, your parents are gonna look at the bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It shows up under a different name.  I hope. Bang Bus.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That wouldn't look good. Maybe I should just pick the one with the least dirty sounding name.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth pulls up in front of a house.</context>
      <utterance>Weapons of Ass Destruction's out then.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could tell my parents I'm doing a project on Rome and I have to research orgies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan changes the radio station. Seth slaps his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for taking him, Seth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch that!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two are so funny. I can't imagine what you'll do without each other next year. Evan told me you didn't get into State.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you know. I got some other places. Good places. I think we'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to miss each other?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss each other? No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's disgusting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth and Evan drive off.</context>
      <utterance>Bye, boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am truly, truly jealous that you got to suck on those tits when you were a baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're being an idiot, man. You really shouldn't park there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk past DIMITRI (18, big Native American guy) as they enter the store. Dimitri aggressively bumps his shoulder into Seth.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck it. I'm a senior about to graduate. They should be suckin' my balls. It's the least they can do for stealing three years of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's wrong with Dimitri?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah dude, I forgot to tell you. I knocked the fuckin' shit out of him in capture the flag last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go to the magazine rack and stare at a Maxim cover.</context>
      <utterance>Good! 9th Grade Camp he gave me whiplash in "King of the Ring." I fucking hate that guy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at those nipples.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're like baby toes.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not fair. I have to hide every erection I get.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I get boners so big I can't hide them. And then I get nervous and my heart starts pounding, and it all just, like, feeds my boner. It just becomes this...thing...that's attached to me. And it won't go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just imagine if girls weren't weirded out by our boners and they actually wanted to see `em, like this shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know it's been, like, a year and a half since I've seen an actual human female nipple. Besides my mom's. I saw it last month, and it was sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit. Liat was two years ago? I guess so. She was insanely hot, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. Too hot. That's what sucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can that possibly suck? I'd be fuckin' psyched if I'd gotten with a girl that hot. You got, like, two dozen handjobs!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And three quarters of a blowjob, But that was fuckin' it. It was the peak of my ass- gettin' career, and it happened way, way, way too early.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're like Orson Welles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly! If I'd built up to it, I'd probably at least be having steady sex with a mediocre-looking girl at this point. I honestly now see why Orson Welles ate his fat ass to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have sex in college. Everyone does. And if not, you'll have the Bang Bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the key is to be good at sex by the time you're in college. You don't want girls to think you suck dick at fucking.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still think you've got a chance with Jules. She got mad hot over last summer, and clearly hasn't realized it, `cause she still flirts with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you joking, man? Let's see here...she dated Dan Remick, Matt Muir, Josh Corber and what's-his-face. All of those were cool guys. She's been hot way longer than you think. Why would she end her high school career with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Helen got with Ariel Shafir.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and he was a complete fucking loser. You're a step up from that. Which is why you should stop being a pussy and do her! You could nailthe shit out of her for, like, two months before you leave. That bitch looks like a good fucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan starts to walk out. Seth follows.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! I'm sick of you talking about her like that, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, you can talk about that bitch all day every single day, but I can't say one thing about her?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't constantly insult her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't insult her! I said she looks like a good fucker! She looks like she can take a dick. That's a good thing. Some women pride themselves on their dick- taking abilities.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo. Seth. Did you hear I'm having the big grad party? Evan, a little scared, keeps his distance.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terry spits on Seth's shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Seth wipes the spit off. He looks at Terry and seems as though he's about to say something, but is interrupted when Terry starts hocking up more spit. Seth runs away as Terry and his friends laugh. He catches up to Evan and they head back to school.</context>
      <utterance>And you're not coming. Tell your fucking faggot friend he can't come either.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. You really bitched out on that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bitched out? You bitched out! You were across the street before I even realized what was going on.  That guy's such a douche bag.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment later a KID with prosthetic leg jogs by.</context>
      <utterance>This...is...bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poo-say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Evan, thanks for the pen.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't worry, no worries. Just keep it. Then you'll just have it, and you won't have to borrow another pen.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks...uh...I was going to ask you, did you hear about Terry's grad party? It's going to be so insane.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's a maybe. But, you know, I gotta, I got my...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>there's so much other fun shit that is going to be going on that night...so, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fun shit? But I, like, never see you at any parties or anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because of all the other fun shit I'm off doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. So why weren't you at Dimitri's party on Saturday?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(The real version of Evan's story is shown through a montage of quick flashbacks.)</context>
      <utterance>Dimitri's? I uh...didn't want to go, because, well, I did other stuff. Saturday...  Oh yeah! Saturday night was awesome!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - V.O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First my parents went out to a double feature, so a bunch of people came over...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An empty bottle of Sambuca in front of them and empty beer cans at their feet, the three boys each shotgun a beer.</context>
      <utterance>...and we had a couple drinks in my basement...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - V.O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and Seth's parents were having this cocktail party, and we went over there to, like, mingle...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys laugh hysterically as they each shake Tobassco Sauce onto their tongues. They writhe around in agony as several adults look at them like they are morons.</context>
      <utterance>...and there were actually some really interesting and, like, entertaining people there...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D - V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and, uh, then we saw some, uh, live music.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you would've loved it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds so fun. I would love to go do something like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen is disappointed in his response.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...well, you know, me and Seth are always cooking up...uh...fun little...events.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, are you guys going to the same school next year?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah. We were going to but, uh, we got into different ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do without him?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same shit I've always been doing. It'll be fine. Don't worry about it. I'm not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Grier, I joined this class because I thought I'd be cooking with a partner. It's not fair. She's never here. I don't get twice the marks for doing all the work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GREIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't invent odd numbers, Seth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan is playfully throwing flour at a tiny Japanese boy. They both laugh hard.</context>
      <utterance>Look at Evan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While I'm over in my unit, isolated and alone, eating my terrible-tasting food because I can't even properly mix ingredients by myself, I gotta look over at that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wash and dry. And that is B.S. I'm like a single mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GREIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, save it for next week. Today Jules' partner isn't here either. Pair up with her. Station four.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The teacher walks away. Seth looks over to station four, nervous as hell. ANGLE ON: Jules, well-dressed and "popular" looking. She stands alone at station four, laying out utensils. Seth musters his courage and walks towards Jules. He stops, unsure of what to say.</context>
      <utterance>Jules?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Seth, your partner didn't come again?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's kind of a personal question.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. It was my attempt at humour.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh, maybe I kidnapped her so you'd be forced to work with me. There's my attempt at humour.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I would call that a success.  Marscampone... scamponee cheese? Is that some kind of new cheese or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All cheese tastes the same to me anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except blue cheese. That stuff is sick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you! Yes! My older brother always eats blue cheese. You know that stuff is actually moldy. Like, they tell you it's moldy, then they tell you to eat it anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well whoever "they" are, they can eat my dick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, probably nothing. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My parents are out of town and I'm thinking of having a party. I don't know how big it'll be, but you should come anyways.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sure. That sounds fun. I love parties.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? I don't usually see you at them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uh...how do I do this?</context>
      <utterance>Oh, uh. It's more of, like, a love-hate thing. Right now I love them, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan is standing by the sink scrubbing a tray. Behind him, at the table, is the small Japanese boy eating the tiramisu.</context>
      <utterance>I'll write down my address and number. ANGLE ON: Evan.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth walks up to Evan.</context>
      <utterance>That's good shit. Huh, Miroki?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: Fogell entering the room</context>
      <utterance>Dude! She's havin' a fuckin' party.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell Fogell about the party.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey guys, I was walking here, and on the way, I saw Nicola, and she was wearing these tight white pants and a black g- string and you could see it right through the pants.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nine thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told her what time it was. It was awesome. She's got the nicest ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like you'd know what to do with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha ha. I'm really gonna miss your knee- slappers when me and Evan are at State.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well I'll be at Junior college where the girls are half as smart, and thus twice as likely to blow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you guys doing tonight?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Sorry. You'll just have to fingerbang yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Seth always said I was too much of a pussy, but he was wrong. It's been arranged. At lunch, I'm going to the same place Mike Snider went to pick up my brand new false identification card.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude! That's perfect, `cause, Evan, didn't you just say that you heard about a party?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up. Who cares? Just be happy he told. And hey! Now you can buy the booze.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds cool. Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GREIR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're not in this class, leave this class!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Well done, man. We'll see you after class.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you tell that nimrod you're not going to room with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...no, not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better, man. That guy is a poon-tang repellent. Seth sees Jules coming.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seth, dishes time. What's the hold up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're getting a fake ID.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you two have four more years to cuddle, so let's get to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, we're going to different schools.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? You're cutting the cord? What's going to happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing! Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? What do people think is gonna happen? That's what I don't get.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not, like, dependent on each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We met when we were 8, we were fine before then. It's not like we do everything together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it looks like we get a little graduation party after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would do terrible things to get with Jules tonight. Terrible things.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit. I'd give my left foot to start dating Helen. She's killin' me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan slams his fist on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, Helen's a bitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fuckin' sick of this shit, man! Seriously. Why do you hate her? Is there even an actual reason? Because seriously, I'm beginning you think you like her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell no! I hate her.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was never going to tell you this story, because I knew that if you heard it you would never want to get with Helen, but over the last few weeks I've been having a hard time thinking of a reason not to. So, here it is. Helen and I went to elementary school together, right?  Well, in the third grade, I had...like...an odd problem. For some reason, I don't know why, I used to have this thing...where I would...like, kinda...sit around all day and draw pictures of dicks.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd just sit there for hours on end drawing dicks. I don't know what it was. I couldn't touch the pen to paper without it drawing a penis.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fucked.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit that's fucked up. Here I am this little kid who can't stop drawing dicks to save his life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that have to do with Helen?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just listen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, he calls my parents and they make me go to a psychologist who kept asking me all these dick questions. My parents wouldn't even let me eat dick-shaped foods for, like, months! No carrots, no Pop-sicles, no hot-dogs. You know how many fucking foods are shaped like dick?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. That's really messed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't even stand to look at her punk face.  I'm going to go take a piss. Peace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Here I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're coming to my party, right? It's fully on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Why? Should I not?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no. I really want you to come. But...uh, you did say you were getting a fake ID or something, is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very right. Right. I'm getting that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you get us drinks?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ummm... I don't know. I... think...maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, you scratch our backs, we'll scratch yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shirley is offended. Jules laughs a little. Seth laughs too hard.</context>
      <utterance>Well, funny thing about my back. It's located on my cock.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha! Alright, sure. I can do that. What do you guys want?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this is actually, like, a big favor, but, well, my parents gave me like a hundred bucks to feed myself for the week, but the house if full of food, so I figure I should just spend all of it on extra drinks for the party.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules hands Seth a hundred dollars.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. I would never even think of doing something that nice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth can't believe what he's hearing. He can barely contain his smile.</context>
      <utterance>Well, this is really nice of you. I mean, I really appreciate this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I just get, like, a shitload of different shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever shit you think people would like, I don't really know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHIRLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want Mike's Hard Lemonade.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'll see you tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls walk off, leaving Seth lost in thought. He suddenly runs down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! I'll see you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GYM TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan says nothing and the teacher soon redirects his attention elsewhere. Evan sees Seth jogging towards him.</context>
      <utterance>Evan, get into the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, just - Evan, listen to me. You know Jules? You know what she just did? She came up to me and asked me if I would buy her alcohol. Not just her, her whole party. Do you know what that means? It means that by some miracle, we were paired up, we talked, and she actually thought of me afterwards. Thought of me enough to decide that I was the guy that she was going to trust the fun-ness of her party with. She wants me! She fucking wants my dick!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever think maybe she's just using you to get her alcohol?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I thought of that! LISTEN TO</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has an older brother! She could have asked him, but she asked me! She looked me straight in the face and asked me. She wants to fuck me, man. Do you understand that? Fucking! Today is the day that fucking has become possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you stupid? You're not going to be able to sleep with her tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's going to be at the party, she's gonna be drunk, and she likes me at least a little, so I can get with her. Then, I make her my girlfriend, and then I fuck her all summer long! Then, by the time college rolls around, I'm the fuckin' fucking master, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make her your girlfriend? Of course! That's good. So, hypnosis, love potion, or mind-control helmet?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once I've gotten with her, I write her love letters, flowers, I'll do anything - I'll be the most pussy-whipped guy in the universe - what chick wouldn't go out with a guy like that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CLASSMATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan shrugs back.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell, Evan?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLASSMATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck off, Greg. Why don't you piss your pants again?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLASSMATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was, like, eight years ago, asshole! He runs off.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna hear the best part?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I haven't?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan looks upset, assuming that Seth is about to trash-talk Helen, as usual.</context>
      <utterance>Helen!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do the same thing, man! Buy Helen her alcohol. Then, tonight, when you guys are both drunk, get with her! This is the last party we're ever going to go to as high school people! I've fully ignored my hatred for Helen in coming up with this, which is a big ass deal. We need to stop being pussy and for once just goes balls out, man! Evan seems to be swayed.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should get Helen alcohol?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course! It'll be pimp, and then you know she'll be drunk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you talked to Fogell?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You talk to Helen, I'll find that retard Fogell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Helen! Hold up. Did you hear about the party tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're not coming, are you?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I just heard. It sounds sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, I am. That's why I came looking for you. Me and some guys are going to the liquor store after class, so I was thinking I could buy you yours, if you needed someone to.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah! That'd be great, that'd save me such a hassle, cause I was going to beg my sister, but yeah, could you get me, like, a bottle of Goldschlager? I'll pay you back tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will absolutely not. It's my treat.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan swings a friendly little punch at Helen's shoulder, but someone walks into him, causing him to nail her in directly in the tit!</context>
      <utterance>Wow. Thanks, Evan.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! You punched my tit!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry! Shit, shit. I'm so sorry! I just wanted to give you a friendly nudge in the arm, you know? I'm so sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it. So I'll see you at the party?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'll see you then. I'm so sorry about that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That douche bag isn't back yet, I've been standing here with my thumb up my ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did it, dude. I even offered to pay for it. It was pimp.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa. That is fucking pimp. Why didn't I do that? Shit. The bell rings.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, what are we going to tell the girls? "Sorry, we couldn't do what we promised because we're dickless incompetents!" We'll never get laid because of that little ass-fuck. How did he get in to State?! He's got shit for brains! Shit! How else can we get liquor?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey guys!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where have you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah! You almost gave me a goddamn heart attack! You better fucking have it, where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell reaches into his pocket and pulls out the fake ID. Evan grabs it.</context>
      <utterance>I got it. It's flawless! It's great, man, look.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay Mr..."McLovin"? What kind of a stupid name is that? What are you trying to be, an Irish R&amp;B singer?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they let you pick any name you want when you get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you picked McLovin?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was between that or Muhammad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why was it between that or Muhammad? Why didn't you just pick a common name?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, Seth, Muhammad is the most commonly used name on earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever actually met a guy named Muhammad?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you actually ever met a guy named McLovin?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! That's why you picked a bad name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You probably have federal agents tracking you for even considering the name Muhammad on a fake ID!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this shit man, you don't even have a first name. It just says "NAME:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One name?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just thought McLovin sounded old, and the chicks would dig it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Under what circumstances would you ever have to show a chick your ID?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She could ask. Or, I could just show it to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit! I don't believe this. This says you're fucking 25! Why didn't you just put 21?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you would ask that. Look, every day, dozens of kids roll into the liquor store with fake ID's trying to act like Joe Casual. Each and every one of these kids just so happens to be 21 years old. Just how many 21 year-olds do you think there are?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fool!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down! It's not terrible! This might work, but it's up to you, Fogell. They'll either think, "Oh, it's another punk kid with a fake ID." Or, "Look, it's McLovin, the twenty five year-old organ donor". What's it gonna be? Fogell takes a deep breath.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am McLovin.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not McLovin. No one's McLovin and this is never going to work. We need a new way to get alcohol. Could we drive to Canada or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk into the staff parking lot. Seth stops.</context>
      <utterance>I still think it's going to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck? Where's my car?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, man! What did I say? I told you that was a dumb idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you park in the staff-</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Fogell.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>`Cause you're not staff.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth storms off. Evan follows him.</context>
      <utterance>I am aware of that, Fagell.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go to your house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we wait for your Mom to piss off and steal your parents' booze like your brother always does. Take a bit from every bottle. Piece of cake. It's not exactly what Jules wanted, but it'll do, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on! Just wear what you wore to school.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you I can't do that. I can't let Jules see me in the same shit I wore at school. It's completely unbecoming.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you just go to your house and get your own clothes? `Cause this is stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're stupid! I can't go home. Then my mom will know the car got towed and I'll be grounded tonight. I'll just stay here all weekend and pick it up on Monday.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the fuck is the dirt bike?  Ah, screw it. I'm just gonna kill everyone. Boom! Die, piggies!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you have bigger clothes?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See what my dad's got.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's, like, 7:30 and my Mom's still here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, here's what we'll do. I'll fuck your Mom in the basement while you steal the liquor.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, asshole. Let's just sneak down there and grab it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe it. They marked them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean they...oh, man! Your parents are fuckers. What do we do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gin? That stuff is literally undrinkable.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the biggest bottle, you douche. Just do it! She's right in the other room!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, the booze?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth runs off with the gin and Coke bottle. Evan quickly closes the cabinet and sneaks off right before his mom enters. Through the window she see's that Seth is already on the front lawn and thinks nothing of it.</context>
      <utterance>Take it!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye, Mom! Love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Love you, sweety.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens it up and takes a whiff.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this mother. Smell it's glory.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He takes a crazy big swig.</context>
      <utterance>Mmm. It's good. Barely a scent.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Seth taste another swig, but makes a strange face. Evan grabs the bottle and takes a swig.</context>
      <utterance>See that? I always said I had the highest alcohol tolerance. I'm like Superman.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fucking water!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We have to go back!</context>
      <utterance>Water?  Fuck. Your brother beat us to the punch.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't go back! She totally knew, she'll bust us for sure, and we have to meet Fogell.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan pulls out his cell and chuckles as he types.</context>
      <utterance>Well, fuck...fine. Text your brother he's a stupid piece of crap.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A vest.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna look like a Pinocchio.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? It's just a vest.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. How many high schoolers you see in vests?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, they got a ton of liquor right in there. If we get it now we can get to the party faster with all of Jules' shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way! I work there. They know I'm not twenty-five.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody said anything about you, dick- mouth. You have one name on your ID. It's out of the equation!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now I'm gonna have to take drastic measures. I'm gonna steal the booze.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! No! Hell no! You can't do that!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. And that way I give Jules back her money, like you did with Helen. That was good thinking, that's fucking pimp. That's how you seal a deal. It won't be hard. Remember Dan Vertlieb stole a keg from here and he's got, like, really bad scoliosis!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not gonna steal it. Fogell, he's not going to steal it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Don't do this! I promise. I'll get the liquor later.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm stepping up. And once I'm up, I don't step back down. Maybe you "State" boys don't understand that. Seth walks to the store.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty two.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth hands the cashier a big EIGHTY DOLLAR BILL.</context>
      <utterance>You certainly are. That'll be eighty dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you kindly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome, Seth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, ma'am. You dropped your purse. Would you like me to help you to your car?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be lovely, young man. Would you like me to buy you alcohol?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be lovely!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enjoy your remaining years!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will. Enjoy fucking Jules!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SECURITY GAURD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We see that the Security Guard is right behind him. Seth doesn't look up, he just stares at the bottle dramatically.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do it kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws the bottle at the guards face. The guard blocks it with his billy club, grabs another bottle, and hurls it at Seth. Seth dodges it by an inch; the bottle hits the OLD LADY in the head.</context>
      <utterance>I never had a choice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, and, uh, my Mom said we can have the TV from her basement and I've got, like, three lava-lamps and one strobe light, so like, we can have that in the room- Evan sees Seth coming out of Shopwell's.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shh. Seth's coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still didn't tell him we're rooming-</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, where's all the stolen liquor?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you! I was gonna do it, but security was tight as shit. I was gonna do it though, don't think I wasn't. Let's go to the liquor store and try your stupid ID. Seth heads towards the bus stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait! I'm gonna put my vest back in my locker!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, here we are. Fogell, are you ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A list? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell reads the list. A worried look sweeps across his face.</context>
      <utterance>We're getting girls their booze so they'll get with us. I put a lot of thought into that list. It's the perfect party bar, so don't mess it up and get Sambuca again.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouzo, Drambuie, Jager, Gold-shlay-ger-</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goldschlager. That's for Helen, so do not forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-Alize, Captain Morgan Rum, Smirnoff Rasberry and a big ass bottle of Popov-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, and Mike's Hard Lemonade.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is too much. I can't get away with this much!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth hands Fogell the money.</context>
      <utterance>What's the difference?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell starts breathing very hard and making an ODD NOISE while doing so.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, man. I'm getting, like, really nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I want to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? You just promised you would. What is this shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if they turn me down?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we're in the same place that we're in right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fucking humiliating! Everyone in the store sees them kicking me out. What if they make me put all the liquor back on the shelf? I can't do that!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This whole thing is bigger than you, asshead! Just go in there and buy the damn alcohol!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if I don't feel like it anymore?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I will kill you! How's that? If you don't buy the alcohol, I will kill you!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Killing me won't get you any alcohol, jerkoff! I'm the one with the ID!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I will kill you, cut off your ugly face, put it over mine, and buy it my fucking self.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth stands for a moment, then suddenly rushes Fogell. Evan stands between them and breaks it up.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have the technology or the steady hands to pull off a procedure like that!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seth, calm down! Fogell, stop being a baby and go buy the alcohol! You said you'd do it, so do it. It's why you bought the ID, so just go do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell walks into the store.</context>
      <utterance>I'll try.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell flinches, shocked someone spoke to him. He keeps walking. He nears a mother and her 17 year old SON. As Fogell passes them, the son seems to recognize him. Fogell clearly recognizes the son. Their eyes meet. Fogell looks in the opposite direction.</context>
      <utterance>Hi there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fogell?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, Fogell. `Sup man. What're you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...nothing. Not Fogell...  Shut up, Moscovitch. You don't know me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CLERK approaches Fogell.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a problem, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Umm, nope, no problem whatsoever.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, did you do this? On the floor?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell is standing in a puddle of beer with beer sprayed all over his legs, holding a can of beer.</context>
      <utterance>No.  I think it happened before.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell walks away.</context>
      <utterance>I think I would know, thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a good ID, right? Mike Snider never had a problem. It's fine. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down.  Did you remember a condom?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You brought a condom?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I figured, you know, might as well. I brought one of those little things of spermicidal lube too. He takes them out of his pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You asshole! You laughed in my face when I said we'd be having sex tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't mean you shouldn't be prepared. You didn't even bring one?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. That wasn't the plan! We had a plan! I can't believe you did that without even consulting me about it!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't really even understand what your plan is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna go down on her for, like, hours. She'll love that. She'll want to go out with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but I figured there's no harm in bringing just one little condom.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And one little bottle of spermicidal lube. That's nuts. You can't let her know you brought that! These girls are 18, not dried up old ladies. They're ready to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. I won't bring the lube.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rings up a six pack of Budweiser.</context>
      <utterance>Hello...  Mindy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fogell just nods kind of proud of himself. She stops ringing stuff up and looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I love that stuff. Been drinking it for years. I heard they recently decided to start adding more hops.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth looks as if he sees something in the distance. He stands upright.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think I could get Helen to do some kind of long distance thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy Shit! It's Cary Hutchins!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't seen her since she switched schools.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She had the biggest tits in the universe. Down the block there is a girl walking a dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard she had breast-reduction surgery. Her tits must be crazy perfect now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth and Evan run off towards the girl.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta see these bastards. Let's check `em out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, I'm gonna pretend to trip and grab `em.  I hope they've healed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A huge smile forms on Fogell's face as he pulls out a wad of money and hands it to the cashier. She starts to gather his change when, SUDDENLY, a BIG GUY runs up and PUNCHES Fogell right in the side of the head!!! Fogell falls to the ground. The dude sticks his hand in the open register, grabs a handful of money and runs! The whole thing is over in a matter of seconds. Fogell is on the ground, dazed and confused.</context>
      <utterance>That comes to a total of $123.59</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell sees the distressed cashier frantically dialing the police.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell happened?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it...I don't believe it....</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a waste.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she fully looked way better before. I thought when they reduced them, they just kind of reshaped them nicer. Made them more supple.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't even begin to imagine the justification for making breasts smaller.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan sees something in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>It's like me making my nuts saggier.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa. What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They see a cop car with the lights flashing parked outside the liquor store. Seth and Evan cautiously approach the liquor store and look inside. They see two POLICE talking with the Cashier, and Fogell is standing right beside them!</context>
      <utterance>Check it out! The cops!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit! They busted Fogell!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, did he punch anyone else?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They chuckle. Then they turn to Fogell.</context>
      <utterance>Apparently, she has an exam.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officers each take out a note pad and a pencil.</context>
      <utterance>We'd like to ask you a couple questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, first things first. What's your name?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name, it's...it's..  Mc..mac..laddle...</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MicMac what?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no I said, "McLovin".</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McLovin?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officers both write down some information.</context>
      <utterance>McLovin.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell looks twice as scared.</context>
      <utterance>Cool name. And your first name?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell trails off mumbling and starts to breathe heavily, making an ODD NOISE. Behind him, in the window of the store, we see Seth and Evan peeking through.</context>
      <utterance>Oh...that's uh...a good one...it's a...an interesting...uh...event...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe this bullshit! I can't...this isn't happening! I didn't even know you could get arrested for this shit! WE NEED THAT FUCKING LIQUOR!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god. Are they gonna take him downtown?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck Fogell! He got arrested! We're on our own.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need a new way of getting liquor.  AAAHHH!! The money! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! How much money can you get?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? Money? What about Fogell?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't matter anymore. I just lost a hundred dollars of Jules' money!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to help him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth steps into the driveway leading to the parking lot.</context>
      <utterance>Help him? What are we gonna do? Bust him out of jail? I don't even know where jail is! What we need is the alcohol, which is impossible because we don't have any fucking money!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Just...calm down. We need to think. We need to think.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a car pulls out of the lot going 10 mph and knocks Seth down!!!</context>
      <utterance>Fuck thinking! We need to act!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the BACKGROUND (not in the view of Fogell and the cops) we see DRIVER of the car, a shady-looking guy in a hockey jersey, gets out of his car and walks over to where Seth is lying, apologizing frantically.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, your name is just McLovin, there's no need to get irrational.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A lot of people have strange names these days.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I once arrested a man-lady who was legally named "Pearl Necklace."</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just... I changed my name. I was going to be a singer. R&amp;B.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. That's not illegal.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, how old are you McLovin? Fogell looks down at the bags of booze again.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old enough for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I see your ID?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell takes his shaking, sweaty hand, sticks it in his pocket, and pulls out his fake ID. He slowly hands it over to Officer Slater. The cops both look at it, then Fogell. Beads of sweat are running down Fogell's face. In the background, Seth pops up and starts kicking the guy's car out of anger. Evan and the driver both restrain Seth.</context>
      <utterance>Um...okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're an organ donor?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to be one but my wife insisted.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officers start laughing. Fogell is shocked. They hand back the ID.</context>
      <utterance>Just like a woman. Even after you're dead, they want to tear your heart out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell points at his giant black eye.</context>
      <utterance>Look. I'm really sorry, but I don't really have any information. I didn't really see him. His fist hit here.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you in a hurry or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, yeah... kinda. I kinda had to catch a bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Umm... near thirteenth and Granville.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell is completely dumbfounded.</context>
      <utterance>We'll take you there, get your information on the way. Sit tight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so sorry, man! I'm so sorry! I didn't see you at all. Are you okay? Are you okay? I'm sorry, man. Look, what can I do? Are you okay? The driver glances at the cop car.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, please don't report me, we can figure this out, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wouldn't I report you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anything! What can I do?</context>
      <utterance>Because I'll do anything! Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have any money?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver reaches into his pocket and hands Seth some money. Seth looks at it. It's seven dollars.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Just take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth stuffs the money in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>What is this? This isn't enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you just came from the liquor store, give us your liquor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't get any. They're not letting anyone in. They're arresting someone or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth, acting poorly, pretends he's way more hurt than he is.</context>
      <utterance>Well, they'll be arresting somebody else if you don't do something quick. Ow! My shoulder! It's killing me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Wait! Okay, you want alcohol? I can get you alcohol. I'm on my way to this party right now. There's gonna be tons of liquor. I will definitely get you plenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth goes over to Evan.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on. Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Jules' money is gone, Fogell's out, we've got no other option. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at the Driver, who is staring at Evan with a dumb expression on his face.</context>
      <utterance>I don't....I don't like this idea at all. I'm just not feeling it. That guy's fucking creepy. Just look at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cause you totally look like his brother.</context>
      <utterance>You know a guy named Jimmy, perchance?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's an idiot. And he's our only hope. Come on, don't break your promise to Helen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, that lady just wouldn't stop crying, huh? And you're the one that got punched. Did you hear her say she has an exam tomorrow? Boo-fuckin'-hoo. Am I right?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heh. Good one.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHEALS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could we have taken her in? Just to scare the shit out of her?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops chuckle as they all get in the cop car.</context>
      <utterance>Hah. Probably could have found a way. But a good general rule is only take people in you want to ride with. And whiny bitches don't make that cut.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an awkward silence, when suddenly Seth starts to wriggle in discomfort.</context>
      <utterance>One of you bros could have sat up here with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth fishes his cell phone out of his pocket and looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>Aaah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>875-6611?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth answers the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jules! What's the haps?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seth! Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jules! I just got in a cab and I'm going to the liquor store as we speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A huge smile sweeps across Seth's face.</context>
      <utterance>Awesome. I can't wait for you to get here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It looks like it could actually be a great party. I think, like, tons of people might show up. I hope they don't trash my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if they want to do that they're going to have to get through me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth hangs up the phone, completely elated.</context>
      <utterance>So I guess I don't have to worry then. I'll see you soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She called, man! That's insane! She's practically begging for it. She said, "I can't wait for you to get here."</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth and Evan are very weirded out.</context>
      <utterance>That sounds like she fully wants it. Where's she gonna get it from, huh, my man?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, are you sure that it's cool we're here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Driver runs into the house happily, Seth and Evan following closely behind.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, definitely. I'm essentially best friends with this guy. A whole bunch of my buddies are coming. Come on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit! Let's grab one of these buckets and go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck do you think you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The guys turn and see that in corner of the kitchen, the Driver, holding a phone, is being yelled at by a massive brute, MARK.</context>
      <utterance>What, man? It's nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You calling more of your stupid friends again? Ya prick.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark, calm down, okay? Just relax.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the fuck out of my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Mark grabs the Driver by the back of the neck and drags him out of the kitchen, down the front hall and out the door. A group of people follow, including Seth and Evan.</context>
      <utterance>Mark, come on. What the heck? Don't be a dick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark! Dude! This is bullshit! Just chi- Mark steps on the Driver's hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Driver takes his hand out from under Mark's foot. He stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhhh! Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Mark becomes enraged. He takes a big step forward and brutally KICKS the Driver square in the nuts! The Driver clutches his nuts and falls to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, man. I'll fucking do this!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark and his buddies head back in, leading them towards Seth and Evan, who quickly duck back into the party.</context>
      <utterance>Francis, you and your idiot friends stay the away from me and mine or I'll flipping shiv your ass!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude, let's slip out the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Come on, we're here. Let's just hurry up and do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to end up like that guy? Not me, I need my nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need this liquor!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need it! I don't need it. I'm going to tell Helen I like her, and then maybe she'll get with me; not after I get her stinking drunk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why haven't you ever made a move, you pussy?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I respect her! I'm not going to put that kind of unfair pressure on her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These aren't girls, they're women! They need our dicks as much as we need their poons - and we all love liquor, so where's the fucking beef?!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're leaving, okay? These guys could kill us. You want to get killed for liquor?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really gonna bail on me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan walks out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth storms off.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay...if that's how you're going to be, then I'll get the booze on my own. And you're not getting any. And neither is Helen!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um...hey...uh, officers. I could answer those, uh, questions now if you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officers start to chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>We get the gist of it. You were buying some beer, some guys came in and robbed the place. I don't think we're gonna find `em this time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was only one guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only one guy? Well, fuck that. We could never catch one guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, McLovin, if it was two guys, we'd have twice the chance of catching one of them. But just one guy? I mean, how are we supposed to find one guy in this whole city?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, McLovin. You know how many people there are in this city? I have trouble finding people I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you guys supposed to be trained or something? Don't you have a computer?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that stuff can help, but if someone walks up to me on the street, and is like, "Hey, find Bob." Well, how the hell am I supposed to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Bob?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. If I don't know who he is, then how am I supposed to know where he is?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you're new to the force, like I am-</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only six months in.  I got two and a half years under my belt.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You learn a lot of crazy stuff. For example- The car radio goes off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a 245 at East 24 and Montgomery. It's Bailey's Bar and Grill. Car 43, respond please. Slater picks up the receiver.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten-four.  Nice. Ya see, Michaels, when ever there's a call for a bar, you take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>Good fucking call, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, McLovin. We got a situation at Bailey's. We have to see to that, but we'll drop you off right after. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael's hits the siren and they drive off.</context>
      <utterance>Um...okay...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes out his vibrating cell phone and looks at the callers name...it's Helen.</context>
      <utterance>Whaa! What the...oh..</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He looks intensely at the cell as it continues vibrating.</context>
      <utterance>Oh dude. Oh dude. Oh dude.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He presses talk.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Okay. Here we go...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eva...lo.................</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone cuts out. Evan sees that he has no reception. He looks back at the party, then at his cell phone. He shakes his head and turns back towards the party.</context>
      <utterance>Helen? Helen?!?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright McLovin, this will only take a few minutes. Just grab a beer at the bar and we'll be done before you know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officers chuckle as they lead Fogell into the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Well...what's goin' on in there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOMELESS GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell quickly sits at the bar by the entrance to the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Everywhere?!? You didn't see me pissin' anywhere!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Officer Michaels walks up to the Homeless Guy.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, Michaels. I've got your back. Show this rummy how we roll.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Homeless Guy turns and sees the cops.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me! Sir!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michaels blocks the door and the Homeless Guy rams into him, knocking him to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Resisting!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slater runs at the Homeless Guy and chases him into the dining area. The Homeless Guy knocks over a table, which Slater trips over.</context>
      <utterance>Good one, Michaels!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I shoot him?!?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Homeless Guy gets up, grabs Fogell and HURLS him into a rack of trays! He then turns to run, but SLIPS on a wet spot and SLAMS his head against the ground! The cops burst into the room to find Fogell panting on his knees with the Homeless Guy unconscious on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Ow!!! Please! Stop, you fucking bum!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McLovin! Nice!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am buying you a beer, McLovin!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guys just nod at Seth and continue to look at him strangely.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, wut up?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that? Is that red wine?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...no. What? I don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That shit you spilled all over yourself, idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>On Seth's upper thigh there is a red splotch about the size of a palm of a hand.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my lord. You were just dancing in there, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guys all burst out laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, so?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fucking blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would I get blood on my leg from---</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some girl perioded on my fucking leg!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth pokes at the splotch.</context>
      <utterance>I've never seen that before in my life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Guy 1 gets up as Seth tries to cover up the mess with his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>That is disgusting.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta show this to Bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Bill? Don't show Bill! No! I can't believe this is happening!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should find who did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is un-fucking-believable. I have to look good tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who'd you dance with?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who gives a shit? Fuck! These aren't even my pants!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PARTY GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks about the right age!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta clean this shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Click. Slater turns his radio down, ignoring the calls.</context>
      <utterance>Calling all units, armed and dangerous man in the vicinity of-</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So anyways, we leave the bar, I'm charmin' her pants off telling her stories of shoot-outs and shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been in shoot-outs!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McLovin, all we do is bonk homeless people on the head. You're practically a cop now.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I pull up in front of her house and she asks me to come inside for some coffee. Of course, I say yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit. So we go into the kitchen. I start taking off my clothes, she fucking flips, starts screaming at me, and I'm like "Can't have coffee without cream." Oh!!! Right? I fucking said that. Then, she slaps me, throws me out. I'm telling you McLovin, stay out of bars.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you don't need to tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, yeah, you gotta look in different places. The gym, an art class, you know, shit like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I met the Missus at paint ball. Can you believe that? I shot her in the neck, and we just hit it off. And my first wife -- who is a whore -- where do you think we met? A bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I find they're always good for a little quick ass. The cops laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet I know your trick, McLovin. You do the whole mysterious guy thing, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell thinks for a moment, he is feeling rather comfortable.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah McLovin, how's it going with the ladies?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops and Fogell burst out laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Well, officers, it's not the going with the ladies I care about, it's the coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees that the cops clearly like him; his confidence level increased, he takes a chance.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! McLovin in the house!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officers glance at each other as sinister smiles creep across their faces.</context>
      <utterance>So...you guys got guns, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We got guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't had one for long, but, man, let me tell you - it's like having two dicks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michaels and Slater look to each other.</context>
      <utterance>Can I...can I hold one? Your gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, if we took the bullets out?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slater pulls out his gun and takes out the clip.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fogell takes the unloaded gun and flops it back and forth in his hands, a huge smile gleaming.</context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. I've never held one. Are they hard to shoot?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're Michaels they are. He can't shoot worth dick.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, old man. I could out-shoot you with my sack tucked between my legs.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only one way to settle this.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are going to shoot something, right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Helen. Hi. I had bad reception. Are you at the party?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm in a cab. I'll be there soon. Are you still coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, definitely. Um, about your Goldschlager...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on there?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, nothing, I just wanted to make sure you were still coming, you know, and that you didn't get caught up at a cocktail party or some club.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. I'm gonna be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I can't wait to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's going to be a real fun...event.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DUDE 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start pouring a baggy of coke on the table when one of them notices Evan standing in the corner.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. And he's a beast.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUDE 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan glances down at his crotch. He is confused and horrified.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Was it you? Are you the guy? The kid with the splotch on his crotch?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. What splotch-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DUDE 4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's he?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUDE 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They draw the coke into lines as Evan slowly heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>He's Jimmy's brother. The dude with the crazy raps, the one I told you about!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dude 3 gets up and blocks the door.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no, that's not me either. Wrong guy, man. Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUDE 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No, that's you, man. You are fully Jimmy's brother! You were just so messed up you can't remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me, man. That wasn't me. I don't even listen to rap.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUDE 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start doing the lines of coke. Evan is very afraid.</context>
      <utterance>It was you! I know it! Come on! Rap! I've been telling these guys about you. Just give them one rap. Come on. Rap. Rap.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GUY 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth turns and sees Mark, the guy who assaulted the Driver, walking towards him. He notices Mark has a splotch on his leg, too.</context>
      <utterance>There! That's the guy!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! You got one, too! We're blood brothers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Horrified, Seth scrambles for excuses.</context>
      <utterance>Shut it, you little shitter! What the hell were you doing dancing with Jacinda?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I...I didn't dance with her! I don't even dance! Never even tried it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then where did that come from, asshole?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Maybe me and you rubbed up against each other at some point. How am I supposed to know?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...cause, yo! Bitches and gats, bitches and gats, what do all of we's got?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUDES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bitches and gats!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we steal all the money?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUDES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bitches and gats!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo! I kill the whores of Vice City with my magnum 9/Take out the punk pigs with my Glok design/ Drink a fifth of Hennessy and get benign/Fuck all the bitches with their asses fine</utterance>
   <speaker>THE DUDES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SOME GUY bursts into the room.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOME GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dude 3 does a line of coke and they all get up together and charge out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Dudes! Looks like a fight!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan and the four dudes who were doing coke walk into the room. Evan is shocked to see Seth at the center of so much commotion. Mark notices the detergent bottle in Seth's hands.</context>
      <utterance>I swear to God it wasn't me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what the fuck is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nothing. It's detergent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. And what are you doing with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mark sees the bottle of MIKE'S HARD LEMONADE in Seth's pocket and takes it out. He looks at it, then looks at Seth with a look of death.</context>
      <utterance>I...uh, I got blood on my pants.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Mark violently SHOVES Seth and throws the beer bottle at his face!!! Seth holds up a detergent jug and deflects the beer bottle.</context>
      <utterance>I brought them from home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DUDE 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold him!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACINDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ruined my birthday!!! You humiliated me!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She charges at him again, arms flailing. Seth scurries around the room, shielding the blows with the detergent bottles. Evan throws the Enormous Guy to the ground and runs. Evan backs off, spots Seth, and follows him out of the party.</context>
      <utterance>You're the one who used my leg as a tampon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been saying some bold words, my friend. Better not mess up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLAM!!! Michaels blasts off a round, which punches a hole right through the center of the "O" in the stop sign.</context>
      <utterance>You can do it, officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boo-yaka-sha!!! Suck it, Slater. Suck my nuts. Long, but gentle.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all laugh hysterically.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! And eat his ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The cops look at each other and shrug.</context>
      <utterance>Can I shoot one?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slater hands Fogell the gun, when suddenly a SIREN can be heard in the distance getting closer.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sure. Here. Go nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck. The cops!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slater grabs the gun out of the disappointed Fogell's hand and holsters it. They all hop into the car.</context>
      <utterance>Let's bail! Shotgun!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the car radio goes off.</context>
      <utterance>Hah, hah! Eat it. So, dudes, what do we do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops stop and listen.</context>
      <utterance>We got a 257 at Fifth and Paysview, all units in the area report to Fifth and Paysview. Car 98. That's you. Do it. Seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son-of-a-bitch.  Car 98, ten-four.  Ya dumb whore. Ha!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean? We gonna get to shoot anyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We'll drop you off after. Cool?</context>
      <utterance>I wish. Probably some lame house party.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, man. Let's show these fuckers how we roll.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...huff...hufff...you fuckin' prick...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You...huff...bailed on me...huff...man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I didn't!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you did! We were supposed to do something and you left instead of doing it! That's the definition of bailing!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you said we should burn our dicks off and I didn't, that's not bailing!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is bailing, if you promised to burn your dick off!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bottom line is you're a bailer. You just bailed on me, you bailed on me this morning when Terry spat on me, and you're bailing on me next year!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! Okay! There it is! It finally comes out!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were supposed to go to college together! Since elementary school! What ever happened to that!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to that, is that you're too stupid to get into the schools I did!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was not too stupid, I was too lazy!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth can't believe it. He's extremely hurt.</context>
      <utterance>You've wasted all my time, you selfish bastard!!! Instead of chasing girls and making friends, I threw away the last three years talking bullshit with you! And now, because of you, I'm going to college a fucking friendless virgin!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting with a girl won't make you any less of a loser next year!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth drops one of the tide bottles and shoves Evan hard. Evan shoves him back.</context>
      <utterance>You talking to me or yourself? You fucking loser!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do they expect us to work these things while we're driving? I can't even work my iMac while I'm sitting at my desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, like, what does that computer do?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty much anything, if you're smart enough to figure it out. Like, who do you really hate? Gimme a name.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susette Graham.</context>
      <utterance>Um...my French teacher. Mrs. Graham.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slater nods. Michaels bring her file up, then punches a few buttons and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Can I do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow, Mrs. Graham will have a boot on her car. Fogell laughs his ass off.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate my dad, too!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. The place should be around here somewhere. McLovin, are the numbers on that side odd or even?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too dark out.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slater gets his flashlight and points it out the window.</context>
      <utterance>We got flashlights.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michaels and Slater start making light saber noises and pretend to fight with their flashlights.</context>
      <utterance>I wasn't even sure light came out of those things. I thought they were just cool looking clubs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit. Shit, shit, SHIT!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe this is happening again.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god...is he...are you gonna make sure he's alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay, we're gonna get out of the car now. McLovin, you stay right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That guy better not be dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry! You pushed me first.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys notice the cops.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't push you into fucking oncoming traffic!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is everyone alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're great.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you should be careful boys. That's how accidents happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, when cops drive like maniacs and hop the fucking curb?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pabst. You boys been doing a bit of drinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No officer. Not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that more beer you got over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Umm, no sir, detergent.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Detergent?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops look at each other, then at the boys.</context>
      <utterance>My clothes are dirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You boys stay right here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, Michaels. The car is completely fucked, and you're the one who fucked it up, so you've got to fix it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We arrest these little crap stains and dump it on them, I'll take care of that. You go make sure McLovin is good to play ball. This is it, Michaels.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna hang with the big boys, you gotta get your hands dirty. You cool?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops nod to each other. Michaels goes back to the car and gets in. Slater walks back over to the boys. He puts his hand on his gun and pulls out his club, scaring the shit out of Evan and Seth.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan and Seth lie down on their stomachs and spread their arms and legs out, terrified.</context>
      <utterance>Get on the ground. Now! Spread your shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Puh...please don't shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Puh- Puh- Please shut the fuck up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was the guy alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michaels looks back at the Homeless Guy, who looks a little bit more awake than before.</context>
      <utterance>What? Oh, yeah, the guy was fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The guy starts to open his eyes a little. Michaels grabs the guy's face and slams it back, knocking him out again. Fogell jumps a little.</context>
      <utterance>Are you awake, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHEALS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Officer Michaels takes out two cigarettes, and gives one to Fogell, who accepts, quivering in fear. Michaels lights his, then passes the lighter to Fogell.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, McLovin. But I really need this to be a private thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHEALS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fogell tries to light his cigarette. It takes a few tries and he starts hacking after the first pull.</context>
      <utterance>Listen McLovin, you... like... Officer Slater and myself, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Umm, yeah, sure. You guys are great.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell continues to painfully suck back on the cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, we're also on probation. You see, we've actually trashed two other cars. The first time wasn't our fault, and the second time a bee flew in and I freaked out. Point is, we trash another car, without a good reason, we're fucked. Know what I'm saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell nods his head, getting some of his cigarette smoke in his eyes. He winces and starts to blink in discomfort.</context>
      <utterance>Now, we're going to arrest these guys, and if you don't mind, which you shouldn't, we'd like you to write a fake witness report saying they jumped out in front of our car. Cool, McLovin?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How tall are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...I don't know, five-foot-ten, eleven?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth nods. Officer Michaels and Fogell get out of the car. Seth and Evan see Fogell and stare in shock as he takes a drag of a cigarette and then flicks it aside.</context>
      <utterance>And you said those were "Pumas?"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops run after Evan! Seth and Fogell look at each other. Seth grabs the remaining detergent jug and runs off in the opposite direction of Evan! Fogell reaches into the cop car, grabs the bags of booze, and follows Seth.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Officer Slater looks back to see Seth and Fogell running.</context>
      <utterance>Seth! Wait up!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops run back into their car.</context>
      <utterance>Shit! Shit! McLovin bailed!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little GIRL runs out and books it into the house. From inside the tent, another kid starts kicking at Seth.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit! Little kids!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth manages to free himself from the tent and he and Fogell fall to the ground. The kids continue to scream.</context>
      <utterance>Ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The guys turn and see a crazed, slightly overweight FATHER in his underwear running at them with a baseball bat. Fogell and Seth scramble to their feet as the Dad takes a swing at them, narrowly missing them.</context>
      <utterance>Get away from my children!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fogell throws his shoulder into the guy, knocking him down. Seth and Fogell run to the backyard gate and try to open it. They can't.</context>
      <utterance>You sick sons-of-bitches!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell starts banging as Seth looks back to see the Dad coming for them. Seth swings the detergent jug at the Father, knocking him on his ass. He quickly gets up and charges, enraged.</context>
      <utterance>Help!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stupid little bastards.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I should fire a shot? Scare `em out?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he fumbles to turn his jacket inside out and get it on, he sees Seth and Fogell running towards him. He pops out of the bush, scaring Fogell and Seth.</context>
      <utterance>Oh god. Oh god. Fuck. Fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I run!?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOMELESS GUY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Fogell looks up and sees the Homeless Guy stumbling towards them, sucking back the bottom of the lost detergent bottle. The Homeless Guy sees they have bags full of booze.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! It's you!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS GUY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got booze in the bag? Can you gimme some?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Fuck off! You already drank our detergent beer!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well, you little shit...ain't got no cop people to help you keep your booze...gimme it... The Homeless Nutcase reaches for the booze. Seth steps in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>That was beer?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back off, or we'll kick the shit out of you!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't do that. He's homeless.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? Who cares? Just because he doesn't have a home doesn't mean he can be a lunatic!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy shoves Seth aside and dives at Fogell.</context>
      <utterance>Give me the booze!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BACK TO NORMAL.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Homeless Guy sees the gold flakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOMELESS GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts frantically picking up the flakes as Evan stares at the remains, shocked. Fogell walks over.</context>
      <utterance>Shit!!! Gold!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on? Where did you come from?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck yeah, guys. We made it. Together and safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe Helen's bottle broke.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure it'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the difference? I thought you didn't need it anyways. I thought you were just going to tell her how you feel, you fucking pussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Well, good luck getting Jule's drunk enough to have sex with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Fogell. Never mind. Evan'll tell you next year.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan stares Fogell down.</context>
      <utterance>You told him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Told me what?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well we have to tell him now.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck, Fogell! You're a god damn idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he knows something's up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just say it!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.  Seth, me and Fogell are rooming together next year.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even get what the big deal is, to be honest.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't tell you because-</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth just goes into the house with the booze, leaving Fogell and Evan.</context>
      <utterance>Save that shit for later. We've got shit to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We never should have had to hide our arrangement.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone turns around and sees the Seth holding all the liquor.</context>
      <utterance>Seth! Everyone, he's here! He's got it!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOM GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got a shit load of booze!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bar is open!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is awesome. Thank you so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry it was late.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. To be honest, people were starting to get seriously pissed off. Listen, I've got to go tell everyone the drinks are here. Don't go anywhere. Promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules walks off.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone drinks and recoils from the taste. A random guy refills everyone's shot glasses.</context>
      <utterance>To Jules!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOM   GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another one, but to you, man! Everyone, to this guy! Who the fuck are you, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seth!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RANDOM GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To Seth!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVERYONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all drink.</context>
      <utterance>To Seth!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone laughs as Seth, very pleased with himself, starts refilling shot glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Let's do another one to me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Becca! Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>BECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where have you been, you almost blew it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Helen. She's been waiting for you. She's right over there. She's been yammering about you all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What did she say? Does she think I'm a good guy? What did she say?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was something like, "I'll fully blow him tonight."</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan looks over and sees Helen standing on the balcony with a big group of people. He gets really nervous.</context>
      <utterance>What?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man. This is too much. Oh god. What do I do? I lost the Goldschlager I was supposed to bring her!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Jordana stole a bottle of tequila from her parents and her and Helen have been going at it. I think she'll be fine in that department. I'd just go over there and invite her upstairs, pronto.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Oh man...  But...she's totally hammered. If I get with her, and I'm not drunk, isn't that, like, date rape?</utterance>
   <speaker>BECCA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not date rape if you're drunk, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan looks at Helen and takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down, Evan. She likes you. She wants to suck on your penis. That's a good thing. He opens the Ouzo and smells it, recoiling in disgust.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Evan takes a mighty swig, then gags and spits it out, spraying it everywhere.</context>
      <utterance>Down the hatch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They call you Nicola, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they call you Fogell.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue dancing.</context>
      <utterance>Some do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan takes a deep breath walks up to where she's laying. She extends her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Evan!!! Hey! Come here!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Evan notices that she seems a little drunk. He helps her up and she collapses onto him, forcing him to hold her up.</context>
      <utterance>Help me up! None of these people will help me up!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen laughs hysterically as she latches onto Evan. He smells her breath. It reeks of alcohol. Evan's drunk, but Helen is completely fucking shit-faced!</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Helen. Sorry I was-</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evan! Oh my god! You are so fucking hilarious!  Do you goes know how fucking hilarious Evan is?  Tell them how hilarious you are!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...well...uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen starts laughing hysterically.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to him!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The group chuckles a little. Helen puts her arms around Evan.</context>
      <utterance>See?!! He is so cute!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been waiting for you for, like, ever. What took you so long? Do you have my Goldschlager?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen picks up a bottle of tequila and shoves it into Evan's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Oh man, it's a crazy story-</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here! Don't worry, we can drink this.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan takes a much-unwanted drink and gags.</context>
      <utterance>I'm already pretty wasted. But...uh...here's to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Light-weight!</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey...me and you should go upstairs now. I really want to...tell you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...uh...uh...you could just tell me right here-</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Let's go upstairs, come on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NICOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McLovin! That's the funniest thing I've ever seen!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both laugh and their eyes meet.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I just thought it sounded old.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm back. I had to thank the peeps for comin' out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth takes a swig of a beer.</context>
      <utterance>Jules! The hostess with the most-est! The woman of the hour!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Seth offers her a beer.</context>
      <utterance>This party's blowin' my ass off! I want you to have a drink with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thanks. I'm good. But, seriously, thanks for getting all the drinks. It really made the night.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules laughs and Seth sees that his charm is working.</context>
      <utterance>It's just how I roll, Jules. No problems, no problems.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jules eyes Seth suspiciously. Seth just looks at her, smiling drunkenly.</context>
      <utterance>Uh...you know...I love talking, and conversing with you, you're so good at it, but I can't hear you. Could we just go on the...uh...balcony or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules walks out of the kitchen. He finishes off his beer and then, happy as shit, drunkenly dances out of the kitchen and after Jules.</context>
      <utterance>Why not? I haven't conversed in ages. Let's do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I so flirt with you in Math.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man. Helen...I want to tell you, I mean, I've wanted to tell you, for a long time-</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I've wanted to get with you so hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Helen yanks him onto the bed and starts sloppily kissing him again. Evan doesn't know what to do. She tries to take off Evan's shirt, but is way too inebriated to undo the buttons. Evan yanks it off.</context>
      <utterance>Like...so hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Evan moves over to help her. He can't do it either.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck...stupid shoe...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen tries to squeeze her feet out, but she can't. She grabs a pair of scissors off a desk.</context>
      <utterance>Shit. Can you, like, slip out?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She snips off the knot and slips her shoe off.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa. Fuckin'...careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen laughs as she staggers to her feet and start kissing Evan. He starts taking off his pants.</context>
      <utterance>You...take off your pants...  Or I'll cut `em off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NICOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe I'm about to get with "Fogell".</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. You're like, the most mysterious guy in the grade. Like, nobody knows anything about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're about to learn a few things.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Whoa! Slow down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd...uh...prefer if we did this at some other time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But...there is no other time. School's up! This is the only time...what's wrong with now?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're drunk. Like, really, really drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? So are you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth is absolutely shocked. It takes his remarkably drunk mind a moment to process this information.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not drunk at all. I don't even drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't drink? But...but, you told me to get the liquor!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm...uh...throwin' a party, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't drink!?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I don't drink.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you, don't want to...uh, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth looks at Jules and realizes that he's screwed up. His eyes start to water.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, no. Not right now, thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhh....man...fuck....</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you crying?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Yeah, so what if I am? I'm a fucking idiot and it was my last chance! So I should be crying.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last chance to do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To make you my girlfriend for the summer, okay? There! You're, like, the coolest person that's ever talked to me, and I thought we'd both be drunk, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would me be drunk have anything to do with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, the front door opens, and a RANDOM GIRL walks out.</context>
      <utterance>`Cause you'd never get with me in your right mind! Look at me!  And now look at you!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDOM GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ricky! Was it a quarter, or an eighth you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>RICKY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The Random Girl notices Seth and Jules.</context>
      <utterance>A fat eighth!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="161" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen crawls onto the bed, pushes Evan down, and starts seriously making out with him, drunker and sloppier than ever.</context>
      <utterance>I wore this for you. Here we go...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evan, I'm so wet.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen shoves her hand down Evan's boxers. Evan jolts, terrified!</context>
      <utterance>You're so beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got such a smooth cock.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan looks really nervous as Helen's hand starts moving up and down.</context>
      <utterance>Um...thank you. I've thought you were a really incredible person for a really long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to get hard for me...real hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm...I'm..I'm about to. But first I just want to tell you exactly how I-</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan is taken aback.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna suck your dick so good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="162" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to do that, you know, we can start this relationship on something more than just that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Evan. I know.  I need you to eat my hairy love crack.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan sits up.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah I do, I want to fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you know I really like you, Helen, but this is...it's just too intense. And I'm so drunk I don't even know how to, like, process-</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just being a pussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Did you just call me a...pussy?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PUKE! Evan watches in horror as Helen vomits all over Jules' bed.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...a scared little pussy-</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh god! Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need Becca...Becca...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll...uh...I'll go get her. Are you going to be okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="163" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a boner.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls a condom out.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Do you have a condom?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out a little bottle of lube.</context>
      <utterance>And lube.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="164" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth looks up at her, drunk as hell, his eyes half-open.</context>
      <utterance>Seth, you...uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Seth blanks out and falls forward. BAM! He head-butts Jules in the face!</context>
      <utterance>You didn't blow it, you're a-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="165" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seth! What the fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...help me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="166" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Seth passes out again. A few moments go by, when SUDDENLY a cop car pulls up in front of the house. Seth opens his eyes and sees the cops.</context>
      <utterance>...sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Two cops get out and start harassing two kids smoking a joint on the front lawn. One of them turns on their flashlight and Seth sees - it's OFFICER SLATER and MICHAELS!!!</context>
      <utterance>Oh no.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Evan...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="167" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Seth bursts into the room and grabs Evan's shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Life's bullshit, huh, Miroki?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' wax off, asshole!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth grabs Evan's wrists and tries to pull him to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>No...I'm helping you, man! Just listen...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Terry (the guy who spat on Seth in the beginning) walks by.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck off, jerk! You're hurting my shoulders!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terry and his buddies laugh their asses off when, suddenly-</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Look, it's Christina and Britney. Have fun boning each other on grad night!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="168" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had a complaint about the noise. It looks like you're having a nice little party here.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan points at the cops.</context>
      <utterance>A nice little underage drinking party.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude! Seth! It's the cops! The cops.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth pulls Evan up and the two drunkenly make their way out of the living room just as the cops step into it.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I've been...! Here...</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, everyone out. Party's over. Get out of here. Michaels turns to Slater.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go upstairs. I told you this would release some anger.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you what would release some anger, if one of these little fuckers touched me and I got to club his face in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="169" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell wears the greatest look of accomplishment one could possibly imagine. SUDDENLY, Officer Michaels bursts into the room and flicks on the lights.</context>
      <utterance>It's...it's in.  It's in.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Nicola screams, grabs her clothes, and runs into the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McLovin? What the fuck?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Officer Slater?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ran away from us!  Michaels! Get up here!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I hit my head when we crashed. I was all disoriented and I just wandered off, confused. Seriously!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up! Wait a minute. How old was that girl? 16, 17? You sick bastard, that's statutory rape, McLovin. Officer Slater appears in the doorway.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McLovin!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was violating a sixteen year-old girl!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell covers himself with the blanket and starts to get up.</context>
      <utterance>What? No! No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="170" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't break the law! I'm not really even-</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit your ass down and keep it down.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nicola, now dressed, emerges from the bathroom. She screams and runs out. They take Fogell's arms and handcuff him.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to jail, fucko.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't take kindly to your type in jail, McLovin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="171" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude. You saved me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I totally did! I wanted to!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna sleep at my house, man? You're my best friend!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah! Sleepover! Fuckin...you got pizza bagels still?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan pulls a half bottle of tequila.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah!!!! Look what else I gots!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start to drink it together.</context>
      <utterance>Nice!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="172" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TERRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>SUDDENLY, a WAD OF SPIT hits Slater in the shoulder! He turns and sees Terry, the guy who spat on Seth. Slater walks over and bashes the kid in the face with his nightstick. The kid drops.</context>
      <utterance>Stupid pigs.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They throw Fogell into the back of the cop car.</context>
      <utterance>That does feel better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="173" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So...am I going to jail? The two cops burst out laughing hysterically.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah!! You're going to fuckin' Azkaban!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are the funniest fuckin' kid I have ever met!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been fuckin' with you! Jesus! I love this kid!</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know you're not twenty five! What are we, morons? My god! What are you? Sixteen?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seventeen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="174" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, boys. What I'm about to show you is pretty much the greatest move in donut- spinning history. Behold: the reverse figure-eight. Slater drives to the other side of the lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, like, what's your official position?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Slater guns it and speeds across the lot, slamming the breaks, spinning wildly in several erratic donuts backward donuts. Slater completely loses control of the car. He smashes through a bunch of shopping carts and slams into a light post, completely fucking up the cruiser. Slater tries to open his door, but it won't budge. He crawls out the missing windshield, slumping onto the ground.</context>
      <utterance>If you were in, you were in. You are no longer a virgin, end of story. Screw cumming.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. I think that's all the fun we're gettin' out of this one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="175" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and by signing this you are officially saying that as we stopped you from being mugged, a crack-head stole our cruiser and did God knows what with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fogell signs the pad.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. That mugger had nothing but murder in his eyes. I owe you my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cops and Fogell push the cruiser towards a small, but steep, hill. They shove it over the edge and watch it roll. It gains speed and smashes into a tree, shattering the windows and crushing the front of the car.</context>
      <utterance>Can we do this already?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we shoot at it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They whip out their guns.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, can you?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER SLATER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm throwin' down the gauntlet. 50 bucks. Whoever hits the gas tank.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER MICHAELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are so fucking on.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOGELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slater hands Fogell his gun. With a huge smile, Fogell raises the gun, aims it at the police cruiser, and BLASTS off round after round.</context>
      <utterance>Can I get a shot?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="176" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe she said that shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my lord. You have no idea!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="177" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then you saved me, man! I fucking love you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fucking love you, too, man! I'm not embarrassed, I just love you!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we say that more? It feels good! I love you more than my brother, man. Like, when you went away for Easter last year, I, like, missed you. You know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth grabs Evan and they hug.</context>
      <utterance>I missed you, too. Come here, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They stop hugging and sit back down. They're laughter slows down and there is a moment of silence.</context>
      <utterance>We'll always be friends. `Cause we love each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>So, like-</context>
      <utterance>Like, three weeks ago I was in you room and, like, you were taking a dump and...I saw your residence placement thingy. I totally saw you're living with Fogell.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be! Don't be! I'm sorry. I was being a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a moment of silence.</context>
      <utterance>I need you to know that it's not like I even want to live with Fogell; it's just that I'm really afraid of living with strangers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="178" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know...I was pissed off I didn't get with Jules, but, like...we really got through a lot of our shit, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, me too. Like, yeah...at least we kind of came together, again.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night, Seth. I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Night, Evan. Love you, man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="179" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...uh...hey. Morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at each other, uncomfortable.</context>
      <utterance>Uh...morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sleep good?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. This is a really good pillow.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth looks at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>Um...</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I should get going.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have to. I'm not, like, doing anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="180" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh...do you want to hang out? I was...gonna go to the mall, actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Cool, well, can I come? I need a comforter. For college.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That'd be nice. I'd really like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="181" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ask me. I don't give a shit if your pants look good.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I need someone's opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. They're way too small.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but when I was wearing your dad's pants last night I realized that if I buy pants that are too small it'll encourage me to lose weight. And in tight pants chicks'll kind of see my dick a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth goes back into the dressing room and wriggles out of the pants. He walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, the male camel toe look is really big this year.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These pants suck. Let's the get the fuck out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="182" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again, I'm so sorry. I can't believe I actually did that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel sorry that I'm making you buy me a new one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: Seth and Evan</context>
      <utterance>I have to. It's puke.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen looks like hell and Jules has a horrible black eye.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at the two girls from afar.</context>
      <utterance>Is that them?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helen looks and notices them. She waves and points them out to Jules. Seth and Evan wave back. The girls get up and start to walk over.</context>
      <utterance>Should we hide?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck that, man. I can't talk to her, look what I did to her!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls walk up to them.</context>
      <utterance>Helen called me a pussy to my face! What am I going to say to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god. I'm so sorry, Jules.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="183" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad, but not great, how about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That looks terrible. No! I mean, it doesn't look terrible, it looks-</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it, Seth. It was an accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you have fun last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you remember much?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really don't remember much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Not really. I remember looking up, and you screaming at me. That's about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't puke on you, did I?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I dodged it. Whizzed right by me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But seriously, I acted like a fuckin' idiot last night. I'm really sorry, you didn't deserve that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="184" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a moment of silence.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I...um...I'm sorry, about all that. Thanks for being such a gentleman.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all chuckle a little.</context>
      <utterance>You look good with a black eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, smart guy. That's why I'm here. I have to go to Macy's to get a shitload of cover-up for the grad photo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man...</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and I'm going to Linen Brothers to buy Jules a new comforter.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! I have to get a comforter too, for college.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you gonna come with me to Macy's and buy me my cover-up, or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Definitely. I'd love to. I had such bad acne last year, I became an expert on the stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could get your college pants there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but wait...you drove me here, Evan drove me here, how do we-</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got my dad's car. I'll take you home, and Evan can give Helen a lift.</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="185" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we can go eat after?</utterance>
   <speaker>HELEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seth and Evan look at each other, odd smiles on both their faces. They didn't blow it.</context>
      <utterance>Sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, uh, I'll call you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah man, have a good one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jules pulls Seth away. Evan and Helen start walking in the opposite direction. As they walk away from one another, Seth and Evan look back and give each other a small and yet emotionally-charged wave. A SLOW, GUT WRENCHING SOUL SONG STARTS TO PLAY. They look as though they're never going to see each other again.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Seth. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
