<movie id="538" title="Sweet Smell of Success">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SWEET SMELL OF SUCCESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>by Clifford Odets Ernest Lehman</utterance>
   <speaker>SWEET SMELL OF SUCCESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Working Script For</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>"GO WITH THE GLOBE"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Read</utterance>
   <speaker>J.J. HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"They eyes of Broadway"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>IGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw Lady, if I looked like you, I'd--</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon...C'mon...</utterance>
   <speaker>IGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Majestically taking his time, Iggy lifts the bundle to his stand and cuts the cord.</context>
      <utterance>Keep ya sweatshirt on, Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>IGGY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annoyed, Sidney throws him a dime, seizes a paper and returns briskly to the orange juice stand.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Fresh, the Globe just came in -- Hey, Sidney, want an item for Hunsecker's column? Two rolls get fresh with a baker! Hey, hot, hot, hot -- etc.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>SIDNEY FALCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From inside comes the sound of desultory typing. Sidney comes up the stairs two at a time and turns into the door.</context>
      <utterance>Publicity</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney vigorously indicates that he doesn't want to take the call.</context>
      <utterance>Just a minute, Mr. Weldon. I think...</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I thought that was Mr. Falco returning. Yes, I'll tell him when he comes in. I know he's been trying to reach you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the third time he's called today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants me to break a leg?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, an arm, he said.  I told him you were sure the item would be in Mr. Hunsecker's column in tomorrow's...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't. I've just seen the early edition.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That makes five days in a row that Mr. Hunsecker's cut you out of his column.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has begun to change his clothes.</context>
      <utterance>May I rent you out as an adding machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sally goes back into the outer room.</context>
      <utterance>Get me Joe Robard.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who else phoned?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The renting agent and the tailor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pay the rent. Let the tailor wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney, in a state of semi-undress, comes to take the phone from her.</context>
      <utterance>It won't leave much of a balance in the bank...  Mr. Robard? Could you locate him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney, Joe. How do you like it? I'm running out of alibis! No, I asked Hunsecker to withhold the item, until he could give it a fine, fat paragraph. The column was running over and I didn't want you kissed off with just a line...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>ROBARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.  What is this, Sidney, a kissing game? You're a liar - that's a publicity man's nature. I wouldn't hire you if you wasn't a liar. I pay you a C-and-a-half a week wherein you plant big lies about me and the Club all over the map.  Yeah, I mean in that sense. But also in the sense that you are a personal liar, too, because you don't do the work I pay you for.  Oh, stop it, Sidney. You're from the country, not me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sally is watching him, unhappy on his behalf.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, wait a minute, Joe. When I saw J.J. last night he said... But Robard has cut off. Sidney hangs up. A silence. Sally tries to be comforting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I could help in some way, Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sally, hurt, says nothing. Presently, he adds:</context>
      <utterance>Help me with two minutes of silence!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go home, Sally. It's late...</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney, with another mercurial change of manner, begins some sarcastic clowning.</context>
      <utterance>I hate to see you like this --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but as a new subscriber you're under no obligation to take more than three books. And if you mail the enclosed card within ten days --</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney, I know you by now. Don't do a dance with me...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean you don't want the extra free gift of a colorful giant map of the world???</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney is abruptly savage.</context>
      <utterance>Sidney, please, dear, if you feel nervous...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what'll you do if I feel nervous? You'll open your meaty, sympathetic arms...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid...you got me so...I don't know what... She is crying. Sidney feels uncomfortable. Not too generously, he relents:</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ought to be used to me by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm used to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings. Sidney is dressed by now. As Sally goes for it, he makes for the outer door.</context>
      <utterance>No. You think I'm a hero. I'm no hero. I'm nice to people where it pays me to be. I gotta do it too much on the outside, so don't expect me to kow-tow in my own office. I'm in a bind right now with Hunsecker so --  Every dog has his day!  Lock up and leave the key.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's for me, tear it up!</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a top coat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And leave a tip in every hat-check room in town? He is already gone as she picks up the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney Falco office... Oh, Miss Kay, he tried to reach you. No, he's at the barbers now. No, that's held over till the Tuesday column...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you ever get messages, Eyelashes? I called you twice.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been up to here. Listen, honey, tell me something. You know Susan Hunsecker...?  Has she been in? I mean lately, in the last coupla days...?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure. Find out for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Frank D'Angelo around?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Sidney has moved away from her.</context>
      <utterance>At the bar - Sidney...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a lollipop that, boy. The kid is only great.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Angelo looks quickly at Sidney, sensing the undercurrent. Then he turns his back on the musicians, remarking in a quiet tone.</context>
      <utterance>And with ten percent of his future, you're great, too, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Went over to Philly yesterday an' seen the folks...it's nice you send them the fifty a month...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See my mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A glum moment. Frank sips his highball: Sidney lights a cigarette, animosity on his face.</context>
      <utterance>I only had a few hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the publicity spread you got the boys for the benefit tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Robard's my client. I did it for him and his club, not your boys. Frank again notes Sidney's resentful manner. Sidney looks towards the musicians.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank, I think maybe you lied to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looka, Sidney, you're my own sister's son, but where does that give you the right to call me a liar?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me that your boy was washed up with Susie Hunsecker, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and it's the truth, to the best of my knowledge. And, frankly, I'm glad. For Steve's sake, I'm glad, not yours. I manage these boys and I got their best interests at heart. Steve shouldn't get mixed up with no bimbo at his age.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told him that?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. Sidney is thinking.</context>
      <utterance>Not in those exact words - you know what a temper he's got.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When do these hot-headed boys of yours go on the road?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coupla weeks. For eight weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a nice tour. All booked?  When was Susie around here last?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four five nights ago. That's how I know the romance is off. Also Steve's in a very bad mood.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Frank, you'd better make sure you're telling me the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like this threatening attitude. When it comes to it, what the heck is it your business what they do, this boy and girl...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney gets off his stool. Casually, but to effect, he adds:</context>
      <utterance>If you knew Hunsecker as well as I did, you might understand why it's my business. Maybe you're walking around blind, Frank, without a cane.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away, glancing towards Steve on the bandstand behind him.</context>
      <utterance>...and in case you didn't know it, Susie Hunsecker's out there on the back step right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks disturbed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi! Susie...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Chico. Paul.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Full house...?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Packin' 'em in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we just sort of got together.  Maybe if you ask Mr. Katz...He writes the stuff, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CORRIDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chico, smiling, explains:</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't waste your time there, man. You've got something better waiting outside...  Susie's out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His reaction betrays some emotion.  Steve moves a quick step towards the door to the courtyard, then hesitates - almost as if he was afraid to go out. He meets Chico's eye again.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did she say...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is amused, but sympathetic.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You proposed to her, not me.  Go get your answer...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney's manner is very friendly. But it is immediately apparent from the reaction of the other three boys that none of them likes Sidney. Fred is deliberately uncomprehending.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Fellows. Where's the Chief?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chico's back is to the closed door which opens onto the courtyard. Chico nods in the opposite direction towards the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Dallas. Is he around?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Upstairs, maybe.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he's around somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is big, you know. Very big! Let's go out later, drink some firewater. With the boys. Fred can call Millie and -</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve, I'd rather you didn't say anything for a day or two...until I tell my brother...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan says nothing. She looks to Steve, smiling, but the smile is not too confident.</context>
      <utterance>He isn't going to like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan stoutly shakes her head. Defensively she reassures Steve:</context>
      <utterance>You sure you don't want me to be with you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve, my brother isn't as bad as he's painted. He isn't perfect, but -</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The topic evidently makes Susan uneasy. In an effort to dismiss something that she does not want to think about, Susan puts her arms around Steve's neck again.</context>
      <utterance>But he isn't going to like this, Susie. And he makes you nervous, not me. No, I take that back - he makes me nervous, too. But I wouldn't give him a second thought if not for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Steve is not so ready to change the subject.</context>
      <utterance>Let's forget him and -</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His stooge, Falco, is around - I saw him walk in.  He's been spying on me for weeks, Susie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darling, I don't care - really I don't. Sidney'd had a secret crush on me for years, but nothing we do is his business -</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he could be reporting back to your brother, couldn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Steve responds. He grins, holds her closer.</context>
      <utterance>Steve, dear, please forget all of this. What can it matter after tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a message for you; I love you.  May I dedicate the next number to you?...And the next, and the next. Every Sunday I'll buy you a new bonnet -</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the stores are open -</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And on Monday, I'll take it off and stroke your light brown hair and -</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And on Tuesday - Hasenpfeffer.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you think I realized I love you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made you write a beautiful song...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh and enjoyably; but then, as the CAMERA MOVES, we realize that Sidney is there on the fire escape above them; his manner is affable.</context>
      <utterance>No, you had me eating that Chinese food!...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steve says nothing. But he obviously resents the intrusion and finds it difficult to conceal the fact. Sidney comes down the fire escape towards them.</context>
      <utterance>Can more than two enjoy this joke...  Hello, Susie, I didn't expect to find you here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's those glossy prints you promised? Tonight's the latest I can place them -</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, thanks, anyway - let's forget it.  It's cold out here, Susie. Steve makes a move to lead Susan back inside. It is a gesture which appears to dismiss Sidney. Sidney chooses to take umbrage:</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steve turns to Sidney; his manner is quiet but challenging:</context>
      <utterance>Let me apologize for getting you that press spread. It's been an honor to serve you gratis.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get the feeling, Falco, that you're always snooping around...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve, stop it please...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aggressively indignant, Sidney throws up his hands; he knocks on the metal of the fire escape.</context>
      <utterance>What are you boys fighting about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill me! Find me a door somewhere - I walked in without knocking! Sidney is trying to needle Steve; Steve's temper would normally have exploded; but now he controls it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm feeling too good to fight with you, but that isn't what I said - I said you snoop. For instance, what were you doing around my hotel the other night?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Begging your pardon, I haven't been down the bowery in years!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on boys, break it up...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The next time you want information, Falco, don't scratch for it like a dog - ask for it like a man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney starts quickly up the fire escape. This makes Steve angry and he steps forward to follow him. But Chico contrives, without seeming to interfere to obstruct Steve.</context>
      <utterance>If you're going home, Susie, I'll drop you off...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time for the next set, Chief...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a minute, Chico.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me you started a polka with Leo Bartha?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He came in last week on a very dull rainy night. I know who he was, but I didn't let on.  He didn't take his eyes off me all night. Listening...? Rita has mistaken Sidney's shrewdly calculating expression for inattention.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Avidly. He was staring.</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Staring. Consequently, when he approached me on his way out I wasn't surprised, but I didn't let on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was writing a special Sunday piece on...?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...cigarette girls... And naturally -</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were thrilled to be interviewed.  Were you "interviewed"?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In his apartment -</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where was his wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know - it's a big apartment. But I wasn't interviewed. In fact, I was totally unprepared for what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're old friends, Chickie - quit it! A big columnist comes in this room, without his ball-and-chain and you make like a delicatessen counter! What did you think would happen in his house?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despite himself, Sidney chuckles; but she is distressed.</context>
      <utterance>But, Sidney darling, the man must be out of his mind - it was only eleven o'clock in the morning!</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney's eyes have been caught by something at the other end of the big room.</context>
      <utterance>For a moment I was so taken aback that I said anything that popped into my sleepy head. If I'm not mistaken, I even ordered the man out of his own house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was furious and, by the time I could have put on a Tropical Island mood, I was out on the street!...  That night Mr. Van Cleve calls me into his office here. He's got nothing against me, he says but he can't afford to antagonize columnists. I told him I still have Sonny at military academy, but Van Cleve's made of ice... Aware that Sidney is moving to leave her so that he can catch Susan, Rita detains him with an appeal:</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think you could do something, Sidney?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rita is anxious to cement the offer. Delicately, she asks:</context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm thinking, Rita. Maybe...</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you still keep your key under the mat?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Angelo hides his feelings, asks:</context>
      <utterance>Frank, I don't want any secrets from you. I proposed to Susie tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she accept?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He mounts the bandstand.</context>
      <utterance>You don't like it, do you. I think she will accept, but I'm not sure. She may be too dependent on her brother.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're touchy, Sidney - don't be so touchy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't looking for a brawl. I came to bring him a present.  Wanna bite to eat? Susan shakes her head. She looks up as she hears the doorman's whistle off screen. Sidney moves forward to escort her to the taxi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feels like a Monday night, don't it...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not to me. Sometimes, the world feels like a cage. Then someone comes along and opens the door...and it's never Monday night again...  I wish you and Steve could like each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We stick in each others craw.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>is some kind of monster.</context>
      <utterance>Well, for one thing, he thinks J.J.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quizzically, she studies Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. But someday I'd like to look into your clever mind and see what you REALLY think of him -</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME SIDNEY AND SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney makes a show of indignation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you come off to make a remark like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think J.J. likes Steve...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frankly, yes, to my surprise. He thinks he's very gifted - those boys'll go a big mile, he thinks. Susan says nothing. Sidney, watching her closely, probes further:</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again Susan nods.</context>
      <utterance>Wedding bells, you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants me to go on the road with them. It's an eight month tour, all the way to Oregon...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, congratulations. But don't go just for the ride! Or didn't you accept the proposal?</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME SUSAN AND SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susan continues.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. Each is concerned with private thoughts. Susan, relaxed, adds quietly:</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to discuss it with J.J. in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's given me a big lift to know that some people want me for myself, not just because I'm my brother's sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan ignores his remark, continuing thoughtfully:</context>
      <utterance>Chickie, I'll have to laugh at that - an attractive girl like you...!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope that J.J. really likes Steve, that it isn't an act.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The taxi has pulled to a stop. Susan sits for a moment before she remarks.</context>
      <utterance>Why should he put on an act? Your brother has told PRESIDENTS where to go and what to do!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Realizing that they have come to their destination, Susan gets up, moving out of CAMERA as she disembarks from the taxi. CAMERA catches a glimpse of apprehension in Sidney's eyes. Quickly, he decides to follow her.</context>
      <utterance>The act would be for my sake, not Steve's...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait for me. I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONGER SHOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney moves after the girl, calling: "Susie!"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not my nature, Susie, but I'll talk to you like an uncle...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move through the doors.</context>
      <utterance>But I don't need an uncle, Sidney.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean because I admire you - in fact, more than admire you - although that's neither here nor there.  Susie, don't sell your brother short. Talk this over with him, I mean - you'll find him a real friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susan looks thoughtful, making no comment.</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME SIDNEY AND SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carefully  he prompts her:</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan turns away and walks out past CAMERA. Sidney watches her.</context>
      <utterance>Any message, in case I see J.J. later?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looks back at Sidney, quietly firm.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns away and walks through the inner door, going down the corridor towards the elevators in background.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Tell him for me that Steve Dallas is the first real man I've ever been in love with...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jimmy! This is a coincidence. I am just going -</utterance>
   <speaker>WELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. A coincidence you should run into the very man you've been ducking all week!  This is my press agent, Joan. Weldon, jibing at Sidney, plays his remarks off the girl, who is amused; Sidney, of course, is not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried to reach you twice -</utterance>
   <speaker>WELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you do for that hundred a week. Fall out of bed?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jimmy, I'm on my way inside right now to talk to Hunsecker. I can promise you -</utterance>
   <speaker>WELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney flinches, his pride touched.</context>
      <utterance>Joan, call a cop! We'll arrest this kid for larceny!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, when your band was playing at Roseland -</utterance>
   <speaker>THE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy, Jimmy dear...</utterance>
   <speaker>WELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abruptly Sidney bursts out, giving as good as he has taken:</context>
      <utterance>Why? It's a dirty job, but I pay clean money for it, don't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No more you don't! What is this - You're showing off for her? They're supposed to hear you in Korea?</utterance>
   <speaker>WELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's intuitive - he knows he's getting fired!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weldon, shepherded by the girl, is already on his way across the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>If you're funny, James, I'm a pretzel! Drop dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>WELDON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was nice knowing you, Sidney. Not cheap - but nice. Happy unemployment insurance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you tonight, Mr. Falco?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is "he" inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But of course...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alone or surrounded?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney moves past CAMERA, coming a couple of paces towards the door to the restaurant. He pauses.</context>
      <utterance>A Senator, an Agent and Something - With - Long - Red - Hair.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl reaches for a book of phone numbers, then remembers:</context>
      <utterance>Honey, get me Mr. Hunsecker.</utterance>
   <speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right inside, Mr. Falco.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the girl, shrugging, puts through the call, CAMERA moves closer to Sidney in the booth. He hears the connection made, speaks at once.</context>
      <utterance>So it isn't Long Distance.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We are close enough to the instrument to hear the sound of a voice on the other end. Though the words are not distinguishable, it is quite clear that the speaker is not talking to the phone. Sidney seems to relax, as if this is something that happens often. He waits, studying his manicured fingertips... Presently Sidney hears the voice on the other end become clearer. It asks: "Yes?" CAMERA moves closer as Sidney says:</context>
      <utterance>J.J.? It's me --</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker's voice, filtered through the sound of the telephone, is sharp and tiny; but the words are now very clear.</context>
      <utterance>J.J., it's Sidney. Can you come outside for one minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I come out? No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to talk to you, alone, J.J., that's why.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had something to do for me - you didn't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I come in for a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>There is a click as Hunsecker hangs up. Sidney, more slowly, also hangs up. Brooding, he comes out of the booth.</context>
      <utterance>No. You're dead, son - get yourself buried!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mac! I don't want this man at my table...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Captain is already there. But now Hunsecker's eyes have switched to Sidney's face. For the briefest of moments, nothing happens. Then Hunsecker, seeming to relax and ignoring the Captain whom he has summoned, turns back to casual conversation with the Senator as if nothing had happened.</context>
      <utterance>I have a message from your sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In foreground, Sidney turns to the Captain with a carved smile, indicating that Hunsecker's change of topic is to be interpreted as sanction for Sidney to remain. The Captain, not entirely convinced, retreats. Sidney finds himself a chair, places it and takes a seat which is near enough to the table to establish his presence. During this:</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, Harvey. We were interrupted before -</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Err...the Supreme Court story, I was telling you - Justice Black.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But I think you had it in the column.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, the Justice, that's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney's interjection is quietly well-mannered. Hunsecker totally ignores it. The other members of the party are a little astonished at the interplay. The girl, in particular, is fascinated; she clearly admires Sidney's looks. The Senator, noting this, glances at Sidney, accepting the point:</context>
      <utterance>Last July, the lead item...</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I believe that's precisely where I read it, too. You see, J.J., where I get my reputation for being the best-informed man in Washington.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now don't kid a kidder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney Falco, sir. And, of course, everyone knows and admires you, Senator Walker.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he indicates the Agent)</context>
      <utterance>Every four years I get less convinced of that. This young lady is Miss Linda James.  She's managed by Manny Davis.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY AND HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney nods pleasantly to the Girl and the Agent.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know Manny Davis.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker is picking up the phone, continuing:</context>
      <utterance>Everyone knows Manny Davis...  ...except MRS. Manny Davis.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes? Go ahead, Billy - shoot...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During the speech, CAMERA eases back to include Sidney again. At the end, Sidney looks up in the direction of the Senator.</context>
      <utterance>Uh huh. Sports cars in California are getting smaller and smaller...the other day you were crossing Hollywood Boulevard and you were hit by one...you had to go to the hospital and have it removed...  You're not following the column: I had it last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe in capital punishment, Senator?</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME REVERSE ANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Senator, amused, asks:</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME HUNSECKER AND SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney glances sidelong at Hunsecker.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker's face hardens; aware of Sidney's impertinence, he does not design to react directly; he turns towards the Agent.</context>
      <utterance>A man has just been sentenced to death...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manny, what exactly are the UNSEEN gifts of this lovely young thing that you manage...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she sings a little...you know, sings...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manny's faith in me is simply awe- inspiring, Mr. Hunsecker. Actually, I'm still studying, but -</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He studies the Girl intently.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What subject?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Girl betrays herself with a nervous glance at the Senator beside her, CAMERA eases back to include him. The Senator is unruffled; gravely, he lights a cigar. The Girl laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Why "of course"? It might, for instance, be politics...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? I mean "I"? Are you kidding, Mr. Hunsecker? With my Jersey City brains?</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again his glance links the Girl and the Senator.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The brains may be Jersey City, but the clothes are Trainor-Norell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SENATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you an actor, Mr. Falco?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I was thinking. Are you, Mr. Falco?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you guess it, Miss James?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's so pretty, that's how.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker has started his speech lightly, but it has built up to enough cold contempt and feeling to embarrass and intimidate the others at the table. In conclusion, Hunsecker, his eyes on Sidney, picks up a cigarette and waits expectantly...</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Falco, let it be said at once, is a man of FORTY faces, not one, none too pretty and ALL deceptive. See that grin? It's the charming street urchin's face. It's part of his "helpless" act - he throws himself on your mercy. I skip the pleading nervous bit that sometimes blends over into bluster. The moist grateful eye is a favorite face with him - it frequently ties in with the act of boyish candor: he's talking straight from the heart, get it? He's got about half-a-dozen faces for the ladies, but the real cut one to me is the quick dependable chap - nothing he won't do for you in a pinch. At least, so he says! Tonight Mr. Falco, whom I did not invite to sit at this table, is about to show in his last and most pitiful role: pale face with tongue hanging out. In brief, gentlemen and Jersey Lilly, the boy sitting with us is a hungry press agent and fully up to all the tricks of his very slimy trade!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Match me, Sidney...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A single close up, to intercut with the above.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The florid man retreats. To cover the embarrassment, the Senator makes a sally in Sidney's direction.</context>
      <utterance>I know - that loafer of yours opens at the Latin Quarter next week.  Say goodbye, Lester!</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I ask a naive question, Mr. Falco? Exactly how does a press agent work...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY AND HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney doesn't answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you answer the man, Sidalee? He's trying to take you off the hook.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just had a good example of it. A press agent eats a columnists dirt and is expected to call it manna.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's manna?</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME HUNSECKER AND SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hunsecker glances spitefully at the Girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heaven dust.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But don't you help columnists by furnishing them with items?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney lifts a mimeographed sheet, as an example.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, columnists can't get along without us. Only our good and great friend, J.J., forgets to mention that. We furnish him with items -</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, some cheap, gruesome gags?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You print them, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, with your clients' names attached. That's the only reason those poor slobs pay you - to see their names in my column all over the world! Now, as I make it out, you're doing ME a favor!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say that, J.J.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The day that I can't get along without press agents' handouts, I'll close up shop, lock, stock and barrel and move to Alaska.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Manny, you rode in here on the Senator's shirt tails, so shut your mouth! The Senator doesn't like this treatment of others and his manner and face show it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, come, J.J., that's a little too harsh. Anyone seems fair game for you tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This man is not for you, Harvey, and you shouldn't be seen with him in public. Because that's another part of a press agents life - he digs up scandal among prominent men and shovels it thin among the columnists who give him space.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker points to the Girl and the CAMERA makes a slight crab movement to include the Girl as Hunsecker points in turn to her.</context>
      <utterance>...is toting THAT one...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another CAMERA movement. Now Hunsecker is directly challenging the Senator.</context>
      <utterance>...around for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He smiles disarmingly.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker rises.</context>
      <utterance>...Are we kids or what?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With Sidney making way for him, Hunsecker walks round the end of the table to the Senator. The Senator faces Hunsecker solemnly.</context>
      <utterance>Next time you come up, you might join me at my TV show.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker matches the Senator's solemnity.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, J.J., for what I consider sound advice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mac, don't let the Senator pay that check...</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA tracks with Hunsecker and Sidney as they move out towards the hat check stand.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take care of it, Mr. Hunsecker.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now they are at the coatroom, Hunsecker smiling.</context>
      <utterance>President! My big toe would make a better President!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Hunsecker's coat, Joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He accepts the proferred coat as he moves past CAMERA.</context>
      <utterance>Find me a good one, Joe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dan, anyone calls, tell 'em I'll be at the Morocco, maybe the Embers.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney catches up with Hunsecker as he moves out onto the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>Very good, Mr. Hunsecker.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney thinks of an impertinent reply, decides not to be drawn and says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Where's your coat, Sidalee? Saving tips?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My curiosity is killing me; what are you so rambunctious about tonight? Sidney again does not answer; this time he points across the street...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's your fat friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, Sidalee, that shows that Lt. Kello likes your people.</utterance>
   <speaker>REVERSE ON KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kello offers his hand to Hunsecker.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker accepting the handshake, winces with pretended pain at what is clearly an over-enthusiastic grip.</context>
      <utterance>It's my Brooklyn background, J.J. I'm good on Yiddish, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kello laughs, releases the grip; Hunsecker strolls past him stoops to lean into the car listening to the police calls on the radio.</context>
      <utterance>Harry, am I supposed to say "uncle"?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The detective inside the car answers, respectfully.</context>
      <utterance>Anything fit to print, tonight?  Hello, Phil. How're the kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, Mr. Hunsecker.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any news fit to print tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just checked "downtown". Quiet everywhere tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Incidentally, what happened to that doll? - You gave me the item last night. Still alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. At Bellevue. Still hanging on. But they still don't know if she was pushed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Phil lifts the radio phone, calling headquarters, Hunsecker turns back to Kello and Sidney.</context>
      <utterance>She mighta jumped. Love suicide?  Check it for me, Phil...it's a real heart throb.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He called you my fat friend.</context>
      <utterance>Say hello to Sidney Falco. Tickle him - he's been a bad boy tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Instantly aware that J.J. is toying with Sidney, Kello offers his large hand to Sidney, who refuses it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know...I know you're the strongest cop in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I call him the boy with the ice cream face!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, that's good - it's nice - in fact, it's APT, Harry!</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I got eyes. I put things together.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The memory of something unpleasant clouds Kello's face.</context>
      <utterance>I remember ONCE when you didn't quite "put things together". Boy! Was the Mayor mad!</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The policeman in the car sticks his head out of the window.</context>
      <utterance>Citizens committees! I didn't mean to hit the boy that hard. Yeah, that's when a feller needed a friend and I won't forget his initials, J.J.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She died twenty minutes ago, Mr. Hunsecker. They're still investigating.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's show business. Thanks, Phil.  See you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hasta La Vista, J.J. Hasta Luego.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spahish...that must show he likes "spigs", too.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA now SHOOTS down 52nd Street. Hunsecker, back to CAMERA, studies the evening, hearing the sound of a screech of female laughter from one of the groups in the distance. A drunk is being thrown out of one of the strip tease joints.</context>
      <utterance>I like Harry, but I can't deny he sweats a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amused, Hunsecker turns back; he signals across the street to the car park, indicating that the big black Lincoln Continental should follow as he strolls with Sidney.</context>
      <utterance>I love this dirty town.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Conjugate me a verb, Sidney. For instance, TO PROMISE! CAMERA TRACKS with them in a CLOSE TWO SHOT. Sidney is alert now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me you'd break up that romance - when?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want something done, J.J., but I doubt if you yourself know what's involved.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a schoolboy - teach me, teach me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker pauses, halts.</context>
      <utterance>Why not break it up yourself? You could do it in two minutes flat.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney follows quickly.</context>
      <utterance>At this late date you need explanations...? Susie's all I got - now that she's growing up, I want my relationship with her to stay at least at par! I don't intend to antagonize her if I don't have to.  Now, be warned, son - I'll have to blitz you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frankly, J.J., I don't think you got the cards to blitz me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Correct me if I'm wrong, but I don't think so...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney steps in front of Hunsecker, blocking his way for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I'll listen one more minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About a year ago, you asked me to do a favor. It was a thing - well, I never did a thing that dirty in all my life. Hunsecker, totally disinterested in Sidney's problems of conscience, signals to his car again, walks past Sidney, who continues rapidly:</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awright, that brings us up to five weeks ago. "Sidney, I got a nasty little problem here." Did I say no? I'm frank to admit - it don't jell as fast as we like... But all of a sudden I CAN'T GET YOU ON THE PHONE NO MORE! WHY?... And why, as of this date, am I frozen out of the column...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you finished?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, lemme finish. I DON'T LIKE THIS JOB! That boy is dumb only on matinee days - otherwise he's got a head. And Susan, like you said, she's growing up. Two heads. What I mean, we got a slippery, dangerous problem here!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not "we", Sidney, you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Correct me if I'm wrong - WE! Because when I'm out on this very slippery limb for you, you have to know what's involved.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney quickly moves into J.J.'s path, desperate to hold his attention.</context>
      <utterance>Ha! My right hand hasn't seen my left hand for thirty years!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let me make a living!</context>
      <utterance>I'll do it, J.J. - don't get me wrong - in for a penny, in for a pound. I'll see it through, but stop beating me around the head.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker walks past Sidney, now making for the car at which the attendant still waits.</context>
      <utterance>What you promised - do it! Don't finagle around. It's later than you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse it, but it's later than you think. That boy proposed tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause.</context>
      <utterance>No wonder you've been so 'feisty' tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney nods.</context>
      <utterance>Can you deliver?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tonight. Before you go to bed. The cat is in the bag and the bag is in the river.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sentence could be severe...</context>
      <utterance>Don't be a two time loser, Sidalee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is satisfied.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLOSER ANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>REVERSE ANGLE. A CAPTAIN approaches Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Sidney. Wanna table?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just hopping tonight. Leo Bartha been in?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Captain nods towards a booth on the other side of the bar where Mrs. Bartha is sitting alone. Seeing that Bartha is not with her, the Captain looks around the bar...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, having supper with the Mrs. She's over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's somewhere...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney is looking back towards the entrance hall, where...</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, I see him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney smiles at Bartha, but the threat is clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cigarettes girl...Rita. And she took out all her hairpins, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney is pulling out of his pocket a pad on which to scribble the item. But Bartha faces him squarely, speaking sotto voce but with emphasis:</context>
      <utterance>I never had the pleasure of meeting your wife. You know what I wonder, Leo? Could you use a hot little item for tomorrow's column?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bartha turns on his heel and turns to walk towards his wife beyond.</context>
      <utterance>What is this, blackmail? Beat it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bartha looks up. What can he do? Begrudgingly:</context>
      <utterance>Leo, I've never had the pleasure of meeting your wife...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loretta...Sidney Falco...</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do, Mr. Falco. If you know anything about horses, sit a minute. Help yourself to a glass of this N.Y. State champagne - that's what my husband buys me. Mrs. Bartha pushes the champagne bottle in Sidney's direction as Sidney sits pleasantly; Bartha concentrates on his sandwich.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the imported wines aren't what they're cracked up to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose side are you on, Mr. Falco, his or mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frankly, Mrs. Bartha, I'm a neutral observer for the United Nations.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Bartha laughs, enjoying his deftness; then:</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your first name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Bartha turns to concentrate on the names in the racing column of the tabloid.</context>
      <utterance>Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No horse running tomorrow by that name...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ought to stop this nonsense, Loretta, these two dollar bets.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's compensation, Leo, for the marginal life we lead.  Sidney, did you hear the story about the cloak-and-suitor who -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right! Tell him, so I can read it in Hunsecker's column first!</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, are you a spy for the other side?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>produces his pad again, begins to write on it.</context>
      <utterance>No, I actually sat down to give Leo an item.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bartha notes Sidney's writing.</context>
      <utterance>Leo, he wants to give you an item - don't be sullen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you mind your own business!</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She returns to her paper, ignoring them, Sidney finishes scribbling the item.</context>
      <utterance>Hitler!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes the item to Bartha, who reads it, briefly. Meanwhile:</context>
      <utterance>Just in case you'd like to print it, Leo. It's a blind - no names mentioned. But for your private information, the guy's name is Dallas.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bartha pushes the item back towards Sidney. Sidney glances quickly at Bartha's stony face then, significantly, turns towards his wife.</context>
      <utterance>There isn't a single name here that gives off vibrations...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bartha raises his head, looks squarely at Sidney with contempt and anger. His wife is unaware of this reaction. Still looking at the paper, she murmurs:</context>
      <utterance>Anything there with a name like "cigarette girl"?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney pushes the item back towards Bartha.</context>
      <utterance>MMmmmm..."cigarette girl"... No, no horse with a name like that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't print blind items.</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looks from Sidney to her husband and back.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this, chess or checkers...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment of chill silence. Then Bartha gets to his feet, signals for a waiter. As Sidney rises also:</context>
      <utterance>Neither does Hunsecker.  He likes to use the real names...</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we running? What am I missing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waiter, the check.  This man is trying to hold a gun to my head!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY AND BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bartha turns challengingly to Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to tell my wife, Sidney...?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is brushing her lap with her napkin.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to tell me that you poured champagne all over my lap.</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME BARTHA AND SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bartha ignores her, again challenges Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on, tell her, I'm waiting!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He glances unhappily at his wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lorry, I can't let this man blackmail me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney decides to retreat. He turns, starts to go. But Bartha blocks his way, holding Sidney and explaining to the Wife.</context>
      <utterance>Blackmail...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants me to print a dirty smear item for keeping his mouth shut A momentarily pause. Then:</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is uneasy, ashamed of himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Foolishly, Lorry, and I hope you'll understand... this cigarette girl...I was kidding around with her...this girl, I mean...I was kidding around and she took it seriously. It was a case of bad judgment, Lorry, bad taste...and I'm just sorry, Lorry, that's all...</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She says nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BARTHA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney tries to brazen it out, sneering:</context>
      <utterance>Your friend Hunsecker - you can tell him for me - he's a disgrace to his profession. Never mind my bilious private life - I print a decent, responsible column - that's the way it stays! Your man - there's nothing he won't print if it satisfies his vanity or his spite! He'll use any spice to pepper up his daily garbage! Tell him I said so and that, like yourself, he's got the morals of a guinea pig and the scruples of a gangster!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Bartha slides along the seat, reaching for her fur.</context>
      <utterance>What do I do now? Whistle "The Stars and Stripes Forever?"</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A waiter approaches Sidney. He has a message.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter nods towards the other side of the circular bar. Sidney, his humiliation and rage still burning, looks off towards...</context>
      <utterance>Otis Elwell wants to see you, Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTIS ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Sidney's viewpoint. Elwell beckons.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see Bartha gave you cold tongue for supper.  Hey, wait a minute!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Otis, if you're trying to blow this brawl into an item for your column - forget it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is dear old J.J. by the way?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call him up and ask - he might drop dead with shock.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it were that easy, you wouldn't find an empty phone booth for the next two hours...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Talk of a wake! - they'd club each other to cater the affair for free!</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME ELWELL AND SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elwell looks up at Sidney as he continues.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the way, did I hear something about J.J. giving you the flit gun treatment - he shut you out of the column.  Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know that lunatic yet? Whims - egotistic whims! Like the gag - when you got him for a friend, you don't need an enemy!  That's what the fight with Bartha was about. "Leo", I says, "Hunsecker froze me out. So I'm eating humble pie this month - please print me an item."</utterance>
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, instead, he printed his heel in your face?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see you're full of human feelings...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has lost interest in Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elwell's voice fades: his attention has been caught by...</context>
      <utterance>Like most of the human race, Sidney, I'm bored. I'd go a mile for a chuckle...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elwell turns back towards the papers on his table, a zippered document case and some publications among which a columnist might search for scandal; among these is a magazine of semipornographic nature.</context>
      <utterance>Three...even four...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you're really washed up with Hunsecker...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elwell shows no undue enthusiasm for the item.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Otis, I make no brief for my bilious private life, but he's got the morals of a guinea pig and the scruples of a gangster.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Sidney doesn't take the paper back; he explains:</context>
      <utterance>A fine, fat dirty item.  Who's it about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A kid named Dallas, who runs a dinky jazz quintet.  He keeps company with J.J.'s screwball sister...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIDNEY AND ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watching Elwell read, Sidney encourages:</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Elwell lays the item down in front of him. Clearly, he is considering it. Sidney prompts again.</context>
      <utterance>It's a real goody if, like me, you wanna clobber J.J.!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elwell nods. But he is still reluctant.</context>
      <utterance>He's got his TV tomorrow. He'd read it just before rehearsals.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm. Trouble is I can't think of any good reason why I should print anything you give me. I can't even think of a bad reason.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rita, say hello to Otis Elwell.</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friends call me Otis - sometimes Tricky Otis.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Otis was outraged when I told him Van Cleve was going to fire you. Tell him not to pay any attention to anything you-know-who says about you-know-what.  Right, Otis?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elwell sits down on the sette, stretches his limbs, smiles at the girl. Rita still says nothing. Sidney mistakes her attitude for acquiescence. He swallows his drink, sets it down.</context>
      <utterance>Right!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rita looks at him sharply.</context>
      <utterance>I thought you two could talk the whole thing over till I got back.</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins at Rita. She doesn't respond. Turning, she goes swiftly through the door into the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>One of those business meetings, honey - always coming up in the middle of the night.</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on. You can drop me off on your way... Emphasizing the asperity in her voice, she closes the door behind her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney is uncomfortable, not sure how Elwell is taking the rejection. Elwell glances at his wristwatch, lays down his drink.</context>
      <utterance>Consternation reigns...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elwell shrugs, remarks pleasantly but with significance:</context>
      <utterance>Now, Otis...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate J.J. -- but not that much at this moment...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes into the bedroom, closing the door after him.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a chance --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you know who that man is?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Otis Elwell. The columnist.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he's a perfect stranger to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rita, who one shoe on, has begun to search for the other.</context>
      <utterance>So take five minutes! Get acquainted! He's an important man - he's lonely - don't be dumb!</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want all of a sudden - Lady Godiva...? Where's my other shoe?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rita jumps to her feet. Her righteous indignation is handicapped by the lop-sided stance caused by the lack of one shoe.</context>
      <utterance>What kind of an act is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think I have any feelings? What am I? A bowl of fruit? A tangerine that peels in a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon! I turn myself inside out to help you and now I'm a heavy.  Here's your shoe, there's your coat, that's the door! Contemptuously he thrusts the coat and the shoe into her arms. The positive force of his manner gives the girl pause. There is a silence. Rita searches for words to explain the offense to her sensibilities.</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney...I...I don't do this sort of thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What sort of thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This sort of thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. Sidney has struck brutally home. Rita's lower lip trembles.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, you need him for a favor, don't you! And so do I! I need his column--tonight.  Didn't you ask me to do something about your job? Don't you have a kid in Military School?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney's manner becomes swiftly sympathetic - but still urgent.</context>
      <utterance>You're a snake, Falco. You're a louse, a real louse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rita begins to waver, her moral indignation losing ground before Sidney's reminders of her dire necessity.</context>
      <utterance>Honey - he's going to help you! You want to lose your job?</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A girl needs a little romancing before she -</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time I'll call in a guy to paint silver stars on the ceiling!</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would you think of me if -</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing I didn't think of you before.</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This attempt at humor signals to Sidney that he has brought her round. He comes to her, pats her in an encouraging manner - to which she does not respond. He turns to the door, and picks up the glasses she has set down on the table behind it.</context>
      <utterance>- that's what I mean!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney goes out.</context>
      <utterance>How many snorts does it take to put you in that Tropical Island Mood?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rita shakes her head morosely. Sidney comes and puts a stiff drink into her hand. Elwell raises the glass toasting the girl, encouraging her to drink. Rita responds dimly.</context>
      <utterance>Havana! That's where we met!</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney laughs, more from relief than from the joke.</context>
      <utterance>Here's mud in your column!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blessings on thee, the both...well... Gotta run now. See you two kids later!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the door Sidney takes cheerful leave of them.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That gives you lots of leeway.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do anything I wouldn't do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elwell begins to laugh. Whatever the memory, it seems to amuse him vastly because he continues to laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Palm Springs. Two years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rita drinks. She adds glumly:</context>
      <utterance>That's right!</utterance>
   <speaker>RITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elwell continues to laugh as we...</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell Sidney.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NEWS VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Globe?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney buys and opens the paper. CAMERA MOVES closer to shoot over his shoulder. We see the gossip column which bears a photograph of Otis Elwell at the top. Smirking with satisfaction, Sidney turns away from the CAMERA and throws the paper into a trash basket before he disappears into the impressive entrance of a large office building. The sign above the doorway reads: THE NEW YORK GLOBE.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme The Record.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no power to retract, Mr. Cummings... I'm only Mr. Hunsecker's secretary. No. Nor can I agree that can retraction is necessary. Thank you for calling. Sidney has come through the newsroom in background. He pauses tactfully, seeing Mary occupied with the lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I fail to see what's amusing about these papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get the boss to sign them.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're important.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the disgruntled lawyer leaves, Sidney comes in, wearing his most winning smile. With a glance after the lawyer, making sure that he is not observed, Sidney greets Mary, assuming a brogue:</context>
      <utterance>You've said that six times - that's why I'm smiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney's hand caresses her shoulder with a gesture which indicates a certain intimacy between them.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mary, me darlin' and phwat are ye up to today?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a question I usually like to ask YOU. Your secretary phoned.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney accepts the paper from Mary, examines the item while he talks to Sally on the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Have you seen this? In Otis Elwell's column.  "The dreamy marijuana smoke of a lad who heads a highbrow jazz quintet is giving an inelegant odor to that elegant East Side Club where he works. That's no way for a card-holding Party Member to act. Moscow won't like, you naughty boy!"</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up, continuing to read.</context>
      <utterance>Sally? I got the message. If D'Angelo calls again, tell him I'll be at the office around noon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could this be that boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dallas? Could be. He doesn't look like a reefer smoker... He discards the paper with a show of disinterest. Mary picks it up again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney moves around behind Mary. His eyes are fixed on a spike which sits on Mary's desk. On it is impaled a proof of Hunsecker's column. Meanwhile, he remarks:</context>
      <utterance>If this is true, J.J.'s going to hit the ceiling...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can it be news to you that J.J.'s ceiling needs a plaster job every six weeks?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney, caught "in flagrante", laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Sidney, you know that J.J. doesn't like people to look at the column proof in advance...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns away, changing the subject (apparently).</context>
      <utterance>Mary, I'm not "people" - there's Falco blood, sweat and tears in that column.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary turns to study him.</context>
      <utterance>How about dinner tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bribing me again?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary is thoughtful. Without malice, in a detached sort of way, she examines Sidney.</context>
      <utterance>And why should I bribe the woman who holds most of my heart?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney finds this analysis hard to take. Again he tries to laugh his way out of it.</context>
      <utterance>You're a real rascal, Sidney. I'd certainly dislike you if I didn't like you. You're an amusing boy, but there isn't a drop of respect in you for anything alive - you're too immersed in the theology of making a fast buck. Not that I don't sometimes feel that you yearn for something better...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mind you looking at the proof of the column in advance, as long as J.J. doesn't know. But don't do it like a boy stealing gum from a slot machine. Sidney doesn't like this; but, on the other hand, he does want to look at the column. After only a momentary struggle, he picks the column off the spike and reads.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who put this item in about the comic?  "If there's a more hilarious funny man around than Herbie Temple at the Palace, you'll have to pardon us for not catching the name. We were too busy screaming." Does this Temple have a press agent?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to the door, grinning.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's one of J.J.'s occasional beau gestes. Evidently the fellow's funny, so he gave him a plug.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your favorite ribbon to go around your favorite chocolates?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks after Sidney, thinks about him for a moment. Then she types.</context>
      <utterance>Let's wait till Christmas - it's more legitimate then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Herbit Temple here yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but you can't come in now!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is already on his way into doorway.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in, Sonny Boy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>EVANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The comedian, Herbie Temple, looks up. Sidney comes through a fire-proof door which separates the stage from the corridors to dressing room. In background two chorus girls in costume are squeezed into a telephone booth. Sidney joins the comedian and the agent; he smiles to the comedian, while he addresses the agent.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't waste words, Herbie, take my word. I says, "look, Figo, I'm not selling you a dozen eggs, I'm selling you HERBIE TEMPLE", I says, so don't gimme your lip!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The agent looks from Sidney to Temple, surprised and displeased.</context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Al!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney has clearly never met Evans; blandly he chooses to regard the agent's remark as an introduction; he offers his hand with generous amiability.</context>
      <utterance>Since when did you two get acquainted?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The comic accepts the hand doubtfully.</context>
      <utterance>How do you do, Mr. Temple...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delighted.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Sidney Falco.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evans stands up, warns the comic.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, delighted...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Temple's smile congeals.</context>
      <utterance>Watch this guy, Herbie, he's a press agent.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You watch him, Al, I s...s...stutter!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Temple, I caught your act the other night and -</utterance>
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you now? On which bounce?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- and I just had to drop by and tell you how great I thought you were.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheers. What time is it, Al?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got ten minutes.  Hope you don't mind, Falco: we're busy and if - Sidney stands up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't mind. I'm busy too.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good! We're all off to Utica, so excuse me, Mr. Frannis-on-the- Portisan. Sidney moves toward the doorway onto the corridor. The chorus girls have now vacated the phone booth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiling wise, Evans shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>But can I ask one impertinent question here? With no criticism intended, because I know, Al, you earn your ten percent, how come you let a sock act like Herbie Temple tip-toe through town without a publicity build...?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney presses, as if annoyed.</context>
      <utterance>We're not buying it, Falco - no fish today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Temple turns away from Sidney, leaving him to Evans.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not selling. I'm just curious, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evans moves to Sidney, trying to shepherd him out the way he came.</context>
      <utterance>Answer the man, Al, if he asks you a question. Quick, before he thinks up another!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Temple doesn't believe in press agents - does that answer you something?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney stops briskly up the stairs into the corridor. Evans, angry, is stalled for a moment of delay action by mention of the magic name of Hunsecker.</context>
      <utterance>Take your hand off, lump!  No one believes in press agents, Temple, when they make claims they can't perform. I got nothing to sell - I didn't come here to peddle - but if I tell a client that Hunsecker will give him space, it's not just talk!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, you bull artist - !</utterance>
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him go, Al...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While doing so, he glances back with disinterest at Evans and Temple. The comedian and the agent exchange looks. Evans is uneasy; he comes up the steps into the corridor to address Sidney with a deflated manner.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, I'll wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax, lump! I told you I'm not selling fish...  J.J...Sidney!...How are you, sweetheart?  Yeah...  Listen, I know it's late, J.J., but is it too late to add something important to the column?  No, not a relative, but important...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The comedian and the agent in foreground, Sidney still on the phone beyond.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, if you got a pencil there I'll suggest a word or two. Uh...uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right. 'Bye...</context>
      <utterance>If there's a funnier man in the world than Herbie Temple at the Palace...uh...pardon us for not catching the name, we were too busy laughing. No, make that 'screaming'.  It's sweet of you, J.J., thanks. Probably see you at Twenty One tonight. No, for supper, late.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Falco.</context>
      <utterance>Speak to this lad, Al, ... to Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and walks away down the corridor. As he vanishes, Temple starts after him.</context>
      <utterance>See me in my office.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney permits himself to be detained.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute.  Speak to him, Al.  Al makes all my deals.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evans, not as wholly convinced as the comedian, comes up to join them. Temple looks at the agent.</context>
      <utterance>I don't like a guy that's quick with the hands.  Temple, you've been three passes behind for twenty years. This could start you off big - T.V. and anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEMPLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it would cost a pretty penny, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tell him, I stutter!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVANS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney, shrugging, makes a negligent exit.</context>
      <utterance>Uh...Why don't we wait till tomorrow?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney turns on Steve, coldly:</context>
      <utterance>You read as you run, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a habit with me. So now I'm briefed. So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank thinks I shouldn't have come here -</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Steve. I said namely you shouldn't go around wild, blaming people without justification.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you might have a faint idea of how this item originated.</utterance>
   <speaker>REVERSE ANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Favoring Sidney. He pauses.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why me...?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's your idea of logic? I tell the Judge I didn't murder the man - the Judge says, "Why not you?"</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only two men in this town could be responsible for that smear - you or Hunsecker or both.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dallas, ask your own manager - he's standing here like a pained wolfhound - Hunsecker and Elwell are enemies to the knife. So how do you get him doing J.J. a favor?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is a favor, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to you, yeah.  Dallas, your mouth is as big as a basket and twice as empty! I don't like you, comma, but neither do I go along with this column saying you smoke marijuana and belong with the Reds. Also, since we're talking repulsive, J.J. won't like this for two cents! Don't give me that look, Dallas - J.J. believes in fair play. And secondly, this could splatter his sister with rotten egg by implication - your her boyfriend!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're talking very fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll tell you what - excuse me for breathing, will ya?  How do you like it? He comes to my office and -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boys, this gets nobody nowhere - you're over excited, Steve and -</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't apologize for me, Frank!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...excited with good reason, I wanted to say.  Because this endangers the future of the whole quintet...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steve, with a glare at both men, goes to the phone on Sally's desk. He dials.</context>
      <utterance>Should I cry...?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...People catch on quick to such an item. Van Cleve already called me - he's firing the quintet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In background Steve speaks quietly into the phone:</context>
      <utterance>Then what are you doing here? Go over there and fight! If Van Cleve fires your boy, it gives a lie the ring of truth!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to speak to Miss Hunsecker, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on our way there now...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you calling her for...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up quietly, looks at Sidney and walks towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>We're on our way to the Elysian Room to dicker with Van Cleve - he's fired us already. I'll call you later, dear... 'Bye!...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Frank.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ugly world, Sidney...  If I told Steve what I really think, he'd tear your head off...</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He brazens it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Angelo shakes his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Angelo goes slowly out.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm interested in his future.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Resentfully, Sidney moves about the room. Sensing the silent accusation against him, he is aggressive.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney comes to the phone on her desk. He dials. Then he glances swiftly at Sally and, carrying the phone, walks into the bedroom, dragging the long cord behind him.</context>
      <utterance>You know, Sally, sometimes I get the impression you think you live in Star-Bright Park. This is life, kid - get used to it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you send my folks in Philly the check...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leaving the bedroom door open, Sidney comes up to her, watches her shrewdly, cautiously.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I put a lotta trust in you, Chickie...</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you do, Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sally is putting paper in the typewriter, trying to hold her head up.</context>
      <utterance>Don't judge a situation where you don't know what's involved...</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney comes closer to her. He puts his hand on the nape of her neck, carrassing her. Under his touch, the girl is unhappy, and yet at the same time, responsive. Sidney still has power over her but she is disturbed by feelings of shame. Feeling her relaxed, Sidney bends and kisses her on the side of the throat with more than negligence, for something about her always excites him; his aggression tune in with her submissiveness.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not judging...</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear, Sidney, I can't help it - sometimes I wonder what I see in you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's no way to talk...</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or what you see in me, for that matter...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay down town tonight. Maybe we'll take in a show, etc.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone in the bedroom rings. Sidney, reacting sharply, forgets his advances to Sally as he turns towards the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>If you want me to -</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, J.J....I presume you saw the Elwell smear.  No, no medals - not yet. Oh, it's worse than that - Aunty Van Cleve is firing them...from the horse's mouth... They were just here - in a panic...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was just there?  You'll be the death of me. Sidalee! Why? Didn't you just tell me that they've already traced this smear to you? All they have to do now is to put two and two together and I'm a chicken in a pot!</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME SIDNEY'S APARTMENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney smiles confidently, answers calmly:</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>J.J., peace on earth, good will to men - it's working out just the way I planned. Yeah, I guarantee this bomb will pop right on schedule, but you have to play your part - you be a Saint and let me be the Devil. But I wanna talk to you first...</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME HUNSECKER'S PENTHOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hunsecker pauses, eyes full of cold voltage.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bangs down the phone, tense thought in his manner.</context>
      <utterance>Don't come here. Susie is up and about.  He called her? You'd better see me at the TV - three o'clock.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SALLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney prepares to leave the apartment. His tone is full of confidence, self-assertive. (For once Sidney is certain that he is smarter, more cunning than even Hunsecker).</context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney makes for the door, goes out.</context>
      <utterance>Chickie, a lotta people think they're smart. You watch. They're dumb: they'll do the work for me! Just watch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="51">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The table can wait. No calls. I have to think about my TV show.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pleased to do. I will come back later.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you put the bread out on the terrace for the birds?</utterance>
   <speaker>NIKKO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiling, Nikko leaves. Hunsecker picks up a pencil and makes a note on a pad, about birds no doubt. Abruptly he looks up, calling:</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but they don't come no more this time of year.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has been trying to pass unnoticed to her room. She comes forward to him; her manner is serious and wary. His act is one of a tasteful Mammy singer, but he is watchful, too.</context>
      <utterance>Susie! Come in a minute, dear...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susie, you're very much in my thoughts today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a question, dear, with that newspaper in your hand...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did Sidney tell you about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, he phoned. I don't know this boy too well. Anything in these charges?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not being partial, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He soothes, smiles indulgent, but watchful:</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not. I'm not!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a paternal gesture of affection, he holds out his arms, inviting her into his comforting embrace. Not wanting to, she walks into his open waiting arms.</context>
      <utterance>Susie, take it easy. I'll trust your judgment - you don't have to protest with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you trembling, dear...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker considers this gravely, as if it was a new and troubling thought.</context>
      <utterance>History repeats itself. Everything that happened to Alan Leslie...began with a smear like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves his arms; he watches keenly.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just as if I've seen a ghost today...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that wasn't your fault, dear, what happened to Leslie. I've told you that a million times... He goes to her gently; she appraises both him and her wrenched life with brooding, frightened eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then whose fault was it, J.J.? It was someone's fault, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't have called the boy exactly balanced...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alan was not...unbalanced when I married him. And he was not...'indifferent to women' no matter what they said!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not fighting with you, puss... She gets up and walks around in considerable agitation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to Hunsecker, her manner firmer.</context>
      <utterance>He never would have killed himself if I hadn't gone through with the annulment. Don't you see that made all the rumors seem true? I should have stood up for him...not run out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>J.J., I want you to get them back their job, Steve and the Quintet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks away with a wag of indignation, but turns, asking:</context>
      <utterance>You mean they've been fired already, on the basis of this crude smear?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan shakes her head emphatically.</context>
      <utterance>Susie, you're sure there isn't some fire where there's this much smoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know Steve. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then maybe you can tell me if he's as solid as you say, why does he rap me every chance he gets?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney is a liar!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who said Sidney?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Staring, he pauses; then he deftly changes the subject.</context>
      <utterance>I said Sidney!...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, dear, we're drifting apart, you and I, and I don't like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we were talking about Sidney?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me finish, dear. You had your say, now let me have mine...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I started to say we're drifting apart. A year ago, in your wildest dreams, would you have walked by that door without taking up this situation with me? Today I had to call you in!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm taking up the situation with you now...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susie, I want to help you--, there's nothing I won't do for you. You're all I've got in the whole, wide world. Hunsecker strides about, elaborately playing on a note of disillusion and pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what have I got? Alimony to a pair of tramps? They're of no concern to me. It's you who count, but don't get me wrong - I don't intend to let you break your neck again!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>J.J., you said you want to help me - prove it!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get Steve back his job...please...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He means that much to you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.  With your "prestige" it only takes a minute - ten cents worth of American Tel and Tel.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're picking up my lingo, hon.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susie, I like this new attitude of yours. You're growing up and I like it! I don't like it when you're limp and dependent, when you're odd and wayward. This gives you a chance for real survival in a very lousy world. Because, don't forget, dear, you won't always have me with you, will you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses to the white desk phone, delaying dialing for a moment:</context>
      <utterance>No, I won't...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan doesn't like this idea, is evasive:</context>
      <utterance>This Dallas boy must be good for you. Why not bring him around today, before the show? This time I'll clean my glasses for a better look.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure I can reach him in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you can if you want to, and I know you'll want to...  By the way, what's your beef against little Sidney?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I'm certain, I'll let you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A man couldn't ask for a squarer shake.  Let me have Billy Van Cleve...  Don't ever tell anyone, Susie, how I'm tied to your apron strings...  Billy! J.J.! What's this about that boy? What boy? Where are we, lug, in a drawing room comedy? You're brain is warming up, sweetheart - yeah, Dallas!...  No, don't explain your point of view, but...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I was reminded of it this morning, when I noticed that the birds had gone South. We want the same kind of freedom for ourselves - that's what the man said!  A man has the right to face his accusers! That's the American Way! Who said? The man said! From..." He turns in exasperation to Burton.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burton departs. Mary whips a second sheet out of the typewriter, hands it to Hunsecker. As he accepts it, Hunsecker looks off towards the auditorium.</context>
      <utterance>Burton, don't stand around. If I go over I'll cut some items off the tail...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"From Washington through to Jefferson, from Lincoln and F.D.R. right up to today - the Democratic Way of Life! That's what the man said! Nowadays it doesn't export to well...  But you know...and I know...that our best secret weapon is D-E-M-O-</utterance>
   <speaker>C-R-A-C-Y.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's never forget it, ladies and gentlemen."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MILDRED TAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's grand, just grand, J.J.!  Is my makeup all right? You know, despite the scads of movies I've made, I've never appeared on TV yet...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Under the pretense of studying the typed script, J.J. walks away across the stage. Sidney strolls after him.</context>
      <utterance>Of course, Mildred. Of course. You look fine.  Mary, help Miss Tam - anything she wants; she's our star today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got that boy coming over here.  What's so funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With a pocket fulla firecrackers - good.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you loused this up but good. If I can trust my eyes, and I think I can, Susie knows all about your dirty work.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't hurt...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't hurt? I had to get him back his job.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like that, too.  Look, J.J., we can wrap this up in one neat bundle, addressed to the dumps - to oblivion. We're going great, but please play it my way. I cased this kid. Know his ins and outs...He's fulla juice and vinegar, just begging for some big shot like you to give him a squeeze. Do little Sidney a favor: squeeze! - You know, J.J. - the porcupine bit - needles.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's too late. I got him back the job...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. Hunsecker renumerates.</context>
      <utterance>No, that's the point - he won't accept your favor! The manager yes, but not the boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well he's got her in a tizzy, I'll tell you that!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, he steams her up - wants her to stand on her own two feet and all that jazz!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who's feet is she on now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Presumably yours...  That's according to St. Dallas.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this boy got that Susie likes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Integrity - acute, like indigestion.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean - integrity?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker gives him certain slow begrudging admiration:</context>
      <utterance>A pocket fulla firecrackers - looking for a match!  It's a new wrinkle to tell the truth... I never thought I'd make a killing on some guy's "integrity".</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Full of beans, ain't you? But you know that you'll stand or fall by what you're doing now...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calculated risk. Only we happen to know, J.J., that you like me. I'm your star pupil -- I reflect back to you your own talent. Hunsecker permits himself a faint smile. Burton is approaching with script in hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney smirks. He turns away and goes off towards the auditorium in the background.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't like to take a bite of you; you're a cookie full of arsenic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still think he's responsible for the smear.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that I'm convinced, but you'll never prove it in a million years.  Steve, you'll do what you want, but it can't hurt; he offers you an olive branch - so today like olives!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steve completes the sentence with a slow shake of the head; compromise is a gesture which he finds very difficult.</context>
      <utterance>I guess you're right, but -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RESUME HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He studies them, then calls out:</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like a wedding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve, you remember my brother...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE &amp; HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steve shakes the hand that the smiling Hunsecker gives.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, son, looks like you went out and bought yourself a packet of trouble...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker.</context>
      <utterance>You've been very kind about it, Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give Susie credit for that. I took her word that there was nothing to the smear. Matter of fact, I'll have my say about smears on the show today. That's why I'd like YOUR personal assurance, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Hunsecker, there's nothing to that smear. You have my sincere word...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll by that, son. Now, you owe ME a favor.  Be good to my kid sister...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susie likes to keep her girlish secrets. But in her heart of hearts I imagine, Dallas, that she fancies you in an uncommon way. Now, what about YOU, son? Not just tom-catting around...I hope?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>J.J., Steve isn't... Hunsecker cuts her off with lazy good nature:</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy, Susie. He wouldn't be much of a man if he didn't understand my concern. Would you, son?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I wouldn't...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker crosses toward Sidney.</context>
      <utterance>Serious as a deacon...I like it. I like your style, son! In a world of old rags and bones, I like it! For instance, take Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Sidney got anywhere near Susie I'd break a bat over Sidney's head!  Sidney lives so much in a moral twilight that, when I said you were coming here, he predicted disaster. You wouldn't take my favor -- you'd chew up the job, he said, and spit it right back in my face!  Any truth in that...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank, you don't listen! J.J. just told you to shut your mouth!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think it's about time you shut yours? Who are you to tell a man like Frank D'Angelo to shut up?!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Steve, on a heated rip, has turned to Hunsecker:</context>
      <utterance>Steve, that isn't important --</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does he have to be here in our hair?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just exactly what are you so hot about?  I mean, I know it's a difficult thing to be an artist in this crudest of possible worlds, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nuts! I'm not here as an artist! I'm here as an average Joe, who happens to love your sister Susie!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frankly, son, you lost me on that last hill. Just give us the punch line...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No punch line. Maybe I was just admiring your know-how---yours and Falco's.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Playing along nicely, Hunsecker looks at Steve and Frank and slowly removes his arm from Susan; he pauses before asking Dallas:</context>
      <utterance>Wild? Take a look at them and see who's wild...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about that...?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve was excited...he didn't mean it exactly the way it's stated here...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you mean it...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY, STEVE, D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hunsecker enters from behind CAMERA.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steve is cornered, the other completely out of play. He pauses:</context>
      <utterance>Both of you keep quiet!  You've made more damage here in one minute than a plague of locusts! If you're tired, Susie, sit down--- this needs investigation!  How did you mean it...?  Come on, let's go! Let's go!...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't take kindly to you and Falco selling me ethics. Who's the injured party here, you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now you're in no position to ask questions! And your snide remarks---</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, I haven't handed over punishing privileges to you YET! Put the whip down and I might respect what you're saying... Switching his leonine tail, Hunsecker looks broodingly at Susie. Frank says one beseeching word, "Steve...", but no one hears him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susie, did you know about this accusation...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Hunsecker, you've got more twists than a barrel of pretzels.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hear that, Susie...  Continue please...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid I can't cope with them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Hunsecker pauses; Sidney throws in a stage whisper:</context>
      <utterance>You're too shrewd for me so I'll just be honest. Susie and I love each other, if I'm not mistaken, and we want to get married.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give him credit---the boy's gall is gorgeous!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we hear what Susie has to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steve walks to Susie, trying to lift her with his hopes and air of gentle urging and support.</context>
      <utterance>That's stout of you, Dallas, but Susie may not care to air her dismal views in public...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susie...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She stares at the floor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susie, as always, is free to say anything she thinks. Go on, dear, say exactly what's on your mind, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those "dears" sound like daggers. May I suggest that you stop DARING her to speak?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I lift my eyebrows? What is this? What are you trying to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to get Susie to stand up to you. But your manner is so threatening that she's afraid to speak!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son, you raise your voice again and you'll be outa here on your golden pratt!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve, if only for my sake, I want this stopped! And the same goes for you, too, J.J.!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He interjects.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susie, I'm sorry if---</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steve turns a blank-eyed stare at him. Tension gone, a slow mumbling fatigue has set in. Hunsecker plays it light:</context>
      <utterance>You see, Dallas, a plague on both our houses...  We may have to call this game on account of darkness...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If looks could kill, I'm dead...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't care about you -- you're fantastic. My whole interest, if it's not too late, is in Susie...and how to undo what you've done to her...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what have I done to her, besides not buy her a new fur coat lately? Sidney, you were right -- the boy's a dilly.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Because I don't like the way you toy with human lives? - Your contempt and malice? Because I won't be the accomplice of your sick ego - and the way it's crippled Susie...? You think of yourself - you and your column - you see yourself as a national glory...but to me, and thousands of others like me, you and your slimy scandal, your phony patriotics - to me, Mr. Hunsecker, you are a national disgrace!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and stares away, but Steve stops him with---</context>
      <utterance>Son, I don't fancy shooting mosquitoes with elephant guns. So suppose you just shuffle along and call it a day...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But my day with Susie isn't over yet and--</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten'll get you fifty you're playing hookey from a padded cell!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You in a mood, Susie, to run over to Milgrim's later and buy a few new frocks?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker again tries to come nearer to her.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm going home.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ignoring the shake of her head, he calls to Sidney.</context>
      <utterance>Want Sidney to drive you over?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drive Susie home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan stops dead.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get you a cab...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes out into the street. Beyond, we see a crushing cab. Hesitating, Sidney adds:</context>
      <utterance>Get away from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Susan has already moved out of shot, hurrying across the sidewalk to hail the taxi.</context>
      <utterance>J.J. asked me to drive you over and -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney no longer hums; after a moment, he answers.</context>
      <utterance>So that's what "integrity" looks like. Well, I'm always willing to learn...  How is that slob, D'Angelo, your uncle?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney's cheerfulness annoys Hunsecker.</context>
      <utterance>My mother's side--her brother. That reminds me, J.J., Susie looks run down. She can stand a vacation and so can you. People say, "Oh, the great J.J., he's made of iron!", but you can use a rest, guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you so chipper about? If I put a cross on every one of your mistakes, you'd look like a graveyard!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not for anything I did today...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker moves out of shot.</context>
      <utterance>Sidney, I know human nature. Susie lied to me - she'll see that boy again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hearing the sound of the door, Sidney turns sharply. CAMERA MOVES to discover that Hunsecker has gone out. Sidney, quickly, finishing the brushing of his hair, follows...</context>
      <utterance>You're right, J.J. - she won't give him up, but it doesn't matter. Because the real "money ball" is the boy, not Susan. And if --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These drinks are warm.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you like to have them on your table.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you a critic?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll change --</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it.  The real money ball is the boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A waiter shifts the position of the salad dish at Hunsecker's elbow.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, the boy...we're on the verge of a farce, a real farce. As I see it, if Susie had stood behind him today he might have proved a threat. But since primarily he's wedded to his work, he's not going to be able to take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter retreats rapidly.</context>
      <utterance>Stop tinkering, pal - that horse radish won't jump a fence!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delicately salting his oysters, Hunsecker looks obliquely at Sidney.</context>
      <utterance>In brief, J.J., it's all over because any hour now the boy will give her up. Is it a farce or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker, with a casual gesture, tugs lightly at the end of Sidney's tie. Hunsecker's gesture is playful, but it inflicts great injury to Sidney's dignity; Sidney cannot bear to be touched; he finds this liberty on J.J.'s part as intolerable as anything he has experienced, and only with great difficulty controls himself. The SHOT FAVORS Sidney.</context>
      <utterance>This syrup you're giving out, Sidney, you pour over waffles, not J.J. Hunsecker! What do you mean that lousy kid will give up my sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY AND HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hunsecker continues:</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you listening?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does it matter who's sister? The main thing, they're through and -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PULLS BACK to include Sidney as Hunsecker tosses in front of him an envelope. Sidney opens it, extracts two steamship tickets.</context>
      <utterance>Brief epitaph: "The boy was talking when he should have been listening."  Bite on this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steamship tickets?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the next sailing of the Mary. Susan's run down - she's never been abroad and as you so cogently put it, I'm not made of iron. Sidney slowly pushes the envelope back to Hunsecker, who leaves it lying on the table before him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good. Now that louse is outa Susie's hair for good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do something that would drive them right back into each other's arms? Not to mention that this time Susie would know who shot the arrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She knows now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why give her real proof? You nearly ruined her with her first husband - and you were right, J.J., - but she almost followed him out the window. What do you want - a chronic invalid?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA MOVES CLOSER as Sidney picks scratch pad up. We can read two words: "Get Kello".</context>
      <utterance>Why, what's tomorrow - a holiday?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'll go home - maybe I left my sense of humor in another suit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving, J.J....</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER AND SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SHOOTING ACROSS Sidney onto Hunsecker.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't remove the gangplank, Sidney; you may wanna get back on board.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney feels the chill of despair upon him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This crab gumbo - terrific!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>J.J., it's one thing to wear your dog collar...but when it gets to be a noose...I'd rather have my freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney begins to get up from the table.</context>
      <utterance>The man in jail is always for freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker looks up at Sidney.</context>
      <utterance>Except, if you'll excuse me, I'm not in jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Sidney's viewpoint.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you're in jail, Sidney. You're a prisoner of your own fears, of your own greed and ambition; you're in jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Hunsecker's viewpoint.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over Hunsecker and the CAMERA PULLS BACK to include Hunsecker in f.g.</context>
      <utterance>J.J. If you're trying to -</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, little boy, don't know who you are! Talking around corners with the big shots, ten dollar dinners - fourteen suits and cashmere coats - you tell yourself THAT'S who you are! Later you won't know who you are without a penthouse on upper Park! But underneath it all, ratting around from day to day, you DO know who you are! You're a fearful, ignorant nobody - a poor wop kid from the slums of Philly - hoping nobody else finds it out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you what I want you to do tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks down on Hunsecker, leans over the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA has PULLED BACK to include Hunsecker, whose attention has returned to his food.</context>
      <utterance>You're blind, Mr. Magoo. This is a crossroads for me. I won't get Kello. Not for a life-time pass to the Polo Grounds. Not if you serve me Ingrid Bergman on a plate.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sidney, I told you -</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>J.J., I swear to you on my mother's life, I won't do it.  If you gave me your COLUMN I wouldn't do a thing like that... But as he speaks the last words, Sidney's voice falters because he has glanced down at the table...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a pleasantly affable way, he leans across the table to tap the hand with which Sidney is leaning on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Helplessly, Sidney unclenches a fist and reveals the slip of paper which he had meant to keep. Hunsecker takes it. With his eyes on Sidney, he slowly tears it up...</context>
      <utterance>And, Sidney, I'll have that piece of paper back...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA TRACKS with them as they come out into the hallway. They move towards the side entrance, away from the elevators.</context>
      <utterance>She'll be down in a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy shrugs impatiently.</context>
      <utterance>What does she wanna see you about?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some passersby come down the hall and enter a waiting elevator, barely glancing at D'Angelo and the boy. D'Angelo feels uneasy.</context>
      <utterance>She didn't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could think of better places to meet her, instead of here. He lives on the whole top floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I doubt that it matters any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He addresses Steve soberly.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve. You made a very dangerous enemy of him today. Matter of fact, I'm very glad we got the tour ahead. If I'm any judge, you hurt him today where he lives... He won't forget it and he won't forgive...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Steve. I'm glad you could come.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you call me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In there...</context>
      <utterance>Would you buy me a cup of coffee?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he walks with her towards the cafe:</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're on our way to Robard's for a benefit. I've only got five minutes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COUNTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too late for service.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just two cups of java.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNTERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We serve here only moka coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Counterman goes to the urn for the coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Make it moke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve...what you tried to do today...you tried to take me up on a high mountain...I couldn't go all the way...I failed you...  Will you forgive me?  Have I lost you, Steve? Have I...?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe I was wrong, too... But there's no doubt, Susie, that we have to face some serious things...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's ever stood up to my brother the way you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you didn't do much about it, Susie. You walked out, and there I was...solo...and not too good at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just didn't think that I could antagonize him, Steve -- for OUR sake, I mean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't care about that now. He knew what he was doing today. He was laying down the conditions under which he MIGHT consent to our marriage - if I would bend to every whim of his, like Sidney! I couldn't do that, Susie...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After a pause, she says:</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're saying goodbye, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN AND STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve flares up.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I'm saying that for your sake you have to make a clean break with your brother!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, please, Steve, please - one step at a time! I was born only yesterday!...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told your brother I couldn't be his accomplice. I can't be yours either, Susie, and encourage him to go on pulverizing you. I know what type - he's my old man all over again! Susan, pathetically despairing, fingers the handle of her coffee cup, which she has not touched. The coat slips from her shoulders...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan turns to him. She is deflated, lacking all will power.</context>
      <utterance>This beautiful coat is more than just a coat... I hate it! It's a mink straight-jacket!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve, I feel exhausted...what do you want me to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do YOU want to do?</context>
      <utterance>Not what you're doing now. At least don't ask me - don't ask him. You're fighting for your life!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are saying goodbye, aren't you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He reacts vigorously, protesting:</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fish four days old...! I can't buy it, Susie! Right out of that mouth I love, like you're a ventriloquist's dummy, your BROTHER is saying goodbye! Gee!...you want me to be honest, don't you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A despairing cry:</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Steve, I don't. I don't. Not if it KILLS me I don't!...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Mr. D'Angelo. Take care of Steve.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks a little way down the corridor, again leaving them alone.</context>
      <utterance>I will, Miss Hunsecker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RESUME STEVE AND D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Angelo turns back to Steve.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steve, still without looking back, walks up the street;</context>
      <utterance>Still there...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steve, his manner full of pain, stops.</context>
      <utterance>Not that I don't like her - she's a very lovely person, but who can tell? A year from now you might thank your stars that it turned out this way.  By the way, Robard said that...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Angelo takes him firmly by the arm.</context>
      <utterance>Frank, I don't want to make the benefit. They'll be jammin' all night, and the way I feel -- I'd like to be alone -- I'd like just to walk and walk and never come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steve looks at him, knowing that he can never shake off the devoted Frank; he shrugs. They walk past CAMERA.</context>
      <utterance>No. I don't leave you alone on a night like this. And, anyway, you promised...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lew, Steve don't feel too good...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to hear it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...So, if you don't mind, he'll leave after this set. In b.g., Sidney sets down his drink, reacting to this information. Robard clamps D'Angelo on the shoulder, reassuring him with warm emphasis:</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like that boy, Frank. Anything he does is okay with me...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>unobtrusively but purposefully towards a telephone booth. He enters and closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>Sidney, thinking rapidly, leaves the bar, moving</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>1ST POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this deal tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of these days I'd like to turn in my badge and tangle with "POPSIE" myself - he's no good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To Kello this is a great joke. He laughs, enjoying Sidney's uneasiness. He begins to "cat and mouse" Sidney.</context>
      <utterance>Can't you wait up the block? It's not going to look so good, right in front of the club...</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nice, Sidney, that you give me this tip...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- He's got them on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney, annoyed at this sarcasm, moves past Kello, not deigning to respond. As he goes by, Kello grasps him forcibly by the arm.</context>
      <utterance>...And he's got them on him. I appreciate a thing like that - I appreciate where you are looking out for the virtue of the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA HAS PANNED to SHOOT towards the car out of which emerges a second detective.</context>
      <utterance>What's your hurry, Snooks?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney jerks his arm away, rapidly retreats a few yards, a safe distance from Kello. CAMERA PANS with him to the bottom of the steps.</context>
      <utterance>Murph, how do you like this face? Why, I'll be darned -- it's melting! Something got you scared, Sidney...? Listen, rectify me a certain thing. Wasn't you kidding, Snooks, when you told J.J. I was fat...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sleep in peace, Kello -- you're skinny -- but J.J. says you sweat!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a fact? He's a dilly, ain't he? By the by, what did he have against this boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He goes out with girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll be darned. And what does J.J. think he SHOULD do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go out with DIFFERENT girls!</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He moves forward a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Could I be wrong?</context>
      <utterance>I get the peculiar impression, Snooks, that you don't like me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Press this in your friendship book...Love is a crooked thing, friendship not...  You see, it comes out in the wash of a few drinks -- I'm a very sentimental guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME ROBARD'S CLUB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve is touched.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up his guitar case and makes for the door. D'Angelo goes a few paces with him, CAMERA TRACKING. Then it moves past D'Angelo, following Steve out onto the sidewalk, where he stands under the light of the club framed against the dark background of the square.</context>
      <utterance>I like it that way, Frank...don't change.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While the change is made, Sidney stands with cocked head, listening in reality or imagination to what is happening down the street. As the barman supplies the change, Sidney goes to the juke box and loads it with nickels saying over his shoulder:</context>
      <utterance>A bunch of nickels, mister!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney puts both hands on the juke box as if leaning on it. With a click, drop and whirl, the music box comes to life; music blares out. Pausing a moment, Sidney turns back toward the bar.</context>
      <utterance>A double Johnny Walker Black. Or whatever you got. Scotch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Robard, somebody just picked up one of your boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What sa -- Wha --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatsa matter, Lou?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They just picked up Steve.</context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to find out myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOITERER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some fat guy...</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND LOITERER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A cop, a couple of cops.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOITERER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They smeared him all over the lot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for your brother. Is he home?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Angelo has no wish to become involved with the girl; he doesn't reply.</context>
      <utterance>No.  Mr. D'Angelo - is something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When does he usually gets in, your night-owl brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Angelo backs away, shaking his head.</context>
      <utterance>Seldom before five.  What's the matter? Would you care to come in a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to the elevator. Susan closes the door, but slowly; she is watching D'Angelo. CAMERA MOVES WITH D'Angelo as he goes to the bell of the elevator and rings it. He remains in this position, waiting for the elevator, but now (believing himself to be alone) he leans his head against the wall and begins to weep, quietly. Surprisingly, Susan is abruptly at his elbow, she seizes him forcibly by the arm, demanding:</context>
      <utterance>No...no. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan is becoming hysterical.</context>
      <utterance>He's in the hospital...He's under arrest, too... They planted reefer cigarettes on him...in his overcoat pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan is sobered by his seriousness.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Hunsecker, if you see him again they might...might kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is "they"?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'ANGELO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ask foolish questions.  Tell your brother I'm a sensible man. He understands only two things - power-politics and homage - tell him I came tonight to pay homage!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He retreats across the threshold of the bedroom, into the outer room.</context>
      <utterance>Where's J.J.?</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME SUSAN AND SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She walks forwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He isn't here...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan comes out of the bedroom, walks past CAMERA.</context>
      <utterance>But he called and said...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He studies the girl, says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>No, I called...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a tone of great despair in her voice. Presently, she recovers, CAMERA eases back to include Sidney beyond. She glances at him.</context>
      <utterance>He's...unconscious...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I...I gave Steve up...  Why did you and J.J. do it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, get a good night's sleep - tomorrow's another day. Feeling sorry for yourself won't help.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about Steve, not myself. I'm even sorry for my brother. To be so lonely, without one real friend in the world - to have to hang on to a worthless rag of a girl like me because she's his only real family -</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>Come on now, chickie, why don't you go to bed...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're going down with the ship.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm sorry for you, too, Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks past him, still aimlessly wandering about the room; then she turns back, indicates herself.</context>
      <utterance>What ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She studies Sidney.</context>
      <utterance>THIS ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you know how my brother will see you after tonight? You'll be the man who drove his little stainless sister to suicide...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RESUME SUSAN AND SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He strides back towards her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susie, whatever problems you have with J.J. - I didn't invent them! What're you blaming me for? If you learned to let out your hatred you would be better off!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah! Like me! I don't choke on my own gall - I fight back! Let THEM choke, not me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a man, Sidney, I'm -</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that bit - you're a girl; you need a man to give you strength! So what do you pick such weak sisters for? Don't you know yet that you fight fire with fire, not with tear drops?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could almost forgive you if what you did to Steve came from jealousy and love...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't do anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves past him. He grips her, turning her around.</context>
      <utterance>...but you did it for greed, Sidney - and that's pathetic.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't run away - I was always the man for you! I'm talking to you out of two years of silence - listen to what I say! Inside of six months -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan makes no move. Hunsecker glances at her, sees Sidney but treats Sidney as if he were invisible.</context>
      <utterance>Go to bed, Susie. It's late...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan walks towards Hunsecker.</context>
      <utterance>What is he doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sidney moves forward also.</context>
      <utterance>I called him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker studies the item in the paper.</context>
      <utterance>That subject it might be better not to start me on.  He's made all the papers tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there something you wanted to say...?  I've put up with a lot of your guff, Susie, because you were a child. But you're a woman now and I suspect, despite my best intentions, more than a bit of a slut...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her head comes up sharply at the insult.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>J.J., if you think -</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't explain, Sidney... It doesn't matter now...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose arms will I have to pry you out of next? Not that I don't think you didn't invite it! I know that look of yours, that pose of being wronged - and how it arouses the crusading instinct in even a Sidney Falco - Hunsecker's rising tide of brutality is having some effect on Susan, and Sidney, fearing for her, tries to intervene.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was trying to build her up, not tear her down -</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that why you were romancing her, you mutt!  Let's call it quits, my dear. I'd like it fine if you found another home. That means the front door is open! Pack your things, rent a moving van and GIT!  And as for marriage, let me hit you with a few choice facts: you aren't ready for marriage! You're incompetent - a capricious and shaky frail with a sick fatality for frail and useless men! Susan is staring sightlessly at the floor near Hunsecker's feet. After a moment she turns and moves to the door of her bedroom; her walk is a little unsteady; she goes inside, closes the door in Hunsecker's face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Much more concerned with his anxiety for Susan, Sidney interrupts.</context>
      <utterance>Now we'll get to you, Sidney.  As far as the column is concerned - tonight you have forfeited every ethical consideration I ever felt for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, J.J., I'll grant you anything you want.  Susie's off her rocker tonight! Go in and see what she's doing! Go in and talk to her quietly - unless you want a corpse! Sidney's conviction is impressive. But Hunsecker is unwilling to admit the danger, he continues.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a cornball you are, Sidney... CAMERA TRACKS to include Sidney. He does not share Hunsecker's confidence; he knocks again, calling:</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(in growing fear)</context>
      <utterance>Susie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! NO! Don't touch me!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Susan strikes at him, a vicious gesture of revulsion. Hunsecker lets her go. She falls into the arm chair, her face hidden from him; she begins to sob.</context>
      <utterance>Susan!...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunsecker would like to comfort her, but he dare not touch her again for fear of inviting another rebuff. He is deeply hurt and wounded. Embarrassed that Sidney should watch this moment, Hunsecker rises. To cover his emotion, he walks to the tray of drinks in background; he pours a brandy and comes back. Stooping, he offers it to Susan. Her only reaction is again to wrench herself away from him, facing the opposite direction.</context>
      <utterance>Go away!...Go away!...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk to her, Sidney...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Over scene the telephone rings. It is ignored. While Hunsecker looks down at the girl, helplessly, the telephone continues to ring.</context>
      <utterance>Talk to her yourself...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Presently, she hangs up. When she becomes aware that Hunsecker and Sidney are waiting for an explanation, she tells them:</context>
      <utterance>Yes...yes...yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steve...is out of danger...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hunsecker nods. He already knows this. Then:</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That means a lot to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA FOLLOWS Hunsecker. It now takes in Sidney who is standing beside him. Sidney has begun to stare fixedly at Hunsecker. (He is now realizing that Hunsecker, although he has been faced with this demonstration of the girl's willingness to kill herself, has still learned nothing, is still continuing in the old pattern.)</context>
      <utterance>But I have to warn you, Susie - for your own sake - he'll still do time...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a hop-head - that's a felony in New York. I can try, of course, to...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A CLOSE UP. Revolted, Sidney breaks in:</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're unholy, J.J.! You'd rather kill this girl than let her go!</utterance>
   <speaker>GROUP SHOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hunsecker wheels on Sidney, bellowing:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen with care - this will cost me everything, so you know I'm telling you the truth!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're incapable of the truth...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During the latter part of the speech, Susan rises slowly to her feet, staring first at Sidney and then, with fearful significance, at her brother. Hunsecker does not look at her; he is concentrated on Sidney. Twice he has been about to demolish Sidney, but he now stops, A THOUGHT IN HIS HEAD.</context>
      <utterance>Susie, there's nothing wrong with Dallas!  Your brother and I arranged it all. And if the Leslie boy is still a squooshy item in your life, forget it! - your brother arranged that one, too! I don't usually give away presents; but this is my gift to you: Get out of here! Leave this man!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is perfectly controlled, smiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like most Italians, Sidney's got a big gift for dramatics. I, however, prefer the cool and stubborn facts. Sidney has not appeared in my column in weeks - check that fact with Mary. That leads right to another fact: Sidney had nothing to lose tonight! To the contrary, dear - ONLY HIS OBVIOUS GREED TO</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind you, not that one true fact didn't come out of Sidney's mouth tonight: self-admittedly, he committed a vicious crime of jealousy against Steve Dallas!  Now we have to clear Dallas, don't we?...But I'll have to sacrifice him...  ...to do it.  Am I doing right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is looking at Hunsecker.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Slowly, Susan nods.</context>
      <utterance>Yes or no, Susie...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. Sidney moves closer to her.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, he's sick and you're the only idiot alive who didn't know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are some tears of pity in Susan's eyes. Once more she moves away from Sidney. Sidney senses that her compassion for Hunsecker might easily lead her once again to slip back into the trap. He insists:</context>
      <utterance>But what are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another pause. Sidney again repeats:</context>
      <utterance>You don't owe your brother a cup of water!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves away from Sidney, CAMERA following her. After a moment, she answers:</context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to Steve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...He's been trying to make my sister behind my back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAFE ON BROADWAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kello is in a phone booth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan turns squarely to face him.</context>
      <utterance>- but it's about time you had a new one.</utterance>
   <speaker>RESUME SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She braces herself to tell him:</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving, J.J.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi!  I just been on the phone to J.J. Kello's manner is almost affectionate. He shakes his head, admonishing Sidney.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been a bad boy, Sidney. J.J.'s going to write about you in his column tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIDNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought he would.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...  And another thing - he's gonna say you 'resisted arrest'...  You know J.J....! Sidney turns away to look back towards Phil. Then, taking Kello totally by surprise, he wheels, striking the cop viciously across the mouth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="159" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA MOVES CLOSER. It is at a low level, still emphasizing the man's dignity. He strolls for a few paces.</context>
      <utterance>Susie?  Are you in bed...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA has now moved so that we are shooting past Hunsecker onto Susan's door. He gets no answer except silence.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have to tell you, of course, that I cleared your boyfriend's name; I didn't let you down...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="160" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A pause. Then, very tentatively, the bedroom door is opened.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting the Mayor to perform the ceremony and - NO, I think I'll fly the Governor down from Albany...  Do you hear...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNSECKER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Now he opens the door and comes in.</context>
      <utterance>Are you listening?...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
