<movie id="547" title="Taxi Driver">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No trouble with the Hack Bureau?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got your license?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why do you want to be a taxi driver?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't sleep nights.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's porno theatres for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PERSONNEL OFFICER, though officious, is mildly probing and curious. TRAVIS is a cipher, cold and distant. He speaks as if his mind doesn't know what his mouth is saying.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I tried that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So whatja do now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ride around nights mostly. Subways, buses. See things. Figur'd I might as well get paid for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A thin smile cracks almost indiscernibly across TRAVIS' lips.</context>
      <utterance>We don't need any misfits around here, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kiddin? Who else would hack through South Bronx or Harlem at night?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to work uptown nights?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll work anywhere, anytime. I know I can't be choosy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's your driving record?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clean. Real clean.  As clean as my conscience.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, son, you gonna get smart, you can leave right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, sir. I didn't mean that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Physical? Criminal?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Age?</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-six.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Education?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some. Here and there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Military record?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honorable discharge. May 1971.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You moonlightin?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I want long shifts.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We hire a lot of moonlighters here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, we ain't that much fussy anyway. There's always opening on one fleet or another.  Fill out these forms and give them to the girl at the desk, and leave your phone number. You gotta phone?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PERSONNEL OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well then check back tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A MAN IN BUSINESS SUIT hails Travis to the curb.</context>
      <utterance>I'm working a single now, which means stretch-shifts, six to six, sometimes six to eight in the a.m., six days a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>MAN IN BUSINESS SUIT, now seated in back seat, speaks up:</context>
      <utterance>It's a hustle, but it keeps me busy. I can take in three to three-fifty a week, more with skims.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should it be grounded?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN BUSINESS SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You can't see it for the fog!</context>
      <utterance>Listen - I mean I just saw the needle of the Empire State Building.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it's a good guess it's grounded.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN BUSINESS SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Empire State in fog means something, don't it? Do you know, or don't you? What is your number, cabbie?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you tried the telephone?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN BUSINESS SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There isn't time for that. In other words, you don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAN IN BUSINESS SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS pulls to the curb. The BUSINESS MAN stuffs a dollar bill into the pay drawer and jumps out of the cab. He turns to hail another taxi.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you should know, damn it, or who else would know? Pull over right here.  Why don't you stick your goddamn head out of the goddamn window once in a while and find out about the goddamn fog!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN IN BUSINESS SUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis writes up his trip card and drives away. It is LATER THAT NIGHT. The rain has turned to drizzle. Travis drives trough another section of Manhattan.</context>
      <utterance>Taxi! Taxi!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>STREETSIDE: TRAVIS' P.O.V. Black PROSTITUTE wearing white vinyl boots, leopard-skin mini-skirt and blond wig hails taxi. On her arm hangs half-drunk seedy EXECUTIVE TYPE. TRAVIS pulls over. PROSTITUTE and JOHN climb into back seat. TRAVIS checks out the action in rear view mirror.</context>
      <utterance>I work the whole city, up, down, don't make no difference to me - does to some.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONTD</mode>
      <context>GRUNTS, GROANS coming from back seat. HOOKER and JOHN going at it in back seat. He's having a hard time and she's probably trying to get him to come off manually.</context>
      <utterance>Some won't take spooks - Hell, don't make no difference tom me. TRAVIS' taxi drives through Central Park.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh baby, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSTITUTE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>It's EARLY MORNING: 6 a.m. The air is clean and fresh and the streets nearly deserted. EXT. of TAXI GARAGE. TRAVIS' taxi pulls into the driveway.</context>
      <utterance>They're all animals anyway. All the animals come out at night: Whores, skunk pussies, buggers, queens, fairies, dopers, junkies, sick, venal.  Someday a real rain will come and wash all this scum off the streets.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONTD</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Each night when I return the cab to the garage I have to clean the come off the back seat. Some nights I clean off the blood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JUDSON 2-3410</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>AND MUST FILE A REPORT Promptly</utterance>
   <speaker>1ST CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... hadda piss like a bull steer, so I pull over on 10th Ave, yank up the hood and do the engine job.  There I am with my dong in my hand when a guy come up and asks if I need any help. Just checking the battery, I says, and, meanwhile...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>2ND CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he thinks I'm going up into The Jungle this time of night, he can shove it.</utterance>
   <speaker>3RD CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck that Violets First. Fucking saddle horse. No, no, the OTB. Fuck them. No, it was TKR. TCR and I'da made seven fucking grand. Fuck them too. Alright, what about the second race?</utterance>
   <speaker>4TH CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis hands his trip sheet to a CAB OFFICIAL, nods slightly, turns and walks toward the door. OUTSIDE, TRAVIS walks pleasantly down Broadway, his hands in his jacket pockets. The sidewalks are deserted, except for diligent fruit and vegetable VENDORS setting up their stalls. He takes a deep breath of fresh air, pulls a white pill from his pocket, pops it into his mouth. Travis turns a corner, keeps walking. Ahead of him is a 24- hour PORNO THEATRE. The theatre, a blaze of cheap day-glow reds and yellows, is an offense to the clear, crisp morning air. The permanent lettering reads, &quot;Adam Theatre, 16mm Sound Features&quot;. Underneath, today's feature are hand- lettered: &quot;Six-Day Cruise&quot; and &quot;Beaver Dam&quot;. Travis stops at the box office, purchases a ticket, and walks in.</context>
      <utterance>Over at Love, this hooker took on the whole garage. Blew the whole fucking joint and they wouldn't even let her use the drinking fountain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CONCESSION GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis rests his elbow on the counter, looking at the Girl. He is obviously trying to be friendly - no easy task for him. God knows he needs a friend.</context>
      <utterance>Kin I help ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your name? My name is Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCESSION GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awh, come off it, Pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm serious, really...</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCESSION GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That what you want?</context>
      <utterance>Ya want me to call da boss? Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCESSION GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, it's alright. I'll have a big Coca-Cola - without ice - and a large buttered popcorn, and...  ... some of them chocolate covered malted milk balls... and ju-jukes, a box. They last.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCESSION GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have ju-jukes. We don't have Coca-Cola. We only got Royal Crown Cola.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCESSION GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis lays two dollar bills on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>That's a dollar forty-seven.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>12.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Male Voice yields to Travis' monotone narration.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twelve hours of work and I still cannot sleep. The days dwindle on forever and do not end.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom, come here a moment.  I think this canvas report is about ready to go out. Check it out with Andy, and if he okays if, have a copy made for the campaign headquarters in every county.  And don't forget to add the new photo releases.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The senator's white paper is almost ready, Bets. Should we wait for that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andy usually just sends those to the national media. The local press doesn't know what to do with a position paper until UPI and AP tell them anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we should try to get maximum coverage for this new mandatory welfare program. Push the issues.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First push the man, then the issue. Senator Palantine is first of all a dynamic man, an intelligent, interesting, fascinating man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You forgot sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't forget sexy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just didn't get around to it, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Tom, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, for Christsakes, you sound like you're selling... I don't know what... cars... not issues.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever wondered why CBS News has the highest ratings?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More people watch it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, forget it if you're not going to be serious,</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, c'mon, I'm listening. I was just...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just what?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy looks toward the street, then back at Tom.</context>
      <utterance>Kidding around... you know, fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe if you'd try thinking once in a while, you'd get somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With who?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy's attention is being distracted by something she sees across the street. She puts on her glasses and looks out across the street again.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, now. You want to know why CBS has the highest ratings? You their news is any different from NBC, ABC? It's all the same news. Same stories. Same order usually. What, you thought they had good news for people, right? You thought that's why people watched CBS? I'll tell you why people watch CBS. Cronkite. The man. You got it? Not the news, not the issues, the man. If Walter Cronkite told people to eat soap, they'd do it. We are selling cars, goddamn it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if Cronkite's so great, why don't we run him instead?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the last. The finish. Period. Some pople can learn. Some people can't. And you wonder why we never get serious----</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure we could run him. You realize he's already of his block association.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been noticing anything strange?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's that taxi driver across the street been staring at us?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What taxi driver?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That taxi driver. The one that's been sitting here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long has he been there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis' cold piercingly eyes Stare out from his cab parked across the street from Palantine Headquarters. He is like a lone wolf watching the warm campfires of civilization from a distance. A thin red dot glows from his cigarette. Tom exchanges Travis' gaze.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know - but it feels like a long time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not rouge. Blush-On, they call it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis appears at the door. He has to push aside the JUNKIES to enter without making physical contact - something Travis would not relish. He may be repulsed with these people and this place, but he is too much a part of this to let his feelings rise to the surface. Wizard gives Travis a perfunctory wave.</context>
      <utterance>The kind with a brush.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis straddles a seat at the table. Dough-Boy gives Travis something between a wink and an eye-twitch saying:</context>
      <utterance>Hey Wizard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's Blush-On. My wife uses it,</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis shrugs and motions for a cup of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Ask Travis. He's the ladies man.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, whatever the fuck it is, she used it. And then the spray perfume. You know, the real sweat kind - and, on top of that, get this, right when we're crossing the Tri- boro bridge - she changes her pantyhose!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis turns his head. He appears not to be interested, but is.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you see anything?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she was trying to keep her skirt down, sort of, you know. But it was pretty obvious what she was doing. I mean, Christ, it was rush hour and the traffic's practically standing still.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Threw on the emergency, jumped the seat and fucked her brains out - What do you think!  What do I have to do? Draw you a picture?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was I supposed to do? I was watching in the rear view. You know, just checkin' traffic.  So howsit?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some fleet driver for Bell just cut up. Just heard it on the radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WAITRESS brings Travis' coffee and a glass of water. He asks for a cheeseburger.</context>
      <utterance>Stick up?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. What do you think? She wanted to get out of the cab. I said Look, you're in the middle of the fucking bridge...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I said, Lady, please, we're on a bridge...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis awaits Wizard's answer.</context>
      <utterance>And what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She stayed in the cab, what's she gonna do? but she stiffed me. A real skunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wizard realizes Travis and Dough-Boy may not have met.</context>
      <utterance>A real skunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Travis, you know Dough-Boy, Charlie</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(laughs)</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. We went to Harvard together.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We call him Dough-Boy cause he likes the dollars. He'll chase a buck straight into Jersey.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis sips his coffee. Charlie T.'s eyelids slip shut.</context>
      <utterance>Look who's talking?  Who else would stay up all night to catch the morning rush hour?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So howsit?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some fleet driver for Bell just got cut up. Just heard it on the radio.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stick up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, just some crazy fucker. Cut have his ear off.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis' eyes turn toward the restaurant's other patrons. POV: THREE STREET PEOPLE sitting at a table. One GUY, stoned, stares straight ahead. A raggedly attractive GIRL rest her head on the shoulder of the other, a heavily bearded YOUNG MAN with a headband. They kiss and tease each other, momentarily lost in their separate world. Travis watches the hippie couple closely, his feeling sharply divided between cultural contempt and morose jealousy. Why should these people enjoy the love and intimacy that has always eluded him? He must enjoy these schizoid emotions, because his eyes dwell on the couple.</context>
      <utterance>In the jungle. 122nd.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You run all over town, don't you, Travis?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis turns back to his companions.</context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' Mau Mau land, that's what it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, you handle some pretty rough traffic, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You carry a piece? You need one?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah.  I suppose not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you ever need one, I know a feller that kin getcha a real nice deal. Lotsa shit around.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis drops two Alka-Seltzer into his glass of water.</context>
      <utterance>The cops and company raise hell they find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truck drivers bring up Harlem Specials that blow up in your hand. But this guy don't deal no shit. Just quality. If you ever need anything, I can put you in touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a fee.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a fee.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never use mine. But it's a good thing to have. Just as a threat.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>well, if there's this many hackies inside, there must be lots of hares outside. And I'm gonna hustle 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What ya gonna do with all that money, Dough-Boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Support my kids. Can you dig it?  nice to meet ya, Travis. So long, Wizard. Say hello to Malcolm X for me.  Charlie T. remains unmoved: He is sleeping.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try holding the match like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is gotta be a game, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This I gotta see.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm great. Always set my fingers on fire. If you want to see another trick. I do this thing with my nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I just wanted to see if you could light it that way. The guy at the newsstand can.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, yes, the guy at the newsstand, Mr. Asbestos...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He happens to be missing fingers. I first noticed when -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he Italian?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, why?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure he's not Italian?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's Black, OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, If he had been Italian, they could have been shot off. Sometimes the mob does that to teach guys a lesson, If they blow a job or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As I said, he isn't Italian. Besides, I thought they just killed them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's symbolic.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be naive. They can't kill everybody. They have different punishments for different things. Like, if they kill a stool pidgeon, they leave a canary on the body.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't they leave a pidgeon instead of a canary?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Maybe they don't leave a canary. Don't be technical. What I'm saying is if this newsstand guy's Italian and his fingers are gone, maybe he's a thief.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First, he's not Italian. Second he's not a thief. I noticed the fingers when he was getting my change - the right change. Two of his fingers are missing. Just stubs. Like they were blown away. I was putting my change in my purse when I saw him get out a cigarette. I couldn't help watching. I was dying to see how he'd light it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the other hand, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, stupid. With the stubs. That's the whole point.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that guy. His hand looks like a paw. An old Black guy, the newsstand at -</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, this is young - well, I'm never sure how old Black people are - but, anyway, he isn't old. That's for sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show me how he did that again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the CAMERA examines Travis' face more closely, one can see the hollowness wrought by lack of sleep and sufficient diet.</context>
      <utterance>I want to volunteer.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis elbows Tom off.</context>
      <utterance>If you'll come this way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I want to volunteer to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BETSY waves TOM off with a short gesture, indicating everything is OK. He walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Bets.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS is on his best behavior. He smiles slightly:</context>
      <utterance>And why is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BETSY is momentarily taken back, but pleased. TRAVIS' presence has a definite sexual charge. He has those star qualities BETSY looks for: She senses there is something special about the young man who stands before her. And then, too, there is that disarming smile. He is, as Betsy would say, &quot;fascinating&quot;.</context>
      <utterance>Because you are the most beautiful woman I have ever seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that so?  But what do you think of Charles Palantine?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who mam?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charles Palantine. The man you want to volunteer to help elect president.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Make a great, great President.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I think he's a wonderful man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to canvass?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, mam.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This takes TRAVIS back a bit. He obviously doesn't have the slightest idea what Palantine's stand on welfare is, in fact, he doesn't have any idea about politics whatsoever. TRAVIS thinks a moment, then improvises an answer:</context>
      <utterance>How do you feel about Senator Palantine's stand on welfare?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy does a subtle double-take: This isn't exactly Palantine's position on welfare. She remain intrigued by Travis.</context>
      <utterance>Welfare, mam? I think the Senator's right. People should work for a living. I do. I like to work. Every day. Get those old coots off welfare and make 'em work for a change.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's not exactly what the Senator has proposed. You might not want to canvass, but there is plenty more other work we need done: Office work, filing, poster hanging.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a good worker, Betsy mam, a real good worker.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>if you talk to Tom, he'll assign you to something.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't mind, mam, I'd rather work for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we're all working tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Betsy mam, I drive a taxi at night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then, what is it you exactly want to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy doesn't quite know what to make of Travis. She is curious, intrigued, tantalized. Like a moth, she draws closer to the flame.</context>
      <utterance>If you don't mind, mam, I'd be mighty pleased if you'd go out and have some coffee and pie with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis rarely smiles, but when he does his whole face glows. It is as if he is able to tap an inner reserve of charm unknown even to himself. Betsy is completely disarmed.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Betsy mam, I drive by this place here in my taxi many times a day. And I watch you sitting here at this big long desk with these telephones, and I say to myself, that's a lonely girl. She needs a friend. And I'm gonna be her friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll be there to protect you.</context>
      <utterance>It's just to the corner, mam. In broad daytime. Nothing can happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right.  All right. I'm taking a break at four o'clock. If you're here then we'll go to the corner and have some coffee and pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I appreciate that, Betsy mam. I'll be here at four o'clock exactly.  And... ah... Betsy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis nods, turns and exits. Tom, who has been watching this interchange with a pseudo- standoffish (actually jealous) air, steps over to Betsy. His manner demands some sort of explanation of what Betsy was doing. Betsy simply shrugs (it's really none of his business) and says:</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just going to find out what the cabbies are thinking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've signed up 15.000 Palantine volunteers in New York so far. The organizational problems are becoming just staggering.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis contorts his mouth to match his mispronunciation, than breaks into a big, friendly, infectious grin. The very sight of it makes one's heart proud. Betsy cannot help but be caught up in Travis' gin. Travis' contagious, quicksilver moods cause:</context>
      <utterance>I know what you mean. I've got the same problems. I just can't get things organized. Little things, I mean. Like my room, my possessions. I should get one of those signs that says, One of these days I'm Gonna Organezizied.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Travis, I never ever met anybody like you before.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can believe that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you live?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It ain't much.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, uptown. You know. Some joint.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why did you decide to drive a taxi at night?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a regular job for a while, days. You know, doin' this, doin' that. But I didn't have anything to do at night. I got kinda lonely, you know, just wandering around. So I decided to works nights. It ain't good to be alone, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After this job, I'm looking forward to being alone for a while.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well...  In a cab you get to meet people. You meet lotsa people. It's good for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of people?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just people people, you know. Just people.  Had a dead man once.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'd been shot. I didn't know that. He just crawled into the back seat, said West 45th Street and conked out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shot the meter off, for one thing. I knew I wasn't goimg to get paid. Then I dropped him off at the cop shop. They took him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's really something.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you see lots of freaky stuff in a cab. Especially when the moon's out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The moon?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy laughs. Travis continues:</context>
      <utterance>The full moon. One night I had three or four weirdoes in a row and I looked up and, sure enough, there it was - the full moon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy cuts Travis' bitterness short:</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. People will do anything in front of a taxi driver. I mean anything. People too cheap to rent a hotel room, people scoring dope, people shooting up, people who want to embarrass you.  It's like you're not even there, not even a person. Nobody knows you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I take lots of taxis.</context>
      <utterance>Com'on, Travis. It's not that bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I could have picked you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Late one night. About three. At the plaza.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three in the morning? I don't think so. I have to go to bed early. I work days. It must have been somebody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy, realizing Travis remembers her precisely, scrambles for a polite rationale for her behavior:</context>
      <utterance>No. It was you. You had some manila folders and a pink bag from Saks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right! Now I remember! It was after the Western regional planners were in town and the meeting went late. The next day I was completely bushed. It was unbelievable.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it wasn't for a drunk I would have picked you up. He wanted to go to the DMZ.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The DMZ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>South Bronx. The worst. I tried to ditch him, but he was already in the cab, so I had to take him. That's the law. Otherwise I would have picked you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would have been quite a coincidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be surprised how often you see the same people, get the same fare. People have patterns. They do more or less the same things every day. I can tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't go to the Plaza every night.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean you. But just ordinary people. A guy I know - Dough-Boy - met his wife that way. They got to talking. She said she usually caught the bus so he started picking her up at the bus stop, taking her home with the flag up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's very romantic. Some of your fares must be interesting. See any stars, politicians, deliver any babies yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, no... not really... had some famous people in the cab.  I got this guy who makes lasers. Not regular lasers, not the big kind. Little lasers, pocket sized, small enough to clip your belt like a transistor radio, like a gun, you know. Like a ray gun. Zap.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What hours do you work?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I work a single, which means there's no replacement - no second man on the cab. Six to six, sometimes eight. Seventy-two hours a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean you work seventy-two hours a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes 76 or 80. Sometimes I squeeze a few more hours in the morning. Eighty miles a day, a hundred miles a night.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be rich.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>it keeps ya busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what you remind me of?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(smiles)</context>
      <utterance>That song by Kris Kristofferson, where it's said Like a pusher, party truth, partly ficition, a walking contradiction.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm no pusher, Betsy. Honest. I never have pushed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean that, Travis. Just the part about the contradiction.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Who was that again?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The singer?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yes. I don't follow music too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis looks at Betsy intently and they exchange smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Kris Kristofferson.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Travis' thoughts are with Betsy, as THREE MEN enter Travis' cab. He activates the meter and pulls off.</context>
      <utterance>I called Betsy again at her office, and she said maybe we could go to a movie together after she gets off work tomorrow. That's my day off. At first she hesitated, but I called her again and she agreed.  Betsy. Betsy what? I forgot to ask her last name again. Damn. I've got to remember stuff like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis checks the mirror. Scanning across the back seat, he recognizes the middle passenger. It is CHARLES PALANTINE, candidate for President. He must have left the Hotel shortly after BETSY. Tom, seated on the jump seat, checks his watch and speaks deferentially to Palantine:</context>
      <utterance>St. Regis Hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Palantine nods as his assistant picks up the thread of an earlier conversation.</context>
      <utterance>It's 12:30 now. You'll have fifteen minutes before the actual luncheon begins.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis recognizes his passenger. He puts out his cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think we have to worry about anybody here committing themselves until things start coming in from California.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, aren't you Charles Palantine, the candidate?</utterance>
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm one of your biggest supporters. I tell everybody that comes in this cab that they should vote for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, thank you Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you'll win, sir. Everybody I know is going to vote for you.  I was going to put one of your stickers on my taxi but the company said it was against their policy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you, Travis, I've learned more about this country sitting in taxi cabs than in the board room of General Motors.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Travis, what single thing would you want the next President of this country to do most?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, sir. I don't follow political issues much.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There must be something...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he should clean up this city here. It's full of filth and scum. Scum and filth. It's like an open sewer. I can hardly take it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Palantine is not a Hubert Humphrey-type professional bullshitter, and Travis' intense reply stops him dead in his tracks. He is forced to fall back on a stock answer but tries to give it some meaning.</context>
      <utterance>Some days I go out and smell it then I get headaches that just stay and never go away. We need a President that would clean up this whole mess. Flush it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what you mean, Travis, and it's not going to be easy. We're going to have to make some radical changes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn straight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't have to spend your money - ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy notices that the seal on the record has not been broken.</context>
      <utterance>He'll, what else can I do with it all?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Travis, you haven't even played the record?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well my stereo player is broke. But I'm sure the record is OK.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your stereo broke? God, I could hardly stand that. I live on music.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't follow music much. I'd like to though.  Honest.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you haven't heard this record yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(sly smile) I thought maybe you could play it for me on your player. Betsy's face backtracks a bit. Maybe she was wrong to go out with this fellow she doesn't know. She makes a polite laugh. LATER. Travis and Betsy are in TIMES SQUARE, turning the corner from Broadway to 42nd Street. Travis carries the album under his arm. They approach the garish marquee of a large midtown porno theatre advertising &quot;The Swedish Marriage Manual&quot;. The box office is flanked on both sides by glass cages filled with explicit publicity stills. Offending portions have been blocked out with black tape. Travis steps over to the window and buys two $5 tickets. Betsy, befuddled, watches him. She doesn't know what to say. Travis returns with the tickets. Betsy still has not fully comprehended what is happening:</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bought a couple of tickets.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this is a porno movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Honest. I've seen them.</context>
      <utterance>No, these are the kind that couples go to. They're not like the other movies. All kinds of couples go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That does it. Betsy just looks at him for a moment, then gets up and starts to leave. Travis, confused, hustles after her. He follows her out of the theatre.</context>
      <utterance>I forgot to get the Coca-Cola.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy looks at Travis, trying to understand him:</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are not the kind of movies I go to.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't follow movies too much...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TICKET GIRL watches expressionlessly from the booth.</context>
      <utterance>You mean these are the only kind of movies you go to?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is sort of high class...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean porno movies.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... mostly...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis gestures toward the long row of 42nd Street marquees, but is interrupted by Betsy:</context>
      <utterance>We can go to another movie if you like, I don't care. I got money. There's plenty...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you just wanted to fuck, why didn't you just come right out and say it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... there's plenty of movies around here. I haven't seen any of them, but I'm sure they're good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm going home.</context>
      <utterance>No, Travis. You're a sweet guy and all that, but I think this is it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean you don't want to go to a movie?  There's plenty of movies around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't feel so good. We're just two very different kinds of people, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's very simple. You go your way, I'll go mine. Thanks anyway, Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But... Betsy...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks to the curb.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting a taxi.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the record?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I call you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>45.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betsy looks for a cab.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy looks at his sad, sweet face and relents a bit.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Betsy, I bought it for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy accepts the record, but quickly turns and hails a taxi.</context>
      <utterance>All right, I'll accept the record.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis feebly protests to no one in particular:</context>
      <utterance>Taxi! A taxi quickly pulls up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Betsy gives instructions to CAB DRIVER, looks briefly back at Travis, then straight ahead. Taxi speeds off. Travis looks around helplessly: A cluster of PEDESTRIANS on the crowded street has stopped to watch the argument. Travis looks back at the woman in the porno theatre box office who has also been following the argument.</context>
      <utterance>But I got a taxi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We hear Travis' Voice on the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I tried to call her several times.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>you feeling better? You said you didn't feel so good...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Travis holds the receiver in his hand. The other party has hung up. TRACKING SHOT across interior lower wall of TRAVIS' APARTMENT. Against the stark wall there is a row of wilted and dying floral arrangements. Each one of the four or five bouquets is progressively more wilted than the one closer to the door. They have been returned.</context>
      <utterance>But after the first call, she would no longer come to the phone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A drama is acted out at PALANTINE HEADQUARTERS: Travis, groggy and red-eyed from lack of sleep, walks into the campaign headquarters about NOONTIME. Betsy is standing near the rear of the office; she ducks from sight when she sees Travis enter. Travis' path is cut short by Tom's large-framed body. There is no live sound.</context>
      <utterance>I also sent flowers with no luck. I should not dwell on such things, but set them behind me. The smell of the flowers only made me sicker. The headaches got worse I think I've got stomach cancer. I should not complain so. You're only as healthy as you feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Travis tries to push his way past Tom but Tom grabs him. Travis says something sharply to Tom and the two scuffle. Tom, by far the taller and stronger, quickly overcomes Travis, wrenching his arm behind his back. Travis kicks and protests as Tom leads him to the front door.</context>
      <utterance>I realize now how much she is like the others, so cold and distant. Many people are like that. They're like a union.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm off duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSIONAL PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean you don't want to go out to Jackson Heights?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm off duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSIONAL PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how come your Off Duty light wasn't on. TRAVIS switches on the Off Duty light.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(gesturing toward top of taxi) it just takes a while to warm up. Like a TV. TRAVIS doesn't budge. PROFESSIONAL PASSENGER curses to himself and exits cab. Travis takes off. POV as Travis' eyes dwell on the young HIP COUPLES coming out of a East Side movie house. LATER THAT NIGHT, TRAVIS pulls over for a young (mid- twenties) MAN wearing a leather sports jacket. TRAVIS eyes his passenger in rear-view mirror.</context>
      <utterance>It was on.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>471 Central Park West.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LATER, TRAVIS' taxi slows down as it approaches 400 block of Central Park West. Travis checks apartment numbers.</context>
      <utterance>TRAVIS' taxi speeds off.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS turns the wheel.</context>
      <utterance>Just pull over to the curb a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's fine. Just sit here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>YOUNG PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA CLOSES IN on 417 Central Park West: TRACKING UP to the seventh floor, it moves three windows to the right.</context>
      <utterance>Cabbie, ya see that light up there on the seventh floor, three windows from this side of the building?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A young WOMAN wearing a slip crosses in front of the light.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya see that woman there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>C.U. TRAVIS' face: it is devoid of expression.</context>
      <utterance>That's my wife.  But it ain't my apartment.  A nigger lives there.  She left me two weeks ago. It took me this long to find out where she went.  I'm gonna kill her.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>C.U. YOUNG PASSENGER's face: it is gaunt, drained of blood, full of fear and anger. Travis does not respond.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think of that, cabbie?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis shrugs, gesturing toward meter.</context>
      <utterance>Huh?  What do you think of that, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>YOUNG PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA returns to SEVENTH FLOOR WINDOW. Woman is standing in the light.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna kill her with a .44 Magnum pistol.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Travis says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Did you ever see what a .44 can do to a woman's face, cabbie?  Did you ever see what it can do to a woman's pussy, cabbie?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG PASSENGER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CAMERA CLOSES IN on Travis' face: He is watching the woman in the seventh floor window with complete and total absorption. It's the same glazed-over stare we saw in his eyes as he watched the porno movie.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to put it right up to her, cabbie. Right in her, cabbie. You must think I'm real sick, huh? A real pervert. Sitting here and talking about a woman's pussy and a .44, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis nods as the taxi speeds off. Dough-Boy slows down near an economy hotel. Not a flop house, but not do fancy they care what the guests do in the privacy of their rooms.</context>
      <utterance>Hello Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis pulls a twenty out of his pocket and gives it to Dough-Boy.</context>
      <utterance>This is fine, Dough-Boy  Pay Dough-Boy here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>20 bucks?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a .44 Magnum?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's an expensive gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy unzips a cowhide leather pouch to reveal a .44 Magnum pistol. He holds it gingerly, as if it were a precious treasure. Andy opens the chambers and cradles the long eight-inch barrel in his palm. The .44 is a huge, oversize inhuman gun.</context>
      <utterance>I got money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could sell this gun in Harlem for $500 today - but I just deal high quality goods to high quality people.  Now this may be a little big for practical use, in which case I'd recommend the .38 Smith and Wesson Special. Fine solid gun - nickel plated. Snub-nosed, otherwise the same as the service revolver. Now that'll stop anything that moves and it's handy, flexible.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Travis hefts the nickel-plated .38, points it out the window.</context>
      <utterance>The Magnum, you know, that's only if you want to splatter it against the wall. The movies have driven up the price of the Magnum anyway. Everybody wants them now. But the Wesson .38 - only $250 - and worth every dime of it.  Throw in a holster for $10.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of these guns are like toys, but a Smith and Wesson, man, you can hit somebody over the head with it and it will still come back dead on. Nothing beats quality.  You interested in an automatic?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want a .32. Revolver. And a palm gun. That .22 there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis holds the .32 Revolver, hefts it, slips it under his belt and pulls his shirt over it. He turns from side to side, to see how it rides in his waist.</context>
      <utterance>That's the Colt .25 - a fine little gun. Don't do a lot of damage, but it's as fast as the Devil. Handy little gun, you can carry it almost anywhere. I'll throw it in for another $125.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much for everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The .32's $150 - and you're really getting a good deal now - and all together it comes to, ah, seven eighty-five for four pieces and a holster. He'll, I'll give you the holster, we'll make it seventy-five and you've got a deal - a good one.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much to get a permit to carry?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're talking big money now. I'd say at least five grand, maybe more, and it would take a while to check it out. The way things are going now $5.000 is probably low. You see, I try not to fool with the small-time crap. Too risky, too little bread. Say 6 G's, but if I get the permit it'll be as solid as the Empire State Building.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, this'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't carry in a cab even with a permit - so why bother?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a firing range around?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis pulls out a roll of crisp one hundred dollar bills and counts off eight.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, here, take this card, go to this place and give 'em the card. They'll charge you, but there won't be any hassle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You in Nam? Can't help but notice your jacket?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis hands Andy the bills. Andy counts them and gives Travis a twenty and five.</context>
      <utterance>Vietnam? I saw it on your jacket. Where were you? Bet you got to handle a lot of weapons out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I was all around. One hospital, then the next.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pockets the money)</context>
      <utterance>It's he'll out there all right. A real shit-eatin' war. I'll say this, though: It's bringing a lot of fantastic guns. The market's flooded. Colt automatics are all over.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy pulls a gym bag from under his bed. He wraps the gun in the sheet in the bag and zips it up. An identical gym bag can be partially seen under the bed. He hands Travis the bag.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like ball games?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can get you front and center. What do you like? I can get you Mets, Knicks, Rangers? Hell, I can get you the Mayor's box.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy closes and locks the suitcases.</context>
      <utterance>Nah. I ain't interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis turns to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Travis, still bareback, passes his stiff arm through the flame of a gas burner without flinching a muscle.</context>
      <utterance>May 29, 1972. I must get in shape. Too much sitting has ruined my body. Twenty-five push-ups each morning, one hundred sit-ups, one hundred knee-bends. I have quit smoking.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Every muscle must be tight.</context>
      <utterance>Total organization is necessary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>LATER. TRAVIS, his shirt still revealing his bare chest, sits on his straight-backed chair watching the TV. The .44 Magnum rests on his lap. The TV is Broadcasting ROCK TIME, a late afternoon local teenage dance and rock show. On screen YOUNG TEENYBOPPERS are dancing, and the TV CAMERAMAN, as any devotee of the genre knows, is relentlessly ZOOMING-IN on their firm young breasts, fannies and crotches -- a sensibility which reflects TRAVIS' own. These supper-hour rock dance shows are the most unabashedly voyeuristic form of broadcasting the medium has yet developed. The HARD ROCK NUMBER ends, and the TV CAMERA CUTS TO the local DISC JOCKEY, a hirsute plastic-looking man about 35. FIVE scrumptious TEENYBOPPERS are literally hanging on his shoulders and arms, their faces turned up to him in droolish awe. Out of his mouth comes an incessant stream of disc jockey blather. He is the complete asshole; I don't know who is currently performing this function in New York, but in Los Angeles his name is Real Don Steele.</context>
      <utterance>My body fights me always. It won't work, it won't sleep, it won't shit, it won't eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>TV DISC JOCKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS watches the show, his face hard and unmoving. He is, as the Scriptures would say, pondering all these things in his heart. Why is it the assholes get all the beautiful young chicks? He takes a swig of peach brandy.</context>
      <utterance>Freshingly, fantastic, freaked-out dance time. Can you dig it? Dig on it. You got it, flaunt it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS moves to activate the meter, when the rear door opens. IRIS is helped out of the cab by a MAN TRAVIS cannot see.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, mister, let's get outta here -- quick.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS cannot see the Sport's face lime green completely, but notices he is wearing a jacket. The voice is that of a man in his early twenties. TRAVIS turns to catch a glimpse of Sport as he walks off with Iris. TRAVIS shrugs and turns around. TRAVIS' taxi pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>Just forget all about this, cabbie. It's nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FEMALE MOVIE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>TRAVIS averts his eyes as the action on screen becomes too graphic. Placing his stiffened right hand beside his eyes, TRAVIS can, by turning it inward, shut off or open up his field of vision by small degrees. MOVIE VOICE DIMINISHES, replaced by SOUND of TRAVIS' voice over.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on, now, down, lick it, come on...  Mmm, that's good. Ahh, ahh, more ...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The idea had been growing in my brain ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONTD</mode>
      <context>All the king's men cannot put it back together again. As the CAMERA reaches the end of its track, it finds TRAVIS, standing, his shirt open, but the mattress. He is wearing the empty holster, and the .44 is in his hand. In the SHOTS that follow TRAVIS gives the audience a lesson in gunmanship: TRAVIS practices fast-drawing the .38 Special from his holster and firing it. He hooks the .44 into his pants behind his back and practices withdrawing it. He holds the .44 firmly at an arm's length, tightening his forearm muscles. He has worked out a system of metal gliders taped to his inner forearm, whereby the Colt .25 can rest hidden behind the upper forearm until a spring near the elbow is activated, sending the .25 flying down the gliders into his palm. He has cut open his shirt to accomodate the gun mechanism and now checks in the mirror to see how well the gun is hidden. He straps an Army combat knife to his calf and cuts a slit in his jeans where the knife can be pulled out quickly. He now tries on various combinations of shirts, sweater and jacket in front of the mirror to see how well he can hide all the handguns he wishes to carry. Finally, wearing two western shirts, a sweater and jacket, he manages to obscure the location of all three guns, although he resembles a hunter bundled up against the Arctic winter. He sits at the table dum-dumming the .44 bullets -- cutting &quot;x's&quot; across the bullet heads. P.O.V.: he scans the objects of his room through the scope of the .38. TRAVIS stands in the middle of his apartment, staring at his PALANTINE wall. His eyes are glazed with introspection; he sees nothing but himself.</context>
      <utterance>... for some time. True Force.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONTD</mode>
      <context>TRAVIS lies on his mattress, all bundled up in his shirts, sweater, jacket and guns. His face is turned toward the ceiling, but his eyes are closed. Although the room is flooded with light, he is finally catching some sleep.</context>
      <utterance>Listen you screwheads: Here is a man ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>62.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The big furry animal drifts into his own world.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONTD</mode>
      <context>C.U. of diary: entry ends with words &quot;Here is&quot; followed by erratic series of dots.</context>
      <utterance>... who wouldn't take it any more, a man who stood up against the scum, the cunts, the dogs, the filth. Here is ...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spanish rhythm and blues blares from a cheap radio. TRAVIS walks over to dairy counter in rear of store, picks out a pint of chocolate milk, goes over to the open cooler and picks through various chilled prepackaged sandwiches. He overhears a VOICE as he looks at the sandwiches. When TRAVIS returns to the counter with the chocolate milk and a sandwich in one hand, he sees a YOUNG BLACK MAN holding a gun on 'Melio. The STICK-UP MAN is nervous, hopped-up, or both; he bounces on the balls of his cheap worn black tennis shoes -- a strung-out junkie on a desperation ride. The STICK-UP MAN, a thorough unprofessional, doesn't notice TRAVIS. 'MELIO watches the STICK-UP MAN closely, deciding what to do himself.</context>
      <utterance>Hey 'Melio.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey dude!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>'MELIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS sets his .32 on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, man. Figured I'd get him on the way out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna have to cover me on this one, 'Melio. I can't stay for the cop show.</utterance>
   <speaker>'MELIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do that, Travis. You're my witness.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>'MELIO smiles and holds up four fingers:</context>
      <utterance>The hell I can't. It's no sweat for you. What is this for you, number five?</utterance>
   <speaker>'MELIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, only four.  Alright, Travis, I'll do what I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS exits. 'MELIO picks up the phone and starts dialing. The bloody BODY lies on the floor unmoving. TRAVIS, still carrying his pint of chocolate milk and sandwich, walks down the empty sidewalk and enters his cab. The street is deserted.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks a lot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wizard demonstrates length of hair and others nod.</context>
      <utterance>You know Eddie, he's the new hippie kid in our group, long hair...</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...he called up the Dispatcher last night. Charlie McCall, our dispatcher...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One-Ball McCall?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cabbies laugh. Across the cafeteria Travis selects a cup of coffee and some pastries.</context>
      <utterance>That's the guy. Eddie calls him up and says, Hey, what do you want me to do. I'm over here at Poly Prep. I got a girl in the back and she doesn't have the fare. She wants me to come in back and collect. What should I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE T</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is on the two-way with about a hundred and fifty cars listenin in.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>meter?&quot; Eddie comes back and says &quot;Two-fifty.&quot; McCall says, &quot;Is she worth it&quot;. More laughter.</context>
      <utterance>McCall says. How much on the</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuckin One-Ball.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the kid says, Yeah. She's about 19, good-lookin. McCall says, What can I tell you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOURTH CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(laughter)</context>
      <utterance>She should have told him to get an OK from the front office.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McCall says, Well, if you want some help I'll see if I can send some units out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE T</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. About a hundred and fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope he had a checker.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Travis, carrying his coffee and pastries, walks over to their table. Charlie T spots him.</context>
      <utterance>She was just a kid. Stoned, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE T</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie forms his hand into a pistol, cocks and fires, making the SOUND, &quot;Pgghew.&quot; TRAVIS nods.</context>
      <utterance>Hiya Killer.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS sits down and the other CABBIES resume their conversation.</context>
      <utterance>You're getting a rep, Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE T</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS reaches into his pocket and pulls out a roll of small denomination bills. The crumpled $20 bill falls onto the table. TRAVIS stares at it a moment. He unfolds a five, gives it to CHARLIE T, then picks up the crumpled $20 and puts it back into his jacket pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Got the five you owe me, Killer?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the action around?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE T</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit yes. Night woulda been dead if I hadn't grabbed an outatowner at Kennedy. Took him roun the horn and got a five dollar tip to boot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of these days we're gonna turn you in, Charlie T. Fleecin the hicks like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember the time this cat picks up four dudes from the other side, Pakastanis I think they were, holds up their passports, to the toll booth collector on the bridge and charges em ten bucks each for 'crossing the border?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>68.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They all laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE T</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, I know'd you to do worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGH-BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Least I'm no airport rat. I work the whole town.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE T</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIZARD gets up to leave.</context>
      <utterance>It's a living.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIZARD gets up, nods and walks toward the CASHIER. After a second's thought, TRAVIS calls to him:</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm shovin' on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIZARD waits for TRAVIS as he takes a final gulp of coffee and catches up with him. CHARLIE T calls to TRAVIS as they go:</context>
      <utterance>Hey Wiz, just a second. I wanna talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE T</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHARLIE T cocks his imaginary gun again, fires and chuckles. WIZARD and TRAVIS nod goodbye, pay the CASHIER and exit.</context>
      <utterance>See ya, Killer. Don't forget your pea shooter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wiz?</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, ah, we never talked much, you and me...</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to ask you something, on account you've been around so long.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot. They don't call me the Wizard for nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I just, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things got ya down?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real down.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It happens.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes it gets so I just don't know what I'm gonna do. I get some real crazy ideas, you know? Just go out and do somethin.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The taxi life, you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like do anything, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A police car stops across the street. TWO PATROLMEN get out and roust the JUNKIE from his doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Travis, look, I dig it. Let me explain. You choose a certain way of life. You live it. It becomes what you are. I've been a hack 27 years, the last ten at night. Still don't own my own cab. I guess that's the way I want it. You see, that must be what I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, a person does a certain thing and that's all there is to it. It becomes what he is. Why fight it? What do you know? How long you been a hack, a couple months? You're like a peg and you get dropped into a slot and you got to squirm and wiggle around a while until you fit in.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's just about the dumbest thing I ever heard, Wizard.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you expect, Bertrand Russell? I've been a cabbie all my life, what do I know?  I don't even know what you're talking about.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither do I, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You got no choice.</context>
      <utterance>You fit in. It's lonely, it's rough at first. But you fit in.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Sorry, Wizard.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Killer. You'll be all right.  I seen enough to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WIZARD gives TRAVIS a short wave implying, &quot;Chin up, old boy,&quot; and walks around to the driver's side of his cab. WIZARD drives off, leaving the street to its natural inhabitants.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betsy, come over here a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it? I'm busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BETSY excuses herself and walks across the platform with TOM. As they stand to the rear of the platform, TOM secretively makes a gesture with his eyes and says out of the side of his mouth:</context>
      <utterance>Just follow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BETSY, putting on her glasses, looks closely. She tries not to make her stare too obvious.</context>
      <utterance>Look there.  No, over further - get your glasses - yes, over there. Isn't that little guy the same guy that was bugging you around the office about a month ago?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't think so.  That's someone else.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA CLOSES IN on TRAVIS BICKLE standing in the CROWD: he has shaved his head to a short stubble. There he is: brush- cut, wearing a giant grin, and a large &quot;Palantine '72&quot; button. Although it is a pleasant sunny day, TRAVIS wears a bulky bulged-out Army jacket. TRAVIS looks warily from side to side and vanishes in the</context>
      <utterance>Now look more closely. Look around the eyes and chin. See? See there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a Secret Service Man?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRET SERVICE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SECRET SERVICE MAN glances at TRAVIS momentarily.</context>
      <utterance>I've seen a lot of suspicious- looking people around here today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRET SERVICE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SECRET SERVICE MAN's gaze follows TRAVIS' finger for a second, then return to TRAVIS.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, lots. I don't know where they all are now. There used to be one standing over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONTD</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it hard to get to be a Secret Service Man?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRET SERVICE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I kinda thought I might make a good one. I'm very observant.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRET SERVICE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SECRET SERVICE MAN is starting to get interested in TRAVIS: he definitely ranks as a suspicious character.</context>
      <utterance>I was in the Army too.  And I'm good with crowds.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SECRET SERVICE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that so?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SECRET SERVICE MAN decides it's time to get some more information on TRAVIS:</context>
      <utterance>What kind of guns do you guys use? .38's?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRET SERVICE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, um, if you give me your name and address, we'll send you the information on how to apply.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You would, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRET SERVICE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Henry Krinkle -- that's with a K. K-R-I-N-K-L-E. I live at 13 1/2 Hopper Avenue, Fair Lawn, New Jersey. Zip code 07410.  Got that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRET SERVICE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, Henry. I got it all. We'll send you all the stuff all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SECRET SERVICE MAN motions to a SECRET SERVICE PHOTOGRAPHER to catch a picture of TRAVIS. TRAVIS notices this, and quickly slips away into the CROWD.</context>
      <utterance>Great, hey. Thanks a lot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, cabbie, you can't park here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>POLICEMAN leans his head in window, inspecting the cab. As he does, TRAVIS slides his right hand into the left side of his jacket, ready to draw his revolver.</context>
      <utterance>You waiting for a fare?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS starts up his taxi and drives off. LIVE SOUND again CEASES as TRAVIS resumes reading letter as taxi drives away. As TRAVIS reads final paragraph, scene CUTS TO INT. APARTMENT where TRAVIS sits at his table.</context>
      <utterance>All right, move it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>TRAVIS, at his desk, examines the card upon which he has just written this letter.</context>
      <utterance>I hope this card finds you all well, as it does me. I hope no one has died. Don't worry about me. One day there will be a knock on the door and it will be me. Love, Travis.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You looking for some action?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...I guess so.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You see that guy over there? (nods) His name is Sport. Go talk to him. I'll wait here. Travis' eyes follow Iris' nod until they reach Sport, standing in a doorway in his lime green jacket. Travis walks toward him. Sport, a thirtiesh white greaser, has the affections of a black pimp. His hips are jiving, his fingers softly snapping. He sings to him self, &quot;Going to the chapel, gonna get married...&quot; His complexion is sallow; his eyes cold and venal. He could only seem romantic to a confused underaged runaway.</context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sport immediately takes Travis for an undercover cop. He extends his crosses wrists as if to be handcuffed.</context>
      <utterance>You name Sport?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Honest, officer.</context>
      <utterance>Here, officer, take me in. I'm clean. I didn't do it. Got a ticket once in Jersey. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your name Sport?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything you say, officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm no cop.  I want some action.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw. $20 fifteen minutes. $30 half hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS digs in his pocket for money.</context>
      <utterance>Take it or leave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS turns to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>No, not me. There'll be an elderly gent to take the bread.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS freezes, not saying anything. He turns back toward</context>
      <utterance>Catch you later, Copper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm no cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if you are, it's entrapment already.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IRIS motions for TRAVIS to follow her and he does. IRIS and TRAVIS turn the corner and walk about a block, saying nothing. IRIS turns into a darkened doorway and TRAVIS follows her. At the top of the dark stairs IRIS and TRAVIS enter a dimly lit hallway. On either side are doors with apartment numbers. IRIS turns toward the first door, No. 2.</context>
      <utterance>Funny, you don't look hip.  TRAVIS walks back to IRIS.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS turns his head toward the OLD MAN who has stood up and is advancing toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey cowboy!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS hesitates a moment, uncertain what to do. The OLD MAN reaches in TRAVIS' jacket and pulls out the .38 Special.</context>
      <utterance>The rod.  Gimme the rod, cowboy.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS looks around IRIS' room: although dimly lit, the room is brightly decorated. There is an orange shag carpet, deep brown walls and an old red velvet sofa. On the walls are posters of Mick Jagger, Bob Dylan and Peter Fonda. A Neil Young album is playing on a small phonograph. This is where IRIS lives: it bears the individual touch of a young girl. IRIS lights a cigarette, takes a single puff and places it in an ashtray on the bedstand.</context>
      <utterance>This ain't Dodge City, cowboy. You don't need no piece.  I'm keepin' time. TRAVIS enters No. 2 with IRIS.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you hang around with them greasers?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A girl needs protection.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. From the likes of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your time mister. Fifteen minutes ain't long.  That cigarette burns out, your time is up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't much of a name.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's easy to remember. Easy Lay.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your real name?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like my real name.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your real name?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Iris.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a nice name.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IRIS unbuttons her shirt, revealing her small pathetic breasts -- two young doves hiding from a winter wind. TRAVIS is unnerved by her partial nudity.</context>
      <utterance>That's what you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IRIS buttons only the bottom button of her shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you remember me? Button your shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I drive a taxi. You tried to get away one night. Remember?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You tried to run away in my taxi but your friend -- Sport -- wouldn't let you.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(looks toward door)</context>
      <utterance>It don't matter. I'm gonna get you outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We better make it, or Sport'll get mad. How do you want to make it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to make it. I came here to get you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS pushes her hand away. He sits beside her on the edge of the bed.</context>
      <utterance>You want to make it like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you listen to me? Don't you want to get out of here?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should I want to get out of here? This is where I live.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're the one that wanted to get away. You're the one that came into my cab.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I musta been stoned.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do they drug you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IRIS tries to unzip TRAVIS' fly. This only unnerves TRAVIS more: sexual contact is something he's never really confronted.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, come off it, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IRIS works on TRAVIS' crotch OFF CAMERA. He bats her hand away.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you want to make it?  Can't you make it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS is getting increasingly panicked, but IRIS only thinks this is part of his particular thing and tries to overcome it.</context>
      <utterance>I want to help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IRIS lowers her head to go down on TRAVIS. TRAVIS, seeing this, jumps up in panic. TRAVIS stands several feet from IRIS. His fly is still open, and the white of his underwear shows through his jeans. He is starting to come apart.</context>
      <utterance>You can't make it, can you?  I can help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck it! Fuck it! Fuck it! Fuck it! Fuck it! Fuck it! Fuck it!</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can do it in my mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IRIS says nothing. After a moment, TRAVIS again sits on the bed beside IRIS. She no longer tries to make him.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you understand anything?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS rests a moment, collecting himself. Finally, he says:</context>
      <utterance>You don't have to make it, mister.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you understand why I came here?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so. I tried to get into your cab one night, and now you want to come and take me away.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you want to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can leave anytime I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that one night?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a pause. TRAVIS smiles and shrugs apologetically. TRAVIS looks at Iris' cigarette. It's burning down to the butt.</context>
      <utterance>I was stoned. That's why they stopped me. When I'm not stoned, I got no place else to go. They just protect me from myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I tried.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand, mister. It means something, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I see you again?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not hard to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean really. This is nothing for a person to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. All right. We'll have breakfast. I get up about one o'clock. Tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IRIS is interfering with TRAVIS' assassination schedule.</context>
      <utterance>Well tomorrow noon there's a... I got a...</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you want to or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS turns; IRIS smiles.</context>
      <utterance>O.K. It's a date. I'll see you here, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Iris?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name's Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS closes the door to No. 2 and stands in the corridor for a moment. The OLD MAN slowly walks from the dark end of the hallway with TRAVIS' .38 in his hand. OLD MAN stands near TRAVIS, and checks his watch.</context>
      <utterance>So long, Iris.  Sweet Iris.  TRAVIS exits.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think this is yours, cowboy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OLD MAN says as TRAVIS walks down stairs:</context>
      <utterance>Here's the twenty bucks, old man. You better damn well spend it right. TRAVIS turns and walks away.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS does not respond.</context>
      <utterance>Come back anytime you want, cowboy. But without the rod -- please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, at least it wasn't chicken.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't? I thought it was. It tasted like chicken.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Senator. That was a class dinner. The St. Regis is a class joint. That was veal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it? It sure tasted like chicken to me.  Lately, everything tastes like chicken to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything? Got to watch your gut.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about it? I took 20 off before we started this thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you've put ten of it back on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten? I don't think so. You really think so? Ten?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those TV cameras do. I caught the rally on CBS. You looked a little paunchy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Palantine gets up and walks over to the window. Its bars form a cross-sight on his head. He thinks to himself:</context>
      <utterance>I don't think I gained ten pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the crowded traffic on Fifth Avenue eighteen floors below. It is a mass of yellow.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and after that Sport and I just started hanging out...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Iris removes her large blue-tinted sunglasses and fishes through her bag for another pair.</context>
      <utterance>Where is home?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She finds a pink-tinted pair and puts them on.</context>
      <utterance>I got so many sunglasses. I couldn't live without my shades, man. I must have twelve pair of shades.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pittsburgh.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't ever been there, but it don't seem like such a bad place.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you want me to go back to my parents? They hate me. Why do you think I split? There ain't nothin there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you can't live like this. It's hell. Girls should live at home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Iris places a large gob of jam on her unbuttered toast and folds the bread over like a hotdog.</context>
      <utterance>Young girls are supposed to dress up, go to school, play with boys, you know, that kinda stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, you are square.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IRIS motions him to lower his voice.</context>
      <utterance>At least I don't walk the streets like a skunk pussy. I don't screw and fuck with killers and junkies.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's a killer?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That fella Sport looks like a killer to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He never killed nobody. He's a Libra.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a Libra too. That's why we get along so well.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks like a killer.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Cancer's make the best lovers. My whole family are air signs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He shoots dope too.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you so high and mighty? Did you ever look at your own eyeballs in a mirror. You don't get eyes like that from...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a brief silence. Iris mind continued to whirl at 78 rpms. She seems to have three subjects on her mind at a time. She welcomes this opportunity to unburden herself.</context>
      <utterance>He's worse than an animal. Jail's too good for scum like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rock music died in 1970, that's what I think. Before that it was fantastic. I can tell you that. Everybody was crashing, hanging out at the Fillmore. Me and my girlfriend Ann used to go up the fire escape, you know? It was unbelievable. Rock Stars everywhere. That Airplane--that's my group, man. All Libras. But now everybody's split or got sick or busted. I think I'll move to one of those communes in Vermont, you know? That's where all the smart ones went. I stayed here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never been to a commune. I don't know. I saw pictures in a magazine, and it didn't look very clean to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you come to a commune with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? I could never go to a place like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I don't get along with people like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You a scorpion? That's it. You're a scorpion. I can tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Besides, I've got to stay here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I can't leave.</context>
      <utterance>I've got something important to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so important?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cab thing is just part time.</context>
      <utterance>I can't say -- it's top secret. I'm doing something for the Army.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You a narc?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I look like a narc?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS breaks out in his big infectious grin, and IRIS joins his laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, I don't know who's weirder, you or me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do about Sport and that old bastard?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just leave'em. There's plenty of other girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just gonna leave 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should I do? Call the cops?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cops don't do nothin.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Never beat me up once.</context>
      <utterance>Sport never treated me bad, honest.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't leave 'em to do the same to other girls. You should get rid of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Just should, though.  Somebody should kill 'em. Nobody'd miss 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God. I know where they should have a commune for you. They should have a commune for you at Bellevue.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Iris. I didn't mean that.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not much with girls, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Iris, I look at it this way. A lot of girls come into my cab, some of them very beautiful. And I figure all day long men have been after them: trying to touch them, talk to them, ask them out. And they hate it. So I figure the best I can do for them is not bother them at all. So I don't say a thing. I pretend I'm not even there. I figure they'll understand that and appreciate me for it. It takes IRIS a moment to digest this pure example of negative thinking: I am loved to the extent I do not exist.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you really think I should go to the commune?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mumbling something about her &quot;shades&quot; again, Iris fishes through her bag until she comes up with another 99 pair of sunglasses and puts them on. She likes these better, she decides.</context>
      <utterance>I think you should go home, but otherwise I think you should go. It would be great for you. You have to get away from here. The city's a sewer, you gotta get out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you don't want to come with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. Otherwise, I would.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sure hate to go alone...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give you the money to go. I don't want you to take any from those guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to -- what else can I do with my money?  You may not see me again--for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE on C.U. of TRAVIS:</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My work may take me out of New York.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>IRIS' ROOM - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sport stands beside the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, baby, don't you feel right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>96.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Iris is wearing her blue-tinted shades.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sport puts his hand on her hips. He is slowly, carefully, smoothly manipulating her. It's the stone black hustle.</context>
      <utterance>It's my stomach. I got the flu.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, baby, there ain't no flu. You know that, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sport puts some slow soul music on the stereo.</context>
      <utterance>Honest, Sport.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sport slowly grinds his hips to hers. Iris starts to move with him. This is what she really wanted. Her man's attention.</context>
      <utterance>You're just tired, baby. You just need your man. I am your man, you know. You are my woman. I wouldn't be nothing without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sport slowly rubs his crotch into her. Iris smiles. She is happy. The music rises.</context>
      <utterance>I know this may not mean anything to you, baby, but sometimes I get so emotional, sometimes I think, I wish every man could have what I have now, that every woman could be loved the way I love you. I go home and I think what it would be without you, and then I thank God for you. I think to myself, man, you are so lucky. You got a woman who loves you, who needs you, a woman who keeps you strong. It's just you and me. I'm nothing without you. I can go like this for ever and ever. We can do it, baby. You and me. Just you and me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and with your help we will go on to victry at the polls Tuesday.  TRAVIS begins moving up into the crowd.</utterance>
   <speaker>PALANTINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONTD</mode>
      <context>PALANTINE steps back, smiling and receiving the applause. Then, nodding, at the SECRET SERVICE MAN he descends the stairs and prepares to work his way through the CROWD. TRAVIS unbuttons the middle two buttons of his jacket, opening access to his holster. With the other hand he checks the .44 hooked behind his back. PALANTINE smiles and shakes a few of the many hands outstretched toward him. The SECRET SERVICE MAN, scanning the CROWD, spots something that interests him. He looks closely. SECRET SERVICE MAN'S P.O.V.: TRAVIS, his face intense, pushes his way through the CROWD. PALANTINE works his way through crowds and cameras. SECRET SERVICE MAN motions to SECOND SECRET SERVICE MAN and points in TRAVIS' direction. TRAVIS slips his hand into his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>On to victory in Miami Beach next month  and on to victory next November!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Sport. How are things?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O.K., cowboy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are things in the pimp business, hey Sport?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here to see Iris.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS pushes SPORT back into the dark recesses of the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Iris?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wha -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Iris. You know anybody by that name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  Hillbilly, you'd better get your wise ass outa here and quick, or you're gonna be in trouble. TRAVIS is being propelled by an inner force, a force which takes him past the boundaries of reason and self-control.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPORT looks into TRAVIS' eyes, saying nothing: he realizes the seriousness of the situation. TRAVIS pulls his .38 Special and holds it on SPORT, pushing him even further back against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>You carry a gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPORT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, mister, I don't know what's going on here. This don't make any sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SPORT reluctantly pulls a .32 caliber pistol (a &quot;purse gun&quot;) from his pocket and holds it limply.</context>
      <utterance>Show it to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IRIS screams in b.g. TRAVIS looks up:</context>
      <utterance>Don't kill me! Don't kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>IRIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS fires the revolver, blowing the back of THE OLD MAN's head off the silencing his protests. The police SIRENS screech to a halt. SOUND of police officers running up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Don't kill him, Travis! Don't kill him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHARLIE T</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHARLIE T. points his pistol/finger at TRAVIS, fires, says &quot;Pow&quot; and laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Howdy Wizard, Killer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE T</speaker>
      <mode>CONTD</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mess with the Killer.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Charlie T.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIZARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hey Travis, I think you gota fare. They all turn. P.O.V. of DOORMAN closing rear door of TRAVIS' taxi.</context>
      <utterance>Howsit, Charlie?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(runs off)</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE T</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS waves back to CHARLIE T. and WIZARD as he runs around cab and jumps in the driver's seat. TRAVIS' taxi pulls away. C.U. TRAVIS at the wheel. A FEMALE VOICE says:</context>
      <utterance>Take it slow, Killer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FEMALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRAVIS recognizes the voice. He looks in the rear-view mirror: It is BETSY. TRAVIS says nothing: he heads toward 56th Street. After a silence, BETSY speaks:</context>
      <utterance>34 East 56th Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an uneasy pause.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Betsy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see where Palantine got the nomination.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seventeen days.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. It won't be long now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is another pause.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I hope he wins.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you, Travis? I read about you in the papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I got over that. It was nothing, really. The papers always blow these things up.  A little stiffness. That'll go away. I just sleep more, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>TRAVIS' taxi pulls up to 34 East 56th Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BETSY digs in her purse.</context>
      <utterance>Here we are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Please.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, please. This fare's on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BETSY gets out of the cab and stands by the right front window, which is open. TRAVIS prepares to drive away.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Travis.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Travis?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETSY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'll see you again sometime, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BETSY steps away from the curb and TRAVIS drives off. She watches his taxi. CAMERA FOLLOWS TRAVIS' taxi as it slowly disappears down 56th Street.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
