<movie id="548" title="Terminator 2 Judgement Day">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John's friend TIM, a thirteen-year-old Hispanic kid, watches as John replies by turning up the volume on the boom box. Janelle gives up with a SLAM of the house's back door.</context>
      <utterance>...John? John! Get in here right now and clean up that pigsty of yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your foster parents are kinda dicks, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme that Phillips right there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John! Get your ass inside right now and do what your mother says! John pins Todd with a defiant glare.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He revs the engine and peels out of the garage, with Tim almost falling off the back. They take off down the street.</context>
      <utterance>She's not my mother, Todd!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's hard to read John's expression.</context>
      <utterance>Major moves, homes! So... where is your real mom, anyway?  She dead or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John twists the throttle angrily and the bike lunges forward.</context>
      <utterance>She might as well be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVERSE ANGLE as she turns slowly into CLOSE UP. SARAH CONNOR is not the same woman we remember from last time. Her eyes peer out through a wild tangle of hair like those of a cornered animal. Defiant and intense, but skittering around looking for escape at the same time. Fight or flight. Down one cheek is a long scar, from just below the eye to her upper lip. Her VOICE is a low and chilling monotone.</context>
      <utterance>'Morning, Sarah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Dr. Silberman. How's the knee?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he switches off, speaks to the interns) She, uh... stabbed me in the kneecap with a screwdriver a few weeks ago. Sarah watches them talking about her through the glass, but can't hear them. She feels like a lab animal. The interns look in at her through the glass as Silberman talks. With her face drawn, eyes haggard and hair wild, she looks like she belongs where she is.</context>
      <utterance>Fine, Sarah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the interns walk on, Silberman steps close to DOUGLAS, the head attendant, and speaks low.</context>
      <utterance>The delusional architecture is interesting. She believes a machine called a "terminator", which looks human of course, was sent back though time to kill her. And also that the father of her child was a soldier, sent to protect her... he was from the future too...  The year 2029, if I remember correctly.  Let's move on, shall we?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DOUGLAS is 6'4", 250 pounds and warm-hearted at a rattlesnake. He nods, catching Silberman's meaning, and gestures for the other attendants to hang back as Silberman moves on in his rounds.</context>
      <utterance>Douglas, I don't like seeing the patients disturbing their rooms like this. See that she takes her thorazine, would you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOUGLAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah faces him, weight centered. Feral eyes darting from one to the other.</context>
      <utterance>Time to take you meds, Connor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Douglas grins, casual --</context>
      <utterance>You take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGLAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you know you got to be good 'cause you up for review this afternoon...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not taking it. Now I don't want any trouble...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGLAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He whips the baton in a whistling backhand, which -- WHAP! Takes her square in the stomach. She doubles over and drops to her knees, unable to breathe. Douglas tips the bed and it slams down with a crash, right new to her. He takes her stun wand from the other attendant and walks forward. TIGHT ON SARAH, grimacing and struggling to breathe.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't no trouble at all --</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stun wand hits her between shoulder blades as she tries to rise. It drives her to the floor, pinning her like a bug. Little ELECTRIC ARCS CRACKLE as the baton makes her writhe in pain. Douglas grabs her by the hair and jerks her up to her knees. Holds the cup of thorazine in front of her lips.</context>
      <utterance>You... son of a... AAARRGH!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGLAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gasping, she chokes the zombie juice down.</context>
      <utterance>Last call, sugar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy money!</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John collects the twenties as the machine kicks them out. A cool and professional electronic-age thief at ten years old.</context>
      <utterance>Where'd you learn all this stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From my mom. My real mom, I mean. Come on baby...  Let's go! They sprint around the corner to an --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John reluctantly shows his friend the Polaroid. It is a shot of Sarah. Pregnant, in a jeep near the Mexican border. John doesn't know it now, but he will carry the photo with him for over 30 years, and give it to a young man named Kyle Reese, who will travel back in time to become his father. Yes, that photo.</context>
      <utterance>That her?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So she's pretty cool, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, no, she's a complete psycho. That's why she's up at Pescedero. She tries to blow up a computer factory, but she got shot and arrested.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John has tried to sound casual, but we see in his eyes that is really hurts. He slaps Tim on the shoulder and they jump onto his Honda. John fires up and they whine off down the alley.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she's a total loser. C'mon, let's check out the 7-Eleven, whatya say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>OFFICER X</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you the legal guardian of John Connor?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Officer X ignores the question. He casually scans the living room.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, officer. What's he done now?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER X</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd shrugs, showing the cop he's past his patience with the boy.</context>
      <utterance>Could I speak with him, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you could if he was here. Be he took off on his bike this morning. Could be anywhere. You gonna tell me what his is about?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER X</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janelle appears in the doorway behind Todd, concerned.</context>
      <utterance>I just need to ask him a few questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a guy here this morning asking about him, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Officer X registers the significance of that. He realizes who the big guy must be. He smiles. Reassuringly shakes his head no.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, big guy. On a bike. Has that got something to do with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER X</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Todd stares unhappily at the cop. Turns to Janelle.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't worry. Do you have a photograph of John?</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the album, Janelle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a gentle smile.</context>
      <utterance>Kyle..? You're dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>REESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. This is a dream, Sarah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts a finger to her lips. Then silently unfastens her restraints. They gaze into each other's eyes. And in the look that his death and the horror she has been through since hasn't touched their love at all.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Yeah. They... make me take this stuff...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She melts into Reese's arms. Pulls him to her.</context>
      <utterance>Hold me.</utterance>
   <speaker>REESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you. I always will.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him passionately. They are locked together in a timeless moment. PUSH IN TIGHT on Sarah as she buries her face in his shoulder. She shuts her eyes tight. Stay on Sarah as Reese speaks. He voice is strangely cold.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, God... Kyle. I need you so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>REESE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Sarah opens her eyes and he is no longer in her arms. He is standing across the room. Pinning her with an accusing gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Where's John, Sarah?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They took him from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>REESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's John who's the target now. You have to protect him. He's wide open.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know!</utterance>
   <speaker>REESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't quit, Sarah. Our son need you.</utterance>
   <speaker>REESE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember the message... the future is not set. There is not fate but what we make for ourselves. He turns toward the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kyle, don't go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>VIDEO SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... it's... like a giant strobe light, burning right through my eyes... but somehow I can still see. Look, you know the dream's the same every night, why do I have to --</utterance>
   <speaker>VIDEO SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>31A The REAL SARAH dispassionately watches herself on the screen. Her expression is controlled. Silberman watches her watching. They are in a brightly-lit interview room. TWO ATTENDANTS stands nearby.</context>
      <utterance>Please continue...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIDEO SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Video Sarah cuts him off, her mood shifting to sudden rage.</context>
      <utterance>Dreams about cataclysm, or the end of the world, are very common, Sarah...</utterance>
   <speaker>VIDEO SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not just a dream. It's real, you moron! I know the date is happens!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIDEO SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure it feels very real to you --</utterance>
   <speaker>VIDEO SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On August 29th 1997 it's going to feel pretty fucking real to you, too! Anybody not wearing number two million sunblock in gonna have a real bad day, get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VIDEO SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax now, Sarah --</utterance>
   <speaker>VIDEO SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is raving, half out of her chair. The orderly moves to inject her with something.</context>
      <utterance>You think you're alive and safe, but you're already dead. Everybody, you, him...  everybody... you're all fucking dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>VIDEO SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>31C Silberman pauses the tape... freezing Sarah's contorted face. Real Sarah turns away from the screen, he expression stony.</context>
      <utterance>You're the one living in a dream, Silberman, not me! Because I know it happens. It happens!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was afraid... and confused. I feel much better, now. Clearer. Silberman gives a calculated paternal smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Your attitude have been very positive lately. Sarah looks up at him. Her voice is hopeful.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has helped me a lot to have a goal, something to look forward to.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she answers, WE PULL BACK, revealing that we have been looking through a one-way mirror from an adjacent OBSERVATION ROOM. In the shadows of the observation room we see that interns from the earlier rounds, and a couple of STAFF PSYCHOLOGISTS. They smoke and make the occasional note.</context>
      <utterance>And what it that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said I could be transferred to the minimum security wing and have visitors if I showed improvement in six months. Well, it's been six months, and I was looking forward to seeing my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. Let's go back to what you were saying about these terminator machines. Now you think they don't exist? CLOSE ON SARAH. Her voice sounds hollow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silberman leans back, studying her. Toying with her.</context>
      <utterance>They don't exist. I see that now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you've told me on many occasions about how you crushed one in a hydraulic press.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I had, there would have been some evidence. They would have found something at the factory.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. So you don't believe anymore that the company covered it up? Sarah shakes her head no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is jokingly saluted by fellow members. Not a lab coat in sight. This is strictly jeans and sneakers crowd. All young and bright. They sit at their consoles drinking Coke and changing technology as we know it. A young LAB ASSISTANT rushes over to Dyson. Name tag says he's BRYANT.</context>
      <utterance>Greetings, troops.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Dyson? The material teams wants to run another test on the uh... on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dyson produces an unusual-looking KEY from his pocket as they stride through the lab. Bryant has to hustle to keep up.</context>
      <utterance>Yup. Come on. I'll get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Mr. Dyson, I know I haven't been here that long, but I was wondering if you could tell me... I mean, if you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRYANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... where it came from.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked them that question once. Know what they told me? Don't ask.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what do you think, Doctor? I've shown a lot of improvement, haven't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We go tight on Sarah's reaction. And we see that Silberman is right. She was playing him and it didn't work. And she knows she's fucked. Her tone becomes quite pleading.</context>
      <utterance>You see, Sarah... here's the problem. I know how smart you are, and I think you're just telling me what I want to hear. I don't think you really believe who you've been telling me today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to let me see my son. Please. It's very important. He's in danger. At least let me call him -- Silberman pins her with his sweet reptilian gaze.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah's eyes turn cold and lethal in one second. She knows she's lost. She knows this guy is just playing with her, and she --</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid not. Not for a while. I don't see any choice but to recommend to the review board that you stay here another six months.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>know what you're doing! You fuck! You're dead! You hear me!! Silberman signals and the attendants drag her out. He looks at the doctors behind the glass. Shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Goddammit. Let me go!! Silberman! You don't</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Model citizen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now don't take this the wrong way, but you are a terminator, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Cyberdyne Systems, Model 101.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John touches Terminator's skin. Then the blood on his jacket. His mind overloads as the reality of it hits him.</context>
      <utterance>No way!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're, uh... like a machine underneath, right... but sort of alive outside?</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit... you're really real! I mean... whoah!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a cybernetic organism. Living tissue over a metal endoskeleton.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This in intense. Get a grip, John. Okay, uh... you're not here to kill me... I figured that part out for myself. So what's the deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mission is to protect you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Who sent you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did. Thirty years from now you reprogrammed me to be your protector here, in this time. John gives him an amazed look.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is deep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this other guy? He's a terminator too, right, like you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not like me. A T-1000. Advanced prototype. A mimetic polyalloy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liquid metal.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Radical.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are targeted for termination. The T-1000 will not stop until it complete its mission. Ever. John mulls that over.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to leave the city, immediately. And avoid the authorities.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I stop by my house?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative. The T-1000 will definitely try to reacquire you there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JANELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the backyard, John's German Shepherd is going bonkers, barking at something.</context>
      <utterance>Janelle? It's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT THE PAYPHONE. John listens, an odd look on his face. He covers the phone's mouthpiece and turns to Terminator.</context>
      <utterance>John? Where are you, honey? It's late. You should come home, dear. I'm making a casserole.</utterance>
   <speaker>TODD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's the goddamn dog barking at?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator takes the phone from John's hand. Janelle's voice is floating through the receiver.</context>
      <utterance>The dog's really barking. Maybe it's already there. What should I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator speaks into the phone in a perfect imitation of John's voice...</context>
      <utterance>John? John, are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm right here. I'm fine.  What's the dog's name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator nods. Speaks into the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Max.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Janelle, what's wrong with Wolfy? I can hear him barking. Is he okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator heads for the bike. John, shocked, stares after him.</context>
      <utterance>Your foster parents are dead. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a minute here, okay? You're telling me it can imitate anything it touches?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John thinks about that, trying to grasp their opponent's parameters.</context>
      <utterance>Anything it samples by physical contact.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like it could disguise itself as anything... a pack of cigarettes?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John's still reeling from meeting one terminator, which now seems downright conventional next to the exotic new model.</context>
      <utterance>No. Only an object of equal size.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, why doesn't become a bomb or something to get me?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It can't form complex machines. Guns and explosives have chemicals, moving parts. It doesn't work that way. But it can form solid metal shapes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We spent a lot of time in Nicaragua... places like that. For a while she was with this crazy ex-Green Beret guy, running guns. Then there were some other guys. She'd shack up with anybody she could learn from. So then she could teach me how to be this great military leader. Then she gets busted and it's like... sorry kid, your mom's a psycho. Didn't you know? It's like... everything I'd been brought up to believe was just made-up fantasy, right? I hated her for that.  But everything she said was true.  We gotta get her out of there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative. The T-1000's highest probability for success now would be to copy Sarah Connor and wait for you to make contact with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator's reply is matter-of-fact.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, great. And what happens to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Typically, the subject being copied is terminated.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>TERMINATED!? Shit! Why didn't you tell me? We gotta right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Negative. She is not a mission priority.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John strides away. Terminator goes after him and grabs him arm. John struggles against the grip. Which doesn't do him much good.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well fuck you, she's a priority to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Starts dragging John back to the bike. John spots a couple of collage-age slab-o-meat JOCK-TYPES across the street and starts yelling to them.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, goddammit! What's your problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TWO JOCKS start toward him. John yells in outrage to Terminator.</context>
      <utterance>Help! HELP!! I'm being kidnapped! Get this psycho off of me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To his surprise, Terminator's hand opens so fast John falls right on his butt. He looks up at the open hand.</context>
      <utterance>Let go of me!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oww! Why'd you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John stares at him in amazement as he realizes...</context>
      <utterance>You told me to.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to do what I say?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is one of my mission parameters.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John grins. He's the first on his block...</context>
      <utterance>Prove it... stand on one foot. Terminator expressionlessly lifts one leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two guys get there and look at Terminator standing there calmly with one leg up in the air. This big guy in black leather and dark glasses, standing like a statue.</context>
      <utterance>Cool! My own terminator. This is great!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST JOCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John turns to him. No longer needing to be rescued.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, kid. You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a hike, bozo.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST JOCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Fuck you, you little dipshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator complies instantly, hoisting him one-handed by the collar. the guy's legs are pinwheeling.</context>
      <utterance>Dipshit? Did you say dipshit?!  Grab this guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Immediately, things get out of hand. The guy's friend jumps behind Terminator and tries to grab him in a full nelson -- Terminator throws the first guy across the hood of a car -- Grabs the second by the hair, whips out his .45 in a quick blur, and aims the muzzle at the guy's forehead. John grabs Terminator's arm with a yell as he pulls the trigger -- John's weight is just enough to deflect the gun a few inches. The guy flinches, stunned by the K-BOOM next to his ear. He stares, shocked. Pissing himself. John is freaking out, too. He screams at Terminator.</context>
      <utterance>Now who's the dipshit, you jock douchebag?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator sets the .45 on the sidewalk. John scoops it up fast then turns to the shocked civilians, who can't believe what just happened.</context>
      <utterance>Put the gun down! NOW!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They do. Fast. John grabs Terminator by the arm and tugs him toward the bike. John still holds the gun, reluctant to give it back.</context>
      <utterance>Walk away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus... you were gonna kill that guy!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John stares at him. Having your own terminator just became a little bit less fun to him.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. I'm a terminator.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, very carefully, okay? You're not a terminator any more. Alright? You got that? You can't just go around killing people!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whattaya mean, why? 'Cause you can't!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator doesn't get it. John just stares at him. Frightened at what just almost happened. He gets a glimpse of the responsibility that comes with power. Finally he hands the .45 back to Terminator, who puts it away.</context>
      <utterance>You just can't, okay? Trust me on this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm gonna go get my mom. You wanna come along, that's fine with me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MOSSBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Weathersby slaps another black-and-white eight-by-ten on the table. A closeup of Terminator taken by the Japanese tourist at the mall. It's the same face.</context>
      <utterance>He killed seventeen police officers that night. Recognize him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSSBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah doesn't react. It's hard to tell she's thinking. Whether she's up hope or is just in a drugged stupor.</context>
      <utterance>This one was taken by a Japanese tourist today.</utterance>
   <speaker>WEATHERSBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah stares up at him. A cold and empty stare. He glances at Silberman. Then at his partner.</context>
      <utterance>Ms. Connor, you've been told that your son's missing. His foster parents have been murdered, and we know this guy's involved. Talk to us. Don't you care?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSSBERG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the uniformed cops opens the door and Mossberg strides into the hall. Weathersby and the two uniforms follow him out, with Silberman right behind.</context>
      <utterance>We're wasting out time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIGHT ON SARAH, slumped under the bright lights. Totally out of it. Then we see her hand, creeping along the edge of the table toward the stack of photos. She slips off the paper clip binding the stills together, and hides it between her fingers. Douglas jerks her up by the arms and leads her out.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, gentleman...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>T-1000</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a Sarah Connor here? She assumes he's with the other cops. Smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHT NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to the inner door to buzz him in and sees Silberman and the cops coming toward the door from the other side.</context>
      <utterance>Running late, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHT NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When she turns back to the window, T-1000's no longer there. She goes to the counter and leans out to see if he's at the drinking fountain or someplace. No. Reception is empty. And so is the long corridor beyond. She frowns. Too weird. 66A Silberman comes through the solenoid door with Mossberg and Weathersby, the two uniformed cops, and the hospital security guard. The guard retrieves his 9mm pistol from a lock-out box behind the night desk. Silberman faces him.</context>
      <utterance>Your friends are on their way out now...</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The security guard nods. Silberman goes back into the secure area of the hospital and the cops walk down the long corridor to the main doors. No sign of T-1000. Mossberg and the other cops exit, and the guard locks the door behind them. 66B The guard walks slowly back along the long corridor. The hall is dark, with the light at the night desk far ahead like a sanctuary. His footsteps ring hollowly on the tile floor. His keys jingle. 66C ANGLE ON FLOOR as the guard's feet pass through FRAME. An instant later the floor starts to move. It shivers and bulges upward like a liquid mass, still retaining the two-tone checkerboard of the tile. It hunches up silently into a quivering shadow in the darkness past the guard. 66D Up ahead we hear typing. The night nurse has her back to us, working. The guard stops as the drinking fountain. Bends to take a sip. Behind him the fluid mass as reaches six feet of height and begins to resolve rapidly into a human figure. It loses the color and texture of the tile and becomes... THE GUARD. T-1000's mass has been spread out a quarter of an inch thick over several square yards of floor. The guard walked over the T-1000, and his structure was sampled that instant. Now we see it drawing in and pulling up to form the figure of the guard. The T-1000/Guard's feet are the last to form, the last of the "liquid floor" pulling in to form shiny black guard shoes. The shoes detach with a faint sucking sound from the real floor as the T-1000/Guard takes its first step. 66E The real guard spins at the sound of footsteps to see... himself. He has one deeply disturbing moment to consider the ramifications of that. Then he sees his double calmly raise its hand and, inexplicably, points his right index finger directly at the real guard's face, about a foot away. In a split second, the finger spears out, elongating into a thin steel rod which snaps out like a stiletto, slamming into the guard's eye. It punches into the corner of the eye, past the eyeball like a trans- orbital lobotomy tool, and emerges from the back of the guard's skull. Life quietly empties from the guard's face. He is dead weight, hanging from the rod/finger with suddenly reacts -- SSSNICK. As the guard slumps, the T-1000 takes his weight easily with one hand and walks him, like it's carrying a suit on a hanger, back toward the night desk. The wounds are so tiny, no blood drips onto the floor. 66F ON THE NIGHT NURSE, glancing up as the T-1000/Guard walks past, dragging something casually which she can't see because it's below the countertop.</context>
      <utterance>Lewis, see these gentleman out and them lock up for the night.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHT NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatcha got, Lewis?</utterance>
   <speaker>T-1000/GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, uninterested. Keeps typing. T-1000 moves past, dragging the unseen guard toward a closet down the hall from the night receiving station. T-1000/Guard removes the Browning High-Power pistol and the keys from the real guard's belt, then stuffs the body into the utility closet.</context>
      <utterance>Just some trash.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>T-1000/GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances toward it. Sees the Beretta in its holster.</context>
      <utterance>All set.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIGHT NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotta check the gun first, Lewis.</utterance>
   <speaker>T-1000/GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>T-1000 opens the locker and blocks it from her view with its body as it mimes putting the gun in. 66H CLOSE ANGLE ON T-1000'S CHEST, from inside the locker. Instead of setting the gun in the locker, it inserts the pistol into it own chest, where is disappears inside like it was dropped into a pot of hot fudge. It withdraws its hand. The chest is once again a surface that looks like cloth, buttons, name-tag etc. You'd ever guess it was really an intelligent liquid metal. T-1000 slams the locker door and waits as the nurse hits the button unlocking the door with a BUZZ-CLACK. T-1000/Guard goes through.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You broke my arm!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's 215 bones in the human body, motherfucker. That's one. Now don't move! 68B Moving rapidly, she whips open a medication drawer and grabs a syringe. They keep a few of these handy for tranking unruly patients. She jams it into the orderly's butt and fires the whole shot. Still holding the empty syringe, she sees what she need next. They keep the toxic cleaning supplies in here to keep the inmates from drinking Drano. She grabs a plastic jug of LIQUID PLUM'R and slams it down on the desk inches from Silberman's eyes. She jams the empty syringe into the plastic jug. Draws back the plunger. The syringe fills with blue liquid. She whips it out of the jug and jams the needle into Silberman's neck. His horrified eyes rack toward it. 10 cc's of blue death fill the cylinder. Her thumb hovers over the plunger. She jerks him to his feet by the collar and gets a tight grip on him, then hauls him through the door. 69 IN THE CORRIDOR outside cell 19 the T-1000 stops and looks in the window. Douglas, his face a bloody mess, yells to be heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGLAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To Douglas' amazement, Lewis the Guard turns impassively and walks away, leaving him shouting soundlessly at the window.</context>
      <utterance>Open the door! The goddamn bitch is loose in the halls!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now remember, you're not gonna kill anyone, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John looks at him. He's not convinced.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John holds his hand up, like he's being sworn in. Terminator stares at John a beat. Then mimics the gesture.</context>
      <utterance>Just say "I swear I won't kill anyone."</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator stops the bike and gets off. The guard, sensing trouble, has his gun drawn as he comes out of the shack. Terminator walks toward him drawing his .45 smoothly. BLAM! He shoots the guard accurately in the thigh. The guy drops, screaming and clutching his leg. Terminator kicks the guard's gun away, then smashes the phone in the shack with his fist. He pushes the button to raise the gate and walks back to the bike.</context>
      <utterance>I swear I will not kill anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator climbs onto the bike. They drive toward the hospital, heading down an ambulance ramp to an underground receiving area.</context>
      <utterance>He'll live.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The attendants' adrenaline levels just went off the scale. The first attendant shakes him head no. The amperage here is really high. The second attendant keys the intercom switch.</context>
      <utterance>Open it or he'll be dead before he hits the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>2ND ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silberman's face is the color of suet.</context>
      <utterance>There's no way, Connor. Let him go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't work, Sarah. You're no killer. I don't believe you'd do it. Her voice is a deadly cold hiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're already dead, Silberman. Everybody here dies. You know I believe that. So don't fuck with me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The attendants looks at one another. One of them hits the solenoid button. The far door unlocks. 71A IN THE LOCKOUT CORRIDOR. Sarah pushes Silberman ahead of her. The nearer, barred door must be unlocked manually. One of the attendants cautiously approaches. Nervously unlocks it.</context>
      <utterance>Open the goddamn door!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Step back!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He does. She faces both of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They comply. She comes through with Silberman, giving them a wide berth. Starts backing down the hall away from them, still holding her hostage. She's actually pulling this off. 71B ANGLE FROM BEHIND HER. What we can see, but she can't see, it a third orderly waiting just around the corner. He's poised, ready to jump her when she comes abreast of him. ON SARAH backing up. She reaches the corner. The third attendant lunges, grabbing her syringe-hand. Sarah spins on the orderly and catches him across the throat with the nightstick. He loses interest fast, dropping to his knees and gagging. Silberman pulls away, screaming at the top of his lungs</context>
      <utterance>Down on the floor! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They scramble up as Sarah takes off like a shot around the corner. One of them hits the panic button and ALARMS begin to sound. 72 IN THE ISOLATION WARD, the T-1000 is looking in at a very stoned attendant inside the nurses' station when the alarms shriek through the halls. It reaches into its chest and pulls out the 9mm pistol. Heads for the security entrance. 73 IN ANOTHER CORRIDOR in the maze of the vast hospital, Sarah flies past us, her bare feet slapping on the cold tiles. The orderlies charge after her. She's like an animal in a maze. She turns the corner, glancing off the wall, and sprints on without slowing. She reaches a steel door. Tries it. Locked. Footsteps like a drum solo behind her. She fumbles with Douglas' keys, breathing hard. Jams the master in. The orderlies are bearing down on her at full tilt. Sarah gets the door open. Dives through. Slams it. She turns a deadbolt knob just as the first orderly grabs the latch on the other side. He's too late. Sarah sees them beyond the window, fumbling with their keys. 73A Sarah is in another sally-port corridor. A jail-cell type barred door is between her and the corridors of the ward beyond. She sprints to the walls of bars, jams her key into the door. She unlocks and pulls open this door just as she hears the latch of the one she just came through being unlocked. She flings herself frantically through the barred door as the first orderly comes through behind her. She slams the bars shut. CLANG. Her keys are dangling from the lock on the other side from her. The orderly is racing at her, white-lipped with rage. She reaches back through the bars, turns the key, and purposefully snaps it off in the lock. An instant later the big orderly slams against the door, grabbing through the bars for her as she dances back just out of reach. He lunges against the steel bars, unbelievably pissed off. Sarah takes off running, looking back at the frustrated orderlies. They're shouting at each other, unable to fit their keys into the lock -- The broken-off key tip makes it impossible to get their keys in. Silberman shouts at them.</context>
      <utterance>Get her!</utterance>
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The orderlies run back the way they came, and along a cross-corridor to another set of doors. 73B ON SARAH as she rounds a corner and sees the elevators ahead. Now she's home-free. At a full-tilt sprint, she's nearly there when the elevator doors part... TERMINATOR steps out... his head swivels to face her. Sarah reacts, stricken by the image from her worst nightmares. Her eyes go wide as momentum carries her forward. Her bare feet slip on the slick tile. She slams to the floor, staring up at the leather-clad figure with the shotgun. She loses all semblance of courage and some of her sanity. She's not even aware that she is screaming, or what would be screaming if she could get the breath to do it. In slowed-down dream-time, Sarah scrambles back along the floor like a crab, spinning and clawing her way to her feet along the wall. She runs like the wind, like in her nightmare. If she looked back she would have seen John step warily out of the corridor behind Terminator. John, however, catches a glimpse of the fleeing Sarah and figures out instantly what happened.</context>
      <utterance>Go around, goddamnit! Go around!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah doesn't hear. She has clicked fully into her own nightmare. They take off running after Sarah. 73C She is pelting down the long corridor, back the way she came. As she reaches an intersection with a cross-corridor a white-clad figure blurs from that corridor. The orderly hits her in a flying tackle. She skids across the floor, shrieking and struggling. The other two orderlies leap into the fray.</context>
      <utterance>Mom!! Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is shouting, pleading, trying to get them to understand what is coming. They grab her thrashing arms and legs. They don't even look where the out-of-control woman is pointing... back along the corridor. They have pinned her to the cold tiles, a ring of faces above her. Silberman leans down to her, holding a syringe with a heavy dose of trank. Sarah cranes her neck and sees the dark silhouette of Terminator coming up behind them. It is exactly her nightmare. She screams in utter hopelessness. Terminator, holding the shotgun in one hand, reaches down and grabs one of the orderlies with his other hand. He hurls the 200-pound guys against the far wall of the corridor. SMACK! He drops to the floor. The other two orderlies react instantly, leaping onto the intruder. Terminator seems to disappear for a moment under the two big guys. Then there is an explosion of white-clad figures, as the orderlies are flung outward like they stepped on a land mine. One crashes through a window of safety glass and is caught before a two-story fall by the outer steel bars. The other crashes through an office door, splintering it into kindling. Silberman has jumped to hold Sarah. He is grabbed by a roll of skin at the back of his neck and lifted like a cat. The doctor feel his feet pedaling above the ground. He looks into the expressionless face. And it hit him. Sarah was right... this guy isn't human. He feels the fabric of reality crumbling. Then he feels himself flying through the air. The wall smacks him, then the floor kicks him in the face. He decides to lie there a second. Sarah blinks, staring up at the figure looming over her. John kneels next to her.</context>
      <utterance>No! Help me! Goddamnit, it's gonna kill us all!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks from Terminator to John. Back to Terminator. Is this a nightmare? Or has she finally gone truly bad? Incredibly, Terminator politely reaches his hand down to her, offering to help her up. The last thing she ever expected to see.</context>
      <utterance>Mom, are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The orderlies are stirring.</context>
      <utterance>Come with me if you want to live.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah, is a daze, takes the huge hand in her shaking fingers. Terminator lifts her to her feet. 73D John sees a GUARD standing thirty feet away, on the other side of the walls of bars. John doesn't know what we know, but he knows something's not right with this guy. Terminator turns to follow John's gaze. The T-1000 had its pistol in its hand, at its side. Terminator pushes John behind him. They start backing up. 73E The T-1000 walks forward, reaching the bars. It doesn't stop. Its body divides like jello around the bars. As it squeezes itself through like metal playdough, its surface reforms perfectly on our side. We see it deform and squeeze through like a viscous paste forced past an obstacle. Silberman has recovered enough to be sitting up and watching this. That faint snapping sound is his mind. There is a CLANK and we see that the guard's gun has caught against the bars... the only solid object. The T-1000 turns its wrist and tries again, slipping the gun endwise through the gap. 73F Sarah is agape. Not reacting. It's been a heavy day for her. Terminator grabs John by the seat of his pants and hooks him up onto his back. John grabs him around the neck. Terminator raises the shotgun and starts backing up.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right, Mom. He's here to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah doesn't need to be told twice. T-1000 walks toward them, opening fire with the Browning Hi-Power. Terminator straight-arms the 12-guage like a pistol and FIRES. The stunned orderlies flop face down on the floor as the corridor is filled with high-velocity lead. One of them, stupidly running for the cross-corridor, gets hit by the T-1000. Terminator is hammered by several slugs, and the T-1000 is cratered by two buckshots hits. It staggers, but comes on. In the craters we see bright mercury before they close and reseal, disappearing in a second. 73G Terminator makes it around the corner and breaks into a run. Ahead, Sarah is already at the elevator. Terminator and John pile in and John slaps the button for "Garage Level". The doors start to close. T-1000 clears the corner. Terminator slams John and Sarah back against the side walls as the T-1000 charges at them, rapid firing the Browning. The rounds hit the steel doors as they close. T-1000 keeps pumping them at the closing gap. 73H Inside, they see the backside of the doors denting with the hits that are punching holes in the other side. 73I The Browning locks open, empty. T-1000 drops it without a glance back. The doors close. K-WHAM! The T-1000 hits them a split second later. The elevator hasn't moved yet. SSWWIKK! 73J A sword-like blade rams through in between the doors, forcing them open. Terminator jams the shotgun through the widening gap. Punches the muzzle right INTO T-1000's face -- BOOM!! 73K We get a glimpse of the T-1000's head blown apart by the blast. It is hurtled back. The doors close. The car descends. 73L ON THE T-1000, outside the elevator. Its head, which is blown apart into two doughy masses lying on the shoulders, reforms quickly. There is no trace of the injury. It sees the closed door and jams its hands between them, its fingertips becoming pry-bars. It pulls the doors apart with inhuman strength 73M and LEAPS INTO THE OPEN SHAFT. It falls two floors and... 74 IN THE ELEVATOR. Out trio hears a loud THUMP on the roof. Terminator, reloading the shotgun, looks up. Sarah grabs the .45 from his waistband and aims it at the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Go! Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cuts the wheel hard. The car slews into a reverse 180, swapping ends with a screech. T-1000 is almost on them. Terminator punches it. The car accelerates forward. 80C T-1000 leaps. Lands on the trunk. Its hand is a metal crowbar slammed down through the trunk lid. Feet dragging on the pavement, it slams its other hand down, punching another metal hook into the trunk lid, pulling itself up. Terminator turns to Sarah.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator heaves himself half out the driver's window. Sarah slaps her foot down on the throttle and steers from the passenger side. 80D T-1000, fully on the car now, holds on with one hook-hand while it slams the other into the back window, sweeping away the glass and missing John by inches as he ducks. It draws back for another swing, lunging forward as -- 80E Terminator whips the shotgun over the roof of the car. Fires point-blank. Hits the T-1000's arm just above the "hand" which anchors it to the car. The 12-guage blows the arm apart, severing the hook-hand. 80F T-1000 tumbles backward off the accelerating car. John looks out the back window, his eyes wide. He sees the T-1000 roll to his feet and continue running. But he's dropping way behind now. Sarah has the car floored and the liquid-metal killer won't catch them on foot. 80G John watches, in awe, as the "crowbar hand", stuck into the trunk right in front of him, reverts to the neutral polyalloy... a kind of think mercury. The gray metal slides off the trunk of the car and falls onto the road to lie there in a quivering blob. 80H The car speeds off into the night. REVERSE on the T-1000, walking now, coming right up into closeup, watching the tail lights recede. It looks down. 80I ANGLE ON BLACKTOP, tight on the liquid metal blob. Next to it is the T-1000's shiny cop shoe. The mercury blob crawls and rejoins the main mass, disappearing into the "shoe".</context>
      <utterance>Drive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>81B TERMINATOR'S POV. A monochrome image of the highway lit bright as day. 81C Terminator replies in a matter-of-fact tone.</context>
      <utterance>Can you see anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah looks at Terminator, still not quite believing this is happening. But this is a different Sarah than the waitress of 1984. She spends only a second or two dealing with the unbelievable. Then she turns to John in the back seat.</context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. She reaches for John and we think she's going to hug him. She starts to rub her hands over him and we realize she's checking for injuries, very clinically the way a vet checks a dog for broken bones. He pulls away from her. He hates her always checking him, treating him like he might break, like some piece of rare china.</context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah looks at him, exasperated and stern.</context>
      <utterance>I said I was okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John stares at her, surprised.</context>
      <utterance>It was stupid of you to go there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see his chin quiver. He's a tough kid, but all he really wants is for her to love him. He hasn't had enough years on the planet yet to be the man of steel she demands.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit, John, you have to be smarter than that. You're too important! You can't risk yourself, not even for me, do you understand? I can take care of myself. I was doing fine. Jesus, John. You almost got yourself killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face crumples. He starts to cry. Sarah gives him a cold stare.</context>
      <utterance>I... had to get you out of the place... I'm sorry, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's trying to be brave, he really is. Terminator turns and sees the water leaking from his eyes. It doesn't make and sense to him.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it! Right now! You can't cry, John. Other kids can afford to cry. You can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John turns away, ashamed. Sarah lets her breath out, realizing how keyed up she is. She turns to Terminator, giving him a wary once- over.</context>
      <utterance>What is wrong with your eyes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's your story?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SILBERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>82A T-1000 walks unperturbed among the milling cops. No one notices him. It slips into its cruiser and drives off into the night.</context>
      <utterance>... it was all true and we're all going to die and the changed, I saw him change!! It's quite pathetic. A nurse shoots him up with a sedative. They lead him away.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This T-1000... what happens when you shoot it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ballistic penetration shocks it, but only for a few seconds. Sarah thinks about that. Then:</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can it be destroyed?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They ride along in silence for a few seconds. Sarah sees something up ahead, some lonely neon in the blackness.</context>
      <utterance>Unknown.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull in here. We have to ditch this car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look like handmade shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah stares into his face, inches away, fighting the pain. She doesn't like him being this close to her to begin with, let alone carving on her.</context>
      <utterance>I have detailed files on human anatomy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bet. Makes you a more efficient killer, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Correct.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIGHT ON SARAH AND TERMINATOR. Sarah starts washing the bullet holes in his broad back with alcohol.</context>
      <utterance>I sense injuries. The data could be called pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator nods. She reaches into the bloody wounds with pliers and finds the copper-jacketed bullets, flattening against the armored endoskeleton. Pulls them out. They CLINK one by one into a glass.</context>
      <utterance>Will these heal up?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She concentrates on removing the slugs. CLINK. CLINK.</context>
      <utterance>That's good. Because if you can't pass for human, you won't be much good to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long do you live? I mean, last?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah nods, pulling out another slug. CLINK. The glass nearly full of flattened bullets. She begins to sew the holes closed with a few wire sutures. John watches in quiet amazement, the two warriors calmly fixing each other.</context>
      <utterance>A hundred and twenty years on my existing power cell.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you learn? So you can be... you know. More human. Not such a dork all the time. Terminator turns towards him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My CPU is a neural-net processor... a learning computer. But Skynet presets the switch to "read-only" when we are sent out alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't want you thinking too much, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we reset the switch?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wipes away the blood and uses the garage-mechanic's air tools to unscrew the port cover. 88A TERMINATOR POV (DIGITIZED) as he watches her work in a mirror they've taken from the washroom. Sarah and John are standing behind him. Her hands are covered with blood, like a surgeon's.</context>
      <utterance>Now open the port cover.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Following the instructions, she reaches in with a pair of tweezers and PULLS -- there is a BURST OF STATIC and the screen goes BLACK.</context>
      <utterance>Hold the CPU by its base tab. Pull.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she sets it on the work table and picks up a small sledge hammer. John realizes what she is about to do. Dives at her as the sledge is whistling down.</context>
      <utterance>Can you see the pin switch? She ignores him. See looks at Terminator. The back at the chip.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slaps his hand down over the chip. Sarah barely stops the sledge before smashing his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>No!!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out of the way, John!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Don't kill him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It, John. Not him. It.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John keeps his hand right where it is.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, it! We need it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're better off by ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's the only proof we have to the future... about the war and all that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't trust it! These things are hard to kill, John, believe me, I know. We may never have this opportunity again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smart kid. He's got her. She nods, reluctantly. He palms the chip and studies it minutely. 89B John takes a pin and moves the almost invisible switch to the other position. It is now in "write" mode. Then he grimaces as he inserts the wafer back into the slot in Terminator's skull. 89C TERMINATOR VISION flares back to life in a burst of static. The image forms. Sarah and John stands behind him in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Mom, if I'm supposed to ever be this great leader, you should start listening to my leadership ideas once in a while. 'Cause if you won't, nobody else will.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John glances sheepishly at Sarah, Then smiles at Terminator.</context>
      <utterance>Was there a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem. None whatsoever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>92B Sarah comes out. She's found a mechanic's coverall inside, used but fairly clean. It doesn't fit her too well, but it's better than the stuff from the hospital. She's still barefoot. The sun, which she hasn't seen in months, hurts her eyes, Terminator and John pull up in the pickup. She gets in.</context>
      <utterance>Are we learning yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just head south.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it under sixty-five. We can't afford to be pulled over. Terminator backs off the throttle slightly.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Affirmative.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator nods, filing away the information. Sarah is ignoring the lesson, lost in thought.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, no. You gotta listen to the way people talk. See, you don't say like "Affirmative" or some shit like that. You say... no problemo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It someone comes off to you with an attitude, you say "eat me"... if you wanna shine them on, it's "Hasta la vista, baby".</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Hasta la vista, baby"?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, or "later, dickwad." Or if someone gets upset you say "chill out." Like that. Or you can do combinations.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chill out, dickwad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's great! See, you're getting it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problemo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John pulls what's left of his Ready-Teller money from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>You got any cash?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah grabs all of it. Peels off a twenty, hands it to John.</context>
      <utterance>Only a couple hundred bucks. I'll give you half.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the truck door and steps out. John turns to Terminator.</context>
      <utterance>Get some food.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>97 THE ORDERING WINDOW as John and Terminator approach.</context>
      <utterance>No sense of humor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's another thing. You could lighten up a bit, yourself. This severe routine is getting old. Smile once in a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smile?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Smile. You know. People smile, right? Watch. Goes to the order window.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. Nice place you got here. How's business?</utterance>
   <speaker>WINDOW WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TERMINATOR POV (DIGITIZED) The real-time image continues while a replay of one of the guys grinning runs in a window. It expands, so that the guy's mouth fills the window. Replays again in slow motion. A vector-graphic of the lips smiling appears, along with an array of symbolic data. Terminator tries it. The result is dismal. A rictus-like curling of the lip. Terminator's next effort is a marginal improvement.</context>
      <utterance>Like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, maybe you could practice in front of a mirror or something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>FIRST KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am not!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John and Terminator watch them rolling on the ground in a fight to the death. Sarah rounds the front of the truck, and sees the kids. John sighs, solemn. He looks up at the cyborg.</context>
      <utterance>Are so!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not gonna make it, are we? People, I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is in your nature to destroy yourselves. John nods, depressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Drag, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to know how Skynet get built. Who's responsible?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man most directly responsible is Miles Bennet Dyson, Director of Special Projects at Cyberdyne Systems Corporation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why him?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a few months he creates a revolutionary type of mircoprocessor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>98B Terminator closes the hood and gets into the truck as he speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Then what?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In three years Cyberdyne will become the largest supplier of military computer systems. All stealth bombers are upgraded with Cyberdyne computers, becoming fully unmanned, Afterward, the fly with a perfect operational record.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a panic, they try to pull the plug.</context>
      <utterance>Basically.  The Skynet funding bill is passed. The system goes on-line August 4th, 1997. Human decisions are removed from strategic defense. Skynet begins to learn, at a geometric rate. It becomes self-aware at 2:14 a.m. eastern time, August 29.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They accelerate back onto the highway.</context>
      <utterance>And Skynet fights back.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. It launches its ICBMs against their targets in Russia.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why attack Russia?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because Skynet knows the Russian counter-strike will remove its enemies here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus.  How much do you know about Dyson?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have detailed files.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to know everything. What he looks like. Where he lives. Everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>TARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going to work all day?</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to a metal box on his desk, about two feet long. As assembly of small cubes. It looks like a dinosaur version of Terminator's CPU.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, baby. This thing is just kicking my ass. I thought we had it with this one...</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... but the output went to shit after three seconds. I'm thinking now it's the way I'm matrixing the command hierarchies...</utterance>
   <speaker>TARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need a break. You'll see it clear when you come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't</utterance>
   <speaker>TARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miles, it's Sunday. You promised to take the kids to Raging Waters today.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her hands. We see a childlike excitement in his face. He wants so badly to share the almost orgasmic thrill of discovery, the satisfaction of creation.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. I can't, honey. I'm on a roll here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Baby, this thing is going to blow 'em all away. It's a neural-net process --</utterance>
   <speaker>TARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. You told me. It's a neural-net processor. It thinks and learns like we do. It's superconducting at room temperature. Other computer are pocket calculators by comparison.  But why is that so goddamn important, Miles? I really need to know, 'cause I feel like I'm going crazy here, sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up his thumb and index finger... a fraction of an inch apart. She picks up the prototype. It doesn't look like much.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, honey, it's just that I'm thiiis close.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imagine a jetline with a pilot that never makes a mistake, never gets tired, never shows up to work with a hangover.  Meet the pilot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the anodized box from her hands and sets it down. Then he puts his hands on her shoulders and kisses her gently. She acquiesces to his kiss.</context>
      <utterance>Why did you marry me, Miles? Why did we have these two children? You don't need us. Your heart and your mind are in here.  But it doesn't love you like we do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarissa glances over his shoulder. She nods her head toward the doorway to the study. Dyson turns and sees their two kids standing there. Danny (6) and Blythe (4) look rumpled and adorable in their PJs. Dyson wilts at their hopeful expressions.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dyson grins. The forces of darkness have lost this round. He holds out his hands and his kids run to him, cheering.</context>
      <utterance>How about spending some time with your other babies?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hears KACHANK! behind her and spins, whipping out her .45 in one motion. ENRIQUE SALCEDA stands behind a rusting jeep, a 12-gauge pump trained on her. He is mid-forties, a tough Guatemalan with a weathered face and heavy mustache. He wears cowboy boots and a flak vest, no shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Enrique? You here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALCEDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His fierce face breaks into a broad grin. The shotgun drops to his side as he walks toward her. When he reaches her he hugs her, then steps back.</context>
      <utterance>You pretty jumpy, Connor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALCEDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oye, Big John! Que pasa? Who's your very large friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALCEDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yolanda. Get out here, we got company. And bring some fucking tequila! A thin Guatemalan KID, FRANCO, eighteen or so, comes out of the trailer with the AK-47, followed by Salceda's wife, YOLANDA. She has THREE younger children with her, from a five-year-old GIRL, JUANITA, to a year-and-half-old BOY. She waves at John. They exchange greetings in Spanish. They seem like nice people. Terminator looks down at John, next to him. He says quietly...</context>
      <utterance>Hmmm. Uncle Bob, huh? Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uncle Bob?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALCEDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him the tequila and takes the child. Salceda takes a long pull from the Cuervo bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, take Pacolito. Thanks, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>SALCEDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator gestures "no" at the proffered bottle, but Sarah grabs it and takes a long pull. She lowers it without expression. Her eyes don't even water.</context>
      <utterance>Drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just came for my stuff. And I need clothes, food, and one of your trucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Enrique.  You two are on weapons detail.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator hooks the chain onto the towhook on the back of the tractor. John hits the throttle and the Cat churns its treads, pulling some massive load. A six-by-eight foot sheet of steel plate moves slowly under six inches of sand. John drags it far enough to reveal... a rectangular hole in the ground. Like the mouth of a tomb. The kid drops down from the tractor and walks to the hole.</context>
      <utterance>Hook it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One thing about my mom... she always plans ahead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I thought you'd like this place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SALCEDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the best truck, but the water pump is blown. You got the time to change it out?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I'm gonna wait till dark to cross the border.  Enrique, it's dangerous for you here. You get out tonight, too, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALCEDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Saralita. Sure.  Just drop by any time and totally fuck up my life. She slaps him on the shoulder.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John grabs an AK-47 and racks the bolt with a practiced action. Inspects the receiver for wear. Doesn't like what he sees. Puts is back. His movement are efficient. Professional. Uninterested.</context>
      <utterance>See, I grew up in places like this, so I just thought it was how people lived... riding around in helicopters. Learning how to blow shit up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator has found a Vietnam-era "blooper" M-79 grenade launcher. A very crude but effective weapon. He opens the breech and inspects the bore.</context>
      <utterance>Then, when Mom got busted I got put in a regular school. The other kids were, like, into Nintendo.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator pauses for a second. The thought never occurred to him. He searches him mind for the answer...</context>
      <utterance>Are you ever afraid?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator slings the M-79 and starts looking for the grenades.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not even of dying?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't feel any emotion about it one way or the other?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John is idly spinning a Sig Saur 9mm pistol on his finger... backwards and forwards like Bat Masteron.</context>
      <utterance>No. I have to stay functional until my mission is complete. Then it doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator pulls back a canvas tarp, revealing a squat, heavy weapon with six barrels clustered in a blunt cylinder. Chain-ammo is fed from a canister sitting next to it. A G.E. MINI-GUN. The most fearsome anti-personnel weapon of the Vietnam era. Terminator hefts it. Looks at John as if to say "Can I? Please?"</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I have to stay functional too.  "I'm too important".</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's definitely you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John thinks he's being causal, but his longing for some kind of parental connection is obvious.</context>
      <utterance>There was this one guy that was kinda cool. He taught me engines. Hold this a second. Mom screwed it up, of course. Sooner or later she'd always tell them about Judgment Day and me being this world leader and that's be all she wrote.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Torque wrench please.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here. I wish I coulda met my real dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They crawl out from under the truck into the bright sunlight.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I guess so. My mom says when I'm, like, 45, I think, I send him back through time to 1984. But right now he hasn't even been born yet. Man, is messes with your head. Where's that other bolt?  Thanks. Mom and him were only together for one night, but she still loves him, I guess. I see her crying sometimes. She denies it totally, of course. Like she says she got something in her eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you cry?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean people? I don't know. We just cry. You know. When it hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pain causes it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-unh, no, it's different... It's when there's nothing wrong with you but you hurt anyway. You get it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator gets into the Bronco and turns the ignition key and the engine catches with a roar.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alriight!! My man!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John grins and does a victorious thumbs up. Terminator imitates the gesture awkwardly. John laughs and makes him get out of the truck, to try the move again. A108 SARAH, across the compound, pauses in her work to watch John and Terminator. A109 SARAH'S POV... we don't hear what John and Terminator are saying. It is a soundless pantomime as John is trying to show some other gestures to the cyborg. Trying to get him to walk more casually. John walks, then Terminator tries it, then John gestures wildly, talking very fast... explaining the fundamental principles of cool. They try it again. Continued ad lib as we hear:</context>
      <utterance>No problemo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Sarah clenches her jaw and goes grimly back to work... a strong woman made hard and cold by years of hard choices.</context>
      <utterance>Watching John with the machine, it was suddenly so clear. The Terminator would never stop, it would never leave him... it would always be there. And it would never hurt him, never shout at him or get drunk and hit him, or say it couldn't spend time with him because it was too busy. And it would die to protect him. Of all the would-be fathers who came and went over the years, this thing, this machine, was the only one who measured up. In an insane world, it was the sanest choice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SALCEDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said you go south with him...  ... tonight, like you planned. She will meet you tomorrow in... But John is moving, running after her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A120B MOVING WITH SARAH as she leaves the compound. We see John running after her... yelling. Can't hear his words. She looks in the rear- view mirror but doesn't slow down.</context>
      <utterance>Mommm!! Wait!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"No fate." No fate but what we make. My father told her this... I mean I made him memorize it, up in the future, as a message to her -- Never mind. Okay, the whole thing goes "The future is not set. There is no fate but what we make for ourselves."</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She intends to change the future somehow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess, yeah --  Oh shit!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dyson.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, gotta be! Miles Dyson! She's gonna blow him away! John motions to Terminator and breaks into a run.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Let's go. LET'S GO!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is tactically dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drive faster.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The T-1000 has the same files that I do. It could anticipate this move and reacquire you at Dyson's house.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care. We've gotta stop her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Killing Dyson might actually prevent the war.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care!! There's gotta be another way. Haven't you learned anything?! Haven't you figured out why you can't kill people? Terminator is still stumped.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PANNING as they pass, revealing the lights of the city ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Look, maybe you don't care if you live or die. But everybody's not like that! Okay?! We have feelings. We hurt. We're afraid. You gotta learn this stuff, man, I'm not kidding. It's important.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>132E IN THE HALL, TARISSA rounds the corner at a dead run. She sees the kids running toward her and grabs them in her arms. Down the hall, in the dark study, she sees Dyson on the floor amid the splinters and shrapnel of the continuing fusillade.</context>
      <utterance>Run, kids! Go! Run!</utterance>
   <speaker>TARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miles! Oh my God!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>132F ON THE FLOOR, Dyson flinches as chucks of wood and shattered computer components shower down on him. He looks desperately toward the door, but knows he'd be totally exposed. He'd never make it. 133 SARAH's rifle empties with a final CLACK! She throws it down and draws her .45 smoothly from a shoulder base. She starts toward the house, snapping back the slide on the pistol, chambering a round. She is in a fast, purposeful walk, keeping her eyes fixed on the target. She is utterly determined to kill this man. 134 FROM UNDER THE DESK Dyson can see a sliver in the backyard. He sees Sarah's feet as she strides toward him. He tenses to make a break for the door. Sarah raises the pistol, eyes riveted ahead, controlling her breathing. Dyson springs up in a full-tilt sprint. She tracks him. He hooks a foot on the cord of a toppled disk drive. BOOM! Her shot blows apart a lamp where his head was. He hits the floor hard, but keeps moving, scrambling forward. Crunch of glass behind his as Sarah's dark form is framed in the blown-out floor-to-ceiling window. Dyson leaps toward the hall. BOOM! Her second shot spins him. He hits the floor in the hallway. Tarissa is screaming. Dyson struggles forward, stunned. There is a .45-caliber hole clean through his left shoulder. He smears the wall with blood as he staggers up. Looking back, he sees the implacable figure behind him, coming on. He topples through a doorway as -- BOOM! BOOM! Shots blowing away the molding where he just was.</context>
      <utterance>Stay back!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Danny! DANNY!</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danny is pulling at Dyson, crying and screaming, as his father tries to stagger forward. Tarissa drops Blythe and runs back for Dyson, grabbing him. Sarah looms behind them with the pistol aimed.</context>
      <utterance>Daaaaddddeeee!</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't fucking move! Don't FUCKING MOVE!!  Get on the floor, bitch! Now!! Fucking down!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BLYTHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't hurt my father!</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please... let... the kids... go...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see her psyching herself to pull the trigger... needing now to hate this man she doesn't know. It's a lot harder face-to-face. She is bathed in sweat, and it runs into her eyes. Blinking, she wipes it fast with one hand, then gets it back on the gun. The .45 is trembling. TIGHT ON SARAH as we see the forces at war behind her eyes. She looks into the faces of Dyson, Tarissa, Blythe, Danny. Sarah takes a sharp breath and all the muscles in her arms contract as she tenses to fire. But her finger won't do it. She lowers the gun very slowly. It drops to her side in one hand. All the breath and energy seems to go out of her. She weakly raises her other hand in a strange gesture, like "Stay where you are, don't move". As if, should they move, the fragile balance might tip back the other way. She backs away from them slowly, panting. It's as if she's backing away in terror from what she almost did. She reaches a wall and slumps against it. Slides down to her knees. The gun falls limply from her fingers. She rests her cheek against the wall. 136A The front door is kicked in. Terminator steps inside. John grabs his sleeve and pushes past him. He scopes out the situation in two seconds... Sarah, the gun, the sobbing family. John moves to Sarah while Terminator checks Dyson. John kneels in front of his mother. She raises her head to look at him. He sees the tears spilling down her cheeks,</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! SHUT UP!! Motherfucker! It's all your fault! IT'S YOUR FAULT!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom? You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't... oh, God.  You... came here... to stop me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches out and takes his shoulder suddenly, surprising him... drawing him to her. She hugs him and a great sob wells up deep inside her, from a spring she had thought long dry. She hugs him fiercely as the sobs wrack her. John clutches her shoulders. It is all he ever wanted.</context>
      <utterance>Uh huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. It'll by okay. We'll figure it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you, John. I always have.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TARISSA looks around at the bizarre tableau. Terminator has wordlessly ripped open Dyson's shirt and examined the wound.</context>
      <utterance>I know, Mom. I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes Tarissa's hands and presses them firmly over the entrance and exit wounds.</context>
      <utterance>Clean penetration. No shattered bone. Compression should control the loss of blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have bandages?</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John disengages from Sarah. She wipes her tears, the instinct to toughen up taking over again. But the healing moment has had its effect, nevertheless. John walks toward Dyson and Terminator.</context>
      <utterance>In the bathroom. Danny, can you get them for us? Danny nods and runs down the hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John draws the Biker's knife from Terminator's boot. Hands it to him.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you people?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator takes off his jacket to reveal bare arms. John takes Blythe by the hands and leads her down the hall, away from what is about to happen. 136B TIGHT ON TERMINATOR'S left forearm as the knife makes a deep cut just below the elbow. In one smooth motion, Terminator cuts all the way around his arm. With a second cut, he splits the skin of the forearm from elbow to wrist. TERMINATOR grasps the skin and strips is off his forearm like a surgeon rips off a rubber glove. It comes off with a sucking rip, leaving a bloody skeleton. But the skeleton is made of bright metal, and is laced with hydraulic actuators. The fingers are as finely crafted as watch parts... they flex into a fist and extend. Terminator holds it up, palm out, in almost the exact position of the one in the vault at Cyberdyne, HOLD ON DYSON reacting to the servo-hand in front of him. He's seen one of these before. Tarissa is screaming now, but he doesn't hear her.</context>
      <utterance>Show him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now listen to me very carefully.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dyson listened while the Terminator laid it all down. Skynet. Judgment Day... the history of things to come. It's not every day you find out you're responsible for 3 billion deaths. He took it pretty well, considering... Terminator finishes speaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around at them, clutching the table like he's about to blow away. His face, his posture, his ragged voice express soul-wrenching terror. This is a man ripped out of normal life into their grim world. His voice is pleading.</context>
      <utterance>I feel like I'M gonna throw up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah speaks from the shadows behind them. Dyson turns to find her looking right at him.</context>
      <utterance>You're judging me on thing's I haven't even done yet. Jesus. How were we supposed to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fucking men... all you know how to do is thrust into the world with your... fucking ideas and your weapons. Did you know that every gun in the world is named after a man? Colt, Browning, Smith, Thompson, Kalashnikov... all men. Men built the hydrogen bomb, not women... men like you thought it up. You're so creative. You don't know what it's like to really create something... to create a life. To feel it growing inside you. All you know how to create is death... you fucking bastards.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Right. How were you supposed to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, Mom, we need to be more constructive here. I don't see this as a gender-related issue.  She's still tense.  We still have to figure out how to stop it all from happening. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I thought... aren't we changing things? I mean... right now? Changing the way it goes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll sell real estate, I don't care,,,</context>
      <utterance>That's right! There's no way I'm going to finish the new processor now. Forget it. I'm out of it. I'm quitting Cyberdyne tomorrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dyson's voice is pitiful.</context>
      <utterance>That's not good enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, whatever you want me to do, I'll do. I just want my kids to have a chance to grow up, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one must follow your work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know about the chip?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What chip?</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They have it in a vault at Cyberdyne...  It's gotta be from the other one like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The CPU from the first terminator.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch, I knew it!</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They told us not to ask where they got it. I thought... Japan... hell, I don't know. I didn't want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those lying motherfuckers!</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was scary stuff, radically advanced. It was shattered... didn't work. But it gave us ideas, It took us in new directions... things we would never have thought of. All this work is based on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must be destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you get us in there, past security?</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dyson looks at her, Terminator, then John. Sees his answer.</context>
      <utterance>I think so, yeah. When?</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to his wife. Her face is streaked with tears, but her eyes are strong and clear. Tarissa puts her hands on his arm. She is stunned by what she's heard, but dealing with it. She believe them.</context>
      <utterance>Now?  Yeah, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARISSA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miles, I'm scared. Okay. But the only thing that scares me more than you going... is you not going. He nods. She's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it safe for them here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take your kids. Go to a hotel. Right now. Don't pack.  Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evening, Paul. These are friends of mine from out of town, I just thought I'd take them up and show them around.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>K-CHAK! Gibbons is staring down the barrels of Sarah's .45 and Terminator's MAC-10.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Mr. Dyson. You know the rules about visitors in the lab. I need written authoriz --</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard is too stunned to move. We see that Terminator is wearing his jacket and one black glove. Gibbon's eyes go to the silent alarm button on the console.</context>
      <utterance>I insist.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibbons nods. He stays frozen. Terminator circles quickly and gets the guard out of the chair. John pulls a roll of duct-tape from his knapsack and tears off a piece.</context>
      <utterance>Don't even think about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOSHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees the desk is deserted and frowns. Figures Gibbons must be in the can, so checks that first before getting alarmed. TRACKING WITH HIM to the restroom around the corner,</context>
      <utterance>Honey, I'm home...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSHIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>142A OVER HIS SHOULDER we see past the door as he pushes it open, revealing Gibbons handcuffed to the urinal. Moshier spins on a dime and sprints to the desk where he slams down on the silent alarm button.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, you shouldn't leave the --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dyson whips around, staring at a light flashing on the console behind him.</context>
      <utterance>What? WHAT IS IT?</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Silent alarm's been tripped. It neutralizes the codes throughout the building. Nothing'll open now. We see his nerve snapping.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should abort.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's right in his face. Somehow, it works for him. He nods, getting some resolve from somewhere.</context>
      <utterance>NO!! We're going all the way! You got that, Dyson?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>145A Dyson leads Terminator and Sarah to the main lab doors. Another servo-lock. He tries his card. Nothing.</context>
      <utterance>You guys get started on the lab... I can open this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He unslings the M-79, pulling it over his shoulder in one motion. Sarah grabs Dyson and drags him back down the hall. Terminator opens the breach and slide in one of the fat 40mm H.E. grenades. He flips the thing closed with a snap of the wrist.</context>
      <utterance>Let me try mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John drops what he is doing, and covers his ears. Terminator fires at inhumanely close range. 145B The door EXPLODES into kindling. The concussion blow his jacket open, and flying shrapnel whizzes all around him. Before the thunderclap has faded Terminator walks into the fire and smoke. John goes back to work without missing a beat. Sarah and a stunned Dyson walk through the burning doorframe into the Artificial Intelligence Lab. A SIREN is sounding. The HALON FIRE-CONTROL SYSTEM has been triggered. The invisible gas roars in, putting out the flames.</context>
      <utterance>John! Fire-in-the-hole!</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dyson runs to a wall cabinet and pulls out some BREATHING MASKS. He hands one to Sarah and dons the other. Then he reaches out to hand one to Terminator.</context>
      <utterance>Fire's set off the halo system! Here... hurry!</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator doesn't need a mask, since is oxygen requirements are so low. He ignores Dyson as he removes his massive backpack and opens it. Dyson shrugs and tosses the mask on a desk. He turns to Sarah.</context>
      <utterance>Here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, all that stuff! And all the disks in those offices. Especially my office... everything in my office!  These, too! This is important.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode>SMASH!</mode>
      <context>148B Sarah goes into Dyson's office and starts hurling everything out the door onto the central junkpile... books, files, everything on the desk. A FRAMED PHOTO of Dyson's wife and kids lands on top of the heap. Tarissa, hugging Danny and Blythe, all grinning. The glass is shattered. 148C Terminator cuts a swath, under Dyson's direction, exploding equipment into fragments with his inhuman swings. SMASH! It's carnage. Millions in hardware, and all irreplaceable fruits of their years of research... shattered, broken, dumped in a heap for the big bonfire of destiny. Dyson stops a second, panting.</context>
      <utterance>And all this here... that's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator hands him the axe. Dyson hefts it one-handed. He turns to a lab table... on it is another prototype processor.</context>
      <utterance>Give me that thing a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Swinging awkwardly but with great force he smashes the axe down onto the processor prototype, exploding it into fragments. His shoulder is agony, but he looks satisfied.</context>
      <utterance>I've worked for years on this thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator shows him a REMOTE DETONATOR, a small transmitter with a red plunger.</context>
      <utterance>How do you set them off?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes a plunger-pushing motion with his thumb and an accompanying "click" sound. Dyson nods. Just then John comes running in, holding up the key.</context>
      <utterance>Radio remote.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it. Piece of cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They run out as the SOUND OF SIRENS grow louder outside.</context>
      <utterance>Go! I'll finish here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll deal with the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember what I said, you can't...</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready to rock?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John tosses her the metal hand. She catches it and bends to put the hand in her empty back-pack. Sarah zips the pack and starts to shuck into it. Dyson's running out of steam. The bandages at his shoulder are soaked with seeping blood. He stands in the middle of the lab, saying goodbye in his mind, looking weak and empty. Terminator strides into the lab.</context>
      <utterance>Ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and John head back the way they came, through security. Sarah sees that in her work, she has set the detonator down twenty feet away, near where Dyson is standing.</context>
      <utterance>Time to go. Right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gingerly picks up the detonator. Starts toward her. Then --</context>
      <utterance>Dyson, hand me the detonator. Let's go --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator grabs him as bullets slam into his broad back. He makes it around the corner with John, out of the line of fire. 162 IN THE LAB, bullets rake over Sarah's head, smacking all around her, clanging into the machine protecting her. She can see Dyson, slumped on the floor. Debris and flying glass rain on her as the SWATs pour on the fire. The detonator is clutched in his hand. He rolls to face her, his eyes bulging from the pain of his torn-up guts.</context>
      <utterance>Mommm!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>162A Sarah hesitates a split second. Then she snap-rolls and fast-crawls through broken glass and debris into the hall where -- TERMINATOR grabs her by the jacket and hauls her roughly to her feet. Bullets rake the walls behind them as they sprint forward. They round the corner. John does a fast take that she's not hit and they run together through the security checkpoint.</context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls a grenade from the bandolier over his shoulder, and slides it into the bore. Flick his wrist. The breech snaps shut. Sarah and John have a split second to duck and cover.</context>
      <utterance>Get back.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>163A They do. KABOOM!!! Twenty feet away the door, and half the wall around it, EXPLODES outward. The backblast hits Terminator full force, but he strides through the smoking hole before the debris has even hit the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Cover you ears and open you mouth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DYSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SWAT Leader seems to see the wires, the claymores, the gas cans all around him for the first time. His eyes, visible through his gas- mask, go very wide. He spins and motions his squad back.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know... how much longer... I can... hold this thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fall back!! Everybody out! Move it! OUT</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slings the grenade launcher over his shoulder and walks out into the corridor. 173B BLAM. A tear-gas grenade ricochets from wall to wall as it flies down the corridor. It skids to rest in front of Terminator, throwing out a white cloud which quickly fills the corridor. 173C In the elevator, Sarah and John are choking, handing the breathing mask back and forth desperately. They're scarred. This looks like it. 173D ANGLE ON THE SWAT TEAM, gripping their weapons at the mouth of the corridor. They watch the boiling cloud, waiting. 173E THEIR POV -- on the wall of boiling smoke. A FIGURE APPEARS. Walking Totally unaffected. Terminator emerges from the smoke. Not even misty-eyed. Not what they expected.</context>
      <utterance>Keep your eyes closed. Don't move.  I'll be back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They OPEN FIRE. The corridor is filled with CRACKING THUNDER. The rounds tear into Terminator's chest. Stomach. Face. Thighs. His leather jacket leaps and jerks as the rounds hit him. The SWATs think the guy's wearing body armor or something. They keep firing. The rounds tear into him, staggering him slightly, but he keeps moving.</context>
      <utterance>Drop him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not hitting him!</utterance>
   <speaker>SWAT #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator draws his .45 smoothly. Unhurried. He shoots the nearest man in the left thigh. As he screams and drops, Terminator shoots him in the right thigh. Terminator bends down and picks up the shrieking man's weapon... the TEAR-GAS LAUNCHER. It is one of those new rotary jobs that hold 12 rounds in a big drum. Terminator shoots the next SWAT in the chest with the tear-gas launcher. The gas canister hits the guy's body armor and doesn't penetrate. But it's like getting slugged in the stomach with a full- swing from a baseball bat. The SWAT fold double and hits the tiles, gasping. Terminator is an image from Hell, a tall figure in shredded black leather, streaked with blood. One eye is a bloody socket, the metal eye-servo glistening. The flesh of one cheek hangs down in tatters, revealing the chrome cheekbone beneath. The whole front of his jacket is blown open, revealing his metal armor chest. The remaining SWATs start to fall back. One turns to run and -- KPOW! A gas canister nail him in the back, sending him sprawling. 173F Terminator fires three gas canisters into the lobby. It fills rapidly with the white gas, cutting the visibility to a few feet. It is total pandemonium. SWAT LEADER crouches in the fog, white- knuckling the rifle. Terminator looms suddenly out of the mist right in front of him. POOM! Terminator drills him in the leg with the .45. As the guy screams and drops rifle to clutch his leg, Terminator rips his gas mask off. The SWAT leader drops writhing to the floor, choking and gagging, clutching his bleeding thigh. Terminator walks up to two SWATs at the front doors. POW-POW. Leg and leg. He snatches their masks as they fall. The gunfire has stopped. Nobody an see anything. Screams and whimpers echo in the smoke.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I am!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drive for a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator slams the shattered windshield with the palm of his hand. Held together by the plastic laminate, the windshield flops out of its frame. It flies over the top of the truck. 191E Terminator pushes his upper body out over the dashboard and stands up. He turns and aims the M-79 one-handed. 191F POOM! The grenade misses the T-1000 by less than a foot. It EXPLODES against the front bulkhead of the tanker, almost at the top. Liquid nitrogen pours from the opening, swept back by the 60-mph windstream. 191G The big-rig swerves as T-1000 regains control. The tanker swings like a pendulum behind the cab. 191H The pickup accelerates, getting back out in front by a few yards. Behind it the big-rig is trailing a swirling comet-tail of nitrogen vapor. It is gaining again. Terminator, still standing, opens the breech and starts to reload. 191I John cuts across the highway and takes an OFF RAMP. 191J T-1000 swerves the smoking behemoth across the lanes and down the ramp after him, still accelerating. It is twenty feet behind them and closing when Terminator closes the breech and FIRES. 191K The grenade hits the front grill and EXPLODES. The radiator is destroyed, along with half the hood. Steam blasts out, obscuring the whole front of the truck. 191L The semi rams the back of the pickup again. Spewing smoke and vapor like some demon locomotive, the tractor-trailer pounds into the back of the pickup. Driving it right through the intersection at the bottom of the ramp, and straight toward --</context>
      <utterance>Where you going?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>194G K-POW! The single shot blows the T-1000 into a million diamonds spraying up into the air. They shimmer across the ground for twenty feet in all directions. Terminator lowers the gun, satisfied. He looks like he needs a vacation. 195 JOHN AND SARAH have seen it from the pickup. She is in bad shape. Conscious but very weak. He tries the door. It's jammed. He kicks it open.</context>
      <utterance>Hasta la vista, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He helps her slide down from the seat of the truck. Her knees give way. John has to take a lot of her weight. He reaches in and picks up the riot gun off the seat. They hobble toward -- 195A TERMINATOR. On his knees, he looks into the dissipating cloud of vapor. The heat of the furnaces has evaporated all the liquid nitrogen. 196 INSERT, TIGHT ON THE FLOOR - the T-1000 shards are melting, liquefying. Hundreds of drops of mercury, spattered across the floor. Orange light of the enormous black-furnaces dances on liquid metal. 197 TERMINATOR struggles to rise. One arm is shattered, the hand smashed and useless. And some leg-servos are damaged. He can barely stand. John and Sarah arrive.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Mom, we gotta get out now, come on. That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have much time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator points. John and Sarah watch as -- 198 INSERT, T-1000 DROPLETS are creeping together. Fusing into larger blobs. These pools shiver and run together, soon forming a central mass. 199 ON JOHN AND SARAH, realizing it's not over.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator gets one of Sarah's arms over his shoulder and they go. BEHIND THEM, something is moving. 200 A HEAD is forming up out of a pool mercury. it rises, as shoulders form. hunching up from the liquid mass. Half-formed, it turns to look straight at them. John looks back in new terror as -- The T-1000 rises to man-height. It is still in mercury form, but its features are forming rapidly. It takes its first step after them. Sarah stumbles and they pull her up. 201 Terminator himself has a pronounces limp, dragging one leg with a shattered ankle joint. John's the one pulling, straining, driving them forward. They round a corner into --</context>
      <utterance>Come on! Let's go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Onto a landing next to one of the SMELTER CRUCIBLES. Molten steel glows bright orange in the crucible of the furnace. Heat shimmers the air, giving everything a hallucinatory quality. John sees Sarah nearby, limping toward him. She can barely move, her leg bathed in blood. He runs toward her.</context>
      <utterance>John? John? Can you hear me? Where are you? 208A He crawls out of the shadows.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIGHT ON SARAH, her stoic face, as she hobbles forward, reaching out to him. Something rises behind her, OUT OF FOCUS. 209 ANOTHER, IDENTICAL, SARAH... but this one has a shotgun. Aimed right at us. 209A JOHN freezes. Which is which? He looks down. The first Sarah's feet are melded with the floor, sucking and fusing with the tiles as she walks. They have the color and pattern of the tiles up to the knee.</context>
      <utterance>Help me, honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, get out of the way!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk to the edge of the pit. Terminator looks down and sees that it is over.</context>
      <utterance>I need a vacation.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John unzips Sarah's backpack and takes out the hand of the first terminator.</context>
      <utterance>Terminated.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will it melt in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Throw it in.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He does. It sinks into the lava. Vanishes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John takes it out of his pocket. Looks at it. Tosses it into the smelter.</context>
      <utterance>And the chip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's finally over.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches a metal finger to the side of his head.</context>
      <utterance>No. There is another chip.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator looks at Sarah. They both know what must be done. John shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>And it must be destroyed also. John suddenly understands what he means.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no no!! It'll be okay. Stay with us!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go away, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The human side of his face is in shadow, so we see mostly the chrome skull and the red eye.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do it. Please... don't go -- Tears are streaming down his face. TIGHT CLOSEUP TERMINATOR, turning toward John.</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must end here... or I am the future.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terminator puts his hand on John's shoulder. He moves slightly and the human side of his face comes into the light. He reaches toward John's face. His metal finger touches the tear trickling down his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>I order you not to!</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah looks at Terminator. Reaches out her hand to shake it. They lock eyes. Warriors. Comrades.</context>
      <utterance>I know now why you cry. But it is something I can never do.  Goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you afraid?</utterance>
   <speaker>TERMINATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and steps off the edge. 213 They watch him sink into the lava. He disappears... the metal hand sinking last... at the last second it forms into a fist with the thumb extended... a final thumbs up. Then it is gone. 214 HOLD ON JOHN AND SARAH, watching through the heat ripples as we --</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>A CARD APPEARS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE BOOM DOWN AND TRACK LATERALLY through a playground in the foreground. Children swinging on swings. Sliding down slides. Timeless things that 4 decades of technical advancement will not change. As we track we hear:</context>
      <utterance>July 11, 2029</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We pass a jungle gym, neither melted nor burned, but full of kids swinging and yelling raucously. Past it we drop down to see a boy pumping the pedals of a tricycle.</context>
      <utterance>August 29th 1997 came and went. Nothing much happened. Michael Jackson turned forty. There was no Judgment Day. People went to work as they always do, laughed, complained, watched TV, made love.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>STILL TRACKING we come to rest on an elderly woman seated on a bench. It is SARAH, now 64 years old. The world has aged her, but she seems at peace in this moment. She speaks into a microcassette recorder.</context>
      <utterance>I wanted to run down the street yelling... to grab them all and say "Every day form this day is a gift. Use it well!" Instead I got drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>There is a man in is forties playing with two small children nearby. He turns. It is John Connor. Through he has the same stern features in adulthood, there is no eye-patch, no scarring. He is far from the haggard man on grim destiny we saw in the world that might have been. But there is still penetrating intelligence, even wisdom, in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>That was thirty years ago. But the dark future which never came still exists for me, and it always will, like the traces of a dream lingering in the morning light. And the war against the machines goes on. Or, to be more precise, the war against those who build the wrong machines.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A FOUR-YEAR-OLD GIRL runs to her to have her shoelace tied.</context>
      <utterance>John fights the war differently than it was foretold. Here, on the battlefield of the Senate, the weapons are common sense... and hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grandma Sarah smiles. It is the only time we have seen her smile so far. She bends as the little girls puts her foot up on the bench. She ties as we hear:</context>
      <utterance>Tie me, grandma.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Sarah ruffles the kids's hair as she runs off to play with her dad.</context>
      <utterance>The luxury of hope was given to me by the Terminator. Because if a machine can learn the value of human life... maybe we can too.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
