<movie id="607" title="World is not Enough The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LACHAISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not the usual Swiss procedure, Mr. Bond, but you understand, a man in my position..</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lachaise takes the joke a little tight-lipped. Gestures for Bond to sit. A GIRL ENTERS, a gorgeous Swiss bombshell in a pin-striped suit. She pushes a cart. On it are a BRIEFCASE and a box of EXPENSIVE CIGARS, which she offers to Lachaise and Bond.</context>
      <utterance>Which is neutral, no doubt.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACHAISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The efficient Cigar Girl brings the briefcase to Bond, setting it in his lap and opening it up...inside is a good deal of CASH in pound sterling.</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't easy, but I retrieved the money. No doubt Sir Robert will be pleased to see it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACHAISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CIGAR GIRL offers Bond a RECEIPT...</context>
      <utterance>In the current exchange rate, minus the fees, of course, and certain unforeseeable expenses. Here is the receipt...</utterance>
   <speaker>CIGAR GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to check my figures?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps back. Bond reaches for the metal case on the desk...the THUGS TENSE...</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps later.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lachaise nods. Bond can have his glasses. He puts them on, gives a cursory look at the receipt...an odd number in pound sterling, calculated down to the penny:</context>
      <utterance>My glasses.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LACHAISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond folds the receipt, slips it into his WALLET...then, he removes the glasses, slowly, deliberately, eyeing Lachaise.</context>
      <utterance>It's all there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a photo from his jacket and lays it on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't come for the money. The report you sold him was stolen from an MI-6 agent, who was killed for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACHAISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did not get the report from an MI-6 agent.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did you get it from?</utterance>
   <speaker>LACHAISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am just a middle man. I am doing the honourable thing and returning the money to its rightful owner...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we know how difficult that can be for the Swiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACHAISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your last chance. Take the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your last chance. Give me the name.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACHAISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. An Armani thug steps up and takes out a gun...</context>
      <utterance>Stripped of all your weaponry, you still threaten me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond's mouth edges into a smile. A flicker of doubt on Lachaise's face -- as Bond's finger finds a protrusion on the tiny arm of his glasses and... KABOOM! The pistol on the table FLASHES...blinding those around, they cover their eyes, stagger back...it is a brief effect, just enough to disorient the thugs and give Bond his opening... He KARATE-CHOPS HENCHMAN 1 unconscious, taking his gun. Kicks HENCHMEN 2 in the face and throws 3 OUT THE WINDOW just as they're getting their bearings. Now he nestles the barrel of his borrowed hand gun into the hollow of Lachaise's cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you failed to take into account my...hidden assets.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name?</utterance>
   <speaker>LACHAISE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alright, alright! But you must protect me! And he freezes. The handle of a THROWING KNIFE is sticking out of his neck. Bond looks up, catches sight of the CIGAR GIRL as she vaults out the broken window and onto THE ROOF. Bond rushes to the window...</context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his name? Our friend from MI-6?</utterance>
   <speaker>CIGAR GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>James Bond.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of M's more accomplished tin soldiers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CIGAR GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He could identify me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches her cheek and moves into the room, pouring two glasses of wine.</context>
      <utterance>If it concerns you...kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's toast this James Bond. We're in his hands now...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MONEYPENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He produces the cigar, now in a large phallic TUBE. Stands it end up on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>James. Brought me a souvenir from Geneva?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought you might want one of these.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONEYPENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gave up a long time ago.  She's in with Sir Robert.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>King moves toward Bond with an easy, patrician smile. Bond notes a TINY BADGE in his lapel -- like the glass eye of a stuffed snake.</context>
      <utterance>Sir Robert King, James Bond.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for getting my money back --never expected to see it again. You're the kind of man I could use. Though I won't offend certain parties by asking you to join King Industries. King looks to M, smiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Construction's not exactly my line.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She couldn't resist. King smiles at Bond. As he goes, he gives M a respectful kiss on the cheek. The door closes. M turns.</context>
      <utterance>Quite the opposite, in fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since Oxford. I knew him when he had nothing but a brilliant mind and enough guts to conquer the world. He's a man of great integrity.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M picks up the report from her desk. Bond notices it is in Russian, with a SEAL from a Russian military agency in the corner: MIRATOM.</context>
      <utterance>Who buys classified reports for three million pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pours a scotch for Bond. He drops some ice in, thoughtful.</context>
      <utterance>It's a report on weapons security in the former Soviet Union, which, as you know, is shaky at best. He's had several instances of sabotage at the pipeline, and he's understandably concerned. He called me the moment he realized its sensitive nature.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops, rubs his thumb and forefinger together -- a strange SIZZLING where he touched the ice. Realization sinks in.</context>
      <utterance>Someone was watching over me in Geneva. A guardian angel with a laser sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M sees the seriousness in his eyes -- stabs at the intercom:</context>
      <utterance>King.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moneypenny, stop King leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONEYPENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Security --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>Q</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up as Bond runs through...</context>
      <utterance>..the hydro boat can operate in three inches of water...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIR ROBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, but I'll count it myself.  Lifetime habit. I'm Scottish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beautiful, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps up to the ridge with him. A breeze blows her hair. They stare out. The sun's rays have broken the clouds and strafe the valley.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Today, of all days, the sun decides to shine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps Sir Robert had a word with the Man Upstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A word? I'm sure by now he's engineered a hostile takeover.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sun glints off her bejewelled earlobe.</context>
      <utterance>You knew him well?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A voice interrupts them, calling from the estate...</context>
      <utterance>He died before he could complete his lifelong dream.  I intend to finish it for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elektra!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks away, the wind pressing her dress against her delicate figure. She looks brave and vulnerable as she walks back toward her father's grand house.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elektra? Running King Industries?  I've known that girl all her life. I'm not sure she knows what she's walking into.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M looks at Bond. Eyes his sling.</context>
      <utterance>She's not a girl anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've scheduled a medical for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's barely a scratch. The Dome broke my fall.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, at least it turned out to have some purpose. Bond gives her a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No-one goes into the field on this unless they're 100%. Dr. Greatrex is waiting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DOCTOR GREATREX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dislocated collar bone. If any more tendons snap...  It won't just be two weeks out of action.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves to him, touches the scarred and bruised bone.</context>
      <utterance>I need you to pass me fit now, Molly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just a scratch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR GREATREX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand comes up, rests on her waist.</context>
      <utterance>James. It wouldn't really be...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he pulls down the zip on her skirt. Flicks the clasp and it drops to the floor. She shakes her head -- as he starts undoing the buttons on her shirt. She's very business-like, despite what's happening.</context>
      <utterance>Ethical? Can't we just skirt the issue?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR GREATREX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...if you showed sufficient...willpower. Promised to slow down. Cut out running, jumping...shooting. All kinds of... And he pulls her toward him, they kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her shirt drops to the floor. She pushes him back, lies on him. Just wearing knickers now. Between kisses:</context>
      <utterance>Strenuous activity?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR GREATREX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then maybe I'd be... open to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps after this ... test?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR GREATREX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...yes?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could come for a second opinion?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When he came within range of the money -- boom. Ingenious. M steps forward. Her fury controlled.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been pawns in someone's game. They tricked us into bringing the money to King. Not just elaborate. Cock-sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the chandelier darkens, the floor brightens into a VAST SCREEN, showing a satellite image of Central Asia and the Mediterranean. M and Robinson walk onto the screen.</context>
      <utterance>And expensive. Cost three million plus.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She causes the desired stir. Bond steps forward from the shadows to get a better view. M sees the sling has gone.</context>
      <utterance>Cheap, if it achieves your aim of de- stabilizing the Western World.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>007. What do you know of the Caspian Sea?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stalin beat him to it.</context>
      <utterance>Caviar capital of the world. Matchless beluga. Firm, yet subtle.  Largest landlocked body of water on Earth. Oil-rich. Hitler wanted it.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Far more oil than anyone thought.</context>
      <utterance>And now it's up for grabs, a goldrush.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Latest estimates, six trillion dollars. It'll make the Gulf look like a puddle, see us right through the new century. The problem is getting the oil out of there.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are four pipelines in the works. Three to the Black Sea, shipping out through the Bosphorus. All vulnerable to unstable governments or Russian blockade.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Sir Robert's goes through Turkey, direct to the Med...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A huge project. The most expensive of the pipelines, but the one supported by every Western leader. None of the American oil companies were willing to take it on. But King has connections to the region. He married into the Vavra family, rich local industrialists. He used those connections to hold it all together.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill the man, kill the pipeline.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tanner notices a RED LIGHT start pulsing. He moves to M:</context>
      <utterance>Not necessarily. Not with Elektra taking over.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M nods grimly. As Robinson distributes sealed envelopes:</context>
      <utterance>Your call to the PM.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They open their envelopes, but Bond received nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Our credibility has been hit hard. We have to hit back harder. Your assignments.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves. Bond is brooding.</context>
      <utterance>I'm waiting for the report on your medical.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns, her brow furrowing.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me about the kidnapping of Elektra King.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you to look at Elektra's files?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took the initiative.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't been given an assignment in this case.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was the one who brought that money in...</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm well aware of your stake in this,</utterance>
   <speaker>007.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you have a point, get to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands her a slip of paper.</context>
      <utterance>The amount of money that killed Robert King is the same amount as the ransom demand for Elektra.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever kidnapped Elektra is the same man who killed her father. M looks at the paper, a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a message. He wants us to know he's back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Claude Serrault. A.K.A...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Renard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir Robert tried to deal with the kidnapping with his own...resources, at first. When Elektra's ear was delivered to him in the post, he came to me.  I advised against paying the ransom. I knew it was Renard. I played it out as long as possible to get a fix on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sacrifice the girl to take out the terrorist?</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to the hologram.</context>
      <utterance>How many deaths is he responsible for? How many innocent people? You may only get one shot at a man like Renard. Same circumstances, I'd do the same again.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond moves toward the ghostly Renard. We now see THE BULLET</context>
      <utterance>We sent 009 down to kill him. Before he could, Elektra escaped. A week later our man caught up with the target. Put a bullet in his head.  That bullet is still there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He survived?</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The doctor who saved him couldn't get it out, so Renard killed him. When Interpol found the x-rays, there was mild jubilation. Effectively, he's a dead man. She presses a button, the hologram turns...</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bullet is moving through the medulla oblongata, killing off his sense of touch. He feels no pain. He can push himself harder, longer than any normal man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'That which does not kill me makes me stronger.'</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Robert is dead. He got his revenge.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MONEYPENNY ENTERS with a file, which she hands to M. M looks over the file: his medical report.</context>
      <utterance>He's not through yet. Renard doesn't blow up five million dollars unless he knows there's more coming in. He's working for someone. Someone who wants to stop the pipeline. And they hired the perfect killer. One with a vendetta against King...and you.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see the good doctor gave you glowing testimonials. 'Exceptional stamina'...</utterance>
   <speaker>MONEYPENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moneypenny disappears out the door. M is all business.</context>
      <utterance>He's always been good at oral exams.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out to the pipeline. Find the insider who switched the pin. If your instincts are right, Renard will be back. He hasn't completed the job. The pipeline is still going forward, and we have Elektra to thank for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They exchange a look. A look of recognition between two professionals, who know the terrible price of what they do.</context>
      <utterance>The worm on the hook again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scottish heavy metal, Q?</utterance>
   <speaker>Q</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(irritated, hands over a WATCH) Your 29th. Try not to lose this one. It has dual lasers and a miniature grappling hook with fifty feet of high-tensile micro-filament, able to support 800 pounds. In the background, we see a man in a sleek black jacket. The man PULLS A STRING...the jacket becomes AN AIRBAG...it envelopes him, he gets impossibly tangled in it. Q ignores it, handing Bond a new pair of GLASSES.</context>
      <utterance>Oh pipe down, 007.</utterance>
   <speaker>Q</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For checking concealed weapons.</context>
      <utterance>New refinement. Sort of X-ray vision.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And other uses, no doubt.</utterance>
   <speaker>Q</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He presses a button and a section of ceiling lowers to reveal a BMW Z7. A MAN in a white coat is loading A MISSILE into one of the headlamps, then steps off the platform. Q gestures to him.</context>
      <utterance>Abuses in your case. You destroyed my hydro-boat in less than seven minutes, as no doubt will be the case with this...</utterance>
   <speaker>Q</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>007, my Deputy Assistant. I'm grooming him to follow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would make you..."R"?</utterance>
   <speaker>R</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahh, the rampant 007 wit. I, of course, am laughing inside. But I dare say you've met your match in this machine.  The absolute latest in intercepts, surveillance and countermeasures. Titanium plating and armor, a multi- tasking heads-up display. Completely indestructible. All in all, rather stocked.</utterance>
   <speaker>Q</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"R" pats the fender, he's pretty damned fond of his machine.</context>
      <utterance>'Fully loaded' I think is the term.</utterance>
   <speaker>R</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do take good care of her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Davidov ignores him, looking the gun over.</context>
      <utterance>I'd rather you didn't play with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond turns to watch a LIFTING HELICOPTER swoop in and drop down an air-conditioned office. Military precision. Davidov's radio crackles out a message and he tosses the gun back to Bond. They start walking:</context>
      <utterance>Quite stunning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...they should have been in place two days ago. That is the target my father set.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've had some trouble with the villagers at Ruan. Some sacred burial plot...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up...a brief moment of RECOGNITION...then back to business.</context>
      <utterance>Miss King...James Bond here to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find me the research on the limestone deposits, go ahead and place these orders, and get the jeep ready. I will go to Ruan myself...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss King, I wouldn't recommend...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She signs some documents and the men file out. She gets up, turning her back to Bond, hands on her hips.</context>
      <utterance>I said, I will go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Davidov nods and leaves. Elektra still keeps her back turned, but he can see her physically change, her shoulders sag, her arms cross in front of her. When she finds her voice, it has a gravelly sound of emotion.</context>
      <utterance>Would you excuse us, Davidov?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I met you at my father's funeral.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't been able to recall a single moment of that day...until now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funerals aren't exactly memorable.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God no. All those horrible loved ones and relatives. I don't want to talk to those people. I just want to...talk to my father.  I loved him. I'm not sure he knew that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that why you want to finish the pipeline?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her muscleman BODY GUARD appears, says briefly:</context>
      <utterance>Partially, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The jeep is ready, Ma'am. Will I be driving with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabor glares at Bond before he leaves.</context>
      <utterance>No, Gabor. We have a guest.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My bodyguard. He follows me everywhere. He's decisive, vigilant. And he makes an excellent omelette.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long has he been with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond takes something out of his pocket, he opens his palm, shows it to her.</context>
      <utterance>Since the kidnapping. Why do you ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does this look familiar to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swallows back emotion. Looks in his eyes, with a sad half- smile that unsettles him.</context>
      <utterance>It's my father's pin. He wore it everyday of his life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you trying to break my heart? Or is it just your way with women?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not the pin your father wore. It's an exact duplicate. Inside is a tiny electrical detonator. We have reason to believe the assassin had an inside accomplice, someone who worked at this company.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you've come here to look after me, Mr. Bond, thank you, but no thank you. I have two bodyguards, I don't need a third... She starts to walk out. He follows her...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The killer doesn't want to see this pipeline continue, doesn't want to see you take over...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's every man within a five mile radius. Including you.  That's why you're here, isn't it? You think I can't do it. You think I'm going to screw up. Or get myself killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think running this pipeline would be a difficult job for anyone. Especially King's daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are wrong, Mr. Bond. In fact, I am the only person who can do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Send the pipe around.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Your father approved this route.</context>
      <utterance>It will take weeks, cost millions.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The first time Elektra has asserted her own authority. The foreman is surprised, angry. But he doesn't question her. She moves toward the helicopter, says to Bond:</context>
      <utterance>Then my father was wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to check the upper lines. Gabor will drive you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Always wanted to see the upper lines.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't take no for an answer, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs, mischief in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond just smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Alright then. Do you ski?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been known to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't land. Wind's too strong!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps into her skis, opens the door. Wind rushes in.</context>
      <utterance>Just hold her steady.  You wanted to see it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God...we're buried alive...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But her breath is coming in short, irregular bursts.</context>
      <utterance>We're alright.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond takes a knife from a sheath around his ankle. Flicks open the small blade. He starts to cut a hole in the snow above their heads. She stops him.</context>
      <utterance>You're not going to.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! It will cave in!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The snow CREAKS eerily, she gasps, terror mounting.</context>
      <utterance>It's the only way out...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond grabs her, holds her tight. She resists, bucks.</context>
      <utterance>I can't breathe, I can't breathe...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, arrested by the strength in his eyes, she calms...</context>
      <utterance>Elektra, look at me, look in my eyes!  You're alright. Everything will be alright. Trust me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. He is wound tight, she senses it.</context>
      <utterance>Are you alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waits.</context>
      <utterance>I need to ask you something. And I need you to tell me the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond looks at her; vulnerable, fragile, trying to be strong. He cannot tell her the truth.</context>
      <utterance>Who is it? Who is trying to kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him, sensing he is withholding something. She turns back to the window. He approaches behind her.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. But I will find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After the kidnapping...I was afraid to go outside, to be alone, to be in a crowd, to do anything at all, until I realized...  There's no point in living if you can't...feel alive. She looks out at the fading sun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>I can't huddle in the shadows. I can't let fear run my life. I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The way I acted, in the snow...you must think I'm a coward.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up at him, into his eyes; they are so close. All she has to do is tilt her mouth upward...she kisses him. His hands come up across her back, pressing her toward him, her body melting into his, and then... He pulls back. Has to physically step away from her.</context>
      <utterance>I think you're one of the bravest people I've ever met.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That was exactly the wrong thing to say. He sees the rebellion flair in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>...you should rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>James...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then take me with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You'll be safe here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to be safe!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>I have to go to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops, his back up...then heads out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Now who's the coward?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valentin Zukovsky.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>BondJamesBond. What brings you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, of course. I need some information.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bond, I'm a civilian. This is my place. Used to be the royal family's, now it's mine. I run my little business, I stay out of trouble...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mafia warlords, Diplomats and spies, consortiums from every country in the world. A nice little rat's nest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to a suspicious-looking Heavy.</context>
      <utterance>Have some of the rat's nest caviar. From my own fishery. They buy my caviar, drink my champagne, lose to my House.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Boa is completely bald, muscular; huge, deadly hands.</context>
      <utterance>Let me introduce you to a former colleague of mine at the KGB. Dmitri Palov, you may know him as...the Boa.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The great 007. For years I have dreamed of closing my hands around your neck.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boa. Have you had any therapy since Perestroika?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Boa leaves, glaring all the while.</context>
      <utterance>Why am I suddenly worried I'm not carrying enough insurance?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you want?</context>
      <utterance>See? You're upsetting my customers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does a terrorist like Renard supply his men with state-of-the-art Russian Army weapons?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond takes from his pocket the fragment of the PARACHUTE. Zukovsky examines the letters.</context>
      <utterance>What? This is not possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I remember my Cyrillic that says 101st airborne division.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you get this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zukovsky shakes his head. Sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Off a high-powered Paraski that was trying to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He notices Bond watching THE HOSTESS BAR...a dark alcove of the casino, where slinky HOOKERS flatter the guests.</context>
      <utterance>The Russian Army, they spend millions on flying skis, but they cannot afford to pay the soldiers. The men, they do what they have to do to feed their families. In this country, for the right price and a pack of cigarettes, you can get anything you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That too. Everyone does what they can to survive.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How high up does this...arms dealing go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bond. If someone wants you dead, it is Renard. Our government has nothing to gain by killing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This hits Zukovsky. He closes down. A chill between them.</context>
      <utterance>But you would have something to gain by killing Robert King. And stopping his pipeline.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond's eyes catch something, someone entering the casino. HIS POV: ELEKTRA...more vibrant than we have ever seen her, living up to her name. She is impossibly glamorous in a sparkling dress that fits like second skin. Her hair is full and tumbling, her eyes are fiery and wild.</context>
      <utterance>Poor Bond. The cold war is over. What have you got left? Economic espionage. Murder in the boardroom. So dull.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond starts toward her, but she tosses her head, defiant, and turns away, making her way to the Roulette tables. Bond follows her across the casino. They are like two cats, moving through this neon jungle, their energy dangerous and sexy, all eyes on them. He takes note as she passes...MINIMUM $100, then $500, $1000... She finally stops at the 'No limit' table. Crowded with the nastiest and richest of the high rollers, Armenians, Turks, South Americans, a computer nerd American and a Russian industrialist's wife, heavy with jewelry and drink. ZUKOVSKY is suddenly there, pulling out a seat for her in the center.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you'd be surprised.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've kept your father's chair free.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And his account?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures to the Dealer, who pushes ten towering stacks of CHIPS toward her. A WAITRESS is right there to take her order.</context>
      <utterance>You have a credit line of a million and a half.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vodka martini.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans in, smiling his charming smile as he says:</context>
      <utterance>Two. Shaken not stirred.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to a SHOW GIRL in a feather headdress and pasties.</context>
      <utterance>Someone wants to kill me, I'd rather die looking him straight in the eye.  What are you doing here? Looking for a woman a little more your type? How about that one?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If this little show is for my benefit, I'll take you home right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes half her chips back onto the table, letting them stand on her bet. The whole table exhales. Then, it starts: bets are placed, gamblers energized by her arrival. Bond scans the room, vigilant, nervous... HIS P.O.V. He zeroes in on Davidov, sidling off, away from the table, trying to look nonchalant, his eyes shifting this way and that...he looks suspicious as hell. Bond watches, his blood running, and then... Davidov slips into the HOSTESS BAR. A HOOKER is soon wrapping herself around him. After a few words, she leads him off toward the back. Bond returns to the game, shaking his head. He watches as</context>
      <utterance>You had your chance, James. Now I'm looking for a bigger thrill.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to be...on top, or not on top?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slowly pulls a pair of SILK ROPES out from her bra and</context>
      <utterance>On top.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Davidov smiles, struggling with his belt. He looks down, gets it, looks up...his heart stops...it is not the hooker in the mirror but...</context>
      <utterance>Tied up, or not tied up?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD'S FRIGHTENING FACE.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HIS P.O.V. Renard's henchman stands by the door, an automatic rifle cocked at Davidov.</context>
      <utterance>Davidov spins.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead, or not dead?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand it's normally good practice to get the feel of the cards before going off the deep end.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with a smile she scratches her cards on the table for a hit. The Dealer gives her an eight. She reveals her cards.</context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rakes in her chips. But Elektra is undeterred. She pushes another pile forward as the next deal commences.</context>
      <utterance>Bust.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like the deep end, James.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this how you spend the money I pay you? And with the rest you hire fools who shoot like blind men?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bond...</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He approaches close to him, stopping at the flaming SCONCE near his head.</context>
      <utterance>Should be dead as well. Your failure today is astonishing. It is a disgrace.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know why the color is blue at the wick? Davidov starts to sweat.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renard touches the glass well of oil.</context>
      <utterance>Because that is where the flame is the hottest.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renard uses his knife and POPS the seal from the lamp, removing the well of oil...a DROP of the hot oil FALLS ON HIS HAND and SINGES IT BLACK in an instant... Renard does not even flinch. Davidov starts talking, trying to placate...</context>
      <utterance>The temperature is close to five hundred degrees.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The plane...it's all been arranged...</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renard raises the container of oil over Davidov's head:</context>
      <utterance>Then you are completely unnecessary...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renard stops, the oil tilted, just ready to pour... His dead eye...has it drooped further since we last saw him?...seems to glitter in the light...</context>
      <utterance>I have the documents, the landing authorizations, the security passes...</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bond is suspicious. We are moving sooner, tonight. We understand each other?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renard lets a TRICKLE OF OIL drop onto Davidov's head... HE SCREAMS as his hair smokes and singes... Renard makes a motion, the THUG releases Davidov, who falls to the floor, clutching his head.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...yes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. He holds her gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Stand or split them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surely you believe in living dangerously.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They eye one another a long while -- sex firmly in the air. She smiles. She moves ALL HER CHIPS forward. Bond catches a look between the Dealer and Zukovsky:</context>
      <utterance>Not at that price. Time to surrender.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>General kerfuffle. Bond looks back toward THE HOSTESS BAR...no sign of Davidov's return...</context>
      <utterance>The House has no limit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Dealer scoops a card from the shoe. Tension. Everyone holds their breath...as he turns over... -- a six. Bust. The audience inhale as one AS THE DEALER TAKES ALL HER CHIPS</context>
      <utterance>Hit me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAVIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Davidov scowls at him. Bond leads Elektra away...</context>
      <utterance>A night of burning passion?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HENCHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir? Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will take care of Mister Bond.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew when you first saw me. You knew it would be like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hand dips in an ice bucket beside the bed. She rubs a slither of ice down her chest, shudders with pleasure. It's a move Bond hasn't seen before. Now she brings the ice to his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Shush.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses his purple flesh. Licks.</context>
      <utterance>Poor shoulder. Looks painful...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slides her tongue back and fore along the groove above the tendon. And he pulls the ice from her hand:</context>
      <utterance>...needs constant attention...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tosses it across the room as passion takes over...</context>
      <utterance>Enough ice for one day.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elektra looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>You never take this off?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches to the large, diamond-encrusted earring and gently plucks it away. Pulls her lush hair back... The lower half of her ear is gone, reduced to a misshapen clump of scar tissue. It is the only mark on her perfect body. A physical reminder of her ordeal. It breaks his heart.</context>
      <utterance>Why do men always want to undress the one part of a woman's body she doesn't want to reveal?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you survive?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are looking at each other, both suddenly feeling something dangerously close to real connection. It is not what Bond expected.</context>
      <utterance>I used my body on the guards. It gave me control. I got to a gun and I took my chance.  I've never told anyone that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds her gaze for a long time before he looks away.</context>
      <utterance>Do you ever stop, James? Do you ever think about...another kind of life?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't afford to. She frowns, slightly. Settles into his chest.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds her, eyes full of conflict, staring into the dark.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I know who you are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Davidov pulls his HAND GUN from inside his coat, but Bond is quicker. With a silenced pistol he shoots Davidov in the head. One little red hole forms in his forehead as his eyes go wide and he crumbles, dead. Bond climbs out of the trunk. Crouches to examine Davidov.</context>
      <utterance>Problem, comrade?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He straightens. Picks up the briefcase. It is locked. He searches Davidov and finds a set of keys in his pocket. He opens the lock. INSIDE THE BRIEFCASE: FOUR STACKS OF MONEY. Documents headed with the official crest of Miratom. A new security tag, it looks just like the dead guy's, but has Davidov's name and picture...some hologrammed (blank) security tags -- and a polaroid-type camera. He picks up a blank security tag and inserts it in the camera. Points at himself, takes a shot. Punches in 'Davidov' on the KEYPAD. Out comes a brand new pass. Bond goes to look in the dufflebag but... A PLANE is approaching...HE LOOKS UP. HIS P.O.V. A Russian military jet appears over the trees, flying low, its red landing lights blinking.</context>
      <utterance>Old habits die hard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hoists the dufflebag over his shoulder and walks out to the plane. He starts up the steps: THE SOLDIER POINTS HIS GUN DOWN AT HIM. Says something to him</context>
      <utterance>Here goes nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldier looks at him, then lowers his weapon.</context>
      <utterance>Romashka.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>COLONEL AKAKIEVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Akakievich isn't exactly what you'd call a looker. Bond offers a disappointed tut as Akakievich walks away. Christmas approaches. He notices her IDA tag -- and an incongruous PEACE TATTOO just above her hip. She's checking him out as well.</context>
      <utterance>Not interested in men. Take my word for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You new?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Viktor Davidov, Miss...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No jokes, I've heard them all.</context>
      <utterance>Doctor. Jones. Christmas Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is wary. It's been a long time since a man this attractive stepped onto her beat. They walk toward the building.</context>
      <utterance>Don't know any doctor jokes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to Len Tashka?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't make it. Splitting headache.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond looks at the ominous radiation WARNING SIGNS.</context>
      <utterance>The soldiers may give you a hard time. Whatever. If we weren't around, they'd have their whole nuclear arsenal lying by the roadsides, rotting in the sun.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She squints at him, taken aback.</context>
      <utterance>Will I need protection?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond turns to go, knowing he misstepped. Christmas then speaks to him, asking a question, IN RUSSIAN.</context>
      <utterance>There's no radiation danger down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond turns, answers IN PERFECT RUSSIAN.</context>
      <utterance>Where is this stockpile going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. Watches him disappear into the building.</context>
      <utterance>To the nuclear facility at Penza 19.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man turns...</context>
      <utterance>Corporal?</utterance>
   <speaker>IT IS RENARD.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see my friend Davidov ran into some difficulty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indeed. Renard starts toward him. Bond draws his gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't come any closer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Bond face off, the malevolent bomb between them, a ROBOT DEVICE beginning to lower it into the pit.</context>
      <utterance>You can't kill me. I'm already dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOND'S P.O.V. TWO OF RENARD'S MEN in the pit, unaware of what is happening above, working directly with the bomb. One of them is using a manual...IT IS JUST LIKE THE STOLEN REPORT, the Miratom seal in the corner. Bond aims his gun at Renard's head.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. Shoot. My men will still steal the bomb, and the shot will bring them directly to you. Renard gestures into the pit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renard resumes walking, around the catwalk at the edge of the pit, toward Bond, slowly, surely, totally fearless.</context>
      <utterance>Who's paying you to destroy the pipeline?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond, out of the corner of his eye, sees Renard's man remove a SMALL DEVICE from inside the bomb. It is the size and shape of a credit card, black, with shiny transistors on it...the man slips it into his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>To die by a man who can't even grasp what he's caught up in...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Revenge isn't so hard to fathom. What's clever is getting someone else to pay for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond cocks the pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Not many people in this world have that kind of fortune.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond's eyes flare in fury. He shoves Renard into the wall and presses the gun to his temple.</context>
      <utterance>You think I fear death? I welcome it. I get on my knees and pray for it. You, on the other hand, you have something to live for, no?  She's beautiful isn't she? You should have seen her before. Flawless, and still so innocent, not such a whore in bed...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will never touch her. You will never get near her.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you forgotten who saved your life in Geneva?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Consider me ungrateful.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's I who should thank you -- for taking that money back to MI-6. So distressing for M. An explosion inside her lair.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll get over it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond strikes him across the temple with his pistol. Renard drops to his knees. He touches his temple, looks at the blood curiously, feeling no pain.</context>
      <utterance>You even brought the plane for us. We really couldn't have done it without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Bond screws a silencer onto the muzzle of his gun:</context>
      <utterance>A man tires of being executed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond knows that, he's heard it somewhere before...IT FREEZES HIM, just a beat, but it is enough... SUDDENLY, the noise of footsteps -- CHRISTMAS JONES, with COLONEL AKAKIEVICH and two armed soldiers. We're with them as they turn the corner of the passageway and see Bond with silenced pistol aimed at the kneeling Renard -- classic execution stance:</context>
      <utterance>But then again...There is no point in living if you can't...feel alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AKAKIEVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drop your gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers' guns are trained on Bond.</context>
      <utterance>Keep away, Colonel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is an impostor.  There's no Davidov at Miratom.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christmas is listening, but Akakievich cocks his rifle.</context>
      <utterance>Here's your imposter. He's paid off the men on the plane outside. They're not taking the bomb to any Russian facility, they're flying it wherever he tells them.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AKAKIEVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he means business. Bond delays ... but has no choice. He pulls the clip from his gun, tosses it down.</context>
      <utterance>I said drop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AKAKIEVICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renard stops and turns. Bond sees him nod to two of his men: one quietly slopes off down the tunnel. The other innocently opens a container...</context>
      <utterance>No -- the bomb does not go anywhere until I am satisfied. All of you to the surface, now...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before she can, two of the FUEL BARRELS HURTLE through the closing iris, clattering into the pit, starting a fire below. Flames licking up the sides of the pit toward them. Bond looks up, sees the ARM OF THE ROBOT LIFTER, stretching upward toward an old SHAFT t the top of the ceiling... He and Christmas scramble up the robot arm, walk along the spider-like web that supported the bomb and find... AN OLD ELEVATOR...powered by a hydraulic system... They get in...hear the rumbling of the fire below...the old elevator moves slowly...the rumbling grows louder...</context>
      <utterance>Close the door! Close the door!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shame you had to spot I wasn't the real thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond FIRES HIS GUN at the hissing hydraulic pulleys and... THE ELEVATOR shoots through the shaft at breakneck speed as</context>
      <utterance>Bond --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They won't get far. Every warhead has a locator card. A Miratom device. Emits a high-pitched signal on Russian emergency frequencies. We can track the bomb.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond removes the locator card from his jacket and shows it to her. It flashes in the sun. Christmas shakes her head, disgusted.</context>
      <utterance>With this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we have the range of Renard's plane?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anywhere in this circle. Iran, Iraq, Pakistan, Syria, Afghanistan...</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moneypenny enters...</context>
      <utterance>Marvellous.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONEYPENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M is surprised.</context>
      <utterance>Elektra King is calling from Baku.</utterance>
   <speaker>MONEYPENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a video line.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The face of ELEKTRA materializes on a large WALL MONITOR.</context>
      <utterance>Put her on the wide screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M exchanges a look with Tanner.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I would never call you except...Bond's disappeared. He...he left my villa, some time in the middle of the night and...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My head of security has been found near a local airstrip, murdered... M leans on the console in front of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll send someone out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELEKTRA, on the monitor, looks about as lost as she ever has.</context>
      <utterance>Could...could you come? M looks up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M stares at the girl's face, her whole sordid history written there. M turns away from the screen and says to Tanner...</context>
      <utterance>I just can't help thinking...I'm next.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me out there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him, shocked, hesitant.</context>
      <utterance>James!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves to Gabor, gets down to help him. He stirs, he is alive, but unconscious. Elektra looks up at Bond.</context>
      <utterance>You look surprised.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you? Are you crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Isn't that your motto?</context>
      <utterance>A little. Does it matter? After all, what's the point of living if you can't feel alive? Isn't that right, Elektra?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or did you steal it from your old friend Renard?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had a run-in, he and I. He knew about us, he knew about my shoulder, he knew exactly where to hurt me... Elektra stands...she begins to tremble.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you saying...Renard is the man who's trying to kill me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can drop the act, it's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking about!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks toward her, threatening...</context>
      <utterance>I think you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the word "love," Elektra explodes. She SLAPS an unsuspecting Bond hard across the face.</context>
      <utterance>At MI-6 we call it Stockholm Syndrome. It's common in kidnappings. A young impressionable victim. Sheltered, sexually inexperienced. A powerful kidnapper skilled in torture, in manipulation. Something snaps in the victim's mind. The captive falls in love with her captor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How dare you! How dare you! That animal!? That monster!? He disgusts me! You disgust me! So he knew where to hurt you, is that it? You had a sling on your arm at the funeral! I didn't have to sleep with you to find that out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He used your exact words.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings, cuts through the tension. Bond and Elektra staring at one another. She lets it ring... Then picks up. Listens, looks to Bond.</context>
      <utterance>You knew. You knew all the time, that he was out there, that he was coming for me, and you lied. You used me, you used me as bait. You made love to me -- what, to pass the time as you waited for him to strike? He has no answer. He can't deny what she says.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves toward her.</context>
      <utterance>He's struck again.  Five men are dead at the pipeline.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm coming with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do what you have to do, but I've called in M. She's en route from London even now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is moving fast, talking fast -- a sense of urgency.</context>
      <utterance>Glad to see you've turned up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They hit about 90 minutes ago. There's a scientist here from the International Decommissioning Agency, Dr. Jones. She has ten crews combing the area. They step out of the bright sunlight and into</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They watch him go. M turns to Bond:</context>
      <utterance>I'll see how they're coming with the power...</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws her away, to a small alcove. Takes something out of his jacket...THE LOCATOR CARD.</context>
      <utterance>You had your hand on the bomb and you let Renard get away with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The report King bought. It's a manual. Renard's men used it to remove this radio tracking device from the warhead.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then Robert was right about a Russian connection.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're getting their weapons from the Russians, but where are they getting the money to buy the weapons? I can't help thinking...the person close to King, the one who switched that pin...</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The inside man?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NOW THE LIGHTS POWER UP, disrupt the intimacy and intensity of their exchange. The room is lined with MONITORS and a huge SATELLITE MAP of the pipeline's meandering path.</context>
      <utterance>Is maybe...the inside woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before he can speak, ELEKTRA calls out, gesturing to A DIM LIGHT flashing on a console in front of her.</context>
      <utterance>A woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Technician comes over. Tanner too, followed by Bond and M.</context>
      <utterance>That's not right.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's an observation and repair rig. Travels along the pipe, checks for broken seals. But it's not supposed to be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Technician flicks two switches. The light continues to flash. Confused, he tries others. No change.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand...</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harried, the Technician activates the wall schematic of the pipeline. A pulse of light travels along the line. And with it, a sense of horror descends...</context>
      <utterance>Where is the rig?</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The parcel's in the post.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's heading for the oil terminal.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where it can do the most damage.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man gets on the phone...</context>
      <utterance>My God.  Have the terminal evacuated.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speed?</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He punches buttons. Christmas has come, stands next to Bond.</context>
      <utterance>Full on. Seventy miles an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One hundred and six miles from the terminal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Technician checks his records, looks up, nods.</context>
      <utterance>It'll reach the other end in seventy- eight minutes.  Any more of these rigs?</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Decisive, Christmas heads for the door, turns to her team:</context>
      <utterance>There's one parked in the passageway ahead of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her IDA colleagues look sheepish. Bond moves to her.</context>
      <utterance>I'll need some help...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For just a moment, Christmas looks wary:</context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M nods to Tanner to follow them. Bond doesn't look at Elektra. But she watches him go...</context>
      <utterance>Unless you'd like to see my ID first. She almost smiles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bonds nods, checks his watch. Christmas looks nervously down the pipe.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she starts the machine off...</context>
      <utterance>Be one along any minute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When this is over we should bury the hatchet. Celebrate. A champagne dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When this is over our bodies may be blown to smithereens.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His lightness relaxes her, she appreciates it.</context>
      <utterance>Alright then, brunch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RADIO MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tanner reports Bond is headed for the rendezvous.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent. Evacuate Miss King and the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M looks at her, then nods, impressed by her courage.</context>
      <utterance>You can evacuate my workers, but I'm not going anywhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christmas presses forward...Bond turns, his feet OUT toward the approaching rig...the lights getting closer... closer... Bond's rig jolts as the other makes contact. He cushions the blow with his feet. Both rigs moving together now, he CLIMBS ONTO THE BOMB RIG...Puts out a hand, helps Christmas across. The bomb sits there, daunting, deadly.</context>
      <utterance>Faster! Get our speed up!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at one another, then set straight to work.</context>
      <utterance>Tactical fission device. Low yield.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The plutonium is missing. They've taken the core!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it's no longer a bomb?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christmas shoots a look, astonished.</context>
      <utterance>Let it blow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking her arm...</context>
      <utterance>But we can stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can't believe what he's saying. His eyes shoot to an INSPECTION HATCH the lights illuminate up ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Let it blow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her, wrenches her away from the bomb.</context>
      <utterance>Trust me. Leave it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GABOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't nuclear...the bomb was a dud. The trigger charge blew out a fifty yard section of pipeline...</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An agonizing beat. The alarm beep sputters and dies.</context>
      <utterance>And Bond?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M and Elektra share a look.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M can't answer. She shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think he's dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M shifts. The hi-tech room is eerily lit by the pulsing red lights on every screen, showing the explosion.</context>
      <utterance>We just have to wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M feels uneasy.</context>
      <utterance>I have a gift for you. Something that belonged to my father. He would have wanted you to have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps this isn't the time...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. She hands M a small box. M unties the ribbon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M opens the box. It is THE EYE OF THE GLENS...the heirloom pin, the original.</context>
      <utterance>He often spoke of how...compassionately you advised him on the best course of action during my kidnapping.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M looks up, horrified, when:</context>
      <utterance>It's very valuable, you know. I just couldn't let it explode with the rest of him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell were you doing? You nearly killed us!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she thinks she got away with it.</context>
      <utterance>I did kill us. She thinks we're dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's part of some plan. She dresses it up like a terrorist attack. The explosion covers up the theft of the plutonium.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's she?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elektra King.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elektra King? Are you insane? This is her pipeline.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Makes her look even more innocent.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would she want with weapons grade plutonium?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christmas stares at him. Wheels turning.</context>
      <utterance>I was hoping you could tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're both chilled by the thought.</context>
      <utterance>You steal an old bomb, small by today's standards, about the size of the one that destroyed Nagasaki, take the plutonium core out of it, intending to use it...  To make a bigger, better bomb.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts fiddling with the radio. Suddenly there's a</context>
      <utterance>I have to get after that core. This is my ass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond grabs the radio.</context>
      <utterance>Tanner to 007, do you read?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loud and clear. I have to speak to M.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It impacts on Bond. His eyes harden.</context>
      <utterance>She's disappeared. And two of our men have been killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks out at the long stretch of pipeline, like a deadly snake with the world for its bed.</context>
      <utterance>She just upped the stakes. All her chips are on the table now. And M's life is part of the bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I promised you champagne, but would you settle for caviar?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He senses something different between them. She tries to hide it.</context>
      <utterance>You're hurting me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, grabs a case off one of his men, opens it up, pulls out a sphere of cobalt blue metal. She looks at it with wary fascination.</context>
      <utterance>Brought me something?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She traces a finger along the metal. A flicker of wonder:</context>
      <utterance>Go on. It's safe. Touch your destiny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Warm.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's sensitive to his buried frustration:</context>
      <utterance>Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've brought something for you as well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renard steps forward. Bars separate him from M.</context>
      <utterance>Just as I promised.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My executioner.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over-praise, I'm afraid. But my people will finish the job.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your people? Your people will leave you here to rot just like you left me. You and my father. He didn't think my life was worth the chump change he spent on a day at the stock market.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is nothing. His kingdom he stole from my mother. The kingdom I will rightly take back. Elektra leaves. Renard is left alone with M.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's insane. Is that what you did to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses close to the bars.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm afraid it is what you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I took her she was...promise itself. So clever, so vibrant, so...full of life force. And you left her there, at the mercy of a man like me. You ruined her. For what? To get to me? She is worth fifty of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head, amused by her pluck.</context>
      <utterance>For once, I agree with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So she used all that brilliance to get revenge on her father, on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes something out of his pocket. A small TRAVEL CLOCK. He sets it.</context>
      <utterance>No. I wanted you. I wanted you for myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He places the clock on a tall stool, just out of reach through her bars. He leaves. We hold on the clock: Eight p.m.</context>
      <utterance>Since you sent your man to kill me, I have been watching time tick slowly away, marching inevitably toward my own death. Watch these hands, M. At noon tomorrow, your time is up. And I guarantee you...I will not miss. You will die. Along with everyone in this city and the future of the West.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are doing, Bond? Trying to impress this innocent thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's no innocent. This is my nuclear consultant.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hands held clear of his body, Zukovsky enters, his evening dress decidedly out of place here.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, I see. A purely...plutonic relationship.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really Bond, couldn't you find a nice Russian scientist with hair growing out of his ears?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your business with Elektra King?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were the one in her business.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She dropped a million and half dollars to the House -- your House. And you didn't even bat an eyelid. She was paying you off. What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond SLAMS Zukovsky hard against a vat of caviar. Wood splits, roe spills onto the floor. Zukovsky is appalled.</context>
      <utterance>As ever you are the spy who has to see a plot wherever he looks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is 5,000 dollars of Beluga ruined!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christmas moves in, intense but firm:</context>
      <utterance>You are out of your league. She's working with Renard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A subtle change in Zukovsky's countenance.</context>
      <utterance>They've stolen a nuclear device.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SOUND OF A HELICOPTER. Zukovsky frowns, the SOUND</context>
      <utterance>Tell us what you know, Zukovsky. Tell us, before its too late. But it may be already:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now...where were we?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A rope!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zukovsky is sinking.</context>
      <utterance>No. The truth!  She thought I was dead -- those blades were meant for you. What do you know that she would kill you for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking -- Zukovsky sees Christmas appear beside Bond:</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks to Bond -- sees he's serious.</context>
      <utterance>Help me, don't let me drown.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, alright! Sometimes I smuggle machinery for her. Russian stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the payoff on the tables?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A special job. A...a...a submarine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To haul some cargo. My nephew, he is Captain of a sub in the Black Sea Fleet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the sub going?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Get me out!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is too big for even you. Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he looks more worried than ever as Bond takes aim with the harpoon gun -- squeezes the trigger.</context>
      <utterance>This is a family matter! If my nephew is in danger, we do it my way, or nothing! Now get me out!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Bond!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond fires. Zukovsky YELLS as the HARPOON SHOOTS TOWARD HIM. It takes him a moment to realize he hasn't been hit -- the harpoon splintering the crate, just missing him. He clings to the crate, exhausted, as Bond and Christmas drag him to safety.</context>
      <utterance>Bond!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He just looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Commander Bond, you are dangerous, unpredictable, and a hothead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zukovsky scowls, wet, angry, looking from his ruined suit to the devastation that was once his caviar factory as, behind him, walkways CREAK, teeter, and CRASH into the sea.</context>
      <utterance>But then again, explosive devices are my specialty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. My way. No MI-6, no Interpol. Just you, me and my people.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Istanbul.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So beautiful. So smooth, so warm.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It stings him. Elektra sits up, pulling a robe around her.</context>
      <utterance>How would you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you like this? Because Bond is dead? It's what you wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renard gets up. Paces the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Of course...</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a...good lover?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renard leans against her desk, closing his eyes, squeezing out the images. After a moment, he SMASHES HIS FIST through the hand-painted wood. Elektra looks up. HER P.O.V. A huge splinter of wood juts out of Renard's hand. Renard looks at it, curious, unfazed.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elektra comes to him. Leads him to the bed. Sits. Gently removes the splinter. Then, she takes an icecube from the bucket. Runs it along his wound.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she runs the ice down his cheek. He shakes his head. Tormented.</context>
      <utterance>What about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she runs the ice down her neck...</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...her fingers becoming wet, she runs the ice down between her breasts, leaving a trail. Teasing...</context>
      <utterance>But surely...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's moving the ice lower on herself... We see her lips open, enjoying the sensation. A beat, then his smile slowly grows. As she does something else.</context>
      <utterance>...You can feel this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember ... pleasure?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLANKING OPEN...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GABOR ENTERS...a burly shadow in the light from the hall. He walks in. Looks at M. Picks up the clock and sets it ON THE</context>
      <utterance>She hurries to her cot and lies down.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINDOW SILL.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M sits up. Looks out to the clock, glowing in the dark.</context>
      <utterance>He leaves, shutting the door behind him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any luck reaching Yevgeny?</utterance>
   <speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to CHRISTMAS AND BOND, pouring over a large MAP OF ISTANBUL spread out on a table.</context>
      <utterance>Negative, comrade.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond notices THE BOA in the corner with some others.</context>
      <utterance>Former KGB surveillance post. The Dye Factory was just a front; now it turns a good profit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zukovsky nods to his old friend.</context>
      <utterance>Your old friend Dmitri.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zukovsky looks at the map.</context>
      <utterance>Today, you are glad to have the Boa on your side.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the good old days, the KGB had three or four spots where our submarines could surface without anyone knowing. But Yevgeny is supposed to be loading cargo.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What class sub does your nephew run?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C-class.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nuclear.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not just nuclear. Powered by a nuclear reactor.  He's not loading any cargo. They want the sub. The sub itself. Put weapons grade plutonium inside the sub's reactor: Instant, catastrophic meltdown.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Made to look just like an accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother of God.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The right kind of explosion in the right spot -- it would block the Bosphorus, cut off the Black Sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why? Eight million people would die, the land irradiated for a hundred years. A cloud of radiation the size of Europe...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because an explosion like that would kill all the other pipelines. There would be only one way to get the oil out of the Caspian and pump it to the world...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The King pipeline.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elektra would control it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If what you say it true...it may be too late for Yevgeny.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain...</utterance>
   <speaker>YEVGENY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir. We are ready to load your cargo. We only have a few hours before we'll be missed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You came with a skeleton crew?</utterance>
   <speaker>YEVGENY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all we can afford these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of his men comes forward with several bottles of brandy and other food.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. We are grateful for your efforts.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have brandy and other refreshments for your men. The Captain nods, pleased.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond stares hard at him. A long beat.</context>
      <utterance>If we're not in time and something has happened to him... you must let me kill them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever gets there first, Zukovsky. They have M.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they drag Yevgeny away, his HAT falls on the ground. Renard picks it up and PUTS IT ON HIS HEAD.</context>
      <utterance>Take them up and throw them in the sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A man appears holding a heavy lead box containing the plutonium. Renard takes the box as if it weighs nothing. Stronger then ever.</context>
      <utterance>We'll be underway in two hours. Use that time to re-familiarize yourselves with your stations. Then ponder how rich you'll be. The re-breathers for the escape are already on board.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you know how it feels. To be locked away, to wonder if they're coming for you, if anyone will ever come for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone will come.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elektra walks to the window. She looks out.</context>
      <utterance>Who? Bond? Bond is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>M watches her, her heart beating.</context>
      <utterance>Somehow, I find that strangely ...disappointing.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elektra picks up the little clock. Walks over to the cell bars.</context>
      <utterance>Elektra. What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she reaches through the bars and HANDS M THE CLOCK. The two women's eyes meet.</context>
      <utterance>Time for you to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns, sees RENARD in the doorway. She crosses to him and SLAMS THE DOOR SHUT behind her.</context>
      <utterance>The reactor is secured.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lays the Captain's hat down. Tries to mask his sorrow.</context>
      <utterance>No. It is the beginning. The world will never be the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Forces himself to leave, heads down the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>It will be yours, and yours alone. Have fun with it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He writes the coordinates down. Bond picks them up.</context>
      <utterance>Comrade, it's faint, but I'm getting something. A signal. Transmitting at...37- 19 degrees north...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the coordinates over to the map and DRAWS A CORRESPONDING LINE across it.</context>
      <utterance>The locator card. It's M.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christmas reads them out as the Operator writes them down</context>
      <utterance>The rest?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond draws another line across the map. At the point at which the intersect...a small island in the Bosphorus.</context>
      <utterance>Forty, forty-three degrees East...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Maiden's Tower.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How appropriate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Bond's instinct are aroused. Out of the corner of his eye, he sees THE BOA set something on the ground and move slowly UP THE STAIRS. Bond looks at the pack he left on the ground... He grabs Christmas and HURLS HER TO THE FLOOR.</context>
      <utterance>I'd heard there were some renovations there...no one would look for a sub in that place in a million years.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zukovsky...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I don't get to the Boa before he gets to Maiden's Tower, M is dead. Bond runs out, into</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christmas eyes Bond anew as Elektra leads him to an ornately carved chair, covered in silk.</context>
      <utterance>James Bond and his amazing resurrection. If only you'd kept away, we might have met again in a few years, become lovers once more.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond and Christmas exchange a look as the guards start her towards some steps. Elektra indicates for him to sit. Behind him, the whole of Istanbul is visible through a large curved window.</context>
      <utterance>Take her to Renard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond ignores her.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty thing. You had her too?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could have given you the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This cuts. She casually reaches behind his neck, flips up a wooden arm to which is attached a metal collar. A GAROTTE.</context>
      <utterance>Not interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond recoils as she fastens the collar... She steps back.</context>
      <utterance>They were digging near here and they found some very pretty vases. They also found this...  I think we ignore the old ways at our peril, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's M?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond keeps his cool:</context>
      <utterance>Soon she'll be everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All this, because you fell for Renard?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves to the back of the chair, twists the screw ONE NOTCH. The effect on Bond is instantaneous as a bolt jolts into the back of his neck, tilts his head back.</context>
      <utterance>Five more turns and your neck will break.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since I was a child, I've always had a power over men. When I realized my father wouldn't rescue me from the kidnappers, I knew I had to form a new alliance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You turned Renard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls the jewel from her ear, reveals the ugly scar:</context>
      <utterance>Just like you...only you were even easier.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns the screw again.</context>
      <utterance>I told him he had to hurt me, he had to make it look real. When he refused I told him I would do it myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you killed your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He killed me! He killed me the day he refused to pay my ransom. A flicker of emotion. Bond is getting to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was this all about the oil?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes are shining. She moves toward the view, gazing out at this spectacular cradle of civilization. Bond works his wristbinds feverishly.</context>
      <utterance>It is my oil! Mine and my family's!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It runs in my veins, thicker than blood. I'm going to redraw the map. And when I am through the whole world will know my name, my grandfather's name, the glory of my people.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She eyes him, impressed that he's worked out her plan. Tightens the screw again. Her confidence amazing.</context>
      <utterance>No-one will believe this melt-down was an accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tightening the screw again:</context>
      <utterance>They will believe. They will all believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she straddles him. She puts the jewel back on her ear. All the time, he's working that wristbind.</context>
      <utterance>You understand? Nobody can resist me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what happens when a man is strangled?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, twists the screw again. A nasty, grinding sound. Sweat trickles from his brow. She licks it away.</context>
      <utterance>Elektra, it's not too late. Eight million people needn't die.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes her hips into his. Turns the screw. The bolt is jammed right into the back of his neck. His face is angled upwards. Breathing is difficult. He glares up:</context>
      <utterance>You should have killed me when you had the chance. But you couldn't. Not me. A woman you've loved.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She fingers the bolt. Prepares to turn it the last time...His hand strains at its binding...</context>
      <utterance>You meant ... nothing ... to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One... last... screw?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elektra freezes. Gets off him. Moves to a window.</context>
      <utterance>Oh James. She begins to turn the screw... ... when SEVERAL GUNSHOTS are heard outside. Bond is on the edge of consciousness.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then his eye falls on the HAT Renard had brought up from below. He knows at once what it means.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for a submarine. It's big and black, and the driver is a friend of mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZUKOVSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks it up, walks to him (surreptitiously sliding a gun beneath it). She proffers the hat...</context>
      <utterance>Bring it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLAM BLAM BLAM -- she fires through the hat. He staggers back. Stares. Slumps down. Lowers his head to the ground. She walks over, puts her heel on his gun arm, presses down, smiling a half-psychotic smile. The gun is pinned. Zukovsky is dying. But he dredges up every last ounce of energy to raise his gun a millimetre off the ground, his outstretched arm already pointing at Bond. Elektra looks surprised, then amused as Zukovsky's finger begins to squeeze the trigger: he's going to shoot Bond! Bond stares back. Zukovsky's eye narrows -- trying for extreme accuracy... BLAM! The SHOT hits the binding at Bond's wrist. Splinters the wood there. ELEKTRA stares at Zukovsky. She didn't see where the bullet went, just that it missed Bond. She watches his head slump further, staring at Bond... A look passes between the two men. Comrades in arms. The merest of smiles. Then the light fades from his eyes. Dead.</context>
      <utterance>What a shame. You just missed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>turns back to Bond. Smiles.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. She picks up a walkie-talkie, speaks into it:</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's under control up here. Are you ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lost for a moment, she breathes heavily. She glances at Zukovsky's corpse. Slightly puzzled, to Bond:</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Au revoir...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she kisses him -- reaches behind to deliver the killer twist... One super-fast movement: Bond's hand breaks free, grabs her throat, tight. He holds her, their faces close together, disdain in his eyes -- hurls her backwards, her hand scratching at his face. Ripping the collar from his neck, he gets to his feet. Moves to Zukovsky, checks his pulse, takes the bloody gun from his fingers. Turns back, to see Elektra disappearing upstairs. A moment's dilemma: should he race below to the sub -- or up to Elektra? He takes off after Elektra, grabs the radio handset.</context>
      <utterance>Zukovsky really hated you.  Time to say goodnight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Bond isn't wavering. Clutches Zukovsky's bloody wet gun. He heads up in the semi-darkness -- and suddenly swings to his right, at an unexpected but familiar Voice:</context>
      <utterance>James. You can't kill me. Not in cold blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bond -- Bond kicks open a door and enters...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds the walkie-talkie to her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Call him off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him seriously. He's giving her a last chance, willing her to save herself and the city.</context>
      <utterance>I won't ask again. Call him off!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond waits...</context>
      <utterance>Renard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And her face breaks into a perverted grin and --</context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't kill me. You'd miss me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELEKTRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She staggers back, shocked at her own mortality.</context>
      <utterance>Dive! Bond -- BLAM! Bond shoots her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks out:</context>
      <utterance>I never miss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there another way?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We go down to the torpedo bay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond is throttling the man with the cable. Speaks into the handset.</context>
      <utterance>Open the tanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the man has stretched his hand to a fire alarm: The KLAXON RESOUNDS.</context>
      <utterance>Tanks open.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flicks a switch;</context>
      <utterance>Bond...</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bond! You have decided to join me on this historic voyage. Welcome to my nuclear family.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really going to commit suicide for her? Renard responds, into the microphone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RENARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In case you've forgotten. I'm dead already.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Renard's face screws up in pain more searing than any he could feel in his skin...he SCREAMS...</context>
      <utterance>Haven't you heard the news? So is she.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bond reads off more lights...</context>
      <utterance>The cover is off the reactor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's sealed himself in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thinking fast, Bond moves to some controls. Hits switches.</context>
      <utterance>He's going to insert the plutonium.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like riding a bike.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of bikes did you ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just wanted to put him on edge...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls Christmas up and they ascend to the next level. No chance to seal the chamber though, the water is already through the hatch.</context>
      <utterance>Climb!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep moving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the box to find the RE-BREATHERS are ripped to shreds. No-one was ever meant to get off the sub. She shows Bond.</context>
      <utterance>Re-breathers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He climbs into the escape chamber.</context>
      <utterance>Never liked those things anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Count to twenty. When you get to twenty open the hatch. It can only be opened for a few seconds or we'll sink.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what if...</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves over and seals the door, wrenches a lever which immediately floods the chamber with water.</context>
      <utterance>Count to twenty. I'll be there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fourteen, one thousand, fifteen, one thousand...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She presses a button...</context>
      <utterance>Twenty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he lets him fall past Christmas, through consecutive open hatches of the sub, crashing into the rising water. Christmas looks down at the floating corpse. Bond watches the gauge -- as it edges DOWN from 5000. The nuclear disaster looks like it's averted. But suddenly water is gushing in from above, through splits in the sub's shell; it's going to sink.</context>
      <utterance>She's waiting for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she won't come. As water courses over them:</context>
      <utterance>We're sinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves to the reactor, closing the cover. Bond uses his strength to push the heavy locking mechanism into place. Bond climbs upwards, dragging Christmas with him.</context>
      <utterance>Help me. We have to seal it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got to get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EST. SHOT - MI-6 - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The damaged wing is being repaired.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any word from him?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still no contact yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love Christmas in Turkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So isn't it time you unwrapped your present?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The satellite image zooms in one particular car parked in a side street. We can just make out Bond's ASTON MARTIN.</context>
      <utterance>That's strange.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The image moves from the car, closes on the garden rooftop. The thermal image is multi-coloured, difficult to decipher.</context>
      <utterance>He must be nearby. M comes over.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>Q</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he points to ONE orange figure lying on the rooftop.</context>
      <utterance>This picks up body heat. Humans should be orange.  There.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tanner, Q and M realize as one that this is an image of two people, one atop the other. And getting hotter.</context>
      <utterance>It's getting redder.</utterance>
   <speaker>M</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bond. Q switches the screen off, clears his throat.</utterance>
   <speaker>Q</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be a premature form of the Millennium Bug.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know James... I think Christmas is coming early this year.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
