<movie id="294" title="Ice Storm The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning ladies and gentlemen -- He sounds like a baseball announcer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PASSENGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What ladies?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul rubs his elbow against the window and looks out into the still-dark early morning. He looks back down at his comic book. On the comic book: Reed Richards (also known as Stretch) has zapped his young son with a cosmic ray gun to neutralize the destructive energy that Annihilus has implanted in him. The Thing, Medusa, Flame, and Richards' wife Sue Storm look on, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>-- this train originating at New York's Grand Central Station is back in service - next stop will be New Canaan, Connecticut. New Canaan, Connecticut, next stop! He moves on to the next car. The train begins to move.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DESTROYED THE WQRLD!"</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul looks up again, thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In issue number 141 of The Fantastic Four, published in November 1973, Reed Richards has to use his anti-matter weapon on his own son, who Annihilus has turned into a human atom bomb. His son is the result of Richards' coupling with the earthling Sue Storm, and the problem is that the cosmic rays that infused Richards and the rest of the Fantastic Four on their aborted moon mission have made young Franklin a volatile mixture of matter and anti-matter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arise and shine, young Hood.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you changed the water in that bong from last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul reluctantly walks over and takes a hit. He coughs, spewing uninhaled smoke.</context>
      <utterance>The water, as you call it, is a special mixture of amaretto and Ben&amp;Ben blended for just the exact chemical interaction with the last of our precious Thai stick.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waste not Master Hood -- that was $20 for the bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, Francis, you are one drug addled elitist freak, and when the revolution comes I do not want to be lined up with you and shot, 'cause you're fucking ripe for political reeducation, you know, like in the fields.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, cancel your mental appointments, baby. What are you, like still stoned from last night?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta get to English class.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Libbets?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What Dostoyevsky is saying here is that to be a Christian is to choose, because you have to choose of your own choice, but since you can't choose to be good because that would be too rational you have to choose to be bad -- it's existential.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEACHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul looks at her, smitten. Marge, Paul's friend, notices his look.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you Libbets, that's a very compelling summary, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, Libbets. Hey, Dostoyevsky, I'm also really a fan, and what you were saying, you know, have you ever read The Idiot?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Idiot?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you liked Notes from Underground, you'll love The Idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great, thanks for the tip.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in love with Libbets Casey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, you've been in love with like every other girl here, I was wondering when you'd get around to Libbets.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's beyond mere physical attraction.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good, because I don't think Libbets is capable of the sex act.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truly? Do speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My diagnosis is messed in the head. A poor little rich girl -- I mean check out the jeans and fur look. And lend your ears to this brutality. Like her mom and step dad and her step-sisters are going to Switzerland to ski over Thanksgiving break -- and like they didn't invite her!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know this shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They did it last year too. It's like traditional or something. They've got this humongoid Park Ave apartment and she just holes up there with a wad of cash.  Aren't the hugely wealthy sad?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think Francis is going to beat me to the punch here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since he sleeps with every girl you ever show an interest in, why don't you just keep your Libbets thing a secret from him?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good thinking Marge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No more man. I'm about to drop as it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul, let me enlighten you about something. You and I exist on two opposite sides of a great existential divide, that being your pathetic virginity on the one hand and my astonishing number of sexual conquests on the other. I'm off to get laid. See you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flame on, asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves his fingers toward Paul's eyes, in the classic "stoned" gesture, then wanders off. Paul looks on at the gathering. Marge waves to him from the dance floor.</context>
      <utterance>And remember, with your erogenous zones lubricated as such with the mighty herb, do not attempt terrestrial contact with members of the opposite sex -- because you drone on like a motherfucker when you're stoned.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you do that man?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sleep all day. I mean, look, it's already getting dark outside, and you're just getting up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, Libbets Casey.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aha! I could sense the vibe.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I right or am I right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. You're not planning --</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My man, I speak to you solely as a comrade in arms offering unconditional aid. I've been giving this one a lot of thought, and I believe that the two of you together might just reach that higher ground that -- A knock at the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Paul rolls off his bed, opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>Hood, telephone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mess with Libbets. I mean it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey guy. Things ok up there? You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well good. Just confirming. You'll be on the 3:50 Wednesday afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well dad, actually I thought I'd take the morning train on Thanksgiving -- got a lot of studying, papers, you know, lab experiments --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lab experiments? Right smart guy -- Paul, you know your mother's gonna be disappointed not to see more of you -- In fact, let me make this more than a simple request guy, I think you should...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>NIXON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, with regard to the questions as to why Americans feel we were wrong to make the tapes, that is not particularly surprising. I think that most Americans do not like the idea of taping conversations and, frankly, it is not something that particularly appeals to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She frowns.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on for a second.  Wendy, you want-to say hi to your brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She gets up sullenly and goes to the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charles.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charles. Have you been keeping out of my shit? Have you refrained from entering the sacred precincts of my room?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have not touched your sh--  Stuff. You watching this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watching what?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nixon, doofus! It's incredible. He should be shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben retreats, going to the wet bar to pour another drink.</context>
      <utterance>He's a liar!  Dean told him on March 21st about Kalmback and Hunt, all about the payoffs to the Watergate burglars, so you tell me where the so-called "Dean Report" is, but you can't because it doesn't exist, because he lied about Haldeman and Erlichman and the April 17 tape, that's why! Liar!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, OK, the defense rests.  Want another?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thank you. We should be off.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotcha. He puts the bottle back down without pouring.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back to Nixon on the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Dinner's on the counter. We'll be at the Williams's -- you know the number.  Paul. Hi. Is there anything you'll want, any particular kind of food or snack or anything we can stock up on?... You're all right? ... OK. See you next week. I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NIXON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Wendy as she regards the TV, hearing her parents' farewells as they leave through the front door.</context>
      <utterance>We must recognize that one excess begets another, and that the extremes of violence in the 1960s contributed to the extremes of Watergate...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His brother came back --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From where?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vietnam.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Are we going to talk about this, about...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should hear. It's very sad, he was --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a benefit for the ACLU or something, and Harry Reems himself was there --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man with the -- from Deep Throat?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The very one -- something about a first amendment defense fund -- well I believe in it --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted took me to see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ted, how romantic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to say, the movie didn't do much for me. But being in that theater, surrounded by all those horny young college boys and perverts, there was something in the air that --</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- pulls right up to the pump, jumps out like there's no gas shortage, oblivious, and by this point everybody in line's piling out of their cars ready to kill the guy, when they notice it's that Reverend Edwards --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Unitarian? The new one?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah -- claims he pulled off Creek Road and didn't notice the line going back Mill Street for half a mile.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's either got his head in the clouds or up his --</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear he's slept with half the women in his congregation --</utterance>
   <speaker>TED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As this is said, Mikey accidentally spills some wine on Ben.</context>
      <utterance>Lucky bastard!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janey leans over with her napkin and attempts a cursory wipe of Ben's pants. Is there a just barely noticeable frisson between Ben and Janey as she removes the napkin? If there is, Elena doesn't -- or pretends not to -- notice.</context>
      <utterance>Hell! -- I mean, no problemo there Mikey. Here, I --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So fascinating. Do you get free tickets to the movies, that kind of thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, my job is just to analyze the entertainment stocks and advise our institutional investors on where to put their money. It's --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be so modest, Ben. It's a job that requires a certain prescience with regards to entertainment trends. You were the first to predict that Billy Jack would be a hit --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>And as usual no one believed me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a bother.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elena realizes that there's an edge to Janey's voice.</context>
      <utterance>I insist.  Don't touch them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really quite all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And to think -- they met at a key party of all things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A key party?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, it's a California thing. That scuzzy husband of hers dragged her kicking and screaming to one when they were out in L.A. you know, the men put their car keys in a bowl, and then at the end of the evening the women line up and fish them out and go home with whoever's keys they've got. Anyhow that's how she met this Rod person or whatever his name is and he's left his wife and she's packing for California. Irwin is devastated. It's so ironic.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ironic?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, um, yes. Ironic. His name is Rod.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you Janey.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was lovely!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Jim, next time you've got to fill me in on whatever it is you're up to these days.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stupid!  Is Wendy Hood your girlfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who said so?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mikey returns to his reading -- a copy of The Sensuous Woman, obviously well pawed over. He absentmindedly picks his nose. As he flips the pages, a beautiful, almost electrical HUMMING SOUND begins to fill his ears. He frowns and pauses to listen to it. Sandy, who has picked up a balsa wood miniature plane, obviously doesn't hear it. Mikey focuses on the plane as Sandy waves it through the air. Perhaps the hum is the sound of its engines as it soars through the sky...</context>
      <utterance>I don't have a girlfriend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- he knows that when the March 24th tape -- you know with Dean, where Dean tells him that there's a cancer growing on the presidency -- She pauses as Beth asks a question.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who? No way. He's like a big infected whitehead wearing jeans. I wouldn't -- She hears the downstairs door open.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She turns her light out.</context>
      <utterance>-- shit, it's my parents.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses before a hall table, and, with his eyes, traces the telephone cord under Wendy's room.</context>
      <utterance>You'd think she'd learn how to cook a chicken, eh? My drumstick was still frozen when you cut inside there. I'm probably going to get whatever that disease -- and Jim, how that guy ever became a millionaire --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But Elena simply continues into the master bedroom. He starts to pull gently on the cord. And continues pulling. No response for a few seconds. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Hmm. I knew she'd still be up. Watch this --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wendy opens the door to her room.</context>
      <utterance>Get to sleep young lady -- and I mean it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fascist!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens it.</context>
      <utterance>If I were a fascist I would have sent you to one of those Southern military academies a long time ago. Now get to bed. She slams the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wendy jumps into bed and under the covers, pulling them up over her head. He stands over her, looking down at the crumpled pile of sheet and blanket.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He places his hand where her cheek should be, and caresses the sheet.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, kiddo. Sleep well, huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good-night dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben turns to the door, where he sees a silent Elena standing in her nightgown, a slight smile on her face.</context>
      <utterance>Good night kiddo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're staring at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't star--</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woolens.</context>
      <utterance>I've been thinking, Ben, about Wendy. I was going to ask if she'd come with me sometime to meet Dr.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That shrink -- the one you always wanted me to see? I thought you dropped him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You think she's ok?</context>
      <utterance>I did, but -- somebody should probably see her, talk to her...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elena just gives him a look, more sad than angry.</context>
      <utterance>Why shouldn't she be?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then again, why should she be? I mean with us, with our...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So maybe you'll come too?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh not again Elena! If we've got problems, why can't you just come out and talk about them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's you Ben who needs to talk. I've had my say, and I'm waiting to hear back from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah but Elena, even you don't believe all that "I'm OK. You're OK" stuff you keep babbling about -- you say so yourself. I've been all ears for about ten years now on his subject, and --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- And you haven't moved out yet. It's because you're too lazy, Ben. Too scared or lazy to either deal with us or simply make a decision --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Elena.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben picks up a pillow and walks out, pausing wistfully at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Sleep in the study? Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The aging boss nods agreement.</context>
      <utterance>But what, exactly, is stagflation, this mixture of inflation and stagnation, and how should we in the securities industry understand and accommodate it? Well -- and I hope I'm not out of bounds here - think of the money supply as a large male organ, continuously inflating, and yet, the societal vaginal cavity simply wants more. As the vicious circle of higher returns without real satisfaction continues, the money-organ may seem to be in demand, but in fact even the most inflated capital is unwanted. This is why I suggest that while we engage this mawing abyss for the highest returns, we at the same time fantasize, so to speak, of the safe harbor of capital appreciation.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHACKLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George Clair just grins.</context>
      <utterance>Brilliant, brilliant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's an obvious rivalry between the two of them.</context>
      <utterance>George, I'm just trying to get a global view of things -- can't just look at the small picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shackley was asking about?</context>
      <utterance>And speaking of which, you have those market share charts Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotcha George, not a problem. Tomorrow. Hey, you want to start covering the old filmed entertainment sector yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben you know that's your territory - and I wouldn't dream to trespass - you're the expert. Hey, how do you think Paramount's gonna do with that Blatty novel, what's it called? The Exorcist?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Overpriced bomb, cost over $6 million -- no stars, and no one's into the horror genre these days anyway. I'm advising the company recommend reducing positions there. It's disaster films that are gonna stay at the top.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brilliant. Hey, you heading out a little early today?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a meeting uptown.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right o'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The secretary pretends not to hear.</context>
      <utterance>Up the organization!  Bastard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd asked for that double martini about three hours ago!</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coming right up, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So asking me out for lunch -- what prompted this exceptional event? -- Of course I'm paying.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have to always go to your club, dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And why are you still calling me dad? You're forty years old already, and --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Well what am I supposed to call you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The martini arrives, along with Ben's beer.</context>
      <utterance>That's besides the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was actually trying to see about getting a little advice, you know --</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They fired you?</context>
      <utterance>Advice? I'm supposed to be getting the stock tips from you, Ben. Unless - have you quit your job?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up and sees his father slurping his martini, not paying attention.</context>
      <utterance>You know, dah--</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually it's not about work, it's advice about --</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh for crying out loud Ben, you don't mean to tell me that your marriage is going down the drain now --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Elena and I have kind of been talking, not really talking, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Your mother, God bless her, stood by me for forty-two years -- we never once contemplated divorce - I assume you're talking here about divorce? The very thought --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But dad, you guys truly hated each other, I mean really hated each --</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Waiter! Where's my cobb salad?  You want advice Ben? If your big brother were still alive I'd have him go out into the back yard and beat some sense into your head. Look kid, you married that woman against my advice --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- What advice? You never --</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's besides the point. The point is if I'd had any sense in me I'd have divorced your mother 40 years ago, and that's the truth, and here it is, 1972 --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben ponders, as the food arrives.</context>
      <utterance>-- 73, and divorce is as easy as paying off a traffic ticket, and for crying out loud, Ben, be a man and just get it over with. I would have if I'd had the chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His father rolls his eyes and stabs his salad with a fork.</context>
      <utterance>But I -- well maybe I love her. Elena.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ Ben! Make up your mind and eat your lunch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elena. Elena Hood, am I right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reverend Edwards. Philip Edwards. You came by and checked out the congregation a couple of times last year.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it was -- I ended up --</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No need to make excuses --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said you licked Dave Brewster's weenie in the third floor bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The conversation peters out at this point, as the two groups of girls give each other the hairy eyeball from afar. Wendy looks through from beneath the bleacher seats onto the field where the boys are playing. A group of boys break from a huddle, Mikey among them. The quarterback takes the hike and Mikey runs out for a pass. As he runs, his breathing increases in volume, filling his ears, and transforming into the humming sound he'd heard before. The quarterback spots him and throws a long one. He runs in an oblivion of beautiful white sound. The ball drops next to him as he continues, in a world of his own, to run. Suddenly, the humming ends and he stops and turns around, to see all the other kids just standing there looking at him. One of them makes a pot-smoking gesture, as if that's the explanation.</context>
      <utterance>She's a liar. I wouldn't touch Dave Brewster's dick if you paid me. It's probably crawling with v.d. after he put it in her, which he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other kids snicker. Wendy looks on, and catches Mikey's eye for a fleeting moment.</context>
      <utterance>Did anybody hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta go. She takes hold of her bicycle and pushes off.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been a tremendously transformative year -- maybe a little controversial of course, but we're breaking down the old Unitarian barriers --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose my reluctance was the group aspect of it -- I've never been much of a joiner, although I still consider myself a somewhat religious person --</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elena looks outside the window, and sees Wendy speed past on her bicycle.</context>
      <utterance>Well I of course flatter myself that our church is not exactly what most people would call organized religion -- at times it's the disorganization that's liberating -- and of course I've begun to minister much more in what one might call therapeutic environments, in small groups, and one on one, couples --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My daughter. I haven't been on a bike for years.  When was the last time you rode a bike?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say you never forget.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Forget how to ride a bike.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, of course you don't, you're right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Wendy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Sandy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mikey was looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy gazes after her. He takes his G.I. Joe out of his coat pocket, and points it at her.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? See ya. She pushes off on her bike.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bam.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want some gum?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.  Twinkie?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the Twinkies back, and pops the gum in her mouth. They stand together chewing.</context>
      <utterance>I'm chewing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you tell Sandy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wendy doesn't say anything.</context>
      <utterance>Tell Sandy? What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't tell him either, did you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janey smiles briefly at this.</context>
      <utterance>We were golfing, and you know, golfing to me is something I'm supposed to enjoy, and I was on the goddam golf team in college, so it's something one would assume I do well -- I used to do well -- but basically these days golfing for me is like hoeing, or plowing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like farming. I am basically chewing up large tracts of expensively landscaped scenery with overpriced sticks, and George Clair has obviously, in the mere two years since he joined the firm, he has obviously been taking secret lessons with a golf pro, and I assume the entirety of his disposable income has been devoted to humiliating me on the golf course. And the guy talks - incessantly -- throughout the entirety of the miserable 18 holes - on topics that are the supposed domain of my department --</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben--</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're boring me. I have a husband. I don't particularly feel the need for another.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're absolutely right.</context>
      <utterance>You have a point there. That's a very good point. We're having an affair. Right. An explicitly sexual relationship. Your needs. My needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys will be home soon.</context>
      <utterance>You should probably get dressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She wraps a blanket around herself and gets up.</context>
      <utterance>Gotcha.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without waiting for instructions, Wendy starts pulling out plates and silverware and setting the table.</context>
      <utterance>Hi Wendy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw you on your bike today.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With Mikey?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mikey Williams?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elena takes this in.</context>
      <utterance>We were just riding around.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wendy continues setting the table.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you looked very -- free -- when I saw you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weightless almost -- as if I were seeing my own memories of being a girl. There was something internal about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom. Are you ok?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wendy, of course. I'm sorry. You must think I'm ripe to be checked into Silver Meadows.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not a psycho!</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The people at Silver Meadows aren't psychos.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. They're rich drug addicts and celebrities. When I saw James Taylor there, and --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been through this Wendy James Taylor was actually at that clinic up near Boston.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I saw what I saw, and if you don't want to believe me --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wendy frowns.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Wendy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They need the money for my band uniform at school.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you quit the band - I never hear you practice anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't really need to practice. I just play a few notes, you know, so I thought maybe I'd stay in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm sure your father and I would love to hear what you're playing these days. Maybe after dinner.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Halfords have invited us again this year.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes up behind her, looks down at the checkbook.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it is a neighborhood tradition.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm, uh, going to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So early?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans over and kisses her on the cheek. She sniffs.</context>
      <utterance>Rough day. Good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He recoils a bit.</context>
      <utterance>Is that a new aftershave?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. Musk, or something. You like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks uncertainly from the room. Does she suspect?</context>
      <utterance>Hmm. Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mikey?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Geometry?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, anything but this English. Sandy puts the open textbook in front of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you so good at math but not in English?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at the book.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not good at math. Just geometry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As Mikey goes on, we see his geometric doodles, and hear faintly the HUMMING SOUND under his voice.</context>
      <utterance>It's like, you know when they say "two squared"? And you think it means 2 times 2, equals 4? But really they really mean a square. A square with a side of two. And the area of the square is four. Like every time you use the word, like squared, or cubed, it's really space, it's not numbers, it's space. And it's perfect space, but only in your head, because you can't draw a perfect square, like in the material world, but in your mind, you can have perfect space.  You know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A knock at the door. Jim stands in the doorway with a suitcase in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. But I just need some help with my homework.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey guys, I'm back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy looks at Mikey as if pondering a lost cause.</context>
      <utterance>You were gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mikey's still flustered.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah Mikey. Yep, I was in Houston, working on some great new ideas about silicon, which comes from sand, very conductive. How you guys doing? How's school?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, I dunno. OK I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks off.</context>
      <utterance>Hmm. Alright!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really didn't notice? Man, he's been gone for three days.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods and puts his suitcase down, then sits heavily on the side of the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Good trip?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It turns out it's a water bed, and his weight creates a wave that nearly pushes Janey off her edge of the bed.</context>
      <utterance>You bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry honey. Hell, we've got to trade this thing in for a normal bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You notice anything with Mikey lately? The kid seemed a little out of it tonight, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tonight? Jim, he's been out of it since he was born.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a look.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, I guess he takes after me, huh? He laughs to himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In many ways, the church-bound tradition of the father, son, and holy ghost is simply a version of the parent-child-adult triad within us all. It's a primitive set of symbols for our inner psychology.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're saying that Christ is the child, and --</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- And God the angry parent, and the Spirit the hope of an integrated adult self.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All well and good -- But tell me again what is it exactly that you believe in?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ask what the point is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Self-realization. Ministering to help people reach their fullest potential. Would you believe me if I told you I want you to see yourself reach your fullest potential and self-realization?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would say it sounds like you're trying to get me into bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's a potential you see yourself fulfilling... I mean...  My, I sound a bit --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. That was stupid of me. I didn't mean to be so rude.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't. You actually, for some reason, you have the effect on me of making me feel just a tiny bit ashamed of myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not too ashamed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you are being rude.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're still trying to get me into bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Dorothy Franklin passes by their table, a smirk firmly implanted on her face.</context>
      <utterance>Ouch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello you two. Am I barging in on some kind of religious study group? Elena, you look marvelous. Will I see you and Ben at the Halford's?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose we'll make an appearance.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Reverend Edwards? Did you make the list?</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe so Mrs. Franklin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She scurries out of the coffee shop.</context>
      <utterance>With the two of you there it will be positively a revival! I'm off!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid she's something of a gossip, isn't she?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid people around here provide her with quite a bit to gossip about.  Take care.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That I will indeed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's all the fines and penalties.</context>
      <utterance>It's not the taxes I object to.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright dad. But you sold the house, you didn't tell anyone, including the IRS, and I'd of certainly liked to have seen if there was any old stuff --</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another pause. Ben decides not to pursue an overworked topic.</context>
      <utterance>It was all junk!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Elena wanted to know when we could expect you on Thanksgiving. It's just going to be you this year.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben spits his drink out.</context>
      <utterance>Ben, I'm going to Florida. I hate Thanksgiving and I hate the cold. I have a new nurse. She's a negro, she weighs three hundred pounds, and I've decided to leave my entire estate to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Benjamin, you're still as gullible as ever.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a joke? You don't tell jokes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I'd start trying. If you don't mind. But I am going to Florida and I do have a new nurse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks again. For the dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for eating it. I don't know why I even pretend I can cook.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to know how to cook.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They smile, barely.</context>
      <utterance>It's not like we're too busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking of going back to school.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Social work?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Educated guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm that predictable? No, you don't have to answer that. It's just that with the kids almost grown --</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls the car over.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have to apologize. I'm too much of a cynic. You actually seem to be trying to figure things out -- don't mind me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the lift. If the bike's any bother--</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None at all. I'll leave it in front of your garage. Happy Thanksgiving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janey marches over to him.</context>
      <utterance>Sandy! Sandy looks up -- busted.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Sandy looks on the verge of tears. She softens and bends down to him.</context>
      <utterance>You little idiotic prick, you could blow yourself fucking sky high with all this demented crap.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.  I'll take this stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going to tell dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would it matter?  And what's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, it's the whip -- the one uncle Frank got me from Mexico.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not packed with explosives, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Play with the whip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Hi Wendy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Mrs. Williams.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mikey, have you heard the explosions coming from the backyard?  Do you know what Sandy's been up to?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses, then walks into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you kids have homework?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY AND WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy comes in, whip in hand, looks over at Mikey and Wendy, then walks over to them, and, without a word, slumps down beside them and watches the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Thanksgiving break. She walks out of the room again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy hesitantly opens the door, as Wendy still hovers by it.</context>
      <utterance>After you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you can...</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Sandy, what were you blowing up out there? Your mom was pretty p.o.'d.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All my model planes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ones you built?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were old. And they couldn't fly anyhow. I'm going to get a radio-controlled airplane at Christmas, and then I'll stuff it full of m-80s and then fly it into Mrs. Burgess's English class and blow it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go to the bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he stays put, unaware it seems that he's blocking the doorway. Wendy looks around -- no one in sight.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy goes wide eyed, and almost against his will backs into the bathroom like a feather.</context>
      <utterance>I'll show you mine if you show me yours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door flips open -- and Janey Williams appears.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want?! What do you want? Get out! Get out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A person's body is his temple, Wendy. This body is your first and last possession. Now as your own parents have probably told you, in adolescence our bodies tend to betray us. That's why, in Samoa and in other developing nations, adolescents are sent out into the woods, unarmed, and they don't come back until they've learned a thing or two.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't ever want to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why'd you come after me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She comes up and together they tug and pull until they succeced in extracting a large, frozen turkey. As they pull it out, it slips from their hands and, after a dull thump, slides along the floor. They smile. Elena bends over to pick it up. Ben observes her. She notices his look.</context>
      <utterance>Elena. I need some help here if this thing's gonna defrost by tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He goes over and picks up the turkey, placing it in the sink. He looks back at her and notices her vaguely distraught look.</context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all right there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Sure, I -- Did you remember to pick up the cranberry sauce?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand together, his concern and her vulnerability forming an awkward attraction between them.</context>
      <utterance>Um, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you like it on your turkey sandwiches.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do. I'm -- are you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I think I am...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know Elena, I've been thinking--</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben, maybe no talking right now? If you start talking, you're going to-- She kisses him as if she needed him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You crying?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just sad Ben -- I mean it was... you were, but, you know. I just don't know...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever that means Elena -- And you complain about me not communicating... I thought it was --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Have you --</context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't mean to sound negative. It was -- But Ben.  What is going to happen with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to bring this up now? What? Did I do something here? Is that it? Is it something I did?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't accusing you, Ben. It's just that we've got to be honest. Not just with ourselves, but with the children.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and starts to get dressed.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, I know. I -- I guess if you want to accuse me, you've got --  Oh hell! I've got to pick up Paul. I almost forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smells the armpits of the shirt he's putting on.</context>
      <utterance>You were saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yikes -- I was hoping to wear this thing to the Halford's Friday.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That shirt?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her ruefully.</context>
      <utterance>Leave it -- I'll wash it for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to follow me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. I -- They're now in front of the Hood's house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Mikey remounts and rides off, Wendy passes her father on the driveway.</context>
      <utterance>Business? Uh, I dunno. Ben grimaces, fiddles for his car keys.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm picking up Paul at the station - want to come?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you been up to?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how's school treating you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Classes?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grades?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone special? You know...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hnnn.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well it's good to see you -- we miss you around the house and all, but this St. Peter's, it's top of the line, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes a sharp turn. Paul puts his arms up on the dashboard to steady himself.</context>
      <utterance>You know Paul, I've been thinking, maybe this is as good a time as any to have a little talk, you know, about -- well --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses to gauge the effect of his monologue on his son, then continues.</context>
      <utterance>Well, the whole gamut. Facts of life and all. Some fatherly advice, because, I tell you, there's things happening that you're probably old enough... well...  For example, on the self-abuse front -- now this is important - it's not advisable to do it in the shower -- it wastes water and electricity and because we all expect you to be doing it there in any case -- and, um, not onto the linen, and not on your sister's underwear or any clothing belonging to your mother --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then Ben runs a stop sign and almost slams into another car.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, Dad --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy! Well. If you're worried about anything, just feel free to ask, and, uh, we can look it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, dad, you know I'm 16.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the more reason for this little heart to heart... great.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, Paul. On second thought, can you do me a favor and pretend I never said any of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the doorway, Elena waits.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Charles.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greetings, Charles.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are the parental units functioning these days?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad's like doing his Up With People routine, mom hasn't been saying much.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Dad seems a little weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both ponder silently. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah well wait till mom opens her mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I operate your telephonic apparatus?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you use the phone downstairs?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calling an individual, Charles, in New York. Confirming a social outing for Friday night.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I come?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a one-on-one kind of date thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With who?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her name's Libbets.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Libbets? What kind of a name is Libbets?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The turkey in?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stuffed and baking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben walks back to the bedroom, smirking.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be out in a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wendy grimaces, as they all bow their heads slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's great we can all be together. And this Thanksgiving, no hysteria, no yelling, especially with grandpa not here, although we miss him. So let's do it right and actually, Wendy, why don't you say grace. You used to love to say grace, remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Dear Lord, thank you for Thanksgiving, and for letting us white people kill all the Indians...</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Mutterings and groans: "Wendy!" "For Christ's sake" etc.</context>
      <utterance>... and steal their tribal lands and stuff ourselves like pigs</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... while children in Africa and Asia are napalmed and --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all unceremoniously start to dig in.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus all right enough!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After the Thanksgiving I had, I need it. You having one?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits next to him, he kisses the back of her neck.</context>
      <utterance>In a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janey gives him a rather contemptuous look.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I think Elena might suspect something.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's all for the better, you know? Yesterday, at dinner, well, she hasn't said anything... has she acted funny to you, I mean, have you noticed anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have I noticed anything? I'm not married to her Benjamin, you are. I think you've probably a better vantage point from which to observe her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janey gets up.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but, I -- I've been working a lot lately, and -- No, that's not it. I guess we've just been on the verge of saying something, whatever it is, just saying something to each other. On the verge.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benjamin looks at her quizzically.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Birth control.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans back onto the bed. Sits back up. Takes a sip of vodka. Puts the glass down. Takes his socks off. He's now in just his jockey shorts and shirt. Faintly, he hears a door close. The front door? He takes another sip. He hears another sound.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Gotcha. She leaves the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He goes to the door and carefully opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Janey? Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He hears, quite audibly, a car door open, close, Janey's car start and pull out. He runs to a front window just in time to catch a glimpse of her driving off.</context>
      <utterance>Janey?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, no one's here. Maybe you want to go to the basement?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we can just watch some TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Hood hears their steps down into the basement.</context>
      <utterance>There's a TV in the basement.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we can mess around. You know, only if you want to...</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you -- with Sandy?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Wendy doesn't seem to hear -- she's drawn to an object lying next to a bean bag chair off to one side.</context>
      <utterance>You like him? He worships you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a look of utter fascination, she picks up a Nixon mask, looking at it as though it were an archeological find.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the mask on.</context>
      <utterance>Wendy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When worlds collide.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ben arrives, folds his arms.</context>
      <utterance>4:30 movie. When Worlds Collide.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you kids doing down here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think we're doing, dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I think? I think you're probably touching each other. I think you're touching that reckless jerk-off, for god's sake, and I think he's trying to get into your slacks. I think, at fourteen years of age, that you're getting ready to give up your girlhood --</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hang on there, Mr. Hood --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you direct a single word at me, Mikey. I don't want to hear it. I'll be speaking with your parents about this situation very soon. Bet your ass on that, son. Young lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talking to me, dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who else would I be talking to? And take that thing off!</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then forget all this stern dad stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands next to Mikey for a moment, both on the verge of tears.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not interested in your smart ass remarks now, lady. Let's go. Right now. You and I can discuss it on the walk home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, kiddo, don't worry about it. I really don't care that much. I'm just not sure he's good enough, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him. They keep walking. She walks through a puddle.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, he's not serious, he'll end up living off Janey and Jim, you watch. It's just that you develop a sense when you get older, if things are going to work out or if they won't, and sometimes it's not worth the mess...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your toes cold?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops and lifts her in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her arms around his neck and he lifts her up. On her face, as he carries her -- a look of blank but real intimacy.</context>
      <utterance>I'll carry you up the drive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dinner in ten minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wendy heads for the stairs, Hood following.</context>
      <utterance>You go dry off now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not much response From Elena.</context>
      <utterance>Never guess where I found her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the basement over at Janey and Jim's. With that weirdo Mikey. Not even a TV on. And they're on the floor and he's got his trousers down though thank goodness she's still dressed. Well, I really let him have it!  ... and Wendy came home peacefully... Hey, should I dress for the Halford's now, or - give me your -</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up to you. I'd like to go early and leave pretty soon after that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get you loud and clear... hey, you look nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what were you doing in the Williams' basement anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, just dropping off a coffee cup. Jim left it, last time he was over. It was on the dash of the car. You were, you know, reading, thought I'd just catch some air. Let's eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh right. The mustache coffee cup. The one that was sitting on the dash.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks down to the kitchen, Benjamin following her.</context>
      <utterance>That one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay out of trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be on the 10:30 train?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah let the guy have his fun. What's the name of this girl with the Park Avenue address?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Libbets. Libbets Casey.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Libbets? What kind of name is Libbets?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... and that ends today's highlight coverage of the Watergate affair.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's for dessert?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His plate slips out of his hands into the trash. He fishes it out and sets it on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>No advice from the experts, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't start.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's on your mind? Don't --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wouldn't make a pleasant evening, if that's what you're after. I don't want to talk about it. Stupid mustache cup.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be dim.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elena, what are you're talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not surprised.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Elena, if you're gonna pull that passive aggressive stuff on me again --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your unfaithfulness -- that's what I'm trying to talk about. Your unfaithfulness. Your betrayal. Your dalliance. And you won't do me the dignity of being up front about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I unfaithful? Is that what you're trying to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a starting place.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what kind of faithfulness are you after?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're going to insult me --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>What else could I be? What else could I be? We're not living in the real world here. You're living out some fantasy land from the past, or some advice or something from those psychoanalysts... there are some hard facts here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the law of the land... the government, the world, those two guys on the Yankees... And I'm not having any fun at it, I can tell you that. I'm not...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh lord. You think I'm so dense. And now you want to be seen with your dense wife at the cocktail party. You want to wear that ridiculous shirt which doesn't go with those pants at all. You want to wear that, and you want me to shake hands with your friends and make conversation and dress up in an outfit that shows a lot of cleavage and you're not going to accord me the respect of talking honestly about this... You don't really know what this feels like.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I do. Do I know what loneliness feels like? Sure I do. I know a lot about it, if that's what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seemingly tired, he stands before her. Silence. Elena sighs, then walks into the den.</context>
      <utterance>Benjamin. That's supposed to explain it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>eyes still glued to the</utterance>
   <speaker>TV)</speaker>
      <mode> TV)</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it a big party? A big neighborhood party?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just curious. If there's a problem, I guess I'll just call you there to interrupt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elena kisses the top of her head.</context>
      <utterance>What sort of problems are you planning exactly?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh I thought I'd steal the station wagon, drive up to a commune. Or set the house on fire. You know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just bundle up. It's supposed to freeze tonight. We'll see you in the morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finishing the last of a celery canoe, she kisses the air next to Ben's ear and gives Elena a manic hug. Then, picking up a white salad bowl from the hall table:</context>
      <utterance>Ben, Elena. Wonderful! Wonderful! So wonderful to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Close on: the bowl full of keys.</context>
      <utterance>Would you care to play? New this year.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strictly volunteer, of course. You can put your coats in the library if you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, damn. Uh, I've left the --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. Yeah, we'll be right back, Dot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This just isn't the best moment for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I know. I had no idea --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That this was going to be a key party?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, if we'd understood we could have invented some kind of excuse. A key party -- did you see how stuffed that bowl was already?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we're here and we don't have to stay -- we ought simply to put in an appearance and then we can head home.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it, Ben --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not staying at this party so we can go home with someone else's wife. That's not why we're here, right? We're simply being neighbors here, and I think we should do just that --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going to --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have some marker, that's what I think, if you want to know the truth. You have some marker and you're going to put it on the house keys so that Janey can find them and then when I get back to the house I'll find the two of you in there and Wendy'll be able to hear you and Paul will be back and he'll hear you and I'll catch you, that's what I think. She'll be swearing and banging against the wall and I'll catch --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rubs her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Elena.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>I don't know --</context>
      <utterance>Elena, it's not what you think. It's not a big plot. Honestly. Honestly. I don't know if you want to go over this now, but it's just something that comes over me. I don't feel good about it. I know I've done what I didn't want to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm really pleased to hear a confession.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elena, you're just getting wound up to get wound up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls the keys out of the ignition, gets out of the car, and slams the door. He follows her.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the diagnosis, Ben. Thank you. So let's just go to this fiasco if that's what you want to do. Let's just go on in. I'd rather talk to anyone else but you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Benjie!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clair, George Clair! What the hell brings you to New Canaan?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's the funniest thing. I've been talking to some investors -- a little outside venture, you understand, between you and me -- about a scheme to manufacture a new Styrofoam packaging. Little peanut like pieces that can really keep an item free from trauma during shipping. Miraculous. Anyway, it turns out the genius behind the whole project is your neighbor, Jim Williams. How about that!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hey, isn't that a one-in-a million coincidence. A real dreamer, Jim Williams, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darned right. Look here, Benj, whaddya make of this sequel to The Godfather? You think it's gonna work?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't see how. I think the public's had its fill of this gangster stuff. No, trust me -- disaster pics. And air hockey.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benjamin catches a glimpse of Janey, voluptuously attired, across the room.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, gonna make a break for the hors d'oeuvres guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, see you bright and early Monday am.  Say, where's the wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh jeez, Benjie. Well, here you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn right, but where the hell were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janey takes a sip of her drink.</context>
      <utterance>Don't bullshit me around, Janey. Jesus Christ, I waited around for more than half an hour, in nothing but my boxer shorts, and -- and what's all that about? What the hell happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A prior engagement overcame me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Benjamin Hood. I have obligations that precede your... from before you showed up. One or two, you know, good-natured encounters, that doesn't mean I'm... I'm not just some toy for you. When I remembered some chores I wanted to get done before the party, I just did them, that's all, because I wanted to do them before I saw Jimmy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jimmy? Jimmy? I don't know how to take this. And what do you mean, Jimmy? I thought you said you and your husband --</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you take it isn't all that interesting to me, Benjamin. I'm sorry --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stalling, he watches her take another sip of her drink and wander off. The air is filled with talk of Watergate, Billie Jean King, the Oil Crisis, the Mets. Benjamin goes over to the couch, where Dave Gorman is chatting up an attractive younger woman.</context>
      <utterance>I just can't believe you could be so --</utterance>
   <speaker>GORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the Monkey House has been a seminal influence on me -- hey Benjamin -- give it a try? This stuff will make some sense out of those larger questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But then, Benjamin changes his mind.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the advice Dave.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Taking the joint, he tugs on it, holding the smoke in his lungs.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, well, what the hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>GORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure is good shit. It's opiated. I had it in my chamber for a while. I was smoking this other --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's what?</utterance>
   <speaker>GORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't fret, Benjie, it's --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises unsteadily, weaving through the room's conversations.</context>
      <utterance>Darn it, Dave.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK MOELLERING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benjamin walks over to a window. The outdoor lamps illuminate a new and heavy downpour of frozen sleet.</context>
      <utterance>Take California. They've got their own airline in-state that's not subject to the fare controls. Compare Sacramento to L.A. on the controlled airlines and you'll see what Friedman is saying -- supply and demand, less restriction.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Libbets Casey, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul Hood.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elevator on the right. Eighth floor -- she's waiting for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Paul opens the door, and enters the apartment.</context>
      <utterance>Open it Paul!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and runs into the den.</context>
      <utterance>Excellent. We were waiting!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And there, in the den, cleaning an ounce of dope on an open copy of Nixon's Six Crises, is -- Francis.</context>
      <utterance>We?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You oughtta read this Hood, Nixon, our leader, all ye need know about the travails of life. Check out the Checkers speech stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Francis. You gonna leave the seeds in there? In the binding like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The television is turned on to a weather report about the coming ice storm.</context>
      <utterance>All will be revealed, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awesome sleet and rain.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Howdy there. You, young knight. Can you check on the mead? Can you sally forth and secure us some more mead?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Moisture! Moisture!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul trudges disconsolately out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Beer. In the pantry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frankie opens them with his teeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Francis licks closed a second joint, then takes the beer and opens it with his rear molars.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's a sellable skill.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul opens the other two beers and hands one to Libbets. They light up a joint.</context>
      <utterance>Hell on the fillings.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's gonna freeze, the big freeze.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts an Allman Brothers tape on the 8-track and turns the TV down.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Paul, are you gonna get home okay? Paul and Francis exchange a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drops the blade and splashes water on her wrist, grabbing some toilet paper and holding it against the tiny wound.</context>
      <utterance>Ouch!</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hears the phone ring and walks downstairs.</context>
      <utterance>Stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hood residence.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're parents at that party?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get in trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. Can't really tell yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry if I got you into trouble. Maybe we don't have to, you know... unless you really want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to Silver Meadow, check out the ice storm... You wanna come.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. OK.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's freezing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy just looks at him. He walks out into the night.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. When it freezes, I guess that means the molecules are not moving. So when you breathe, there's nothing in the air, you know, to breathe in to your body. The molecules have stopped. So it's clean.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reverend Edwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits beside her.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you might find it in your heart to call me Philip?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're here... I'm a bit surprised.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes the shepherd needs the company of the sheep.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Philip's about to reply, but thinks better of it. They sit glumly next to each other for a minute. Then Philip rises.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to try hard not to understand the implications of that simile.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHILIP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks swiftly to the hall and hurriedly fishes his keys out of the bowl, then heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out some bottles.</context>
      <utterance>Eureka.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pockets the Seconal and turns out the light.</context>
      <utterance>Valium. Seconal. Uh,  Par-er-goric?  Francis Chamberlain Davenport the Fourth -- tonight you sleep the sleep of the just.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And whence has yon virginal maiden absconded?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul takes out the bottle and opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Like into one of the other 20 or so bathrooms they've got in this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check it out. Not for the faint of heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pharmaceutical! You are a god.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He hands a pill to Francis, then pretends to pop one into his mouth and takes a swig of his beer. As Francis downs his own, Paul pockets his unswallowed pill.</context>
      <utterance>One for you and one for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No candy for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Groovy.  Young master of the revels, a treat for our hostess?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, uh, I don't, it's really --</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on Paulie, share the wealth. You copped 'em from her mom's stash anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Libbets reaches into his pocket and pulls out the bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Libbets, you really shouldn't mix and match, you know with the beer. I'll put 'em back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens up the bottle and takes one out.</context>
      <utterance>Oh far out, Paulie. Hey look, these expired like five months ago. You think they're better aged?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should have just a half.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul looks on, thwarted.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the advice dad. She takes the pill.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Benjie, feeling no pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As the Indian saying goes, pain is merely an opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOLAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks across the room as Maria and her son Neil (stringy hair, acne, tie-dyed turtleneck, patched jeans) are engaging Janey and Philip Edwards in conversation.</context>
      <utterance>Hey -- check it out. Maria Conrad's brought her son.  I wish some of the gang had brought their daughters! Ben feels a wave of distaste at the joke.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NEIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As Werner says, there is nothing to get. That's It. When you get that there's nothing to get. That's the training, when you ask yourself, the question, "What is is?"</utterance>
   <speaker>JANEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, this is the training, where they don't let you go to the bathroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was the hardest part. But I did it. And you get into some far out shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>FRANCIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul is sitting on the couch, and Libbets comes back and sits at his feet, facing up to him.</context>
      <utterance>The foot... the foot... toeclipper man...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Libbets is herself somewhat in dreamland.</context>
      <utterance>I guess he's just real exhausted from, you know, tests and stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know Libbets, I really feel, you know, like a real connection to you --</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah but you don't even know me really.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure I do, you know, like your aura. That you give off.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like very positive, and I feel a real special feeling, because you really --</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I have a special feeling too, because I do. It's special.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do? I'm glad. Because I feel for you --</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I have a feeling for you too, because you're just like -- I feel for you like you're -- you're just like --</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL AND LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- like a brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you're not alone with that line.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIBBETS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Cool. So, how about we take a bath together?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She scoops up the bowl and places it on a high end table which has been put in the middle of the room.</context>
      <utterance>OK everyone. We have a little business to attend to now. So everyone who'd like to stay, please gather in the living room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elena waves at Janey Williams, who is standing across the living room. Janey looks back without expression.</context>
      <utterance>We're not going anywhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hood residence.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charles, what time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this Charles?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, ten-o-five. Why? Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm, uh, in the midst of a moral dilemma. And I was wondering, because I know you're a very moral person, and --</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I guess I better get to the train.</context>
      <utterance>Shit. I can't really talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing at home on a Friday night?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul hangs up the phone and looks down at Libbets. Libbets' Allman Brothers tape has run out. The machine makes a repeated clicking sound as the take up real continues to circle. The only other sound is the noise of the wind and rain lashing against the apartment's windows.</context>
      <utterance>I have plans.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what shall the order be, alphabetical? In order of appearance?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIERCE SAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nervous laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Golf handicap! Lowest handicap does the honors.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Golf handicap? Ladies, isn't it up to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA CONRAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria chooses Stephen Earle. Hands the keys to him. A smattering of applause as she takes his arm and they leave.</context>
      <utterance>Oh I'll go first, damn it. Let's just line up and get it over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIE EARLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neil watches his mother's exit.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MRS. GADD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my own husband. Isn't that against the rules?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try again?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. GADD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Gadd smiles as they leave, obviously happy to go. Finally, only Mark Boland, Neil Conrad, Janey and Jim Williams, Rob and Dot Halford, Sari Steele, Benjamin and Elena.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I think not.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elena steps forward. Benjamin is obviously agitated. Close on Janey's hands selecting -- away from Ben's equine key ring. She lifts up another key ring -- Neil Conrad, the teenager. She hands the self-important-looking Neil his keys and they turn to go. Jim Williams smiles mysteriously to himself. Ben suddenly lurches forward, semi-drunkenly, trying to separate Neil from Janey.</context>
      <utterance>Getting down to the wire!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry... maybe I should... the bathroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right down the hall, Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROB HALFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elena and Jim look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, we didn't put our keys in at all. But you won't spread it around? It's my party, and Dot isn't... hey, we're just going to slip upstairs for a while. You folks like a cup of coffee or something before we go?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim and Elena stand there alone.</context>
      <utterance>Rob, we'll fix it for ourselves. You two go and get acquainted. We'll let ourselves out the front door.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I have to say I don't have much faith that my car keys are still in that bowl. Doesn't seem entirely safe, leaving your car keys around?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes the bowl and dips her hand in. Two sets are left. One, her own, she avoids. She takes out Jim's keys and walks across the room, handing them to him.</context>
      <utterance>Let me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, but -- oh, I don't think so. It's been kind of a discouraging evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You couldn't have hoped for much better when you came up the walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sit down on the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>Somehow it was different in my imagination when I thought about it. Actually, I didn't think about it at all, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want coffee or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe they have one of those filter jobs in the kitchen --</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Elena, the fact that we're neighbors... you know, close friends, well it sort of makes this a little strange, don't you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both look at their hands.</context>
      <utterance>My husband is probably passed out in the bathroom, or at least he wishes he were. I've been married to him for 17 years and I don't have any intention of going in there to get him... so what I'm proposing is that since your wife has gone off with a boy, and since you are standing here alone, I'm proposing that you and I do what makes sense. Stay warm. Pass some time. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now don't make me feel as if I'm being too forward, OK? If you don't</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hey. Let's go for a drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Shall we clean up around here first? Do you think it's all right--</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But they still walk around turning off lights. In the hallway, Elena looks a bit mournfully at the light seeping from underneath the bathroom door. She hears the sound of running water from inside. Then she goes into a sideroom and joins Jim. They pick up their coats.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, that wasn't in the contract.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns on the ignition, and the vents start to blow cold air at them. He leans over and kisses her.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to have to defrost this thing for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That starts it. He jumps at her, unbuckling her and unzipping himself. They tangle uncomfortably for a few seconds. And then, comically, he's in her. With a groan, it's over in a flash. Jim pulls himself off, readjusting his pants.</context>
      <utterance>Do these seats go back?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elena has somehow worked herself into the cavity of the glove compartment, and is trying to figure out how to extricate herself.</context>
      <utterance>That was awful, really awful. I'm so sorry, Elena.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things are really rotten at home. You wouldn't believe how rotten. Janey's sick. She's unstable, I guess... it's not the right time to tell you... but that's it -- it's like I can't make her happy, the boys can't make her happy, she just doesn't --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, maybe we should just go. I've got to look in on the kids. Paul is supposed to be coming back in from the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, let me make it up to you -- I can do better than that, honestly</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we can talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's fine. I wouldn't expect you to see it any other way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you just need -- look, can you wait here a sec, I need to tidy up -- just a minute, I'll be right back. You'll wait?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the door and walks back to the house.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elena.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben, I've got a ride home. Maybe you should sleep this one off on the couch here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll drive you --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits on the toilet next to him, stroking his hair.</context>
      <utterance>Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He sits, accepting and quiet.</context>
      <utterance>You're in no condition to drive. We'll talk in the morning, OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll get some sleep on the couch out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. I'll try. And we'll talk in the morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll talk in the morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wendy wanders into the living room, then climbs the steps. The sound of the wind and the darkness begin to scare her. She goes into Mikey's room -- it's even more of a disaster zone than usual. She sees on the wall his dark-light poster of the 12 (sexual) positions of the zodiac. She notices the black garter belt on the floor, and picks it up, absentmindedly swinging it in her hand as she walks out of the room. She walks back down the stairs and into the kitchen, leaving the garter belt on the counter. She opens the refrigerator, grabs a jar of peanut butter, and scoops some up in her finger. As she puts her finger in her mouth --</context>
      <utterance>Anyone home? Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives out a little yelp.</context>
      <utterance>Wendy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sandy, you scared the shit out of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just thought I'd stop by.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mike's out -- I think he went to Silver Meadow to see if you were hanging around there.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you his girlfriend?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. You?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Well, I guess we can walk from here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs over to a side table and sees the clock: 11:10.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit! Paul gets up, looks down at her. She snores.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He grabs his comic books and runs for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit oh shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit oh shit. C'mon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the dog tag on the doll, and G.I. Joe emits a plastic macho voice.</context>
      <utterance>Check this out. He's supposed to talk all kinds of stuff, but he's like malfunctioned.</utterance>
   <speaker>G.I. JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mayday! Mayday! Get this message back to base!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wendy takes the doll and yanks the cord.</context>
      <utterance>Same thing. Again and again.</utterance>
   <speaker>G.I. JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mayday! Mayday! Get this message back to base!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During the course of his monologue, as Wendy looks on, Sandy calmly ties a noose for his doll.</context>
      <utterance>It's gonna get a lot colder tonight, I predict. Probably a blackout. Do you have candles in your house? I know where the candles are, and I have my own flashlight. Over there. Also, I know where every emergency exit is on this floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the noose over the doll's head, as Wendy holds him.</context>
      <utterance>This knot's called a bowline.</utterance>
   <speaker>G.I. JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mayday! Mayday!</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy drapes the noose over the edge of a dresser drawer. G.I. Joe dangles. They both look at him in silence. The silence continues.</context>
      <utterance>Let's hang him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it wasn't raining we could take him outside and blow him up.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes him down and lays him flat on the bed. And then begins to remove his clothes. Sandy looks on, desirous.</context>
      <utterance>He wouldn't blow up. He'd just get all mangled or twisted.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well.  It looks like someone got to his private parts before us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Communist Viet Cong.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wendy slides up on the bed where Sandy sits, a pillow on his lap, and one by one, with exaggerated slowness, she removes her snowboots, as if they were stiletto heels.</context>
      <utterance>They left it in the jungle. They speak with high seriousness.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy begins to shake.</context>
      <utterance>Can I get into your bed?  With you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We -- we have to go to the guest room. We can't stay in here. What if Mikey? My parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy begins to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about them. They're at that party, getting drunk and falling all over each other and making jokes about McGovern and stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his hand, and they walk out of the room and down the hall, into the guest room.</context>
      <utterance>It's just -- it's just --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vodka?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She fills the glass to the brim and hands the bottle to Sandy. They clink and each toss back a sip -- Wendy almost the entire glass. Sandy coughs and gags, but swallows.</context>
      <utterance>You never tasted the stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He does.</context>
      <utterance>Try again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It feels warm.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One more shot?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They drink.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Under they go, and soon every layer of clothing emerges.</context>
      <utterance>Under the covers.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy begins to laugh, and soon Wendy joins him. They roll around on top of each other for a while.</context>
      <utterance>Get 'em off.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever had a nocturnal emission?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>That's the name for when you wake up and find this little pool of sticky stuff, like after a sexy dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy doesn't answer, but climbs back on top of her and kisses her neck.</context>
      <utterance>They didn't tell you this stuff yet? What planet do you live on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice. Are you drunk?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. How do I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy rolls off her and lies on his back.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know either. You spin around, when you lie down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He yawns. She yawns.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think I'm spinning. They cuddle up together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to come in, get a cup of coffee -- warm up? I can either walk you home, or you could crash in the guest room.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Maybe coffee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks into the kitchen. The pipes have begun to burst. There's a water leak running down the walls, forming a puddle on the floor. Elena has walked into the kitchen behind him. She leans against the counter, picking up the garter belt without thinking for a second, then putting it back down.</context>
      <utterance>Phone's out. I hope the pipe's --</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elena climbs the stairs in her bare feet.</context>
      <utterance>Oh well. Why don't you put on some dry socks -- and we've got some rain boots in the guest closet back there. Last room upstairs -- back of the hall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elena walks out of the room, back to the kitchen. Wendy gets out of bed quietly, leaving Sandy sleeping peacefully. She looks at him lovingly, and tucks the blanket back up around him.</context>
      <utterance>Get dressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wendy enters. She looks inquisitively at the two adults.</context>
      <utterance>You should let him sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's dad?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elena sits next to her. They both raise their cups and sip the coffee, not noticing the simultaneity of their movements.</context>
      <utterance>It'll warm you up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes softly by them toward the body of his son.</context>
      <utterance>Ben? He's too breathless to speak. They stand there, looking down at Mikey. Behind Elena and Wendy, Jim appears.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sandy, now standing inside the foyer, pushes himself back against the wall as they pass, without expression. After a moment, from outside, the Hoods can hear Jim's wailing.</context>
      <utterance>Jim -- he was just up -- in Silver Lane -- I think maybe -- a power line -- Jim picks up his son. He carries him silently into the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think? Maybe we should call someone --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The phone's out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Well, we can just --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wendy has been watching Sandy through the screen door.</context>
      <utterance>Ben, I don't think he wants us here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns back up the front steps and gently goes in --</context>
      <utterance>Wait, I --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh you know, for a minute I thought it was --</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul? Yeah. You think --</utterance>
   <speaker>WENDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's probably been waiting all night at the station.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something -- your mother and I -- have to tell you two -- Elena puts her hand out, almost touching him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paul looks at Wendy, silently asking her what's happening. She casts her eyes downward, as does he.</context>
      <utterance>Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELENA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
