<movie id="67" title="Battle of Shaker Heights The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To give himself courage, he SINGS Tommy Dorsey's "I'll Be Seeing You [in all the old familiar places]" while maneuvering the Jeep through the bushes and rocks. He drives straight for a fallen LOG, GUNS the engine and tries to go over it. The Jeep's FRONT WHEELS catch on the log. The BACK TIRES spin. Kelly gets out. Takes off his M1 combat helmet and wipes his face. Assesses the situation. He grabs a BRANCH. Jams it under the wheel, trying to lever the Jeep free. When -- The STUTTER of a nearby MACHINE GUN startles him. The branch SNAPS against Kelly's weight. He slips and falls in the mud.</context>
      <utterance>Where the hell are those Krauts?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Determined, he grabs his pack and carbine and sets off on foot through the forest.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bingo.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGAINST THE TREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pulls out his dog tags and kisses them grimly.</context>
      <utterance>Kelly focuses himself. Then he shoulders his carbine.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes his Smith &amp; Wesson 1917 PISTOL from his pistol belt and steps out into the SUNLIGHT FIELD in plain sight of the guards. Surely he knows they can see him. He must want them to see him. But they don't. Too busy passing nudie wallet photos. Halfway across the open grass, Kelly raises the pistol but does not aim it. Just strides steadily closer, arms spread out, making himself an easy target. Crazy as it seems, Private Kelly Ernswiler is trying to get himself killed.</context>
      <utterance>"And so they buried Hector, breaker of horses."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Kelly whips around to face a third German, the OFFICER. His pistol points right into the Officer's shocked pink young face. Point blank range. Only - Kelly doesn't fire. He just lowers the pistol. The German smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Eine maus findet den kase.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill me Adolf.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Infantrymen have recovered from their idle and come running. One of them yanks Kelly's hands behind his back and pushes him into the barn roughly. Kelly doesn't struggle.</context>
      <utterance>Mien Prisoner!</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Siegfreid and Roy. What are you waiting for? Kill me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The German Officer produces a piece of paper and a fountain pen.</context>
      <utterance>Come on you pussies. Let's get this over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly takes the pen and examines it.</context>
      <utterance>You will write your mother. Tell her how you will die now.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer pokes the paper.</context>
      <utterance>Genuine Third Reich issue, no less. Nice work.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will write. How you die alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother and I don't have that kind of relationship.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly thinks about it for a minute - should he or shouldn't he - but sighs and begins writing. After a few lines, the Officer snatches the paper away and passes it to an Infantryman.</context>
      <utterance>Write.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough. Now you will beg for your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What don't you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>INFANTRYMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer wheels around and scowls at the speaker. He seems to be getting a bit hysterical.</context>
      <utterance>The protocol says we should -</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the fucking protocol.  Beg! He and Kelly glare at each other. The Officer FIRES his Luger into the rafters.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beg - for - your - life!</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer grabs his throat.</context>
      <utterance>You got to be kidding me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly laughs. The officer slaps him. Kelly jerks away.</context>
      <utterance>Silence. Now I have a little fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's against the rules.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've never killed anyone before, have you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GI shoots the two infantrymen who fall in exaggerated pain and commence death throes. Quick as a flash, the GI's Colt 1911 PISTOL is at the German Officer's neck, his M-1 in his other hand.</context>
      <utterance>I shower in the blood of my victims --</utterance>
   <speaker>GI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No wonder you smell so bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GI's eyes widen. He looks at Kelly.</context>
      <utterance>Don't shoot, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>GI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you look at the manners on this guy?  Remember to thank me when I kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer SHRIEKS, grabs at his neck, and falls.</context>
      <utterance>No, really, not in the neck - But the GI does anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>GI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. My elaborate death scene wasn't going anywhere anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>GI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to give you a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay. They'll get me eventually. If you can't get killed in a war, when can you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GI holds out his hand.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. Look on the bright side.</utterance>
   <speaker>GI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly takes the hand of the grinning all-American type guy. About his own age, but BART takes up more space.</context>
      <utterance>Bart. Bart Bowland.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelly. Kelly Ernswiler.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bart?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean - that's Irish, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow man, this is a really beautiful scene and all, but I have to interrupt.  Why the fuck did you have to shoot that cap so close to my neck? You gave me a powder burn.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer gets up and dusts off his uniform.</context>
      <utterance>Listen you wienerschnitzel. You should talk. You slapped me. I'm not your bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what was that whole creepy death wish thing about?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well it didn't work, now did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I get so caught up in the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer grins.</context>
      <utterance>And what was that ridiculous shit about making me write to my mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inspired, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude, you made him write to his mother? Who are you, Dr. Phil?</utterance>
   <speaker>INFANTRYMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart helps him up and checks his regulation-issue Timex.</context>
      <utterance>Can we get up now?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The German Officer crosses his arms.</context>
      <utterance>Might as well. There's only an hour left anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Admit it. You were scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly gets up from the chair and falls over. His legs are still tied.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That Willys yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart unfolds an entrenching tool from his belt and digs under the back wheels, building up dirt. Then he goes around to the front and puts his shoulder against the hood. Bart rocks the Jeep while Kelly pumps the gas. The Jeep finally pulls free and SPRAYS Bart with mud.</context>
      <utterance>Yup. Just got her. Three summers packing out at Shop Rite.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks over his shoulder and starts backing away.</context>
      <utterance>My bad. Thanks though.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart stands there, dripping with mud, shocked. About a hundred feet away Kelly stops.</context>
      <utterance>See you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart walks towards the Jeep. Kelly backs it up again.</context>
      <utterance>Well, come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart climbs in.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't resist.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real funny, Ernswiler. You might still get your chance to die today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Character building? Those crazy guys from Ann Arbor tied them to a dock.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what you get for invading Wisconsin.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D-Day at Kenosha was nothing. At Guadalcanal Chillicothe there was a guy who actually injected himself with malaria.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both eat for a minute.</context>
      <utterance>That's crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you live, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shaker Heights.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That explains the death wish. Me too. What street?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Penn Place.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm, don't know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Kelly looks at Bart.</context>
      <utterance>It's not technically in Shaker Heights - but I go to Shaker Heights High.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Langely Prep.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to hear that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I got kicked out of Shaker Heights High because my birdhouse came unglued in honors woodshop.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart throws his napkin on his plate.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. I would have gone to Langely myself only my polo pony had the fits.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No matter.  We're all soldiers here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right./Here, here./ Whooping, cheers, etc.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Service our lawnmower.</context>
      <utterance>You should come over some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would, but then I might soil my croquet whites. You understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly watches Bart go into his house and smiles in spite of himself.</context>
      <utterance>How bourgeois. Cheerio then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly doesn't smile at this. He looks at the sandwiches and puts his finger to his chin in a gesture so facetious it's downright angry.</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant Keller! How was the war? Did we win?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe grabs two pieces of bread from a loaf. He looks kind. A bit ill-used by life. The phrase "rode hard and put away wet" comes to mind.</context>
      <utterance>Let me guess. Happy Meals for the wavy gravy wellness center?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finishes that sandwich and adds it to the pile. Kelly pauses while opening the refrigerator. His back tightens. He slams the door with his foot.</context>
      <utterance>As usual, your cynicism is refreshing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe pauses over a slice of bread only briefly. The hostility is nothing new.</context>
      <utterance>As usual, your cheerful optimism makes me ill.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly walks through the kitchen and out the back door.</context>
      <utterance>You should get that checked.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure thing, doc. Say hello to Leif Garrett for me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>MAO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son of Eve. You are very dirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A rough charge. You know.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grandmother Xiou-Xiou dabs at the painting.</context>
      <utterance>Now you try.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She loves the gold. Always overuses it. And usually her touch is so light.</utterance>
   <speaker>XIOU-XIOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve moves along the row, stopping to look at the paintings in progress.</context>
      <utterance>Gold is the color of the sun.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Eve has stopped behind Mao's painting. She's not paying attention to Kelly.</context>
      <utterance>You know why we never have anything to eat in this house?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gestures at the image of a horse done Santa Fe style, lots of pastels, very abstract. Mao looks at her quizzically.</context>
      <utterance>Mao, what did we say about the eyes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More - empathy?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. And didn't I tell you to put in more cacti?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His family nods in support of this rash aesthetic statement. Eve rolls her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No, no more cacti. Too busy. Simplicity is best.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly breaks in.</context>
      <utterance>Oh boy. I'm not having this battle with you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve moves down the line.</context>
      <utterance>Because your husband takes food from his own family to feed every loser druggie in Cleveland.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this the family nods and smiles to each other, pleased with the news.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you can always chip in here. We're ordering pizza later.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve looks up at him for the first time. Takes in his filthy uniform.</context>
      <utterance>No. Some people have to work later.  Will you drop something off at the dry cleaners for me tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweetie, you know what we said about paying for the war things. Nothing's changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the only thing I ever ask you for --</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be dramatic.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve stops at Mother Ling's painting.</context>
      <utterance>But it's important to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mother Ling looks up at Kelly, who's scowling. She smiles and nods, understanding.</context>
      <utterance>You're just going to have to find a way to pay for it yourself then, I guess.  No - not that way - the sky should be stormier. Angry clouds.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly leaves. Eve's busy talking.</context>
      <utterance>Why do I bother?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More brown, less blue.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks at him and bites into the sandwich.</context>
      <utterance>Now Keller, who needs that sandwich more - you or the daughter of a crack addict trying to make a new life?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly leaves with the sandwich. Abe sighs and picks up more bread.</context>
      <utterance>How about the son of a heroin addict trying to get ready for work?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That went well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly doesn't stop working. He's got a system.</context>
      <utterance>So how'd your battle go today? I still don't understand how you could reenact the Battle of the Bulge in seventy-two degree weather.  Didn't all those guys freeze to death?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, a Port-a-John fell over on a couple of guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly grabs another handful of cans.</context>
      <utterance>War is hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly pauses. He puts two cans on the shelf very deliberately.</context>
      <utterance>Then why do you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're never more alive then when facing simulated death.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks at her, thinks about this, and stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Really? Maybe I should try it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah covers her head, huddled behind the boxes of cat food, dodging cans.</context>
      <utterance>You are William J. Stone of the 1st Airborne, pinned down in Noville. The Germans have the high ground and they're shelling your position heavily.  You're holed up in a stone barn. Sustaining heavy casualties. Running low on ammo. The cries of wounded men fill the air like the cries of hungry babies.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your commanding officer gets hit in the face, dies. At 1 p.m. you lose radio contact with headquarters. If you withdraw, the Germans will flank the entire Allied forces arrayed along Bastogne and break the front. What do you do? What do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly goes back to stocking, satisfied.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Battle of Bulge, the Southern Shoulder, December '44.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah stands up and starts to wander away but Kelly makes a peace offering.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry I asked.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah looks at her feet, considering whether or not to accept it.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Want a snack? We got a whole shipment in of busted Oreo's.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll accidentally drop a couple pints of milk and meet you over there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The frozen food woman came in with her kids. They must eat out of those little cardboard trays every night. One of the kids looked like cardboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know we stock more flavors of cat food than we do baby food?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fishes for a cookie.</context>
      <utterance>Sixteen flavors of baby food including the toddler meals-in-ajar, thirty- one flavors of cat food.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ANGRY WOMAN pushes open the swinging door of the backroom with her loaded shopping cart.</context>
      <utterance>Next time you should tell that woman to buy her kid some cat food.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah gets up. Kelly stays right where he is, finishing a cookie.</context>
      <utterance>Is this store open? I've been waiting up front. If the store's closed, it shouldn't have a sign that says twenty- four hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a lot of coupons and I don't want to be here when they expire.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah smiles and hurries away.</context>
      <utterance>Charge her double for everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly shakes his head and gets a book out of his locker.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you looking at, GI Jane?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No really, what makes you think you can look at me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I honestly didn't know it was you. I thought it was a free preview of the Spice Channel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance shakes his head and pulls Bridget to him, grinding his pelvis against hers.</context>
      <utterance>That's pretty funny. You got dental insurance? Kelly closes his locker and walks away. Bridget wipes her mouth guiltily.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurries through to the next slide. It doesn't matter anyway. Everyone is almost asleep. Except Kelly, who becomes increasingly irritated the more Mr. Norman talks.</context>
      <utterance>Whoops!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly shifts in his seat.</context>
      <utterance>And here, at Gettysburg, the ranks of Union soldiers fought bravely on. They were willing to give their lives so that others might be free.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a problem Mr. Ernswiler?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Mr. Norman doesn't start talking again. He waits, looking at Kelly, smiling blandly. Until the silence becomes uncomfortable. And Kelly gets mad.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Isn't this analysis a tad simplistic? I mean, maybe for a second grade history class, sure - but to insist on still characterizing the Civil War as some moral struggle? The soldiers were drafted - the only ones who had to fight were the ones who couldn't afford to pay their way out.  Why don't you talk about the Draft Riots? Where are your slides for that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HOLMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly doesn't move. He's not into this.</context>
      <utterance>What gives you the idea that you can or ought to question the curriculum?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or question your teacher?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ms. Holmstead is exasperated, but she likes him in spite of herself. He's a smart cookie. She's got to change her strategy. She leans back in her chair.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I mean, who ever heard of a classroom dialog? Not Socrates.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelly, you're a very bright boy. But you're making some serious mistakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her chair SQUEAKS as she leans forward and looks at Kelly intently.</context>
      <utterance>I don't need to. Everyone else makes them for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This anger must be masking a lot of hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmstead tries again. She looks down at his file.</context>
      <utterance>I was wondering what the tissues were for.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly shrugs. Holmstead searches his face for any clues.</context>
      <utterance>I see you're not going to college next year. What are your plans?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I get through to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head and swings her chair towards the window and gazes out at the front walkway of the school. Her face clears. Something's clicked.</context>
      <utterance>Advertisers use status and sex to appeal to my demographic.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we can come up with a punishment which might actually be more of an opportunity for you to realize your true potential.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly hardly stops walking.</context>
      <utterance>You upset Bridget.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need to apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance runs and grabs Kelly's backpack.</context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do, make out with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you fucking with me? You little fucker. Want to play, fuckface?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly tries to start walking again but Lance has hold of him.</context>
      <utterance>You just used fuck as a verb, noun, and adjective. Impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance grabs Kelly's arm and yanks it back. Kelly still seems unconcerned. Suddenly he pulls away, but Lance keeps hold of his backpack. Lance holds the backpack up next to his head and points at it, gleeful. Lance walks away towards his car. Kelly runs after him. Lance holds Kelly off easily with one hand and throws the backpack into his SUV. They STRUGGLE for a minute, until Lance pushes Kelly away, gets in the car. Kelly runs next to the car and pounds on the window as Lance drives off. Finally, Kelly gives up. Lance turns out of the parking lot and HONKS the horn. Kelly shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Let's see what Beetle Bailey's got in his knapsack.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rim job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelly. Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You work here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a couple days a month, to get a heads-up on the latest stuff. What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking for a backpack.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that all? Don't bother. I have a couple extras at home. I could give you one if you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, I guess.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly holds up a flask in a leather case.</context>
      <utterance>My dad's real into hoarding.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grant's field flask.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. Your dad should meet my history teacher. He sent me to the principal's office today for questioning his G- rated interpretation of the Civil War.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would, but now the principal's making me give a speech on the Civil War at an assembly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is he, some kind of sadist?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She thinks she's doing me a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, she must think you're really screwed up. Are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends on who you ask. Everyone's got an opinion.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stonewall Jackson's.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly nods. That is balls.</context>
      <utterance>Can you imagine that? Losing your leg and getting back up on your horse? Unbelievable. What balls.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart puts down the box carelessly and paws through the piles.</context>
      <utterance>He's got so much crap crammed in here he doesn't even notice when it's missing. I saw a backpack in here somewhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought he had a couple.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd feel weird taking one out of the tomb of Tutenkamen anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me, you shouldn't.  Where'd your old one go?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lost it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. Kelly decides to tell him.</context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone took it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You let someone take it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't let him. I told off some idiot --</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like your mouth gets you into trouble a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's older. Definitely in college, if not out. And totally shockingly beautiful. Otherworldly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, it's not me, it's the world. TABBY, Bart's older sister comes in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tabby, this is Kelly.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give him any money, whatever you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly laughs. And looks at Tabby more closely.</context>
      <utterance>All these little old ladies are looking for him in Arizona. He took their retirement money and bought defective bazookas with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very funny. We're paying attention to you, are you happy now?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finally, my life is complete. Fait accompli.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Minnie's making sloppy joes. Want one?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens the fridge and gets a yogurt.</context>
      <utterance>Sloppy joe? Sloppy no.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby leaves. Kelly's distracted.</context>
      <utterance>I have to go take a shower. Will you call me when Miner gets here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Miner?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart rolls his eyes, indicating what he thinks of good old Miner. Kelly nods, doesn't say anything.</context>
      <utterance>The fianc.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly glances at the door Tabby left from.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, I'm going to the flea market on Saturday. I have a line on a couple dealers. You could get a backpack there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah? Flea market, land of bargains.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks at Bart with suspicion -- and respect.</context>
      <utterance>Especially if you know who to talk to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Cro-Magnons grunt approvingly at this witty repartee.</context>
      <utterance>Hey fuckface. Like my new hat? I just joined the Boy Scouts.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ooh. The Cro-Magnons laugh at Lance and EGG him on - "You gonna take that?"/"He just called you a fag", etc. Lance frowns and grabs Kelly.</context>
      <utterance>If you stay in it long enough, maybe you'll get your fudgepacker badge.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still holding on to him with one arm, he SLAPS Kelly hard across the face with the other. Kelly's knees give a bit. Lance holds him up.</context>
      <utterance>You're a regular Howie Mandel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance looks over at her and releases Kelly.</context>
      <utterance>Lance!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly is hurt but covering.</context>
      <utterance>Okay babe.  One day you and me will be alone. And won't that be nice?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly frowns and adjusts his clothes. Tries to re-wet the dry inside of his mouth with his tongue. He turns slowly and trudges up the stairs. Sarah has been watching the whole thing from the door.</context>
      <utterance>Too bad my mom won't let me date yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you mess with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right. I should give him a break.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks at the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Kelly, you're home. Good. I need you to go to the art supply store for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve goes to her purse and rifles through it to find her wallet.</context>
      <utterance>Get Abe to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was going to but he had to go lead a meeting at Care House.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make it up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Where have I heard that before?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly jabs at the remote.</context>
      <utterance>When are you going to give me a break?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve waits through this.</context>
      <utterance>Let me think - maybe when I finally forget every single word of The Little Mermaid soundtrack I'd listen to in the car waiting for him to score. No, probably when I don't prepare myself before I go into the bathroom, expecting to find him passed out on the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, you know what? I know I'll be able to put it all behind me when I go away to college.  Only, I can't go because someone spent my college fund on Mexican Black Tar. So looks like I'll have to try to forget at Shop Rite, where I'll be working for the rest of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve comes over to Kelly. He sighs and puts his hand out.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. You have every reason to crawl into the corner and give up. But please just get me some paints first.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him the money.</context>
      <utterance>What do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her hand up but he moves away from it.</context>
      <utterance>We need burnt sienna, cadmium red, and midnight blue. Two tubes of blue.  What happened to your face?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes Tabby a second to recognize him.</context>
      <utterance>They're having a sale on glitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hello. What happened to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby looks at him suspiciously like she's not sure whether to believe him. Tabby finishes with the mediums and moves onto the paints. Kelly follows her, staying in the opposite aisle.</context>
      <utterance>Tennis injury.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You paint?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you see... That's a difficult question.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How so?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In spite of herself, Tabby laughs at this. This gives Kelly more confidence. He leans over the aisle to see what she's looking at.</context>
      <utterance>I don't really feel comfortable calling anything done since the Renaissance "painting." We might have a more experimental interaction with the picture plane, but our skills have suffered from it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're working with acrylic. Why? Oil's much - richer.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh you're not one of those oil snobs are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly comes around and leans nonchalantly against the shelves, knocks more things over and fumbles to replace them.</context>
      <utterance>Of course not.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just - isn't acrylic a bit - jejune?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jejune? You're jejune. How old are you anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby walks to the counter with her brushes.</context>
      <utterance>Older than my years.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks down and partially confesses.</context>
      <utterance>And you paint?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you know, my mother's kind of an artist, so -</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby signs the slip and takes the bag. She walks out, Kelly with her, matches her pace, talking.</context>
      <utterance>That explains it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That explains nothing. Doesn't anyone believe in innate knowledge anymore? Michelangelo was fifteen when he painted the Infanta.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby gets into her car. Kelly leans into her window.</context>
      <utterance>Infantas are Spanish. Michelangelo was Italian.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby tries to conceal her smile and starts her car.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly. One world, one people. Just like Jesse Jackson envisioned.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drives away. Kelly stands there watching. Then he winces.</context>
      <utterance>Well - Kelly. Nice talking to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell did you just say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SKINNY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That there's actual sand from Iwo Jima.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Or your sister's sandbox.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKINNY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it don't come with no certificate of authenticity.  I could write one up for you, I suppose. Get it notarized.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, that's quite all right. Actually, I'm in the market for medals.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKINNY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart acts casual, hands clasped behind his back.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. I got a couple purple hearts. A Silver Star. DSC. Can't sell them to you though. They were gramp's.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKINNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They have a lot of sentimental value</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKINNY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart pulls out a paper bag and offers it to the skinny guy, who looks inside.</context>
      <utterance>A lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKINNY GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly is shocked. The skinny guy looks at his suspiciously.</context>
      <utterance>General Ulysses S. Grant's field flask, my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The skinny guy looks at Bart, and in the bag again. He goes to get the backpack. Kelly's impressed by this smooth exchange.</context>
      <utterance>Throw in one of those backpacks and we'll call it even.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buying and selling US service medals is illegal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. That's why the resale value is so high.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what they teach you at Langely?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be so nave. We all have our skeletons. Some of them just pay more than others.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'm not even going to ask about the flask.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ask, don't tell. The army gets everything right, don't they?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You boys look like Goldwater fans.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never been accused of that before.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well jeez, you don't have to be insulted.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman considers this, her fan working back and forth lazily.</context>
      <utterance>Anything military?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart paws through the box. Acts casual.</context>
      <utterance>Fish around in that cigar box.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want for the box?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be so hasty.  I got a few Geraldine Ferraro pins I'm looking to unload.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goldwater fan. I think that's some kind of insult.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at Dartmouth. Where are you going to go to school?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, you have that luxury.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't have much say in the matter. Everything has been decided for me since birth. I'm not whining about it. Play the hand you're dealt, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy for you to say. You got a royal flush.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They eat for a minute to the soothing sounds of the BINGO</context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy? My life sucks. Everyone's always telling me what to do. You can't fight it. Go with the flow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Tabby?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She got to go where she wanted. Sarah Lawrence. Six years. She's almost done with grad school. Yale.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't think people actually went to Yale.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I mean, she drives off in her car in September. For all we know, she could just pull her car over in Albany and sleep there until May.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart does some fake sign language to help Kelly out.</context>
      <utterance>It was a joke. Joke?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart pushes Kelly, who grabs his arm like it got hurt.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Is that what one of those sounds like? Somehow, I always imagined they would be funnier.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Sarah Lawrence? Isn't that for lesbians?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to your face?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember the backpack incident?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Interested, Bart leans forward.</context>
      <utterance>The one with mad cow-diseased hamburger meat for brains? That would be the one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to lower myself to his level.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not. But there are alternatives</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alternatives?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Haven't you ever heard of the 193rd Special Operations Wing?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well do you want to get this guy or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart tosses his wrapper at the trashcan. Kelly watches it hit the rim and go in.</context>
      <utterance>All right. Let's get the fuck out of here, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have some things to show you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once we've gathered the intelligence, the plan will reveal itself.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart opens a pad.</context>
      <utterance>We don't plan first?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it limits our scope - what's the objective?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Humiliation. Rage. Despair.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart grabs a book and starts flipping through pages. Tabby enters with an armful of art supplies.</context>
      <utterance>Easy enough. 'Nam's probably our go- to war for that sort of thing. I have the declassified briefs from the Phoenix Project around here somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. I have some stretcher bars out in the car. Can somebody help me bring them in?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart doesn't look up. He grabs another book.</context>
      <utterance>Of course we'll drop what we're doing because what you're doing must be more important.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart raises his eyebrow. Kelly shrugs off the look.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. I mean, I'll help.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll find those reports.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="43">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby wrestles with the bolt of canvas.</context>
      <utterance>Gold. The color of the sun.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the Cleveland waterfront.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As the viewer, I get to decide what it is, I'm afraid. And it doesn't look a thing like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the light. I was playing with diffusion.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well make sure you put it away when you're done with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly resumes his tour of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Very funny, wiseass.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must be nice to have a place like this to get away to.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Farmer?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby unrolls the canvas and measures lengths.</context>
      <utterance>Farmer?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The boyfriend.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miner? What about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he an artist, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly is silent for a while, fiddling with a clamp light.</context>
      <utterance>No. Definitely not. Thank god.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said your mom was a painter?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby cuts the canvas.</context>
      <utterance>She was, well - is I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She used to be. But then my dad - wasn't working anymore so she turned it into a business. She has a family of Chinese immigrants in the garage making them for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like Andy Warhol's Factory.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More like Andy Warhol's tool shed. It was nice before, though. My playpen used to be in her studio.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. So you really grew up with it. What does, did, your dad do?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a VH-1 documentary without the music.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Tragedy struck?" Kelly nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"And then, things took a turn for the worse."</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, just wait. Those burnout types always have a triumphant comeback tour.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby sits back on her heels and looks at him. Bart's head appears in the open door.</context>
      <utterance>I already changed the channel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ Kelly, I let you go out on a little supply line assist and you're gone for days. Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have fun, boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If only it were fun. War's deadly serious, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I used to think you were the only crazy one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart leaves. Kelly stands by the door. This is his only chance.</context>
      <utterance>Enough with the mind pollution, Hanoi Hannah.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm worried about you playing with diffusion unsupervised.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I might have to come by and show you the proper safety procedures. Some time in the presence of an art prodigy would do you good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I have room for a playpen in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby smiles. Kelly leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Ouch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, you have a thing for my sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? No, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They skirt around the pool.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody does.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just have a few things in common.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh really, like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you. It's my feminine side.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't wear women's clothes when you're alone, do you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure doesn't move. Kelly doesn't know what to do.</context>
      <utterance>Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks around, worried. In this house an unresponsive dad isn't necessarily sleeping. Should he wake up his mom? He shakes the figure slightly. It rolls over, only it's not his dad. It's some scabby ADDICT. Kelly yanks his hand away.</context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADDICT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment.</context>
      <utterance>Wha?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly frowns.</context>
      <utterance>Keller. There's a meteor shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe laughs.</context>
      <utterance>A funny thing just happened. A little trip down memory lane. I thought you were on our couch, dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly nods, considering this.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you mean Emmett? They didn't have an empty bed for him at Care House.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well that's one of your more brilliant ideas.  Have you thought about the fact that it might be dangerous? That he might steal something, or go into cardiac arrest? Drink all our cooking wine? Which he seems to have done.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just needs a place to sleep for the night.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe slams his hands down on the arms of his chair.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. Besides, having him here makes it feel like home.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly claps slowly.</context>
      <utterance>I've been straight for four years, almost five. A third of your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Big whoop. I've been straight the whole time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly gets up.</context>
      <utterance>I hate to tell you this, but I'm not your problem anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe looks at Kelly.</context>
      <utterance>No. That's the one thing I get to decide.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other. Kelly shakes his head and goes inside. Abe looks up at the sky.</context>
      <utterance>Let me know. I can wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keller, there's a meteor shower.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he's leaving.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly hands the glasses over. Bart looks through them. Then he puts them down.</context>
      <utterance>Let me see. Don't be a farb, give them up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys looks at each other.</context>
      <utterance>The coast is clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart opens up a duffel bag and pulls out a yellow jumpsuit which he puts on. Kelly looks through the binoculars.</context>
      <utterance>Let me prepare to deploy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this going to work?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've planned for every contingency using the tried and true techniques of the last great world power.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Save it for the press conference.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE LAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart is dressed in an official-looking yellow jumpsuit with telephone repairmen's tool hanging from his belt and a hard hat on. Kelly carries a toolbox.</context>
      <utterance>The boys climb down out of the tree house.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Kelly. Then he holds up one finger and gestures "go." They sneak hunched over towards the fence. A LITTLE GIRL comes out of the house and stops when she sees them. Bart and Kelly look at each other. Bart takes the toolbox and gestures to Kelly by pointing at the girl and covering his mouth. Kelly peels off towards the girl while Bart continues across the lawn. The girl starts to SCREAM. Kelly swoops up and covers her mouth with his hand. He tucks her under his arm and runs towards the opposite side of the house. He puts the girl down, still covering her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Stay low. On my signal.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl nods. Kelly takes his hand off her mouth and starts to sneak away.</context>
      <utterance>We're the good guys. If you scream, the bad guys are going to come and burn down your house. Okay? So stay here and be quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly runs across the street to get a view of the front door.</context>
      <utterance>My dad has a gun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>NEIGHBOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly starts and turns.</context>
      <utterance>Can I help you, young man?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly grabs a few blades of grass.</context>
      <utterance>I was just inspecting your lawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you thought about Astroturf? It takes a lot less water to keep green. I mean, no water, technically.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not interested.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly gets up and starts to walk down the street, only - Lance PULLS UP in his SUV. Kelly darts behind a parked car and watches Lance go into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. I see. Okay then.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance comes right back out. He forgot something in his car.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly moves around the car, trying to keep it between him and Lance. Bart comes down the front walk whistling and eating a cookie. He smiles at Lance, now coming back up the walk.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly follows him on the other side of the row of cars until Lance's house is out of sight. Then he gets in step beside Bart.</context>
      <utterance>Smile worker bee. I'll be your boss some day. Bart nods and tips his HARD HAT.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What an asshole. His mom gave me cookies, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get it done?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ask stupid questions. Let's go home and listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart FLIPS the ON switch and Lance's Mom's voice fills the room. The boys smile with delight.</context>
      <utterance>It was a five-watt FM bug, so we should be in range -</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So then I told her, "Harriet, with potato salad like that it's no wonder Ray-Ray's cheating on you."</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE'S MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly shakes his head as the women natter away.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. But I was thinking it. Instead I just told her to add more vinegar next time, and -</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think we can use any of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be patient. It's voice activated, so we'll get everything. Trust me. It's going to be great.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly gets up to leave while Bart fiddles with the knobs.</context>
      <utterance>All right, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We reconnoiter tomorrow at nineteen hundred hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve looks at her husband and sees he's not paying attention. He seems a little out of it. He's pushing his food around on his plate.</context>
      <utterance>-- And if we don't sell them there, we'll set up on the corner of Stevens and Lane, by the gas station. That's a good location.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you listening to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you make this with more chili pepper than usual?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly comes in, walks through the kitchen and up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>The same as always.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelly. Want dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>His parents eat for a minute in silence. Abe winces and puts down his fork. Eve smiles tenderly at him.</context>
      <utterance>I ate.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe puts his hand over hers.</context>
      <utterance>One day, we're all going to be happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really too perfect, actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly hits a button. The tape clicks ON. From the speakers comes:</context>
      <utterance>I can't describe. Just hit play. It's all cued up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, that makes me nervous. Me no likey.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But baby, my birthday's coming up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still. That's not a good enough reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. A little action. A little prime time action.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But people might see us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly stops the tape.</context>
      <utterance>That's the point. That's what makes it sexxxy. Dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart and Kelly share a look. Kelly grins.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's draw up the plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All we have to do is fill in the details and let Operation Deadmeat begin.</context>
      <utterance>I have a few notes jotted down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus, I'm so sorry - He starts picking them up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around. If Lance showed up it wouldn't be good for either of them. Kelly hands her the rest of her stuff. They part ways. Kelly shoves a piece of paper into his pocket. Principal Holmstead CLICKS down the hall in her heels and Kelly DUCKS into a doorway just in time. He turns and pretends to look at a posted announcement as she passes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's okay -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She dots her I's with hearts. And her L's are loopier. The L is very important.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both crouch over the paper.</context>
      <utterance>I'm working on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel kind of bad for her. She's a nice girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes collateral damage can't be avoided.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes back from the table.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does that look?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly takes out a fresh sheet of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty good. I think we're ready to manufacture a document.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Begin. "Hey Daddy. It's your birthday and you've been a very bad boy. But so has the baby. Both baby and Daddy have to get punished, only this time</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Baby will be waiting where Daddy least expects her. Love, Bridgie." Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly just looks at him. Bart's already asked this question.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't afford any errors.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart turns to him and puts a hand on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>You don't need to tell me. It's my ass on the line. Kelly pulls up in front of Bart's school.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish I could be there to see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll get the de-brief.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a day that will live in infamy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You couldn't do any better than that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart hops out and salutes Kelly, who give him the thumbs up in response and pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>I don't hear you coming up with anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's gotten into you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance cackles.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing, you bad girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bell RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Did you drink a bottle of Robitussin before school again?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bridget looks a little scared.</context>
      <utterance>See you soon, my naughty baby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks down at his desk and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>It's my birthday! I'm going to get a present.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Damn it, fuckface. What're you smiling about? You wish you were me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance leaves like a house afire.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Palmer? May I be excused?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eine maus findet den kase.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls open the door. Nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy's here for the Easter egg hunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snatches the note. His eyes widen as he reads.</context>
      <utterance>Ooh, push my buttons.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah. Oh yeah. You little minx.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I just got this note last period.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The secretary hands Bridget the message. She looks at it.</context>
      <utterance>Well I don't have anything here for you - let me look again. Oh yes, the MENSA called.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIDGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool. They want me to be an honorary member.  Is that like a sorority or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He unbuckles his pants and lets them drop to him knees.</context>
      <utterance>Bridgie? Come on, daddy's sick. He needs his medicine. He spots a WOMAN in the shadows. It must be Bridget.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rips off his shirt and shuffles across the dark stage toward her.</context>
      <utterance>I brought our friend along. He's happy to see you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bridget, standing in the doorway, covers her mouth in horror.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you all looking at?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, he's got a hard on.</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance stumbles off stage to HOOTS and CATCALLS, but mostly hysterical LAUGHTER.</context>
      <utterance>Eeeeew.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They raise their glasses to each other.</context>
      <utterance>Yup. There it was. The whole school saw it. Wasn't too impressive either.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To Operation Mincemeat.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both take swallows of scotch. Kelly retches.</context>
      <utterance>To the 193rd.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly finishes his scotch.</context>
      <utterance>How does it feel to give better than you get?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Real good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want some more?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mind if I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The drink again. Kelly's feet are up. For the first time, he looks comfortable.</context>
      <utterance>That's my boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his foot down like a kickstand.</context>
      <utterance>You know what this is?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighteen volts of pure freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly runs his hand lovingly along the frame. Then he looks up at Sarah.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it is. Unless you know how to handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah gets on behind him.</context>
      <utterance>You ever seen the freshly waxed floor in the produce section glistening under full florescence? It's breathtaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his foot up and kicks it into gear. The Electro-shopper takes off - barely. Kelly takes the corner too sharp and clips the edge of an END CAP DISPLAY of cereal boxes -- they fall to the floor. The Electro-shopper inches forward.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on tight.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close call.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been drinking?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MINNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelly? Bart's not here, he -</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's all right. Actually, I'm here to see Tabby. Just to do a little painting with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's out back in her studio.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="80">
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. I warned you I'd come.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes back to painting. Kelly stands there for a minute, waiting for her to say something else, give him an invitation. She doesn't. Until she looks up and sees him standing in the same place.</context>
      <utterance>You did.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I should go --</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks through them and picks one.</context>
      <utterance>Well you're here now. Go ahead. Set your canvas up. Use one of the ones in the corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brushes are in the jar. Paint's in the drawer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off his backpack and opens it.</context>
      <utterance>I brought my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly busies himself pulling out paints and other supplies. He can't help but look at her. The light hits her hair and she glows. She catches him looking.</context>
      <utterance>Well then.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it mess up your concentration? Me being here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns back to her painting.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly sets up his canvas.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. That's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just don't talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would I?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly feels the tubes of paint. Nervous. Squirts some color out. Looks over his shoulder at her. He's trying to get his act together, to be cool about being there, in the studio, alone with her. Trying to figure out how to play it.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Irony. I like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Miner opens the door. See Kelly. Smiles like the stockbroker he is and crosses to him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Hey babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miner holds out his hand for a good old-fashioned shake. Kelly takes it.</context>
      <utterance>Miner Webber.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miner looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>Webber Miner.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelly. This is Kelly -</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelly Ernswiler. Sorry. I -</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite all right.  So, what do we have here, a little painting class?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelly's a friend of Bart's. He paints.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly smiles eagerly at Miner over the edge of his canvas.</context>
      <utterance>Oh? What's your real job?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be stock boy at the Shop Rite. But, as President Don Kaminsky says, every employee is part owner. So you could say I'm a captain-of- industry in training. Kind of capitalist larva.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's quite an image.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only if you see the most magical part. Do you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly spreads his arms out and flaps them a little.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miner stares at Kelly. He can't tell what he might be making fun of, or if it might be him.</context>
      <utterance>One day I'll be a beautiful butterfly. First I'll have to be a pupa though. I figure I won't be going out much then. Pupa: the awkward adolescence of the insect world.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly rolls his eyes at this uninspired response, though Miner doesn't see it. He grabs Tabby's paintbrush and pulls her to him.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever it takes to get you through the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have the afternoon off. Come away with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not at a good stopping point.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly smiles his most idiotic energetic smile and slaps paint on his canvas in exaggerated strokes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on. They'll still be here.  I know you'll still be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really shouldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But everyone will be coming soon. And it will get all crazy, and we won't have any time to ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby kisses Miner. He realizes there's no convincing her and sighs.</context>
      <utterance>We will. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>MINER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like tonight? We can practice honeymoon suite.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miner looks at Kelly, who looks away. Then he puts his hands in his pockets and leaves. Tabby and Kelly paint in silence for a while. Kelly moves around to look at his canvas from different angles, like he's copying what he thinks a painter would do.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe. Probably.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he always like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby stops and puts down her brush.</context>
      <utterance>Overbearing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just because he didn't want to picture you as a pupa?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly paints.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, he will - later. When he's alone. Whether he wants to or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that though. How he wanted you to stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to be with me. What's so bad about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly is suddenly very involved with his painting. He has a hard time making eye contact with Tabby.</context>
      <utterance>Just because some one wants to be with you doesn't mean they're good for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one should ever ask you to stop. If you stop, you might not be able to start again. Or you might start again, only things will be different.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's sweet -</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not sweet, actually. It's just the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up her brush.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I can take care of myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When's the wedding?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks at her seriously.</context>
      <utterance>At the end of the month. But don't ask me about it. It makes me nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Is something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Awkward silence.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly stops and sighs, now back in serious artist mode.</context>
      <utterance>What are you painting?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby stops painting.</context>
      <utterance>Really, there are so many layers of - imagistic symbolism - that I really don't feel comfortable summing it up, but, well - it's a recurring dream image. A mermaid riding a rocket ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, "how?" Sidesaddle. She's riding it sidesaddle. She's got a fish tail, for chrissake. I haven't decided yet if she's got scuba gear on or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly puts up his thumb in an approximation of an artist's gesture.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have any idea what you're talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, some people actually say what they really think.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if they don't know what they really think?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter. It's called being yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds boring.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly stops squeezing paint onto his palette. His gestures slow down. He's taking this in. Then he shakes it off.</context>
      <utterance>Not boring. Scary and wonderful and exciting.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. I'm trying to create here. Stop distracting me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom's got you working late?</utterance>
   <speaker>XIOU-XIOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly walks over and sees what she's working on. A beautiful spare Chinese landscape.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. You're really good. Why do you make those stupid animals for mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>XIOU-XIOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Each painting is a lesson. Here - She gets out a piece of paper for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm making a lot of art these days. I guess that means a lot of lessons.</utterance>
   <speaker>XIOU-XIOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Each line has a whole drawing contained in it. Each drawing has a whole life contained in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly watches her for a minute, the delicate whoop and swirl of her strokes. He dips a brush into the ink and watches Xiou-Xiou's restrained and confident movements. Eve leans against the doorframe.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's all?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly puts down the paintbrush.</context>
      <utterance>Hey you two. I'll try not to act surprised. It might spoil the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do this. I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly avoids her eyes as he leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Keller, I think I'm missing some art supplies. Have you seen them around the house?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I haven't.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what to do with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>XIOU-XIOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve looks over Xiou-Xiou's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>You son is not yet cooked. Give him time.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When are you going to let me give you your own show? We could do it for real.</utterance>
   <speaker>XIOU-XIOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem. When you offer me an eighty-twenty split.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- But I told you I want to take German --</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart frowns.</context>
      <utterance>German's a Cold War language. You can't get any kind of State Department position without more diverse linguistic training than that. You'll take Chinese.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we on the same page?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone eats in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Same page.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATHILDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby puts down her fork.</context>
      <utterance>So darling, when are you going to bite the bullet and do the seating arrangement?</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't deal with that stuff, ma. I don't care who sits next to whom. I should have eloped.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mathilda looks surprised. This could go either way.</context>
      <utterance>After all, Mrs. Bowland, sometimes when you bite the bullet, it explodes in your mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATHILDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, I've never thought about it before but that is a rather strange expression, isn't it? You wouldn't say, "Sooner or later you've got to put the grenade in your pants," would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But have you ever noticed how in movies they always bite the grenade before they throw it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby throws Kelly a grateful glance, for getting her out of a conversation she didn't want to have.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but they never take a bite out of their pants. Everyone but Bart LAUGHS.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATHILDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What an unusual conversation! Do you have similar discussions at the dinner table with your family, Kelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All but Bart LAUGHS again.</context>
      <utterance>Basically. I ask why all the furniture is missing and my Dad reminisces about dropping acid and watching Neil Armstrong walk on the moon.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He talks about art.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART/MATHILDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks down at his plate.</context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My mother's kind of an artist, so -</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mathilda salts her food.</context>
      <utterance>You come from a creative family, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATHILDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish my boys would talk to me about my passions. I can't get them anywhere near the subject of my garden.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I noticed your magnolias. Very fine specimens.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATHILDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mathilda beams.</context>
      <utterance>They are fine, aren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, Kelly, try a bit of these leeks. Minnie has a way with the white sauce.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dad has this friend who's a director. He's shooting a documentary for the History Channel.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly stops playing and looks at Bart.</context>
      <utterance>He needs some guys to do a reenactment of some European theater battles for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart's eyes stay on the screen.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to be on the History Channel?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't asked you yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly jabs at his controller.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly gives Bart a derisive glance.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if you want to. Next weekend. But you have to take it seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flickering TV light illuminates Bart's pinched look.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? Of course I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This annoys Kelly.</context>
      <utterance>From what I've seen, you play fast and loose with your characterizations. This has got to be straight up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart glances at him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not "fast and loose." I play the emotional truth. I make it real.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like back in the dining room?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>What does that have to do with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I noticed your magnolias. Very fine specimens." That was real? Kelly's video game character dies. He drops the controller.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this about?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My own agenda? What other reason is there to do anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks at Bart in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just saying. I know the difference between fantasy and reality.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart won't meet his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Are you saying I don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart pauses the game.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly gets up and grabs his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me your dad was a burn-out?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves. Bart un-pauses the game and continues playing.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you steal from yours?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly frowns at the Principal's back as she CLICKS away. Sarah appears. They walk down the hall together.</context>
      <utterance>Kelly! I told some of your teachers about your presentation. We're all really looking forward to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What presentation?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to talk about it. As a matter of fact, do me a favor and pretend you never heard anything about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Um.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, Sarah?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nothing. I - Kelly starts to pull ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have an extra ticket to Aerosmith this weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw Sarah, that's really great, I mean. It's just that - I'm busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Yeah, I figured. Okay. I'll see you in the dairy section, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands there looking lost.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tracked you down. There's someone I'd like you to meet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you one too?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do you see in that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Living, dying, camaraderie, bravery - the big stuff. Things we don't have anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie sorts his tiles and scowls. He leans in to Kelly's face, giving him the eye.</context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly is taken aback by this.</context>
      <utterance>And do you think it's brave getting trench foot and syphilis, eating another ration of spoiled frank and beans out of a dented can?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie leans back and nods, thinking about Kelly's response. He no longer seems angry.</context>
      <utterance>Well, no -</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that wouldn't be much fun, would it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlie sets down a tile and pulls at his chin.</context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart gives Kelly a significant look. Kelly doesn't notice. He's looking closely at Charlie.</context>
      <utterance>Parts of it were kind of fun though. I got separated from my platoon and lived for two weeks in the forest of the Ardennes living off what I could kill.  I felt very close to the land.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I met him when my mom made me go around caroling with the Youth Group.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't really believe that stuff about Berlin? And Hitler's compound?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart grins.</context>
      <utterance>Of course it matters. Doesn't the truth matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly avoids this by getting out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. You tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want a drink. Let me borrow a couple bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you not to play him for money.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart returns the pump and screws in the gas cap.</context>
      <utterance>I was trying to be nice. He's your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. You should know better. What do you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then he glances towards the gas station and sees EVE, set up in the adjacent abandoned lot. She's got the van parked there with the sliding door open and paintings propped around on display.</context>
      <utterance>Mountain Dew -</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Eve has seen him. She shields her eyes with her hand and calls to him.</context>
      <utterance>-- Oh shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly backtracks towards the car.</context>
      <utterance>Kelly!</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve walks over to them. Kelly can't get out of it.</context>
      <utterance>That woman's calling you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve smiles brightly.</context>
      <utterance>Bart. Meet my mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart is surprised but recovers his manners quickly, just like he's been taught to.</context>
      <utterance>What a nice surprise. It's so nice to finally meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Likewise. So, doing a little business?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly shifts his weight from foot to foot. Eve looks at both of them.</context>
      <utterance>A little is right. But I work it as much as I can. Eve laughs.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what have you boys been up to?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bart took me to meet his friend Charlie at the Old Soldiers' Home.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlie at the Old Soldiers' Home?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You boys should swing by Care House. There are some Vets there.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve watches a car pull into the lot next to the van.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well - okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly visibly bristles at the thought of his parents entertaining Bart.</context>
      <utterance>I should go. But you boys should come over to our house some time.  I know your family must get tired of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve looks at Kelly. Then she runs back over to the van.</context>
      <utterance>Not at all. But I'd love to, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There you go. Now you know everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly rolls his eyes and gets back in the car.</context>
      <utterance>What's your problem? She's pretty cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you want your soda?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So filming's on Saturday. Can you make it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly doesn't say anything.</context>
      <utterance>Good. It's gonna be really cool. He's got an explosives expert coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly runs his hand through his hair. He can't bring himself to say what's really on his mind.</context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly picks up Bart's Colt and sights with it. Bart frowns. He knows Kelly's avoiding the real stuff.</context>
      <utterance>Remember that stupid speech?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart polishes his combat boots.</context>
      <utterance>I'm supposed to give it next week.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should talk to my dad about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart keeps his head down, polishes intently.</context>
      <utterance>You think he'd go for that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. He loves you. He was talking the other day about helping you out.  Want to go to Dartmouth?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was. If you applied for Spring Semester, he could "pull some strings."</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think that would work for me. Considering -- my background.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, probably not.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart checks his bandoleer and cartridges.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not properly socialized. I wouldn't fit in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's bullshit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart pauses, darts his eyes at Kelly.</context>
      <utterance>Tell that to my family. They're like your fucking fan club.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even Tabby likes you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So much she ratted me out to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she's inviting you to the wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart watches Kelly's face.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you probably won't enjoy that much, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart throws his olive drab socks at Kelly's head.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking about. Weddings? I love weddings. I always get drunk and make out with someone's cousin.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, I'll call mom's nephew Fletcher and tell him to expect a little action.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fletcher, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's twelve. Let me give some advice. He's very into sharks at the moment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you tell -- Tabby turns toward him. She's crying.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He knows he should leave, but Kelly just stands there. Kelly runs his hand along his pants in a nervous gesture. Tabby dabs at her face.</context>
      <utterance>What? Oh, I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Miner and I broke up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honestly? I didn't think you two were right for each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly walks over to her painting.</context>
      <utterance>You did, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like this painting. Stare at it too long and you can't see it anymore. But if someone else sees it for the first time, they can tell exactly what it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly stops, taken aback. He walks away from the painting.</context>
      <utterance>I don't need any more bullshit right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He could never understand you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly walks to the window and looks out.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not as complicated as you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby laughs/cries at this.</context>
      <utterance>I never said you were complicated.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby nods. She's starting to calm down a little.</context>
      <utterance>He just wasn't the right one.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby looks at her shredded tissue. Kelly sits down on the couch next to her.</context>
      <utterance>There's more to it than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really sorry. I really am.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly pats her knee awkwardly.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby turns her face to Kelly's.</context>
      <utterance>Don't cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like me, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby closes her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks scared. He wants to retreat. But he calms himself down.</context>
      <utterance>No, I mean -- you like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I think you're amazing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long pause. Then -- Kelly kisses her. She kisses back and they fall against the couch together.</context>
      <utterance>Well, do something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATHILDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Minnie's starting dinner. Is Kelly coming over?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mathilda pauses and looks at her son.</context>
      <utterance>Not tonight, ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATHILDA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you with the 101st or the 82nd?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, 82nd today. It's not my usual division. Technically, my patches indicate -</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever. Make yourself comfortable. We'll be a while setting up. Some of the other boys are over by craft service.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly doesn't go anywhere.</context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The snack table. It's over there. Someone will come get you when we're ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Is Bart Bowland here yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bart? Oh, Harrison's son. I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ok. Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MAKEUP ARTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelly Ernswiler, private first class.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAKEUP ARTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets out some pomade and runs a comb through his hair, slicking it back.</context>
      <utterance>All right, Kelly. Let's take a look at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAKEUP ARTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly grins. When she walks away he messes up his hair again. He scans the crowd. No Bart. The A.D. walks over.</context>
      <utterance>That's it, handsome.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, everyone. We're going to start positioning. Then we'll go through a few rehearsals.  You, you and you - go over there by that tree. You and you guys, behind the hill.  Okay, who's got the Jeep?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That MG? She's mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly tries to act casual.</context>
      <utterance>Great. We'd like to use it. Can you drive it beyond the hill over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks towards his Jeep and pauses.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. I don't think that would be a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen Bart Bowland? Has he checked in?</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly nods, wondering a bit. But it's soon forgotten.</context>
      <utterance>Don't know. We've got enough people. It doesn't matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hot Lips, old girl, you're going to be famous.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay people. Listen to my voice. From now on, you do whatever this voice says. Take your place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart steps out of the barn.</context>
      <utterance>Password.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Where the hell have you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No where.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart doesn't say anything.</context>
      <utterance>They put you over here with me? That's great. I think we'll get some close- ups. They want me to drive old Lippy. Isn't that awesome?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell's your problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ought to fucking kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly shakes his head, avoiding Bart's eyes, trying to keep it normal.</context>
      <utterance>You had to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just do whatever the fuck you want. And consequences don't matter, do they?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart looks at Kelly. Sees nothing but a kid in an old Army uniform.</context>
      <utterance>Are you out of your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he still won't look at Bart.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck do you think she's going to do, run off with you? The blood rises to Kelly's face.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly's hands turn white around the rifle.</context>
      <utterance>You're a seventeen-year-old bag boy. She's a Yale grad student. Talk about living in a fucking fantasy world.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart comes closer. Uncomfortably close.</context>
      <utterance>No. You'd rather have me be miserable like you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And looks Bart right in the eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Once again, you've displayed your uncanny ability to nail the truth of a character. Kelly finally raises his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart lunges at Kelly.</context>
      <utterance>Stop talking out your dad's mouth and use your own for once.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Standby for rehearsal. Cue the explosion.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAY CLOUD EXPLODES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the field. Soldiers leap out of trenches.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing happens.</context>
      <utterance>Cue the Jeep.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The A.D. shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Cue the Jeep. Cue the fucking Jeep!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart and Kelly continue to fight.</context>
      <utterance>What the H. Christ is going on over here?</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart sits on the ground, out of breath.</context>
      <utterance>Follow him. Are you getting it?</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The A.D. directs the camera at Bart.</context>
      <utterance>We can use this. We'll cut it together.</utterance>
   <speaker>A.D.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart pushes the camera away.</context>
      <utterance>Get close on him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're going to have to. Your father's at the hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve plays with her keys. Then she stops.</context>
      <utterance>Which one of his loser friends ended up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly feels the sensation of falling, like a dream. Then he snorts and rolls over, away from his mom.</context>
      <utterance>They think he has stomach cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve looks at the back of Kelly's head. She's tired but still trying to deal.</context>
      <utterance>Oh this is just perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would you say something like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it seems to fit.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly gets up. Puts his feet on the floor. His shoulders are slumped.</context>
      <utterance>"Seems to fit." Do you understand what I just said?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, do you want to say it again?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelly -</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up and holds the door open for her. Eve looks at him, heart heavy. She leaves. Kelly sits on the bed. Then he looks at the rabbit painting. He grabs it off the wall and SLAMS it backwards against the floor so he doesn't have to look at it. The painting falls back against the bayonet fixed to Kelly's rifle and TEARS. He KICKS it.</context>
      <utterance>I have to go to work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly doesn't say anything.</context>
      <utterance>I forgot to tell you this box was booby-trapped.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The concert was lame. The opening act singer ripped his leather pants during a stupid dance routine and stormed off stage.  Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lance?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly gathers an armful of paper towels.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I'm busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah puts a couple of rolls on the shelf.</context>
      <utterance>I doubt it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly stops what he's doing.</context>
      <utterance>Um, I don't have a perfect life, if that's what you're asking.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah drops the rolls she had in her hands.</context>
      <utterance>No, Sarah, actually, I'm not asking. I never ask you anything but you just talk anyway. Have you ever noticed that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves. Kelly shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops when he sees Tabby and Miner sleeping together on the couch. Tabby opens her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I hoped you were up -</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly goes and takes his painting off the easel.</context>
      <utterance>Kelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly leaves.</context>
      <utterance>I just came to get this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly stops and turns around.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess the wedding's back on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby smiles sadly.</context>
      <utterance>We talked.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm really sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand there in the yard. Tabby wraps her arms around herself.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby looks at Kelly, pained.</context>
      <utterance>My dad's got cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>TABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a step towards him. He backs up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Kelly.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks at Tabby for a second, then turns and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>I guess we all get what we deserve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MR. NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly closes his eyes. He had forgotten - or tried to forget.</context>
      <utterance>Kelly! There you are. I was just telling the class about our special treat today. Mr. Ernswiler is going to be giving the three first-period history classes a little talk about the Civil War.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The class bolts for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Let's all make our way in an orderly fashion down to the auditorium, shall we?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Norman looks at Kelly pleasantly.</context>
      <utterance>Orderly, I said orderly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what are we waiting for? I'm so looking forward to hearing your views.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HOLMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For those of you who haven't had the chance to get to know Kelly, you should know he has a very interesting hobby. He takes part in reenactments of World War II battles right here in Ohio.</utterance>
   <speaker>AUDIENCE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scattered LAUGHTER. Kelly frowns.</context>
      <utterance>I did that too. When I was seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly rises to scant applause. He stands at the podium, looking out at the crowd. He looks down and thinks. He looks back up. The silence stretches. Kids start giggling. Finally he leans into the microphone.</context>
      <utterance>He has an unusual first-hand knowledge of history. We recently discovered that this extends beyond World War II to the Civil War, which he is going to discuss with you today. Kelly?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks off stage.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMSTEAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, go after him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly frowns at the lock.</context>
      <utterance>What, they re-assign you to the bicycle brigade?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad, cause I'm not. Remember that little show I put on for the school?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks up at Lance.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, come on. Pants down? Doll? Hard on?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh that. I heard about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And did you hear me and Bridget aren't going out anymore because of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't been following the story.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah well, let's get this over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance pushes Kelly away from his bike. Kelly falls back on his hands. He squints up at Lance and moves back towards his bike. Lance KICKS him back with his foot and looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>It is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just let me go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance KICKS him again. Kelly breathes hard.</context>
      <utterance>Did you call me a homo?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't a good time for me. Let's re-schedule.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance picks Kelly up and SLAPS him hard on the face.</context>
      <utterance>No time like the present.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lance PUNCHES Kelly and he reels. Then Kelly lunges for him and they fall to the ground. Kelly swings wildly but Lance pins him down and gives him a few good ones. Then Mr. Norman comes out.</context>
      <utterance>First you should probably get me to write home to my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Norman rushes over to them. Kelly scrambles up and rips at his bike lock, gets on his bike and rides away. Mr. Norman tries to take a panting Lance by the arm but Lance shakes him off.</context>
      <utterance>Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get off me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks up at her. He's still got the cut eyebrow, which has split back open, and some dried blood under his nose.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Kelly. What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve comes over and tilts Kelly's head back to look at the cut. This is the first time she's touched him. She gets some antiseptic and ointment from under the sink along with Band-Aids and goes to work.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Let me see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly lets her dab at his face. He closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Ow.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly opens his eyes and pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going over to see dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve puts a butterfly bandage across Kelly's eyebrow.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly pulls his head away.</context>
      <utterance>And you need to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At this point that's not an option.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve looks at Kelly sadly.</context>
      <utterance>Now's not a good time, ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's never a good time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>You can't make me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not about you anymore --</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve rises to her feet. He's just sent her over the edge.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you get it? It was never about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is wrong with you? When are you going to stop blaming us, blaming him? I'm sick of you being angry. I want to be angry! They just took out half of your father's stomach -</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops and breaks down.</context>
      <utterance>You will not tell me what's enough. You don't know about anything. All you do is fight fake battles, in the woods, on the playground. But this, right here, us - this is the real one, the only one worth anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man I love is dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve looks at her son. Her face looks older.</context>
      <utterance>That's between you and him.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve leaves. Kelly sits on the toilet, lost.</context>
      <utterance>If I made a mistake, if you felt left out, I'm sorry. But I can only deal with one thing at a time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HARRISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't sit any of Mathilda's sisters next to me if you can help it.  Oh, hello. So nice to see you. Thank you for coming. Bart comes outside, also dressed as an usher.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the priest?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart walks down the steps and looks down the street. Kelly's walking towards him. IN HIS DRESS UNIFORM. Bart walks down the street to meet him.</context>
      <utterance>He should be here any minute. Calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly looks down. He can't meet Bart's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was invited.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I uninvited you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart looks at Kelly and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>It's not your wedding.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you wearing that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't let you come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tabby gets out in her wedding dress. Has there even been a more glorious woman? Will there ever be again? Her MAID OF HONOR leads her around to the side of the church. Kelly watches every step.</context>
      <utterance>Because you know why. Just go home. Kelly finally looks up at Bart and nods. A Town Car pulls up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>She looks beautiful. Tell her - give her my congratulations. Kelly walks off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>XIOU-XIOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh! Son of Eve. You startled me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She examines it and takes out a wet sponge. She wipes it across the back of the canvas.</context>
      <utterance>Grandma Ling. Can you fix this?</utterance>
   <speaker>XIOU-XIOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She works silently for a minute. Kelly watches her. She cuts a small piece of canvas to repair the hole.</context>
      <utterance>Your mom made it for you. I can fix it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you come here to work on your own stuff? Don't waste your time on this.</utterance>
   <speaker>XIOU-XIOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns the painting over and gets out some paints to touch it up.</context>
      <utterance>I never waste time.</utterance>
   <speaker>XIOU-XIOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See. Everything can be mended.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're trying to tell me something, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>XIOU-XIOU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no. I could not tell you anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. Kelly.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey dad. How you feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They gave me some stitches downstairs.  Three.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get punched?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A couple times, actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly comes into the room and sits in a chair.</context>
      <utterance>I know the feeling. Come on in and watch some television. Don't worry, this one's bolted to the wall. As you can see, my reputation precedes me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any battles this weekend?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A few.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe and Kelly look up at the television in the corner.</context>
      <utterance>Busy, busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Answer me this: how come no one ever reenacts the Vietnam War?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'd be pretty depressing, wouldn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both continue to look up at the television.</context>
      <utterance>I guess it would.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plus that, you'd have to have protesters and stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Folks dressed up like your mom and me. People reenacting fleeing to Canada, burning draft cards. I guess that would ruin the spirit of the thing, now wouldn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abe looks at Kelly.</context>
      <utterance>I could make it work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly nods. Eve wakes up.</context>
      <utterance>I bet you could.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kelly, is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were expecting some one else?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eve looks at Kelly, her face full of love and sadness.</context>
      <utterance>He looks good.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly nods slowly, taking this in. And it is finally too much. He breaks down and cries. For the fear and the misplaced rage, the fights and the stubbornness. But finally, relief. They walk back down the hall together. Eve reaches out and puts her hand on Kelly's neck.</context>
      <utterance>He looks just like you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. You going away already?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. The have this intensive summer orientation thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart puts the box in the car.</context>
      <utterance>Is that good?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's optional, but dad thinks it would be "a good way to meet people."</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's probably right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand there.</context>
      <utterance>He usually is.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly gives him a little ra-ra with one hand. Bart smiles. Kelly's been doing his research.</context>
      <utterance>Well, go Big Green.</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly lifts his foot up to the pedal of his bike.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bart laughs a little and shakes his head. Kelly is gone. Harrison comes out.</context>
      <utterance>Have fun. And get laid, will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>BART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harrison checks the ties on the roof.</context>
      <utterance>Everything you'd let me bring.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARRISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah picks some bagels.</context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come you don't work here anymore? The Electro-shopper's getting rusty.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a summer internship at an ad agency.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fancy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's great. Kelly moves around to her other side, closer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah moves away. Once bitten twice shy and all that.</context>
      <utterance>Hey -</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When are you going to get a real job?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Probably when I figure out something better to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah walks to the front of the store. Kelly walks with her.</context>
      <utterance>You can't be a stock boy your whole life.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sarah turns to him at the checkout aisle.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah I can. I mean, I probably won't, but I could.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it was good seeing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember that presentation I told you never to ask me about again?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly keeps talking. Many of the OLD SOLDIERS sleep.</context>
      <utterance>Lee arrayed his defenses over here. Only this time, Grant was ready for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SOLDIER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is boring.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD SOLDIER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Let's see that slide of the wife again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MR. NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remarkable, remarkable. And they never knew?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The real kicker was moving those cutouts of tanks around. The thought we had a whole regiment over there, but it was just a couple of us and those Hollywood props.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's amazing. Art playing a part in war.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kelly tries to gesture to Sarah "no."</context>
      <utterance>You're damned right. We practically won the thing right there.  Now this is more like it. Anyone care to place a wager on the table?</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you think it would be more fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Norman smiles at the group.</context>
      <utterance>I can't imagine having more fun that I am now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're never been to a French whorehouse, I take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. NORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, my.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still don't understand how you did that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SARAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls away. He watches her go.</context>
      <utterance>I spent my summers with my grandma in the Catskills. She didn't give me any spending money.  So I played the bones for ice cream.</utterance>
   <speaker>KELLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hot damn.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
