<movie id="249" title="Grapes of Wrath The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="227">
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you be back?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see him climbing into the cab of the truck from the right side. Getting behind the wheel, he is releasing the handbrake when Tom appears at the driver's seat window.</context>
      <utterance>Couple a weeks. Don't do nothin' you wouldn't want me to hear about!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about a lift, mister?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He indicates a "No Riders" sticker on the windshield.</context>
      <utterance>Can't you see that sticker?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After a moment of hesitation the driver releases the brake.</context>
      <utterance>Sure I see it. But a good guy don't pay no attention to what some heel makes him stick on his truck.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Tom scrunches down on the running board the driver throws the truck into gear and it moves. The scene dissolves to the CAB OF THE TRUCK. It is day, and Tom is seated beside the driver, who is surreptitiously eyeing him, trying to confirm some suspicion--an inspection which Tom ignores at first.</context>
      <utterance>Scrunch down on the running board till we get around the bend.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goin' far?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a few miles. I'd a walked her if my dogs wasn't pooped out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lookin' for a job?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, my old man got a place, forty acres. He's a sharecropper, but we been there a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cautiously, the driver's eyes drop to Tom's feet. We see TOM'S SHOES. They are prison shoes--new, stiff and bulky. Curiosity is in the eyes of the DRIVER as they shoot a swift glance at Tom. TOM is looking straight ahead, with the dead- pan look that prisoners get when they are trying to conceal something. The DRIVER'S eyes take in Tom's hands and the stiff coat.</context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been doin' a job?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seen your hands. You been swinging a pick or a sledge--that shines up your hands. I notice little things like that all the time.  Got a trade?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you get to it, buddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get to what?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I mean. You been givin' me a goin' over ever since I got in. Whyn't you go on and ask me where I been?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't stick my nose in nobody's business.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw--not much!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stay in my own yard.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen. That big nose of yours been goin' over me like a sheep in a vegetable patch. But I ain't keepin' it a secret. I been in the penitentiary. Been there four years. Like to know anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't got to get sore.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. Ask me anything you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me neither. I'm just tryin' to get along without shovin' anybody around, that's all.  See that road up ahead?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a sigh of relief the driver puts his foot on the brake. The TRUCK stops and Tom gets out. He look at the uneasy driver contemptuously.</context>
      <utterance>That's where I get off.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver throws the truck into gear. He doesn't like this at all.</context>
      <utterance>You're about to bust to know what I done, ain't you? Well, I ain't a guy to let you down.  Homicide!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never asked you!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carrying his coat under his arm, TOM wipes his face with his cap as he cuts off the road to acknowledge the greeting.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmmm he's my saviour. Mmmmm my saviour, Mmmmmmmmmm my saviour now.  Howdy, friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops, grateful for the momentary relief of the shade.</context>
      <utterance>Howdy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, ain't you young Tom Joad--ol' Tom's boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. On my way home now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I do declare!  I baptized you, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, you're the preacher!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Used to be. Not no more. I lost the call.  But boy, I sure used to have it! I'd get an irrigation ditch so squirmin' full of repented sinners I pretty near drowned half of 'em!  But not no more. I lost the sperit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pa always said you was never cut out to be a preacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got nothin' to preach about no more--that's all. I ain't so sure o' things.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should a got yourself a wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At my meetin's I used to get the girls glory-shoutin' till they about passed out. Then, I'd go to comfort 'em--and always end up by lovin' 'em. I'd feel bad, an' pray, an' pray, but it didn't do no good. Next time, do it again. I figgered there just wasn't no hope for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never let one go by me when I could catch her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you wasn't a preacher. A girl was just a girl to you. But to me they was holy vessels. I was savin' their souls.  I ast myself--what is this call, the Holy Sperit? Maybe that's love. Why, I love everybody so much I'm fit to bust sometimes! So maybe there ain't no sin an' there ain't no virtue. There's just what people do. Some things folks do is nice, and some ain't so nice. But that's as far as any man's got a right to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a little snort?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Course I'll say grace if somebody sets out the food--  --but my heart ain't in it.  Nice drinkin' liquor.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ought to be. That's fact'ry liquor. Cost me a buck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been out travelin' around?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you hear? It was in the papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I never. What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(He drinks)</context>
      <utterance>I been in the penitentiary for four years.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me for asking.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mind any more. I'd do what I done again. I killed a guy at a dance. We was drunk. He got a knife in me and I laid him out with a shovel. Knocked his head plumb to squash.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you ain't ashamed?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He had a knife in me. That's why they only gave me seven years. Got out in four--parole.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't you seen your folks since then?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but I aim to before sundown. Gettin' kind of excited about it, too. Which way you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pause at the edge of the shade, squint up at the sky, and then move off. The scene dissolves to the SURFACE OF A DIRT ROAD by daylight. Leaves are scuttling across it. The top soil begins to fly up. It is not a hard wind as yet, but it is steady and persistent. Tom's and Casy's feet walk into sight.</context>
      <utterance>It don't matter. Ever since I lost the sperit it looks like I just as soon go one way as the other.  I'll go your way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe Ma'll have pork for supper. I ain't had pork but four times in four years--every Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be glad to see you pa. Last time I seen him was at a baptizin', an' he had one a the bigges' doses of the Holy Sperit I ever seen. He go to jumpin' over bushes, howlin' like a dog-wolf in moon-time. Fin'ly he picks hisself out a bush big as a piana an' he let out a squawk an' took a run at that bush. Well, sir, he cleared her but he bust his leg snap in two. They was a travellin' dentist there and he set her, an' I give her a prayin' over, but they wasn't no more Holy Sperit in your pa after that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lissen. This wind's fixin't to do somepin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom, holding his cap on his head with his hand, looks up... The TOPS OF THE TREES are bending before the wind. TOM AND CASY continue walking.</context>
      <utterance>Shore it is. It always is, this time a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it fur?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TOM AND CASY are almost being blown along and dust is rising from the road.</context>
      <utterance>Just around that next bend.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your granma was a great one, too. The third time she got religion she go it so powerful she knocked down a full-growed deacon with her fist.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The JOAD CABIN is an ancient, bleak, sway-backed building. There is neither sign of life or habitation about it.</context>
      <utterance>That's our place.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma?... Pa?... Ain't nobody here?  Somepin's happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a match?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Presently, after shuffling about, he has found them and lights one. He holds it up, lighting the room. A couple of wooden boxes are on the floor, a few miserable discarded things, and that's all. Tom's eyes are bewildered.</context>
      <utterance>There was some pieces of candle always on a shelf.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're all gone--or dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They never wrote you nothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the floor he picks up a woman's high button shoe, curled up at the toe and broken over the instep.</context>
      <utterance>No. They wasn't people to write.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dropping the shoe, he picks up a battered felt hat.</context>
      <utterance>This was Ma's. Had 'em for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This used to be mine. I give it to Grampa when I went away.  You reckon they could be dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dropping the hat, he moves with the candle toward the door to the back, the only other room of the cabin. He stands in the doorway, holding the candle high. In the BACK ROOM the scene moves from Tom at the door across the room to the shadows, where a skinny little man sits motionless, wide-eyed, staring at Tom. His name is Muley.</context>
      <utterance>I never heard nothin' about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Muley! Where's my folks, Muley?</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Muley does not reply. He is looking up at Casy as he enters.</context>
      <utterance>I know that! But where they gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Muley Graves.  You remember the preacher, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't no preacher anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, you remember the man then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY AND CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad to see you again. Glad to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now where is my folks?</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gone--  --over to your Uncle John's. The whole crowd of 'em, two weeks ago. But they can't stay there either, because John's got his notice to get off.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what's happened? How come they got to get off? We been here fifty years--same place.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever'body got to get off. Ever'body leavin', goin' to California. My folks, your folks, ever'body's folks.  Ever'body but me. I ain't gettin' off.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But who done it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen!  That's some of what done it--the dusters. Started it, anyway. Blowin' like this, year after year--blowin' the land away, blowin' the crops away, blowin' us away now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some say I am.  You want to hear what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MULEY is seen at close range. Not actually crazy, Muley is a little touched. His eyes rove upward as he listens to the sound of the storm, the sough of the wind and the soft hiss of the sand. Then...</context>
      <utterance>That's what I asked you, ain't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scene dissolves to MULEY'S DOORYARD. It is a soft spring day, with the peaceful sounds of the country. Seated in a three-year-old touring car is THE MAN, a city man with a collar and tie. He hates to do what he is doing and this makes him gruff and curt, to hide his misgivings. Squatted beside the car are Muley, his son-in-law, and a half-grown son. At a respectful distance stand Muley's wife, his daughter, with a baby in her arms, and a small barefooted girl, watching worriedly. The men soberly trace marks on the ground with small sticks. A hound dog sniffs at the automobile wheels.</context>
      <utterance>The way it happens--the way it happened to me--the man come one day...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fact of the matter, Muley, after what them dusters done to the land, the tenant system don't work no more. It don't even break even, much less show a profit. One man on a tractor can handle twelve or fourteen of these places. You just pay him a wage and take all the crop.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we couldn't do on any less'n what our share is now.  The chillun ain't gettin' enough to eat as it is, and they're so ragged we'd be shamed if ever'body else's chillun wasn't the same way.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't help that. All I know is I got my orders. They told me to tell you you got to get off, and that's what I'm telling you. Muley stands in anger. The two younger men pattern after him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean get off my own land?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now don't go blaming me. It ain't my fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose fault is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know who owns the land--the Shawnee Land and Cattle Company.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the Shawnee Land and Cattle Comp'ny?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't nobody. It's a company.</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They got a pres'dent, ain't they? They got somebody that knows what a shotgun's for, ain't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it ain't his fault, because the bank tells him what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Where's the bank?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tulsa. But what's the use of picking on him? He ain't anything but the manager, and half crazy hisself, trying to keep up with his orders from the east!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then who do we shoot?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brother, I don't know. If I did I'd tell you. But I just don't know who's to blame!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm right here to tell you, mister, ain't nobody going to push me off my land! Grampa took up this land seventy years ago. My pa was born here. We was all born on it, and some of us got killed on it, and some died on it. And that's what makes it ourn--bein' born on it, and workin' it, and dyin' on it--and not no piece of paper with writin' on it! So just come on and try to push me off! The scene dissolves to the BACK ROOM. The sound of the storm is heard again as Tom and Casy watch Muley.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see MULEY at close range.</context>
      <utterance>They come. They come and pushed me off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They come with the cats.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scene dissolves to a MONTAGE OF TRACTORS: tractors looming over hillocks, flattening fences, through gullies, their drivers looking like robots, with goggles, dust masks over mouth and nose--one after the other, crossing and recrossing as if to convey the impression that this was an invasion of machine-men from some other world.</context>
      <utterance>The cats--the caterpillar tractors.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scene dissolves to MULEY'S FARM. We see the backs of Muley and the two younger men standing shoulder to shoulder watching a lumbering tractor headed straight toward them. It is at some distance. Muley holds a shotgun. His son has a baling hook. The son-in-law has a two-by-four. Behind them is their cabin. Frightened and huddled together are the women and children. The roar of the tractor comes closer.</context>
      <utterance>And for ever' one of 'em ten-fifteen families gets throwed outa their homes--one hundred folks with no place to live but on the road. The Rances, the Perrys, the Peterses, the Joadses--one after another they got throwed out. Half the folks you and me know--throwed right out into the road. The one that got me come a month ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TRACTOR stops. The driver takes off his goggles and dust mask. Like the others he's a country boy. His face is sullen. Muley is lowering his shotgun. There is a surprise in his face as he recognizes the driver.</context>
      <utterance>I tol' you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves forward, followed by his son and son-in-law in the TRACTOR. Davis is wiping his face as they walk toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Why, you're Joe Davis's boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like nobody drawin' a bead on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what are you doin' this kind a thing for--against your own people?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For three dollars a day, that's what I'm doin' it for. I got two little kids. I got a wife and my wife's mother. Them people got to eat. Fust and on'y thing I got to think about is my own folks. What happens to other folks is their lookout.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this is my land , son. Don't you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see THE WOMENFOLKS. A small girl pulls her mother's dress.</context>
      <utterance>Used to be your land. B'longs to the comp'ny now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he fixin' to do, ma?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back to the TRACTOR AND THE MEN:</context>
      <utterance>Hush!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have it your own way, son, but just as sure as you touch my house with that cat I'm gonna blow you plumb to kingdom come.</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little girl begins to whimper.</context>
      <utterance>Don't! Please don't!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TRACTOR moves across the yard, nosing a chair out of the way, and with a rending of boards hits a corner of the house, knocking a part of the foundation away. The corner of the house sinks. MULEY lifts his shotgun, aims it, holds it, and then slowly lowers it. As he stands looking at what has happened his shoulders sag. He seems almost to shrink. The scene dissolves to MULEY, once more in the back room of Tom's old home, as the sound of the storm continues.</context>
      <utterance>I'm tellin' you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was the use. He was right. There wasn't a thing in the world I could do about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it don't seem possible--kicked off like that!</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom rises in his agitation and bewilderment.</context>
      <utterance>The rest of my fambly set out for the west--there wasn't nothin' to eat--but I couldn't leave. Somepin' wouldn't let me. So now I just wander around. Sleep wherever I am. I used to tell myself I was lookin' out for things, so when they come back ever'thing would be all right. But I knowed that wan't true. There ain't nothin' to look out for. And ain't nobody comin' back. They're gone-- and me, I'm just an 'ol graveyard ghost--that's all in the world I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm touched.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You're lonely--but you ain't touched.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It don't matter. If I'm touched, I'm touched, and that's all there is to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down at Muley.</context>
      <utterance>What I can't understand is my folks takin' it! Like ma! I seen her nearly beat a peddler to death with a live chicken. She aimed to go for him with an ax she had in the other hand but she got mixed up and forgot which hand was which and when she got through with that peddler all she had left was two chicken legs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes are dull on the floor. The sound of the dust storm continues strongly. The scene dissolves to the EXTERIOR OF THE CABIN at night. It is several hours later and the sound of the storm has faded out. Now all is silence as first Tom, then Casy, and finally Muley steps out of the cabin and looks around. There is still a slight fog of dust in the air, and clouds of powderlike dust shoot up around their feet. All three men have wet rags tied over their mouths and noses.</context>
      <utterance>Just a plain 'ol graveyard ghost, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's settlin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you figger to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hard to say. Stay here till mornin' an' then go on over to Uncle John's, I reckon. After that I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen!  That's them! Them lights! Come on, we got to hide out!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hide out for what? We ain't doin' nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're trespassin' ! It ain't you lan' no more! An' that's the supr'tendant--with a gun!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CAR approaches at some distance, the headlights moving up and down as the car rides a dirt road. A PART OF THE COTTON FIELD: Muley leads the way.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Tom. You're on parole.</utterance>
   <speaker>MULEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All you got to do is lay down an' watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't they come out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TOM, CASY AND MULEY lie flat, listening to the sound of the car going away.</context>
      <utterance>Muley?  He ain't here. The car moves on.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DRIED CORNSTALKS, seen by daylight, fade in. The cornstalks, their roots blown clean and clear of the earth, lie fallen in one direction. This is what has happened to farms that were once rich and green. Then Uncle John's cabin comes into view. It is just after sunup. The air is filled with country sounds--a shrill chorus of birds, a dog barking in the distance. The cabin is of the same general appearance as the Joad cabin but even smaller. Smoke curls from the chimney. We see a PLATTER ON A TABLE, inside the cabin. The platter is filled with sidemeat. Over the scene comes Ma Joad's voice.</context>
      <utterance>Anybody ever 'tol me I'd be hidin' out on my own place...! He whistles, as the scene fades out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she speaks, a man's scrawny hand reaches forward and sneaks out a piece of sidemeat. Five people are seated around the breakfast table on chairs or boxes. They are Pa, Grampa, Granma, Noah, and Uncle John. Two children, Ruthie and Winfield, stand to the table, because there are no more chairs. Their heads are all bent as Ma, standing with a fork in her hand between the table and the stove, ends the grace. Heads lift and there is a bustle as Ma turns back to the frying pork on the stove and the others truck into their food. Granma points a spiteful finger at Grampa.</context>
      <utterance>Lord, make us thankful for what we are about to receive, for His sake. Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seen you!--You et durin' grace!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't he messy though!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seen him!--gobblin' away like an ole pig!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NOAH is solemnly studying a handbill. Over his shoulder the HANDBILL can be read: "800 PICKERS WANTED--WORK IN CALIFORNIA" We see NOAH AND UNCLE JOHN.</context>
      <utterance>Whyn't you keep your eyes shet durin' grace, you ole...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it say again?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noah frowns at the print.</context>
      <utterance>Says plenty work in California-- peaches. Eight hundred pickers needed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait'll I get to California! Gonna reach up and pick me an orange whenever I want it! Or grapes. That there's somethin' I ain't never had enough of! Gonna get me a whole bunch a grapes off a bush and I'm gonna squash 'em all over my face and just let the juice dreen down offen my chin!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Puh-raise the Lawd for vittory!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I get me a whole washtub fulla them grapes and jest sit in 'em and scrooge around till they was gone!  I shore would like to do that! RUTHIE AND WINFIELD are snickering. Ruthie has smeared her face with mush. She pulls Winfield around to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins to slobber in mimicry. Winfield snickers. At that instant Ma enters, unobserved, and without a word give Ruthie a fine wallop. Nobody else pays any attention to the slap as Ma, a bucket in her hand, moves on toward the door. We see her now in the BACKYARD, first at the door, then moving toward the well. She stops dead still, her eyes gazing outward. TOM is looking at the household goods piled around the yard, to be taken to California. Casy is in the background. Then Tom looks up and see Ma (out of the scene). His face softens. He moves toward her.</context>
      <utterance>Look. I'm Grampa!</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God. Oh thank God.  Tommy, you didn't bust out, didya? You ain't got to hide, have you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a sigh and a smile, and her eyes full of wonder, she feels his arm. Her fingers touch his cheek, as if she were blind. Swelling with emotion, Tom bites his lip to control himself.</context>
      <utterance>No, Ma. I'm paroled. I got my papers.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was so scared we was goin' away without you--and we'd never see each other again.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CASY, with great politeness, turns his back to the scene and keeps well away from it. TOM now looks around at the dusty furniture piled around the yard.</context>
      <utterance>I'd a found you, Ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Muley tol' me what happened, Ma. Are we goin' to California true?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got to, Tommy. But that's gonna be awright. I seen the han'bills, about how much work they is, an' high wages, too. But I gotta fin' out somepin' else first, Tommy.  Did they hurt you, son? Did they hurt you an' make you mean-mad?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mad, Ma?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes they do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Ma I was at first--but not no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes they do somethin' to you, Tommy. They hurt you--and you get mad--and then you get mean--and they hurt you again--and you get meaner, and meaner--till you ain't no boy or no man any more, but just a walkin' chunk a mean-mad. Did they hurt you like that, Tommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Ma. You don't have to worry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the DOOR, Pa is staring toward them, his mouth open.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God. I--I don't want no mean son</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSIDE UNCLE JOHN'S CABIN, all but Granma are staring toward the door. Then all but Granma scramble to their feet, headed for the door.</context>
      <utterance>It's Tommy!  It's Tommy back!  What'd you do, son--bust out?</utterance>
   <speaker>WINFIELD AND RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom's outa ja-ul! Tom's outa ja-ul!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children and Grampa scramble out first, followed hurriedly but less rowdily by Uncle John and Noah. Granma, aware only that there is some excitement, looks interestedly after them but decides against any activity.</context>
      <utterance>I knowed it! Couldn't keep him in! Can't keep a Joad in! I knowed it from the fust!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I al'ays said: "Tom'll come bustin' outa that jail like a bull through a corral fence." Can't keep no Joad in jail!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't bust out. They lemme out. Howya, Noah. Howya, Uncle John.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOAH AND JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, Tommy. Glad to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bust out?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The roar increases. A home-built TRUCK comes around the corner of the house. Once a Hudson sedan, the top has been cut in two and a truck body constructed. It is driven now by Al, and on the front seat with him are Rosasharn and Connie. The arrival, as the truck moves into the yard, increases the excitement, and the scene is a little incoherent with the talking and shouting and the noise of the jalopy.</context>
      <utterance>Parole.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL AND ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Tom! Howya doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rosasharn! Hi, Rosasharn! Howya, Al!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The jailbird's back! The jailbird's back!</utterance>
   <speaker>OMNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Ma! Hi, Connie! Hiya, Grampa!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Connie Rivers with her. They're married now.  She's due about three-four months.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, she wasn't no more'n a kid when I went up.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bust outa jail, Tom?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw. They paroled me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heh'o Tom.  This is Connie, my husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If this don't beat all!  Well, I see you been busy already!</utterance>
   <speaker>OMNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An automobile horn sounds sharply. Their laughter halted as though cut by a knife, they look off. A TOURING CAR has stopped in the road by the house, the engine still running. One man drives, the other talks.</context>
      <utterance>Lookut his face! Y'see his face? Lookut Rosasharn! Y'ever see anything like her face when Tom said it? Look around, Rosasharn! Let's see it again!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the BACKYARD the people are silent, their faces without expression, as all gaze toward the touring car.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Joad! John Joad!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't forgot, have you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ain't forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comin' through here tomorrow, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The touring car's engine is still heard after the men drive off. The Joads watch the car, their heads turning, their eyes following, expressionless. The scene dissolves to the BACKYARD just before dawn. Now and then a rooster crows. A couple of lanterns light the scene as the man load the truck. It is nearly done, the body piled high but flat with boxes, and more tied on running boards. Al has the hood open and is working on the motor. Noah, Casy, Uncle John, Connie, Pa, and Tom are at various tasks. They talk as they work.</context>
      <utterance>I know. We be out. We be out by sunup.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you get all this money?</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sol' things, chopped cotton--even Grampa. Got us about two hunnerd dollars all tol'. Shucked out seventy- five for this truck, but we still got nearly a hunnerd and fifty to set out on. I figger we oughta be able to make it on that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy. After all, they ain't but about twelve of us, is they?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll prob'ly ride like a bull calf-- but she'll ride!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSIDE THE CABIN, Ma sits on a box in front of the stove. The fire door is open and the light shines out. The room itself has been pretty well stripped, with only trash and discarded things left. In Ma's lap is a pasteboard shoebox and she is going through the meager treasures stored in it, to see what must go and what she can take with her. Her eyes are soft and thoughtful as each item brings a memory, but not sad. Occasionally she smiles faintly. She pulls out a letter, looks at it, starts to throw it into the fire, then puts it back in the box. Her hand pulls out a PICTURE POSTCARD. We see it in Ma's hand. It is a picture of the Statue Of Liberty. Over it: "Greetings from New York City." She turns it over. It is addressed: "Mrs. Joad RFD 254 Oklahomy Territory." In the space for a message: "Hello honey. Willy Mae." MA, after a moment of studying it, throws the card into the fire. She lifts the letter again, puts it back. She pulls out a worn NEWSPAPER CLIPPING. We see it in Ma's hand. The headline is: "JOAD GETS SEVEN YEARS." MA drops the clipping into the fire. Rummaging around, she pulls out a small CHINA DOG. We see it closely as before. On it is printed: "Souvenir of Louisiana Purchase Exposition-- St. Louis--1904." MA studies the dog, smiling, remembering something that it meant in her life. Then she puts in in a pocket in her dress. Next she pulls out some pieces of cheap jewelry; one cuff link, a baby's signet ring, two earrings. She smiles at the ring, then pockets it. The cuff link too. The earrings she holds for a moment longer, then looks around to make sure nobody sees, then holds them to her ears, not looking into any kind of a mirror, just feeling them against the lobes of her ears, as once perhaps she wore them. Her eyes are grave.</context>
      <utterance>Reckon we better begin roustin' 'em out if we aim to get outa here by daylight. How about it, John? How you boys comin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about it, Ma?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom disappears. Ma looks at the earrings, and then at the contents of the box. She lifts out the letter again and looks at it. Then, without drama, she drops it into the fire. She watches it burn. Her eyes are still on the flame as she calls.</context>
      <utterance>I'm ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the BACKYARD it is grey dawn. There is a thrill of quiet excitement as they all stand around the loaded truck, hats on, putting on coats. The ones missing are Ma, Rosasharn, the children, and Grampa. Pa is in charge.</context>
      <utterance>Rosasharn honey! Wake up the chillun. We're fixin' to leave. The flame dies down.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Grampa? Al, go git him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom easily lifts her up the step. The two children come running out of the house, chanting.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna sit up front! Somebody he'p me!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE AND WINFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goin' to California! Goin' to California!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kids climb up first, on top.  Al's gonna drive, Ma. You sit up there with him and Granma and we'll swap around later.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't gonna sit with Grampa!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Connie, you he'p Rosasharn up there alongside Ruthie and Winfiel'.  Where's Grampa?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where he al'ays is, prob'ly!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All have obeyed and are aboard but Pa, Tom, and Casy, who is watching the springs flatten out.</context>
      <utterance>Well, leave him a place, but Noah, you and John, y'all kinda find yourself a place--kinda keep it even all around.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think she'll hold?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she does it'll be a miracle outa Scripture.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All turn. In a CORNER OF THE HOUSE Al is pulling Grampa gently but firmly, the old man holding back, and furious. He flails feebly at Al, who holds his head out of the way without effort.</context>
      <utterance>Lemmo go, gol dang it! Lemmo go, I tell you!</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wasn't sleepin'. He was settin' out back a the barn. They's somepin' wrong with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al permits Grampa to jerk loose and sit down on the doorstep. The old man is miserable and frightened and angry, too old to understand or accept such a violent change in his life. Tom and Pa come up to him. The others watch solemnly from their places in the truck.</context>
      <utterance>Ef you don't let me go--</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, Grampa?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't nothin' the matter. I just ain't a-goin', that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you mean you ain't goin'? We got to go. We got no place to stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't talkin' about you, I'm talkin' about me. And I'm a-stayin'. I give her a good goin' over all night long-- and I'm a-stayin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you can't do that, Grampa. This here land is goin' under the tractor. We all got to git out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All but me! I'm a-stayin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout Granma?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take her with you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But who'd cook for you? How'd you live?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Muley's livin', ain't he? And I'm twicet the man Muley is!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now listen, Grampa. Listen to me, just a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I ain't gonna listen either. I tol' you what I'm gonna do.  And I don't give a hoot in a hollow if they's oranges and grapes crowdin' a fella outa bed even, I ain't a- goin' to California!  This here's my country. I b'long here .  It ain't no good--  --but it's mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma. Pa.  Grampa, his eyes hurt and hunted and frightened and bewildered, scratches in the dirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All watch him worriedly.</context>
      <utterance>And can't nobody make me go, either! Ain't nobody here man enough to make me! I'm a-stayin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Either we got to tie him up and throw him on the truck, or somepin. He can't stay here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't tie him. Either we'll hurt him or he'll git so mad he'll hurt his self.  Reckon we could git him drunk ?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't no whisky, is they?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. There's a half a bottle a soothin' sirup here.  It put the chillun to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't taste bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they's some coffee here. I could fix him a cup...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. And douse some in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ma is already pouring coffee into a can as GRAMPA is seen.</context>
      <utterance>Better give him a good 'un. He's awful bull-headed.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Muley can scrabble along, I can do it too.  I smell spareribs. Somebody been eatin' spareribs? How come I ain't got some?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got some saved for you, Grampa. Got 'em warmin' now. Here's a cuppa coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awright, but get me some a them spareribs, too. Get me a whole mess of 'em. I'm hongry. He drinks the coffee. Pa and Tom watch him. He notices nothing. He takes another dram of the coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scene dissolves to the TRUCK. It is just after dawn. Pa, Tom, and Noah are lifting Grampa into the truck. He mumbles angrily, but is unconscious of what is happening.</context>
      <utterance>I shore do like spareribs. He drinks again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy, easy! You wanta bust his head wide open? Pull his arms, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't a-goin', thas all...</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The engine rattles and roars shakily. Grinning with excitement, Pa sits down and pats Grampa clumsily.</context>
      <utterance>Put somepin' over him, so he won't git sun-struck.  Ever'body set now?  Awright, Al, letta go!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The truck starts to move heavily. Casy stands watching it.</context>
      <utterance>You be awright, Grampa.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good-by, an' good luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, wait! Hold 'er, Al!  Ain't you goin' with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, get on, plenty room!</utterance>
   <speaker>OMNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quickly he climbs aboard. The truck rattles into motion again.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, come on, Casy, plenty room!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we go!</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't you gonna look back, Ma?--give the ol' place a last look?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're goin' to California, ain't we? Awright then, let's go to California.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That don't sound like you, Ma. You never was like that before.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She continues to stare straight ahead. The TRUCK is lumbering up onto a paved highway. The scene dissolves to a MONTAGE: Almost filling the screen is the shield marker of the U.S. Highway 66. Superimposed on it is a montage of jalopies, steaming and rattling and piled high with goods and people, as they pull onto the highway, to indicate as much as possible that this departure of the Joad family is but part of a mass movement of jalopies and families. The signs of towns on U.S. Highway 66 flash past--</context>
      <utterance>I never had my house pushed over before. I never had my fambly stuck out on the road. I never had to lose... ever'thing I had in life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="342">
   <speaker>GRAMPA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't a-goin'... ain't a-goin'...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a quilt pulled from the truck Ma runs ahead as Tom carries Grampa toward a clump of woods back off the highway. The others get down soberly from the truck, all but Granma, who is dozing. Cars pass-a fast car passing a jalopy. Tom is letting the old man down gently as Ma adjusts the quilt on the ground. Death is in Grampa's eyes as he looks up dimly at them.</context>
      <utterance>'S all right, Grampa. You just kind a tar'd, that's all. Somebody fix a pallet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GRAVE, at night. In the clump of woods, lighted by two lanterns, The Joad tribe stands reverently around an open grave. Having read the note, Tom puts it in a small fruit jar and kneels down and, reaching into the grave, places it on Grampa's body.</context>
      <utterance>This here is William James Joad, dyed of a stroke, old old man. His folkes bured him becaws they got no money to pay for funerls. Nobody kilt him. Jus a stroke an he dyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figger best we leave something like this on him, lest somebody dig him up and make out he been kilt.  Lotta times looks like the gov'ment got more interest in a dead man than a live one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not be so lonesome, either, knowin' his name is there with 'im, not just' a old fella lonesome underground.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Casy, won't you say a few words?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't no more a preacher, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know. But ain't none of our folks ever been buried without a few words.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll say 'em--an' make it short.  This here ol' man jus' lived a life an' jus' died out of it. I don't know whether he was good or bad, an' it don't matter much. Heard a fella say a poem once, an' he says, "All that lives is holy." But I wouldn't pray for jus' a ol' man that's dead, because he's awright. If I was to pray I'd pray for the folks that's alive an' don't know which way to turn. Grampa here, he ain't got no more trouble like that. He's got his job all cut out for 'im--so cover 'im up and let 'im get to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMNES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scene fades out. HIGHWAY 66, in daylight, fades in: an Oklahoma stretch, revealing a number of jalopies rattling westward. The Joad truck approaches. In the FRONT SEAT OF THE TRUCK Tom is now driving. Granma is dozing again, and Ma is looking thoughtfully ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Ma?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wasn't that the state line we just passed?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes'm, that was it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your pa tol' me you didn't ought to cross it if you're paroled. Says they'll send you up again.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it, Ma. I got her figgered out. Long as I keep outa trouble, ain't nobody gonna say a thing. All I gotta do is keep my nose clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe they got crimes in California we don't know about. Crimes we don't even know is crimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it, Ma. Jus' think about the nice things out there. Think about them grapes and oranges--an' ever'body got work--</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta git out!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First gas station, Granma--</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta git out , I tell ya! I gotta git out !</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the truck slows to a stop a motorcycle cop approaches after them. Looking back, Tom sees him bearing toward them. He looks grimly at Ma.</context>
      <utterance>Awright! Awright!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They shore don't waste no time!  Take her out.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Save your strength, lady.  Get goin', buddy. No campin' here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ain't campin'. We jus' stoppin' a minute--</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lissen, I heard that before--</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cop looks startled, puzzled, but Tom shrugs a disclaimer for responsibility in that quarter.</context>
      <utterance>I tell ya I gotta git out!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's kinda ol'--</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell ya--</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma... all this, will it hurt the baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now don't you go gettin' nimsy-mimsy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I'm all jumpy inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, can't nobody get through nine months without sorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But will it--hurt the baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They use' to be a sayin': A chile born outa sorrow'll be a happy chile. An' another: Born outa too much joy'll be a doleful boy. That's the way I always heard it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't ever get scairt, do you, Ma?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes. A little. Only it ain't scairt so much. It's just waitin' an' wonderin'. But when sump'n happens that I got to do sump'n--  --I'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't it ever scare you it won't be nice in California like we think?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No, it don't. I can't do that. I can't let m'self. All I can do is see how soon they gonna wanta eat again. They'd all get upset if I done anymore 'n that. They all depen' on me jus' thinkin' about that.  That's my part--that an' keepin' the fambly together. As the music ends we see a GROUP ON THE PORCH STEPS. The men murmur approbation of Connie's playing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thas my son-in-law.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sings real nice. What state y'all from?</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oklahoma. Had us a farm there, share- croppin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Till the tractors druv us out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We from Arkansas. I had me a store there, kind of general notions store, but when the farms went the store went too.  Nice a little as you ever saw. I shore did hate to give it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wal, y'cain't tell. I figure when we git out there an' git work an' maybe git us a piece a growin' lan' near water it might not be so bad at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>OTHER MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they talk, a SECOND MAN, standing on the edge of the group, begins to grin bitterly. He is much more ragged than the others.</context>
      <utterance>Thas right... Payin' good wages, I hear... Ever'body got work out there... Can't be no worse...</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GROUP turns to look at the Man.</context>
      <utterance>You folks must have a pot a money.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good wages, eh! Pickin' oranges an' peaches?</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gonna take whatever they got.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so funny about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so funny about it? I just been out there! I been an' seen it! An' I'm goin' back to starve-- because I ruther starve all over at once!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatta you think you're talkin' about? I got a han'bill here says good wages, an' I seen it in the papers they need pickers!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awright, go on! Ain't nobody stoppin' ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't gonna fret you. Go on!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, buddy. You jus' done some jackassin'! You ain't gonna shut up now. The han'bill says they need men. You laugh an' say they don't. Now which one's a liar?</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what does that prove?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a long worried silence. The proprietor leans forward angrily.</context>
      <utterance>Look at 'em! Same yella han'bill-- 800 pickers wanted. Awright, this man wants 800 men. So he prints up 5,000 a them han'bills an' maybe 20,000 people sees 'em. An' maybe two-three thousan' starts movin, wes' account a this han'bill. Two- three thousan' folks that's crazy with worry headin' out for 800 jobs! Does that make sense?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROPRIETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you, a troublemaker? You sure you ain't one a them labor fakes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear I ain't, mister!</utterance>
   <speaker>PROPRIETOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, don't you go roun' here tryin' to stir up trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around at the men, trying to control his emotions, and then he walks away into the darkness. There is an uneasy silence.</context>
      <utterance>I tried to tell you folks sump'n it took me a year to fin' out. Took two kids dead, took my wife dead, to show me. But nobody couldn't tell me neither. I can't tell ya about them little fellas layin' in the tent with their bellies puffed out an' jus' skin on their bones, an' shiverin' an' whinin' like pups, an' me runnin' aroun' tryin' to get work--  --not for money, not for wages--jus' for a cup a flour an' a spoon a lard! An' then the coroner came. "Them children died a heart-failure," he says, an' put it in his paper.  Heart-failure!--an' their little bellies stuck out like a pig-bladder!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all rise as at a signal, all moved and worried by the Second Man's outburst. TOM, PA AND CASY move away, worry on their faces.</context>
      <utterance>Well--gettin' late. Got to get to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>S'pose he's tellin' the truth--that fella?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's tellin' the truth awright. The truth for him. He wasn't makin' nothin' up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about us? Is that the truth for us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You folks aim to buy anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Need some gas, mister.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got any money?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatta you think:--we's beggin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>FAT MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just ast, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, ask right. You ain't talkin' to bums, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kinda pie y'got?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Banana cream, pineapple cream, chocolate cream--and apple.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut me off a hunk a that banana cream, and a cuppa java.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make it two.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two it is.  Seen any new etchin's lately, Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you see your way clear to sell us a loaf of bread, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This ain't a groc'ry store. We got bread to make san'widges with.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, ma'am... on'y it's for a ole lady, no teeth, gotta sof'n it with water so she can chew it, an' she's hongry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whyn't you buy a san'wich? We got nice san'widges.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shore would like to do that, ma'am, but the fack is, we ain't got but a dime for it. It's all figgered out, I mean--for the trip.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't get no loaf a bread for a dime. We only got fifteen-cent loafs.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give 'em the bread.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll run out 'fore the bread truck comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mae shrugs at the truck drivers, to indicate what she's up against, while Bert mashes his hamburgers savagely with the spatula.</context>
      <utterance>Awright then, run out!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pa and the two children come in as Mae opens a drawer and pulls out a long waxpaper-covered loaf of bread. The children have been drawn to the candy showcase and are staring in at the goodies.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This here's a fifteen-cent loaf.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you--could you see your way to cuttin' off ten cents worth?</utterance>
   <speaker>BERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give 'im the loaf!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir, we wanta buy ten cents worth, thas all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can have this for ten cents.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wanta rob you, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking out his pouch, Pa digs into it, feels around with his fingers for a dime, as he apologizes.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead--Bert says take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But when he puts the dime down on the counter he has a penny with it. He is about to drop this back in the pouch when his eyes fall on the children staring at the candy. Slowly he moves down to see what they are looking at. Then:</context>
      <utterance>May soun' funny to be so tight, but we got a thousan' miles to go, an' we don't know if we'll make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children look up with a gasp, their big eyes on Mae as she moves down behind the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Is them penny candy, ma'am?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which ones?</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mae looks from the candy to the children. They have stopped breathing, their eyes on the candy.</context>
      <utterance>There, them stripy ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, them? Well, no--them's two for a penny.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He places the penny carefully on the counter and Mae holds the sticks of candy out to the children. They look up at Pa.</context>
      <utterance>Well, give me two then, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door slams. Bill turns back from staring after them.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Them wasn't two-for-a-cent candy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Them was nickel apiece candy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both reach in their pockets, but when Fred sees what Bill has put down he reaches again and duplicates it. As they go out of the door...</context>
      <utterance>We got to get goin'. We're droppin' time.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So long.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, wait a minute. You got change comin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Mae watches them through the window, her eyes warm, Bert walks around the counter to the three slot machines, a paper with figures on it in his hand. The truck roars outside and moves off. Mae looks down again at the coins.</context>
      <utterance>What's it to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bert.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What ya want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he looks we see the COINS ON THE COUNTER. They are two half-dollars.</context>
      <utterance>Look here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a rattle of coins as Bert hits the jackpot. In his left hand on the machine is a paper with three columns of figures on it. The third column is much the longest. He scoops out the money.</context>
      <utterance>Truck drivers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ARIZONA BORDER, in daylight, fades in. It is in a gap in the mountains and beyond can be seen the Painted Desert. A border guard halts the Joad truck. He is not as tough as his words indicate, just curt and matter-of-fact.</context>
      <utterance>I figgered No. 3 was about ready to pay off. The scene fades out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>California.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long you plan to be in Arizona?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No longer'n we can get acrost her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got any plants?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No plants.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Go ahead, but you better keep movin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The truck rattles into movement. The scene dissolves to a MONTAGE superimposed on the shield marker of U.S. Highway 66 and the Joad truck. Signs flash by: FLAGSTAFF, WATER 5 A GAL, WATER 10 A GAL, WATER 15 A GAL, and finally, NEEDLES, CALIF. In the foreground, their backs turned, the Joads stand on and about their truck looking in a long silence at what can be seen of California from Needles. Their silence is eloquent. The faces of the Joads are blank with dismay, for this is an unattractive sight indeed.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. We aim to.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There she is, folks--the land a milk an' honey--California!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other in disappointment.</context>
      <utterance>Well, if that's what we come out here for...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's nice on the other side. Them pitchers--them little pos'cards-- they was real pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, sure. This here's jus' a part of it. Ain't no sense a gettin' scairt right off.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Joads and the landscape are seen again. Then the scene dissolves to the BANK OF A RIVER. The camp at Needles is on the bank of the Colorado River, among some willows. We see the man of the family sitting chest-deep in the shallow waters, talking, occasionally ducking their heads under, reveling in this relief. In the background are the towering mountains.</context>
      <utterance>Course not. Come on, let's get goin'. She don't look so tough to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got that desert yet. Gotta take her tonight. Take her in the daytime fella says she'll cut your gizzard out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's Granma since we got her in the tent?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's off her chump, seems to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's outa her senses, awright. All night on the truck keep talkin' like she was talkin' to Grampa.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's jus' wore out, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shore would like to stop here a while an' give her some res' but we on'y got 'bout forty dollars left. I won't feel right till we're there an' all workin' an' a little money comin' in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOAH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like to jus' stay here myself. Like to lay here forever. Never get hungry an' never get sad. Lay in the water all life long, lazy as a brood sow in the mud.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look up as a man and his grown son stand on the bank.</context>
      <utterance>Never seen such tough mountains. This here's a murder country, just the bones of a country.  Wonder if we'll ever get in a place where folks can live 'thout fightin' hard scrabble an' rock. Sometimes you get to thinkin' they ain't no such country.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the swimmin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dunno. We ain't tried none. Sure feels good to set here, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind if we come in an' set?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start to shuck off their clothes. THE MAN, excluding those undressing, form another scene.</context>
      <utterance>She ain't our river. But we'll len' you a little piece of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goin' west?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. We come from there. Goin' back home.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's home?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Panhandle, come from near Pampa.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you make a livin' there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man and his son sit down in the water.</context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya know, you're the second fella talked like that. I'd like to hear some more about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man and his son exchange a glance, as though the Joads had touched on the deadliest of subjects.</context>
      <utterance>Me an' you both.</utterance>
   <speaker>SON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ain't gonna tell you nothin' about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If a fella's willin' to work hard, can't he cut her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a disturbed silence as the Joads study the man, but he obviously has no intention of saying anything more. Finally Pa turns to his brother.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, mister. I don't know ever'thing. You might go out an' fall into a steady job, an' I'd be a liar. An' then, you might never get no work, an' I didn't warn you. All I can tell ya, most of the folks is purty mis'able.  But a fella don't know ever'thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, you never was a fella to say much, but I'll be goldanged if you opened your mouth twicet since we lef' home. What you think about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think nothin' about it. We're a-goin' there, ain't we? When we get there, we'll get there. When we get a job, we'll work, an' when we don't get a job we'll set on our behin's. That's all they is to it, ain't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You people got a lotta nerve.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crossin' the desert in a jalopy like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been acrost?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, plenty, but not in no wreck like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we broke down maybe somebody'd give us a han'.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe. But I'd hate to be doin' it. Takes more nerve than I got.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you worry, Granma. It's gonna be awright.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANMA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grampa... Grampa... I want Grampa...</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the GAS STATION again with the truck pulling away. The First Boy, a lad who knows everything, stands looking after them, shaking his head. His assistant is cleaning up the pumps.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you fret now. The truck moves off.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy Moses, what a hard-lookin' outfit!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All them Okies is hard-lookin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, but I'd hate to hit that desert in a jalopy like that!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you and me got sense. Them Okies got no sense or no feeling. They ain't human. A human being wouldn't live like they do. A human being couldn't stand it to be so miserable.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NOAH is seen hiding behind a corner of the GAS STATION. Peering out, he sees that the truck has gone. He turns to walk away into the darkness. The scene dissolves to a RIVER BANK at night, and Noah is once more seated in the shallow water, splashing, looking up at the mountains, content. The TRUCK is rattling along U.S. Highway 66, across the desert, in the night. In the DRIVER'S SEAT Tom is driving, Al and Pa are by his side.</context>
      <utterance>Just don't know any better, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a place! How'd you like to walk acrost her?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People done it. If they could, we could.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lots must a died, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RUTHIE AND WINFIELD huddle together in THE TRUCK, eyes wide with excitement.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we ain't out a it yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This here's the desert an' we're right in it!</utterance>
   <speaker>WINFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wisht it was day.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom says if it's day it'll cut you gizzard smack out a you.  I seen a pitcher once. They was bones ever'place.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man bones?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MA AND GRANDMA are seen again. The old woman lies still, breathing noisily. Ma continues to pat her.</context>
      <utterance>Some, I guess, but mos'ly cow bones.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems like we wasn't never gonna do nothin' but move. I'm so tar'd.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Women is always tar'd.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't--you ain't sorry, are you, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but--but you seen that advertisement in the Spicy Western Story magazine. Don't pay nothin'. Jus' send 'em the coupon an' you're a radio expert--nice clean work.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we can still do it, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't give up, honey. The family's got to get acrost. You know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ma does not answer immediately. Her head lifted, she is staring at Granma's face. Then slowly she withdraws her hand from Grandma's heart.</context>
      <utterance>Ever'thing all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this here?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agricultural inspection. We got to go over your stuff. Got any vegetables or seed?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MA gets down off the truck, her face swollen, her eyes hard. There is an undercurrent of hysteria in her voice and manner.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we got to look over your stuff. You got to unload.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, mister. We got a sick ol' lady. We got to get her to a doctor. We can't wait.  You can't make us wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Well, we got to look you over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officer lights his flashlight on Granma's face.</context>
      <utterance>I swear we ain't got anything. I swear it. An' Granma's awful sick.  Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wasn't foolin'! You swear you got no fruit or vegetables?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I swear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ma climbs back up beside Granma.</context>
      <utterance>Then go ahead. You can get a doctor at Barstow. That's just eight miles. But don't stop. Don't get off. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The truck starts.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, cap. Much oblige.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will ya look at her!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One by one, they climb down.</context>
      <utterance>I never knowed they was anything like her!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts back. MA is holding to the rear of the truck, her face stiff and swollen, her eyes deep-sunk, her limbs weak and shaky.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Ma? I want Ma to see it. Look, Ma! Come here, Ma!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma, you sick?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya say we're acrost?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Ma!</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God! An' we're still together-- most of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn' you get no sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was Granma bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Granma's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since before they stopped us las' night.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An' that's why you didn't want 'em to look?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With the valley for background, Ma looks down on it.</context>
      <utterance>I was afraid they'd stop us an' wouldn't let us cross. But I tol' Granma. I tol' her when she was dyin'. I tol' her the fambly had ta get acrost. I tol' her we couldn't take no chances on bein' stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far you figger you gonna get this way?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is a two-pump station and one of the pumps has a car, with the attendant servicing it. The Joad truck stops by the other pump and Tom, wiping his face with his sleeve, grins and address himself to the policeman. The others stand listening solemnly in the background.</context>
      <utterance>Right here. We give out a gas.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the bes' place to get some work aroun' here?  Don't matter what kin' either.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I seen one a them things I must a seen ten thousan'.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't it no good?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not here--not now. Month ago there was some pickin' but it's all moved south now. Where'bouts in Oklahoma you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sallisaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I come out from Cherokee County--two years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, Connie's folks from Cherokee County--</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, ma'am, let's don't go into it. I already met about a hundred firs' cousins an' it mus' be five hundred secon'. But this is what I got to tell you, don't try to park in town tonight. Keep on out to that camp. If we catch you in town after dark we got to lock you up. Don't forget.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what we gonna do ?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strolls away, the Joads looking concernedly after him, just as the gas station attendant comes briskly to them after disposing of the other car.</context>
      <utterance>Pop, that just ain't up to me.  But I don't min' tellin' you, the guy they ought to lock up is the guy that sent out them things.</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many, folks?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The attendant regards him in disgust. The scene dissolves to HOOVERVILLE, by day. A large migrant camp, a typical shanty town of ragged tents and tarpaper shacks, jalopies and dirty children. A dozen or more children pause to watch as the Joad truck lumbers down a dirt incline from the road and stops at the edge of the camp in front of one of the most miserable of the shacks. The Joads regard the camp with dismay.</context>
      <utterance>One.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She shore don't look prosperous. Want to go somewheres else?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let's set up the tent. Maybe I can fix us up some stew. The truck moves into the camp through a lane of children. The scene dissolves to the JOAD TENT. In front of it, Ma is on her knees feeding a small fire with broken sticks. On the fire is a pot of stew. Ruthie and Winfield stand watching the pot. About fifteen ragged, barefooted children in a half- circle are now around the fire, their solemn eyes on the pot of stew. Occasionally they look at Ma, then back at the stew. Presently one of the older girls speaks.</context>
      <utterance>On a gallon a gas?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could break up some bresh if you want me, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to get ast to eat, hunh?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn' you have no breakfast?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, ma'am. They ain't no work hereabouts. Pa's in tryin' to sell some stuff to get gas so's we can get along.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a long silence. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Didn' none of these have no breakfast?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did. Me an' my brother did. We et good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy chokes, his lip sticks out.</context>
      <utterance>Then you ain't hungry, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We et good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's a good thing some a you ain't hungry, because they ain't enough to go all the way roun'.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pa and John enter.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, he was braggin'. Know what he done? Las' night, come out an' say they got chicken to eat. Well, sir, I looked in whilst they was a-eatin' an' it was fried dough jus' like ever'body else.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is dishing the stew into tin plates. The children's eyes follow the spoon, and then the first plate, to John. He is raising the first spoonful to his mouth when he notices them apparently for the first time. He is chewing slowly, his eyes on the children, their eyes on his face, when Tom and Al enter.</context>
      <utterance>Go get Tom an' Al.  I dunno what to do. I got to feed the fambly. What'm I gonna do with these here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take this.  I ain't hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatta ya mean? You ain't et today.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but I got a stomickache. I ain't hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You take that plate inside the tent an' you eat it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't be no use. I'd still see 'em inside the tent.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You git. Go on now, git. You ain't doin' no good. They ain't enough for you. The children retreat a step, but no more, and then look wonderingly at him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes in the tent hurriedly to hide the fact that tears have come into her eyes. The children pounce on the pot, silently, too busy digging for the stew to speak. INSIDE THE TENT they have all finished their stew already.</context>
      <utterance>We can't send 'em away. Take your plates an' go inside. Take a plate to Rosasharn.  Look. You little fellas go an' get you each a flat stick an' I'll put what's lef' for you.  But they ain't to be no fightin'!  I don't know if I'm doin' right or not but--go inside, ever'body stay inside.  They ain't enough. All you gonna get is jus' a taste but--I can't help it, I can't keep it from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You men want to work?</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure we wanta work. Where's it at?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tulare County. Fruit's opening up. Need a lot of pickers.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You doin' the hirin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm contracting the land.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whay you payin?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, can't tell exactly, yet. 'Bout thirty cents, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why can't you tell? You took the contrac', didn' you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's true. But it's keyed to the price. Might be a little more, might be a little less.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, mister. I'll go. You just show your license to contrack, an' then you make out a order--where an' when an' how much you gonna pay--an' you sign it an' we'll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You trying to tell me how to run my own business?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'F we're workin' for you, it's our business too. An' how do we know--  --you ain't one a the guys that sent these things out?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twicet now I've fell for that line. Maybe he needs a thousan' men. So he get's five thousan' there, an' he'll pay fifteen cents a hour. An' you guys'll have to take it 'cause you'll be hungry.  'F he wants to hire men, let him write it out an' say what he's gonna pay. Ast to see his license. He ain't allowed by law to contrack men without a license.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other man gets out of the COUPE. He wears riding breeches and laced boots, carries a pistol and cartridge belt, and there is a deputy sheriff's star on his brown shirt. He smiles thinly and shifts his pistol holster as he starts toward the group. THE MEN are watching the deputy approach.</context>
      <utterance>Joe!</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see? If this guy was on the level, would he bring a cop along?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever see this guy before?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he do?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's agitatin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm.  Seems like I have. Seems like I seen him hangin' around that used car lot that was busted into. Yep, I'd swear it's the same fella.  Get in that car.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got nothin' on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open your trap again and you'll go too.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men say nothing.</context>
      <utterance>You fellas don't wanta lissen to troublemakers. You better pack up an' come on to Tulare County.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the agent gets into the coupe FLOYD'S thumbs hook over his belt and he looks off, away. TOM'S look away is an answer. His thumbs also hook over his belt.</context>
      <utterance>Might be a good idea to do what he says. Too many of you Okies aroun' here already. Folks beginnin' to figger it ain't maybe safe . Might start a epidemic or sump'n.  Wouldn't like a bunch a guys down here with pick handles tonight, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes hold of Floyd's left arm. At the same time Floyd swings, smacks him in the face. As the deputy staggers, Tom sticks out a foot and trips him. Floyd is already running through the camp. The deputy fires from the ground. There is a scream. A WOMAN is looking down at her hand, the knuckles shot away. The COUPE is seen as the agent steps on the gas to get away. As Floyd gets in the clear, the DEPUTY, sitting on the ground, aims his pistol again, slowly, carefully. Behind him Casy steps up, gauges his distance, and then kicks him square in the base of the skull. The deputy tumbles over unconscious. Tom picks up the pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Now, you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme that gun. Now git outa here. Go down in them willows an' wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't gonna run.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He seen you, Tom! You wanta be fingerprinted? You wanta get sent back for breakin' parole?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Tom strides away there is the distant sound of a siren. Casy empties the gun and throws cartridges and gun aside. The men, aghast, have been standing back, worried and excited and apprehensive. They wish nothing like this had happened. The women have gathered around the wounded woman, who is sobbing. Now at the sound of the siren everybody begins to move uncomfortably toward his tent or shack. Al looks admiringly from Casy to the unconscious deputy. Everybody has disappeared into his tent but Al and Casy. The siren draws nearer.</context>
      <utterance>Hide in the willows. If it's awright to come back I'll give you four high whistles.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on. Get in your tent. You don't know nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some body got to take the blame. They just got to hang it on somebody, you know.  An' I ain't doin' nothin' but set around.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But ain't no reason--</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lissen. I don't care nothin' about you, but if you mess in this, your whole fambly li'ble to get in trouble, an' Tom get sent back to the penitentiary.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I think you're a darn fool, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al heads for the Joad tent and Casy kneels down and lifts the deputy. He wipes his face clean. The deputy begins to come to. An open car curves off the highway, stops in the clearing, and four men with rifles pile out. The deputy sits rubbing his eyes and Casy stands.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's goin' on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This man a yours, he got tough an' I hit him. Then he started shootin'-- hit a woman down the line--so I hit him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well--what'd you do in the first place?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two of the men have helped the deputy to his feet. He feels the back of his neck gingerly.</context>
      <utterance>I talked back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They's a woman down there like to bleed to death from his bad shootin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a look at her.  Mike, is this the fella that hit you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was me, all right. You just got smart with the wrong fella.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look like him, but... maybe it was. I ain't sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a deputy on either side of him, Casy climbs in the back seat. The sickish deputy is helped into the car. The other man comes running back.</context>
      <utterance>Get in that car.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what you gonna do? Must be thousands of 'em around here, sore and hungry and living in them dumps. What you gonna do about 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta hold 'em down. Hold 'em down or they'll take over the whole country. That's all you can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave him alone, Ma--Al's just billy- goatin' around--</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure! I was just aimin' to meet up with a couple girls I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know no girls around here. You're lyin', You're runnin' away !</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut it out, Ma, or I'll--</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll what ?... Come on, Pa. Come on an' whup me. Jus' try it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now don't get sassy, Ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Al ain't a-goin' away, an' you gonna tell him he ain't a-goin' away.  An' if you think diff'unt, you gotta whup me first. So some on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never seen her so sassy.  An' she ain't so young, neither!</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd come back--</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jus' sassy, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sassy my foot! I'm jus' sick and tar'd a my folks tryin' to bust up. All we got lef' in the worl' is the fambly--an' right down at bottom that's all we got to have! Ef some of us dies, we can't he'p that--but ain't nobody else runnin' away!</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it ain't runnin' away, Ma. All I wanta do is go away with another fella an' look aroun' for work by ourself--</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you ain't a-goin'! Ain't nobody else a-goin'! We got here an' we gonna stay here, together! As long as we got the fambly unbroke I ain't scared, but it's a long bitter road we got ahead of us--  --an' I'm here to tell ya ef anybody else tries to bust us up anymore I'm a-goin' cat wild with this here piece a bar-arn! As she gets ready for whatever... IN THE SHADOWS, twenty feet away from the tent, Tom whistles softly.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN FRONT OF THE JOAD TENT, all but Ma are looking off. Ma still eyes Pa.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Al!</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom? You can come on. They gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got to get outa here right away. Ever'body here? Where's Uncle John?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a matter now?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fella tells me some a them poolroom boys figgerin' to burn the whole camp out tonight. Got to get that truck loaded--what you doin' with the jack-handle, Ma?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA, PA, AND AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Al's tryin' to go away... She jus' got sassy... All I aimed to do...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a silence that stops Tom in his rush of preparation.</context>
      <utterance>Awright, you can fight it out later. Right now we got to hustle. Where's Connie?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Connie's gone.  Lit out this e'enin'--said he didn't know it was gonna be like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad to get shet of him. Never was no good an' never will be--</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pa! Shh!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come I got to shh? Run out, didn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut it out, Pa. He'p Al with the truck.  Don't fret, honey. You goin' to be awright.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom, I jus' don't feel like nothin' a tall. Without him I jus' don't wanta live.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scene dissolves to HOOVERVILLE, at night. The jalopies are lumbering up on the road, one after the other, as the migrants scatter before the threatened invasion. IN THE JOAD TRUCK, Tom is helping Rosasharn into the front seat, beside Ma. The others are aboard except Al. Tom hands Al a wrench.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe he'll be back. We'll leave word for him. Jus' don't cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just in case. Sit up back an' if anybody tries to climb up--let 'im have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't got nothin' in my han'.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the FRONT SEAT of the truck, Tom drives, Ma sits in the middle, Rosasharn on the other side.</context>
      <utterance>Give 'im a fryin' pan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe Connie went to get some books to study up with. He's gonna be a radio expert, ya know. Maybe he figgered to suprise us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe that's jus' what he done.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma, they comes a time when a man gets mad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom--you tol' me--you promised you wasn't like that. You promised me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, Ma. I'm a tryin'. If it was the law they was workin' with, we could take it. But it ain't the law. They're workin' away at our spirits. They're tryin' to make us cringe an' crawl. They're workin' on our decency.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You promised, Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a-tryin', Ma. Honest I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta keep clear, Tom. The fambly's breakin' up. You got to keep clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he slows down the truck, we see that half of the ROAD is blocked with boards and red lanterns. a group of men swarm around the Joad truck as it stops. A leader leans in Tom's window.</context>
      <utterance>What's that--detour?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the FRONT SEAT of the truck Tom's hand reaches for the jack-handle on the seat at his side but Ma's hand clutches his arm in a steel grip.</context>
      <utterance>Where you think you're goin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well--  --we're strangers here. We heard about they's work in a place called Tulare.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom's arm trembles as he tries to pull it away, but Ma holds on tight.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you're goin' the wrong way, an' what's more, we don't want no more Okies in this town. We ain't got work enough for them that are already here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way is it at, mister?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You turn right aroun' and head north. An' don't come back till the cotton's ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TRUCK turns around. In the FRONT SEAT Tom is almost sobbing with anger as he maneuvers the truck around.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="111">
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sump'n got to happen soon. We got one day's more grease, two day's flour, an' ten potatoes. After that...  An' Rosasharn, we got to remember she's gonna be due soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sure is hell jus' tryin' to get enough to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BUICK ROADMASTER which has been speeding toward them stops suddenly. Driving it is a husky man, named Spencer, whose manner is amiable and disarming.</context>
      <utterance>Fella tells me they's three hunerd thousan' aroun' here like us, a- scrabblin' for work an' livin' like hogs. Can't figger what it is, but sump'n's wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You people looking for work?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister, we're lookin' even under boards for work.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you pick peaches?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can pick anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is electrifying news, as their faces show.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there's plenty of work for you about forty miles north, this road just outside Pixley. Turn east on 32 and look for Hooper's ranch. Tell 'em Spencer sent you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they snap into action to get under way again the scene dissolves to the FRONT SEAT, Al driving, with Ma and Tom beside him. They are all smiles, their faces glowing with excitement.</context>
      <utterance>Mister, we sure that ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fust thing I'll get is coffee, cause ever'body been wantin' that, an' then some flour an' bakin' powder an' meat. Better not get no side- meat right off. Save that for later. Maybe Sat'dy. Got to get some soap too. An' milk. Rosasharn's got to have some milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get some sugar too, for the coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I jus' can't remember when I felt so good before!</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The scene dissolves to the ENTRANCE OF THE HOOPER RANCH in daylight. A gravel road leads from the paved highway to the big wire gates, which are enclosed. Along the side of the paved highway are parked a dozen jalopies, the migrants sitting soberly in them. Fifty or sixty other migrants line the gravel road and the junction with the paved highway. Five jalopies are in line waiting to enter the gates. And the scene is overwhelmingly policed. There must be ten motorcycle cops around. Six are dismounted and strolling to keep order among the migrants along the road. Three, their motorcycles roaring, flank the line of five jalopies. As the Joad truck drives up, we see the FRONT SEAT. Tom, Al, and Ma are beholding the scene with bewilderment.</context>
      <utterance>Know what I'm a-gonna do? I'm a-gonna save up an' go in town an' get me a job in a garage. Live in a room an' eat in restaurants. Go to the movin' pitchers ever' night. Cowboy pitchers.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, a wreck?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you think you're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fella named Spencer sent us--said they was work pickin' peaches.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to work, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure do.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull up behind that car.  Okay for this one. Take 'em through.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter? What's happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The motorcycle escort forms around the line of six cars and a deafening din is raised, of motorcycles, sirens, and an inexplicable blowing of horns on the jalopies. At the same time, as the gates open and the six cars start through, flanked by the motorcycle cops, the migrants begin spasmodic shouts, but what they say cannot be understood. As the cars move slowly, Tom and Al in the FRONT SEAT are puzzled and worried at the demonstration.</context>
      <utterance>Little trouble up ahead, but you'll get through. Just follow the line.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe the road's out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT THE GATES the heckling from the bystanders is spasmodic, not continuous, as the six jalopies in line pass through the gate into the Hooper ranch. Two men stand beside the gates with shotguns. They keep calling.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what these cops got to do with it but I don't like it.  An' these here are our own people, all of 'em. I don't like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Joad truck passes through the gates. IN THE HOOPER RANCH the six jalopies are halted at the end of a camp street. The houses are small, square blocks, set in line. One, a little larger, is a grocery store. Casually about are men in pairs with metal stars on their shirts and shotguns in their hands. Two bookkeepers are already passing down the cars and jotting down information.</context>
      <utterance>Go on, go on! Keep movin'!</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to work?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, but what is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not your affair. Name.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many men?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Women?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can all of you work?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, I guess so.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to the next car. The Joad truck starts... AT HOUSE 63, as the Joad truck pulls up, two deputies approach. They look closely into each face as the Joads pile out. One of the deputies has a long list in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. House 63. Wages 5 cents a box. No bruised fruit. Move along and go to work right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joad. Say, what is this here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not here. Take a look at his license.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>542-567 Oklahoma.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't got it. Guess they're okay.  Now you look here. We don't want no trouble with you. Jes' do your work and mind your own business and you'll be all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ma and Rosasharn step inside the house. It is filthy. A rusty tin stove resting on four bricks is all the one room contains. Ma and Rosasharn stand looking around at it. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>They sure do want to make us feel at home all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gonna live here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, sure. It won't be so bad once we get her washed out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like the tent better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OUTSIDE, a clerk with glasses appears, pushing a cart loaded with three-gallon buckets.</context>
      <utterance>This got a floor. Wouldn't leak when it rains.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's still Joad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All y'all go. Me an' Rosasharn'll unload. With their buckets they shuffle away toward the peach trees-- Tom, Pa, Uncle John, Al, and the two children struggling with the enormous containers. The scene dissolves to the INTERIOR OF HOUSE 63 at night, a lantern lighting the scene. Sitting wherever they can, the Joads have finished their supper of hamburgers. And grateful they are too, for the meat.</context>
      <utterance>Six.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got any more, Ma?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. That's all. You made a dollar, an' that's a dollar's worth.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That!</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They charge extry at the comp'ny store but they ain't no other place.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't full.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, tomorra you'll get in a full day--full day's pay--an' we'll have plenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't think jus' reachin' up an' pickin'd get you in the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think I'll walk out an' try to fin' out what all that fuss outside the gate was. Anybody wanta come with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm jus' gonna set awhile an' then go to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think I'll look aroun' an' see if I can't meet me a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thing's been workin' on me, what they was yellin' about. Got me all curious.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got to get a lot curiouser than I am--with all them cops out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I be back a little later.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You be careful, Tommy. Don't you be stickin' your nose in anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you think you're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought I'd take a walk. Any law against it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you just turn around and walk the other way.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean I can't even get outa here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not tonight you can't. Want to walk back?--or you want me to whistle up some help and take you back?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard watches him as he walks back and then douses his flashlight. At a SECTION OF WIRE FENCE, watching his chance, moving silently, Tom drops on the ground, on his back, gets his head under the bottom wire, and pushes himself under and outside. Rising, he crosses the paved highway. AN EMBANKMENT across the road from the wire fence: Tom clambers down it, moving quietly. He picks his way down the shallow ravine. A TENT: there is a light inside and there are the shadows of figures. In the background, beyond the tent, is the silhouette of a small concrete bridge spanning a small stream. Following a trail, Tom enters and approaches the tent. (The opening is away from him.) IN FRONT OF THE TENT, a man sitting on a box looks up suspiciously as Tom enters. His name is Joe.</context>
      <utterance>I'll walk back.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evenin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jus' goin' pas', that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know anybody here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A head sticks out of the tent. Until he speaks, Tom does not recognize Casy.</context>
      <utterance>No. Jus' goin' pas', I tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Casy! What you doin' here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if it ain't Tom Joad. How ya, boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought you was in jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSIDE THE TENT, three other men sit on the ground as Casy brings Tom in. One's name is Frank.</context>
      <utterance>No, I done my time an' got out. Come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This the fella you been talkin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is him. What you doin' here, Tommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Workin'. Pickin' peaches. But I seen a bunch a fellas yellin' when we come in, so I come out to see what's goin' on. What's it all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This here's a strike.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, fi' cents a box ain't much, but a fella can eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fi' cents! They pain' you fi' cents?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. We made a buck since midday.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lookie, Tom. We come to work here. They tell us it's gonna be fi' cents. But they was a whole lot of us, so the man says two an' a half cents. Well, a fella can't even eat on that, an' if he got kids...  So we says we won't take it. So they druv us off. Now they're payin' you five--but when they bust this strike ya think they'll pay five?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. Payin' five now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't expeck we can las' much longer-- some a the folks ain't et for two days. You goin' back tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I aim to.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well--tell the folks inside how it is, Tom. Tell 'em they're starvin' us and stabbin' theirself in the back. An' as sure as God made little apples it's goin' back to two an' a half jus' as soon as they clear us out.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They listen. Then:</context>
      <utterance>You hear sump'n?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell 'em. But I don't know how. Never seen so many guys with guns. Wouldn't even let us talk today.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try an' tell 'em, Tom. They'll get two an' a half, jus' the minute we're gone. An' you know what that is? That's one ton a peaches picked an' carried for a dollar. That way you can't even buy food enough to keep you alive! Tell 'em to come out with us, Tom! Them peaches is ripe . Two days out an' they'll pay all of us five!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They won't. They're a-gettin' five an' they don't care about nothin' else.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But jus' the minute they ain't strike- breakin' they won't get no five!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An' the nex' thing you know you'll be out, because they got it all figgered down to a T--until the harvest is in you're a migrant worker--afterwards, just a bum.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five they're a-gettin' now, an' that's all they're int'rested in. I know exackly what Pa'd say. He'd jus' say it wasn't none a his business.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess that's right. Have to take a beatin' before he'll know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We was outa food. Tonight we had meat. Not much, but we had it. Think Pa's gonna give up his meat on account a other fellas? An' Rosasharn needs milk. Think Ma's gonna starve that baby jus' cause a bunch a fellas is yellin' outside a gate?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got to learn, like I'm a-learnin'. Don't know it right yet myself, but I'm tryin' to fin' out. That's why I can't ever be a preacher again. Preacher got to know .  I don't. I got to ask .</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't tell. Seems like I hear sump'n, an' then I listen an' they ain't nothin' to hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(He exits)</context>
      <utterance>'Tain't outa the question, y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank's head sticks in the door. His voice is an excited whisper.</context>
      <utterance>All of us a little itchy. Cops been tellin' us how they gonna beat us up an' run us outa the country. Not them reg'lar deppities, but them tin- star fellas they got for guards.  They figger I'm the leader because I talk so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quickly Casy turns the light down and out. He gropes for the door, followed by Tom and the other man.</context>
      <utterance>Turn out that light an' come outside. They's sump'n here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="63">
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are night sounds but little else to be distinguished.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno. Listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't tell if you hear it or not. You hear it, Tom?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear it. I think they's some guys comin' this way, lots of 'em. We better get outa here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Halted, uncertain, they stand as three men with stars on their coats and pickhandles in their hands slide down the EMBANKMENT. Two of them hold lighted flashlights.</context>
      <utterance>There they are! Stand where you are!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are faint responses from a distance. CASY AND TOM are alone. The others have fled. The deputies approach, their lights on Casy and Tom.</context>
      <utterance>That's him! That one in the middle, the skinny one! Chuck! Alec! Here they are! We got 'em!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, you fellas. You don't know what you're doin'. You're helpin' to stave kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swings the pickhandle. Casy dodges but the stick cracks his skull. He falls face down out of the light. The deputies watch for a moment but Casy doesn't stir.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, you red--</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like to me you killed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TOM, seen close, is breathing hard, his eyes glistening.</context>
      <utterance>Turn him over. Put the light on him. Bending over, their bodies hide Casy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the deputies straighten up, Tom steps forward, grabs the pickhandle from the man who felled Casy, and swings. The blow strikes the deputy's arm, sending his flashlight flying, and the scene is in semi-darkness as Tom swings again. There is a grunt and a groan as the deputy goes down. Then all is confusion. Backing away, swinging the pickhandle, Tom bolts, splashes a few yards through the stream, turns and gains a better start by throwing the pickhandle at his pursuers. They duck, and Tom disappears into the night. The other men rush through the scene in pursuit. THE SECOND DEPUTY is seen bending over the body of the man Tom laid out.</context>
      <utterance>Serves him right, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's that flash?</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The light flashes on the man's face.</context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, he's good and dead! You see that fella that done it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TOM is seen crashing through the bushes, his face bloody. The scene fades out. THE EXTERIOR OF HOUSE 63 fades in. It is day. Ma comes down the street with a bundle under her arm and enters the house. INSIDE HOUSE 63, Rosasharn sits by the window as Ma enters.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't sure--but I caught him one across the face, and believe me, I give him a trade-mark he ain't gonna be able to shake off easy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody ask anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No'm.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rosasharn takes her post at the door as Ma kneels on the floor beside Tom, puts down the rag bundle, and gets a basin. Tom, who is under a quilt, is with his back alone visible. She speaks softly, guardedly, as she bathes his face.</context>
      <utterance>Stand by the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it feel, Tommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Busted my cheek but I can still see. What'd you hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you done it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I kinda thought so. Felt like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Folks ain't talkin' about much else. They say they got posses out. Talkin' about a lynchin'--when they catch the fella.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They killed Casy first.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ain't the way they're tellin' it. They're sayin' you done it fust.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They know what--this fella looks like?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They know he got hit in the face.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Ma. But--I didn't know what I was doin', no more'n when you take a breath. I didn't even know I was gonna do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's awright, Tommy. I wisht you didn't do it, but you done what you had to do. I can't read no fault in you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna go away tonight. I can't go puttin' this on you folks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom! They's a whole lot I don't understan', but goin' away ain't gonna ease us.  They was the time when we was on the lan'. They was a bound'ry to us then. Ol' folks died off, an' little fellas come, an' we was always one thing-- we was the fambly--kinda whole an' clear. But now we ain't clear no more. They ain't nothin' keeps us clear. Al--he's a-hankerin' an' a- jibbitin' to go off on his own. An' Uncle John is just a-draggin' along. Pa's lost his place--he ain't the head no more. We're crackin' up, Tom. They ain't no fambly now. Rosasharn--  --she gonna have her baby, but it ain't gonna have no fambly. I been tryin' to keep her goin' but--Winfiel'-- what's he gonna be, this-a-way? Growin' up wild, an' Ruthie, too-- like animals. Got nothin' to trus'. Don't go Tom. Stay an' help. Help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Ma. I shouldn't, though. I know I shouldn't. But okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom puts his head under the quilt. Ma turns, faces the door, her body protectively between Tom and whatever threatens.</context>
      <utterance>Here come a lot of people.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKKEEPER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGRANT'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OUTSIDE HOUSE 63, the bookkeeper has encountered the newcomers.</context>
      <utterance>Ten of us. Whatcha payin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>House 25. Number's on the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, mister. Whatcha payin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two and a half cents.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two an' a half! Say, mister, a man can't make his dinner on that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it or leave it. There's 200 men coming from the South that'll be glad to get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But--but how we gonna eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOOKKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I didn't set the price. I'm just working here. If you want it, take it. If you don't, turn right around and beat it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIGRANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way is House 25?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That Casy. He might a been a preacher, but--he seen a lot a things clear. He was like a lantern--he helped mw see things too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At night, the TRUCK is backed up to the door of House 63; it is already loaded. Ma is speaking in a low voice to Tom, who is peering out from under a mattress in the truck.</context>
      <utterance>Comes night we'll get outa here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's jus' till we get some distance. Then you can come out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd hate to get trapped in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom disappears. Ma turns, her back to the truck. The guard plays his flashlight on the Joads, who stand watching him ominously.</context>
      <utterance>What's goin' on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're goin' out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got a job offered--good job.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Let's have a look at you.  Wasn't there another fella with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean that hitch-hiker? Little short fella with a pale face?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess that's what he looked like.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just picked him up on the way in. He went away this mornin' when the rate dropped.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he look like again?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Short fella. Pale face.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was he bruised up this mornin'? About the face?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't see nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quickly, Al is in the driver's seat, with Ma and Pa beside him. The truck rattles into motion and moves down the street. AT THE GATES TO THE RANCH another guard flashes a light as Al stops the car.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goin' out for good?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Goin' north. Got a job.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the gate and the truck goes through. It turns from the gravel road onto the paved highway.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al shows his pleased pride in her quiet approval.</context>
      <utterance>You done good, Al. Just good.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know where we're a-goin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma... you know, if Connie was here I wouldn't min' any a this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, honey, an' just as soon as we get settled Al's gonna set out an' look for him. How 'bout gas, Tommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then it is night, and the TRUCK is still making distance. On a COUNTRY ROAD, in grey dawn, with a deafening clank under the hood, the Joad truck pulls to a stop off the side of the road. Al is driving. Asleep in Tom's arm in the front seat, Ma stirs awake as Al turns off the ignition and gets out. He lifts the hood.</context>
      <utterance>Full up. Uncle John come through with five bucks he been hol'in' out on us since we lef' home. The TRUCK keeps moving along.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's hotter'n a heifer.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out the pieces. Tom gets out and takes off the radiator cap. There is a geyser of steam. In the back of the truck the others stand looking on, sleepy-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>Fan-belt's shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any gas?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gallon or two?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, looks like we done it this time awright!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All look. Tom climbs on the running board the better to see.</context>
      <utterance>Tommy.  Some smoke up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like about a mile. Reckon she'll make it?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She got to make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Al starts the truck, the scene dissolves to a weather- beaten wooden sign: "PERMANENT CAMP NO. 9" "DEPT. OF</context>
      <utterance>Don't know--but it's better'n this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the FRONT SEAT Al leans angrily out of the driver's window. Tom is keeping his face away from the caretaker's line of vision.</context>
      <utterance>You hit 'er too fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the idea of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al starts climbing out. Pa jumps down from the truck.</context>
      <utterance>Well, a lot a kids play in here. You tell folks to go slow and they liable to forget. But let 'em hit that hump once and they don't forget!</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got any room here for us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're lucky. Fellow just moved out half-hour ago.  Down that line and turn to the left. You'll see it. You'll be in No. 4 Sanitary Unit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toilet and showers and washtubs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean you got washtubs? An' runnin' water?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am.  Camp committee'll call on you in the morning and get you fixed.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cops?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Ma, Pa, and Al look at each other in almost incredulous bewilderment, Tom climbs out of the truck.</context>
      <utterance>No. No cops. Folks here elect their own cops.  The ladies' committee'll call on you, ma'am, about the kids and the sanitary unit and who takes care of 'em.  Come inside and sign up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take 'er on down, Al. I'll sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gonna stay, ain't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSIDE THE SHACK, Tom enters warily, alert for any indication that either his name or his scar may have been learned and telegraphed here. But the caretaker obviously attaches no significance to either. The shack is bare but for a cot, a table, a chair, and an electric light. The caretaker is seated at the table, pen in hand, a soiled ledger open, when Tom enters.</context>
      <utterance>You're tootin' we're gonna stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean to be nosy, y'understand. I just got to have certain information. What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joad. Tom Joad.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE JOAD TRUCK is seen in front of its camp site as the Joads descend.</context>
      <utterance>How many of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout it, Uncle John? Gotta pitch this tent.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a-comin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't look so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't so good, but--I'm a-comin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="73">
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Camp site costs a dollar a week, but you can work it out, carrying garbage, keeping the camp clean--stuff like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll work it out. What's this committee you talkin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got five sanitary units. Each one elects a central committee man. They make the laws, an' what they say goes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you aimin' to tell me that the fellas that run this camp is jus' fellas--campin' here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the way it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An' you say no cops?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No cop can come in here without a warrant.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't hardly believe it. Camp I was in once, they burned it out--the deputies an' some of them poolroom fellas.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't get in here. Sometimes the boys patrol the fences, especially dance nights.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got dances too?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got the best dances in the county every Saturday night.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, who runs this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Government.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why ain't they more like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You find out, I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything like work aroun' here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't promise you that, but there'll be a licensed agent here tomorrow mornin', if you want to talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma's shore gonna like it here. She ain't been treated decent for a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That cut you got?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crate fell on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better take care of it. Store manager'll give you some stuff for it in the morning. Goodnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he exits we see the GOVERNMENT CAMP, with Tom coming out of the shack, amazement still on his face. As he walks slowly down the main camp street we share the revelation of the place to him. It is nearly daylight. Roosters crow in the distance. The street is neat and orderly in a military way, its cleanliness in sharp contrast to anything he has known before. Inside the tents people are stirring. In front of one tent a woman is cooking breakfast. A baby is in her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good mornin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he walks on, Tom draws a breath of exultation. As he moves on, looking around, we see the EXTERIOR OF SANITARY UNIT NO. 4, a cheap frame building the purpose of which is pretty obvious. Ruthie, warily alert lest she be caught, is peering in the door. She looks a long time and then she runs out of the scene. WINFIELD is seen asleep in a quilt on the ground when Ruthie enters and rousts him out.</context>
      <utterance>Mornin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Git up. I got sump'n to show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatsa matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Ain't nobody gonna say anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He follows her into the unit, big-eyed with excitement and apprehension. There is a silence. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Won't they ketch us?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another silence. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Them's where you wash your han's.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINFIELD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's these?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another silence. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Well, I reckon you stan' in them little rooms--an' water come down outa that there little jigger up there--take a bath!</utterance>
   <speaker>WINFIELD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jes' like in the catalogues, ain't they!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seen 'em b'fore you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINFIELD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you done it! You busted it!</utterance>
   <speaker>WINFIELD'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terrified, Winfield comes dashing out of the unit but Ruthie grabs him just outside the door. Beginning to cry, he struggles to get away.</context>
      <utterance>I never--</utterance>
   <speaker>WINFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lemme go! I didn't go to do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep qui'te, will ya! Shet your mouth!</utterance>
   <speaker>WINFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never knowed it! All I done was pull that string!</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lissen. You done busted it. You hear?  But lissen here. I won't tell nobody, y'understan'?</utterance>
   <speaker>WINFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUTHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>--if you won't tell what I done! He nods quickly. Then Ruthie begins to walk away with what she fancies is an innocent, nonchalant stroll, yawning casually. Sniffling a little, Winfield mimics her, a very innocent walk and yawn indeed. The scene dissolves to a DITCH. Alongside the ditch are some lengths of concrete pipe. Tom and the two Wallaces are in the ditch, Tom and Tim picking, Wilkie shoveling.</context>
      <utterance>I won't--</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If this don't feel good!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait'll about 'leven o'clock, see how good she feels then!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems like a nice frien'ly fella to work for, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lotta these little farmers mighty nice fellas. Trouble is they're little, they ain't got much say-so.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Thomas, the farmer, a stock man wearing a paper sun helmet, enters. His face is worried as he squats down beside the ditch. What he has come to say has taken some effort and he is still uncertain and annoyed. The men stop work.</context>
      <utterance>Shore looks like my lucky day, anyway. Gettin' some work at las'.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lissen here. Maybe I'm talkin' myself outa my farm, but I like you fellas, so I'm gonna tell you. You live in that gov'ment camp, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you have dances every Saturday night?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We sure do.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, look out next Saturday night.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you mean? I belong to the central committee. I got to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you ever tell I told.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the association don't like the government camps. Can't get a deputy in there. Can't arrest a man without a warrant. But if there was a big fight, and maybe shooting--a bunch of deputies could go in and clean out the camp.  Like last night. Lissen. "Citizens, angered at red agitators, burn another squatters' camp, warn agitators to get out of the county."</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen. What is these reds? Ever'time you turn aroun' somebody sayin' somebody else's a red. What is these reds, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I tell you. They was a fella up the country named King--got about 30,000 acres an' a cannery an' a winery--an' he's all a time talkin' about reds. Drivin' the country to ruin, he says. Got to git rid of 'em, he says. Well, they was a young fella jus' come out an' he was listenin one day. He kinda scratched his head an' he says, "Mr. King, what is these reds you all a time talkin' about?" Well, sir, Mr. King says, "Young man, a red is any fella that wants thirty cents a hour when I'm payin' twenty-five."</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't talkin' about that one way or the other. All I'm saying is that there's going to be a fight in the camp Saturday night. And there's going to be deputies ready to go in.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why? Those fellas ain't botherin' nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you why. Those folks in to being treated like humans. Suppose the Government closes its camps. Suppose too many people pass through 'em. Well, when those people go back to the squatters' camps they'll be hard to handle.  Go on back to work now. Maybe I've talked myself into trouble, but you're folks like us, and I like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMITTEE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ev'nin', ma'am. Who'd you say invited you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUESTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister an' Mizz Clark, they ast us.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMITTEE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is an air of eager anticipation, of gay celebration, and everyone is in his or her best--the men in clean washed overalls, clean shirts, some with ties, their hair damp and slicked down, the women in their nicest. Through the gate, inside the camp, can be seen the outdoor dance floor, brightly lighted, with the camp musicians already tuning up, and around the dance floor scores of wide-eyed children. INSIDE THE GATE TO THE CAMP, we see Wilkie and a dark- complexioned man named Jule standing among a group inside watching the arrivals. They watch sharply, eyeing everyone, listening to every credential. As his employer, Thomas, comes through the gate with his wife, Wilkie grins and greets him with a handshake.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, ma'am. Come right in, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hidy, Mr. Thomas. Hidy, Mizz Thomas.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You watching out, ain't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you worry. Ain't gonna be no trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the DANCE FLOOR, and after three pats of the foot, to get the tempo, the home talent dance orchestra swings into music. INSIDE THE JOAD TENT, Rosasharn dressed in her nicest, sits gripping her hands together, the music seeming to bring her to the verge of tears.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma...  Ma, I--I can't go to the dance. I jus' can't Ma. I can't hardly stan' it, with Connie not here--an' me this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, honey, it makes folks happy to see a girl that way--makes folks sort of giggly an' happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You an' me's goin' together--jus' you an' me. We're a-goin' to that dance an' we're a-goin' to jus' set an' watch. If anybody says to come dance--why I'll say you're poorly. But you an' me, we're gonna hear the music an' see the fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSASHARN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An' you won't let nobody touch me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiling mysteriously, Ma fishes in a pocket in her dress and brings out the envelope of her treasures. From it she produces the earrings and holds them up in front of Rosasharn's wide eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No--an' look what I got for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="98">
   <speaker>WILKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They tell me you're half Injun. You look all Injun to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three men from the touring car are at the gate. Wilkie and Jule watch them.</context>
      <utterance>No, jes' half. Wisht I was full- blooded. Gov'ment'd be lookin' out for me an' I'd be ridin' around in a Buick eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMITTEE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who give you the invitation?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fella named Jackson--Buck Jackson.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMITTEE MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three men stroll past Wilkie and Jule, whose eyes follow them.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Them's our fellas.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the DANCE FLOOR. The musicians are at it and the fiddler is calling turns.</context>
      <utterance>Jes' got a feelin'. They're kinda scared too. Follow 'em an' get a holt of Jackson. See if he knows 'em. I'll stay here. Wilkie moves after them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIDDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well in front, among the older folks and children who surround the floor, are Ma and Rosasharn, clinging close. A young man stops in front of them.</context>
      <utterance>Swing your ladies an' a dol ce do. Join han's roun' an' away we go! Swing to the right an' a swing to the lef'. Break, now break--back to back!</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three men stroll into sight and stand watching the dancing. One glances at Ma and Rosasharn but does not speak. Ma has smiled back at him. WILKIE AND JACKSON are seen; removed somewhat from the dance floor they are peering in the direction of the three men.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you wouldn't think it, but your pa was as nice a dancer as I ever seen, when he was young.  Kinda makes me think a ol' times.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seen 'em before. Worked at Gregorio's with 'em. But I never ast 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We find ourselves INSIDE TIM WALLACE'S TENT. The five members of the central committee, Tim Wallace, chairman, look grave as a 15-year-old boy reports.</context>
      <utterance>Awright. Keep your eye on 'em. Jus' keep 'em in sight, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seen 'em, Mr. Wallace. A car with six men parked down by the euc'lyptus tree an' one with three men on the main road. They got guns, too. I seen 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Willie. You done good.  Well, it looks like the fat's in the far this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What them deppities want to hurt the camp for? How come they can't leave us be?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What we oughta do, we oughta git us some pickhandles an'--</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! That's what they want. No sir. If they can git a fight goin', then they can run in the cops an' say we ain't orderly--</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a grim pause at this news. Tim's eyes go hard.</context>
      <utterance>They're here. We got 'em spotted.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you got ever'thing ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't gonna be no trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't to hurt them fellas.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to worry. We got ever'thing arranged. Maybe nobody'll even see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just don't use no stick nor no knife, no piece a arn. An' if you got to sock 'em, sock 'em where they won't bleed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awright. An' if she gets outa han', I'll be in the right han' corner, this side the dance floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilkie makes a mocking military salute as he and Tom exit. The committee men look worriedly after them.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't gonna get outa han'.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mighty sure a themselves, looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>TIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In front of the JOAD TENT, dressed to kill, is Al, ready for the festivities. He wears a tight-fitting wool suit, a tie on his shirt, yellow shoes, and his hair is damp and slicked down. He rubs his hands together in anticipation as he strolls in the direction of the dance floor. At ANOTHER TENT, a blonde girl sits on a box as Al enters. Casually he throws open his coat, revealing a vivid striped shirt. This is designed to stun his quarry.</context>
      <utterance>All I hope, I hope they don't kill nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gonna dance tonight?  I can waltz.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nothin'--anybody can waltz.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not like me! A fat woman thrusts her head out of the tent.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shrugging, Al winks at the girl and moves on, stepping and moving his shoulders and snapping his fingers in time to the music, a very gay fellow indeed. The blonde girl's eyes follow him. Then she turns and glances cautiously toward the tent. ON THE DANCE FLOOR, we see Ma and Rosasharn as Tom enters and stands between them. This is during a pause between dances and only a few couples stand on the floor waiting for the music to begin again. We also see the three men very casually looking around--but no more casual looking than Wilkie, standing just behind them, idly whistling.</context>
      <utterance>You git right along! This here girl's spoke for. She's gonna be married, an' her man's a-comin' for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's gettin' prettier, Ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The music starts again, once more the dancers move onto the dance floor. The three men exchange a glance and step casually to the edge of the dancing space, one in the lead. They survey the scene, but for the moment make no further move. The atmosphere is tense.</context>
      <utterance>Girl with a baby always gets prettier.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AL, taking the blonde girl's hand, steps onto the dance floor. Encircling her waist, they begin to dance. They are a smooth, rhythmic couple who move as one being.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Ma.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you said anybody can waltz... How'm I doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't hold me so tight.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, I ain't hardly touchin' you!</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're ticklin' me!</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That comes from not holdin' you tight enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLONDE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this moment the leader of the three men (the other two directly behind him) enters the scene.</context>
      <utterance>Now I can't breathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll dance with this girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind the three men a solid wall of migrants are closing in quietly, Tom and Wilkie in the middle.</context>
      <utterance>You an' who else?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His fist goes back, his left hand reaches for Al's collar. At the same instant Tom grabs him, Wilkie claps his hand over the leader's mouth, at least fifteen other men have similarly collard the other two invaders, and they are all lifted bodily. There is not a sound as the three men, held in iron grips, are whisked from the dance floor and into the crowd. Two touring cars have stopped in front of the closed GATE and the deputies have drawn guns.</context>
      <utterance>Don't gimme no argament--  --you little--</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open up! We hear you got a riot.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Riot? I don't see no riot. Who're you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deputy sheriffs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a warrant?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't need a warrant if it's a riot.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the deputies, puzzled and uncertain, look toward the DANCE FLOOR, we see the music, the dancing, the gaiety continuing as if nothing had happened. WITHIN THE JOAD TENT at night, several hours later: the tent is black, Tom strikes a match. From a piece of wood on the ground or floor he selects one from several cigarette butts and lights it. While he is doing so, he lifts his head suddenly, and listens. In the CAMP STREET we catch sight of legs walking, the ground lighted from a flashlight. Two pairs of the legs wear state policemen's leather leggings. The third pair are the caretaker's. They stop behind a car. The flashlight plays on the license plate. One of the state cops leans down to copy the license number in a booklet. Then they move on. TOM has lifted the edge of the tent a trifle, enough to see out by flattening his head on the floor. The LEGS are now seen at the Joad jalopy. The light is on the license plate. The cop leans over and copies the number. They move on. TOM, lowering the edge of the tent, sits up. Quietly he pushes aside the piece of carpet that covers him. He is wearing his clothes. We see the policeman's CAR at the caretaker's hut. The two policemen get into the car.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't know what you gonna do about it, because I don't hear no riot an' I don't see no riot, an' what's more I don't believe they is no riot.  Look for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got no right to arrest anybody without a warrant, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car drives off, leaving the caretaker looking somberly after it. WITHIN THE JOAD TENT, his cap on, fully dressed for travel, Tom is tieing the ends of the carpet into a shoulder bundle. Rising, he slings it across his shoulder. As he tiptoes toward the door:</context>
      <utterance>We'll have a warrant--just as soon as we check with headquarters.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment he looks into the darkness in her direction.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't you gonna tell me goodbye, Tommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has risen, pulling the quilt around her. He takes her by the hand.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't know, Ma. I didn't know if I ought.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They go out. Tom leads Ma around BEHIND THE TENT, to a SECTION OF WIRE FENCE. There is a bench there. Tom leads Ma to it and sits her down. He sits beside her.</context>
      <utterance>Come outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They was some cops here, Ma. They was takin' down the license numbers. It looks like somebody knows sump'n.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It had to come, I reckon, soon or later.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to stay. I'd like to be with ya--  --an' see your face when you an' Pa get settled in a nice little place. I sure wish I could see you then. But--  --I guess I won't never be able to do that. Not now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could hide you, Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you would, Ma. But I ain't gonna let you. You hide somebody that's kilt a man an'... an' you'd be in trouble too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awright, Tommy. What you figger you gonna do?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I been thinkin' about, Ma? About Casy. About what he said, what he done, an' about how he died. An' I remember all of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a good man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been thinkin' about us, too--about our people livin' like pigs, an' good rich lan' layin' fallow, or maybe one fella with a million acres, while a hundred thousan' farmers is starvin'. An' I been wonderin' if all our folks got together an' yelled--</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy, they'll drive you, an' cut you down like they done to Casy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They gonna drive me anyways. Soon or later they'll get me, for one thing if not another. Until then...</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't aim to kill nobody, Tom!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Ma. Not that. That ain't it. But long as I'm a outlaw, anyways, maybe I can do sump'n. Maybe I can jus' fin' out sump'n. Jus' scrounge aroun' an' try to fin' out what it is that's wrong, an then see if they ain't sump'n could be done about it.  But I ain't thought it out clear, Ma. I can't. I don't know enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'm I gonna know 'bout you? They might kill you an' I wouldn't know. They might hurt you. How'm I gonna know?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, maybe it's like Casy says, a fella ain't got a soul of his own, but on'y a piece of a big soul--the one big soul that belongs to ever'body-- an' then...</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what, Tom?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it don't matter. Then I'll be all aroun' in the dark. I'll be ever'where--wherever you look. Wherever there's a fight so hungry people can eat, I'll be there. Wherever there's a cop beatin' up a guy, I'll be there. I'll be in the way guys yell when they're mad--an' I'll be in the way kids laugh when they're hungry an' they know supper's ready. An' when our people eat the stuff they raise, an' live in the houses they build, why, I'll be there too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understan' it, Tom.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me neither.  It's jus' stuff I been thinkin' about. Gimme you han', Ma. Good-by.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good-by, Tom. Later--when it's blowed over--you'll come back? You'll try to fin' us?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Good-by.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks away. She stands looking after him. He's leaving her forever--she knows it. She lifts her hand and waves. She tries to smile. TOM turns, waves, smiles. His lips form the words: "Good-by, Ma." Then he strides away into the darkness. The scene fades out. The JOAD TRUCK fades in. It stands loaded in front on the Joad tent while Al, Pa, Uncle John, Ma, and the little fellas pile in the last article in a fury of excitement. Beyond, in the background, another jalopy is being prepared for travel with the same feverish haste. It is day.</context>
      <utterance>Good-by, Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL, PA, JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get them buckets on! Somebody tie down the mattress! You little fellas keep outa the way!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What y'all hurryin' so for? Tell me they got twenny days work.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Other jalopies in the background are being readied for leaving-- an excited, hopeful exodus on a new report of work.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir, an' we aim to git in all twenny of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready, Ma?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get Rosasharn.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make her easy, John. Watch her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll be awright.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready, Pa?</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The truck wabbles into motion. Al races the engine. It nearly crashes another wheezing jalopy at the corner. When it turns the corner we see the GATE, and a line of loaded jalopies that ride out to the highway. The caretaker waves and the migrants wave back.</context>
      <utterance>Let 'er go, Gallagher!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARETAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck to you! Good luck, ever'body!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE JOADS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Joad truck turns onto the highway. In the FRONT SEAT Al is driving, Ma in the middle, Pa on the outside.</context>
      <utterance>Good-by, Mr. Conway! Much oblige to you for ever'thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty days work, oh boy!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be glad to get my han' on some cotton. That's the kin' a pickin' I understan'.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. Maybe twenny days work, maybe no days work. We ain't got it till we get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatsa matter, Ma? Gettin' scared?</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Ain't ever gonna be scared no more.  I was, though. For a while I thought we was beat-- good an' beat. Looked like we didn't have nothin' in the worl' but enemies--wasn't no body frien'ly anymore. It made me feel bad an' scared too--like we was lost... an' nobody cared.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch me pass that Chevvy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ma places her hand on one of Pa's and pats it.</context>
      <utterance>You the one that keeps us goin', Ma. I ain't no good any more, an' I know it. Seems like I spen' all my time these days a-thinkin' how it use'ta be--thinkin' of home--an' I ain't never gonna see it no more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Woman can change better'n a man. Man lives in jerks--baby born, or somebody dies, that's a jerk--gets a farm, or loses one, an' that's a jerk. With a woman it's all one flow, like a stream, little eddies, little waterfalls, but the river it goes right on. Woman looks at it like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that ol' coffeepot steam!</utterance>
   <speaker>PA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe, but we shore takin' a beatin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
