<movie id="202" title="Family Man The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate hands Jack a new copy of Vonnegut’s “Cat’s Cradle.”</context>
      <utterance>I got you a few necessities...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack accepts the book but he’s unable to take his eyes off Kate. She hands him a cassette.</context>
      <utterance>Your copy was a mess...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every one of these songs will remind you of me in a slightly different way...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All in one tape?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate leans over and kisses him passionately on the lips.</context>
      <utterance>I also put side two of London Calling on there...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>He looks at her, his eyes welling up. He pulls her close, kissing her deeply. Then...</context>
      <utterance>That was not officially the goodbye kiss. It was just an interim kiss...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jack takes Kate’s hand, getting up, turning sadly to the gate.</context>
      <utterance>This will be the final boarding call for Pan Am flight 4 to London, Heathrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack pulls out a BLUE PAN AM TICKET ENVELOPE. Kate nods. They embrace and kiss again. As they separate.</context>
      <utterance>You have your ticket?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack takes one lastlook at her, then heads for the gate. Kate stands there, watching him go. Then... ...a moment of intuition. Something isn’t right. She looks at Jack, about to disappear into the jetway, trying to decide...</context>
      <utterance>I’m not even gonna say it, Kate. Maybe it’ll be like I never left...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack turns. Kate approaches him.</context>
      <utterance>Wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a bad feeling about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About the plane? What do you think it’s gonna crash? Don’t say that...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at the gate...the last few passengers are boarding, then back into Jack’s eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I know we’ve talked about this a thousand times and we both agree that going to London is the right thing to do. But in my heart... this feels wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don’t go, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean don’t go at all? What about my internship?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe me I know what an incredible opportunity this is for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For us, Kate.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, for us. But...I’m afraid that if you get on that plane...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate looks at him, pleading with her eyes, but she can’t say...</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go. I’m sorry, you should just go...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you’re right. What are we doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes narrow as he measures her determination...</context>
      <utterance>We're being responsible. Go. Get on the plane.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the hell outta my sight. You bother me. A laugh from Jack. Kate gives him a calm smile and a nod - it's not entirely convincing but it's enough for Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her in his arms one last time and hugs her tight. Jack looks toward the gate, the line disappearing...Kate grasps his shirt tightly.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'm going...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't seem to let go of you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sober look in Jack's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You hear me complaining about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Kate nods, then, with resolve...</context>
      <utterance>Look, we're at the airport and no one ever thinks clearly at the airport so we should just trust the decision we already made. You've been accepted to one of the best law schools in the country, I've got this internship at Barclay's Bank. We have a great plan, honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack is jolted by her words.</context>
      <utterance>You want to do something great, Jack? Let's flush the plan...start our lives right now, today...I don't know what that life's gonna look like but I do know it has both of us in it. And I choose us...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Her words sink in...A long moment of decision...He looks toward the gate, only one person left in line...back to Kate...imploring him with her eyes. Finally...He kisses her deeply on the lips...</context>
      <utterance>The plan doesn't make us great, Jack. What we have together, that's what makes us great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...a smile from Kate...relief...then...</context>
      <utterance>I love you, Kate...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack gives her one final kiss then walks pensively to the gate, handing the attendant his ticket, not able to look back. Kate watches him go, tears streaming down her face, as the gate door closes behind him. She waits, almost willing it to open again...waiting...waiting...but it doesn't...</context>
      <utterance>...and a year in London's not gonna change that. A hundred years couldn't change that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>4	INT. JACK'S BEDROOM - CONTINUOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Close in on the bed where JACK CAMPBELL, now 35, sans mustache and long hair, opens his eyes. A FLASH of bright morning light from the window. Jack shields his eyes, turning his head toward the bathroom where he sees... A WOMAN'S BACK...draped in a towel...an incredible back, neither flabby nor overly toned, beautifully curved...Jack focuses on it a moment. As the woman turns to him... PAULA. Beautiful, late 20s, a toothbrush in her mouth...</context>
      <utterance>...impeccably decorated and obsessively neat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A playful smile from Paula.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you don't mind. There were like ten new ones in the cabinet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paula smiles, moves over to a chair and grabs a little black dress hanging neatly over it.</context>
      <utterance>It's not what you think. I took Mentadent public...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you really mean what you said about Tuscany?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last night was great...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are an amazing lover. You should be giving motivational seminars.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack grabs his Frank Mueller watch from the night stand, puts it on his wrist. He looks at Paula as she slips the dress on.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. You're not bad yourself...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like that, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>Tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Christmas Eve, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paula laughs.</context>
      <utterance>So we'll get egg nog.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go to my parents' house out in Jersey. Would you like to come?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jersey? You know what the traffic's gonna be like?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paula approaches Jack, leaning over him, her long hair dangling on his chest.</context>
      <utterance>I'm taking the train...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you have anywhere to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stays there, confident, sexy, waiting for an answer...</context>
      <utterance>I've got plenty of places to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I can try and sneak away some time tomorrow morning...  Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's something you feel strongly about.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paula walks to the door, then turns back to Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was nice meeting you, Jack...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Peterson.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PETERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Jack. You don’t have to stop singing on my account...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It’s because I’m shy, Betty. So, when are you going to leave that old corpse Mr. Peterson and run away with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PETERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doors open to the lobby. Mrs. Peterson walks out ahead.</context>
      <utterance>You know you could never satisfy me the way he does...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TONY THE DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas, Mr. Campbell.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How’d you do this year, Tony?</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY THE DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About four grand. And a bottle of twenty five year old scotch from Mrs. Johnson in 9D. I’m putting it all in commercial paper like you said.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack exits the building...</context>
      <utterance>Just until the Deutsche Mark turns...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack notices Alan Mintz playing with the cherub.</context>
      <utterance>...if MedTech's shares sink any lower than...  ...forty three, we're in trouble with the stock valuation. So for god's sake watch what you say to your institutional customers...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Alan looks up.</context>
      <utterance>...we still have almost a full day of trading before zero hour and I don't want any trouble...  ...penny for your thoughts, Alan...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Jack. I told Dee and the kids I'd be home by dinner. You know, it being Christmas Eve and all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that tonight? A LAUGH from the group. Jack approaches Alan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I like being here on Christmas Eve, Alan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another LAUGH. Even Jack lets out a good-natured chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Maybe...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A chuckle from the group...the esprit de corps seems to energize Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, maybe I do have a touch of tunnel vision this holiday season. But in two days we're going to announce one of the largest mergers in U.S. corporate history. Thirty billion dollars...  When this kind of deal turns up you get on and you ride it `till it's over. You don't ask it for a vacation...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Enthusiastic nods and words of agreement from the suits around the table...</context>
      <utterance>December 26th. After that there'll be so much money floating around here it'll be like Christmas every day...  December 26th, people. If you'd like to celebrate that day, you all have my blessing...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack approaches Alan.</context>
      <utterance>You're right, Jack. Sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to be sorry, Alan, I want you to be excited. I want my gift to be the first one you open this year. You know why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MURMUR of excitement in the room, even Alan cracks a smile. Jack puts a hand on Alan's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Because my gift comes with ten zeroes at the end...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good man...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack pops a peppermint Lifesaver in his mouth as Adelle hands him his messages.</context>
      <utterance>Only eight thirty? What's the matter, had some last minute shopping to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You too? This holiday's about giving, Adelle. And I'm giving everything I've got to this deal, so in a way, I'm more Christmassy than anyone...  Lifesaver?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They approach an office, the words, "Jack Campbell - President" stenciled on the glass...</context>
      <utterance>You're a ray of sunshine, Jack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, and Oxxford called...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets to the last message, sees the name on it, and reels back.</context>
      <utterance>Ooh, my suits are ready...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kate Reynolds...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stares at the message like he's looking at a ghost.</context>
      <utterance>Her assistant said you could call her at home after eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her assistant?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah Jack, her assistant...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kate Reynolds was my girlfriend in college. I almost married her...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You? Married?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hutton...</context>
      <utterance>Almost married. And almost a junior broker at E.F.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't want me to go to London. We're standing at the airport saying goodbye and she asks me to stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you left her? Just like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, no. I thought about it for practically the entire flight...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop Jack, I'm getting all weepy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took the road less traveled, Adelle.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack pauses, focused on the message, his mind drifting back... Adelle begins dialing the number. Finally, Jack reaches out and hangs up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>And look where it's led you...  I'm gonna get her on the phone...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?! You almost married this woman. Aren't you even curious what she wants?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle rolls her eyes at him.</context>
      <utterance>She's probably just having a fit of nostalgia. You know, lonely Christmas Eve, call the one that got away, that kind of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack looks up as PETER LASSITER, 60s, founder and chairman of P.K. Lassiter and Associates, saunters into the room.</context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, it's ancient history...</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lassiter heads to the bar like he's done it a million times.</context>
      <utterance>Eight forty-five on Christmas Eve and Jack Campbell is still at his desk. There's a Hallmark moment for you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter. I don't see you rushing home to trim the tree.</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's because I'm a heartless bastard who only cares about money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lassiter drops down in a soft leather chair opposite Jack.</context>
      <utterance>And God love you for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just got a call from Terry Haight. Bob Thomas is nervous...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'll happen when you're about to spend thirty billion dollars on some aspirin...</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone's gonna have to nurse him through this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you staring at my breasts, Peter?</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you, tiger..</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack pauses for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Aspen.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adelle rolls her eyes at him...</context>
      <utterance>Call Aunt Irma. Tell her I won't be able to make it tomorrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack glances at Adelle, then looks back at Lassiter.</context>
      <utterance>You're a credit to capitalism, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Peter, lemme ask you a question. An old girlfriend calls you out of the blue on Christmas Eve...</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You suddenly having trouble getting dates?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not by a long shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack shoots Adelle a satisfied smile, crumpling up Kate's message and tossing a perfect hook into a N.Y. Knicks hoop.</context>
      <utterance>Then leave it in the past. Old flames are like old tax returns. You keep `em in the file cabinet for three years and then you cut `em loose.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll leave from the office tomorrow afternoon. Call the group. Schedule an emergency strategy session for noon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'll be a nice little holiday treat.</utterance>
   <speaker>15	EXT. LASSITER BUILDING - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A single light remains on in the building.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks outside the front door to the snowy, quiet street.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Campbell. Why didn't you call down, I would've had Joe get your ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking I might walk tonight, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nod from Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Nice night for it. I'll have Louis send your car home.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas to you, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack puts on a pair of soft leather gloves and heads out into the crisp night air...</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. To you too...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack notices Cash talking to himself, seemingly crazy. Jack approaches Sam Wong at the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah...yeah, yee-ah! She's a certified winner...paper- thin but good as gold...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Egg nog?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM WONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dairy case. Five dollar.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack grabs a carton of egg nog, then notices Cash handing Sam Wong his ticket. Jack heads back toward the counter...</context>
      <utterance>Y'all do the lotto here...? `Cause I got me a winner...I know, I know, Lotto keeps the black man down... but not me...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...06...14...18...48...right there. Four numbers...that's two hundred and thirty eight dollar...  Merry Christmas and shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM WONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ticket bad. You draw in lines with pencil.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you talkin' about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM WONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman with the baby looks over...the college kid looks up, nervous...the drunken Santa, bottle of bourbon in hand, starts to walk by Jack...Jack instinctively puts an arm out, holding the Santa back...</context>
      <utterance>You draw lines with pencil! I know about this!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What!? Look at the ticket...!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM WONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Santa looks at Jack, confused.</context>
      <utterance>Get out, I call 911.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman with the baby puts a loaf of bread back on the shelf, starts nervously inching toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>You're lookin' at me, you're not even lookin' at the ticket!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM WONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You leave now. Take ticket somewhere else.  Next customer in line...!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You first generation, xenophobic, money-theistic, hot pastrami sandwich making...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAM WONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just watching...Cash shoves the ticket in Sam Wong's face...</context>
      <utterance>Get out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash turns to Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Let me see that ticket.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at the woman, the college kid, the Santa, then...</context>
      <utterance>Was I talkin' to you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Cash walks over to Jack...</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'll buy it from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The patrons exchange nervous glances...Jack watches, confused.</context>
      <utterance>Guy in $2,000 suit gets ass kicked tryin' to be a hero. Film at eleven...  What?! Oh no, not another lookie-loo. You know how big a job this is?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cash throws a bottle of Perrier against the wall, it SHATTERS. The woman reels back in terror with the baby...</context>
      <utterance>You're double bookin' me! You're gonna get double billed! Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a flash, Cash whips a .38 from the back of his pants, aiming it at Jack's face. The woman SCREAMS, covers her baby.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, c'mon...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stares at Cash, trying his best to keep his cool...</context>
      <utterance>Do you want to die?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you do...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash gets closer...</context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm talking about a business deal here. I buy the ticket for two hundred, take it to a store where the guy behind the counter...  ...doesn't have a death wish  ...I just made myself a quick thirty eight dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like I said, it's a business deal...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash narrows his eyes...then, a smile as he puts the gun back into his pants...</context>
      <utterance>Damn, you are the real thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cash starts out of the deli. Jack follows...</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Jack, let's get outta here...  You were lookin' at me, papa, you shoulda been lookin' at the ticket. That ticket was legit, B. You're fake...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you know my name was Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I call all you white guys "Jack." Jack nods...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know you seem pretty relaxed for a guy who just had a gun pulled on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no way I was gonna die in that deli...  Let's just say I've been on a lucky streak lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack hands him the money.</context>
      <utterance>A lucky streak, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Jack nods.</context>
      <utterance>Sound pretty sure of yourself, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're telling me, you've got a gun to your head and you don't think for one second, what if this, what if that, maybe I shouldn't do this, I shoulda done that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash looks at him, then smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I don't do that. That's just not for me...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash is about to take off...</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Jack. Nice doing business with you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash turns around.</context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to carry that gun around for, anyway? You're just gonna do something you'll regret...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack casually takes the egg nog out of the bag, opens the carton...</context>
      <utterance>You want to talk about regrets, you're talking to the wrong person.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just saying that you seem like a smart guy. At a certain point you're gonna do something, and then there's no turning back...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack takes a sip of the egg nog.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, in most cases that'd be true.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean there must be programs out there, opportunities...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look from Jack...</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, wait a minute... you're tryin' to save me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh man, you're serious...  This man thinks I need to be saved!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash looks at Jack...</context>
      <utterance>Everyone needs something.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? What do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just said everyone needs something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got everything I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash looks at Jack. He smiles and shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. It must be great being you. You got it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm not saying you'd be able to do it without some hard work...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still think this is about me, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure it's about you. But it's about society, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with that, Cash turns and leaves Jack alone on the street with his egg nog...</context>
      <utterance>Oh man, I'm gonna enjoy this one... Just remember, Jack, you did this. You brought this on yourself...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack jumps as he hears Kate talk for the first time... Suddenly, the door bursts open...A SIX YEAR OLD GIRL, ANNIE, in a little nightgown, walks into the room carrying an 18 MONTH OLD BOY, JOSH, SINGING at the top of her lungs...</context>
      <utterance>Mmmm...ten more minutes, Jack... it’s Christmas...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annie places Josh on the bed and then jumps up herself. She gestures to the dog, patting the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Jingle bells, Santa s mells, Rudolph laid an egg...la la la, la-la la la, la la la la la...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>The dog faithfully jumps on the tiny bed, joining everybody else and leaving very little room. Annie starts jumping.</context>
      <utterance>You too, Luce...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rise...and...shine...!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at this activity like a man at his own funeral.</context>
      <utterance>You’re jumping, sweetheart...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom, don’t you think we need to open the presents?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Josh crawls directly up to Jack’s stomach, climbing on.</context>
      <utterance>Mommy needs five more minutes in la la land. That could be her present...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That’s it. Jack moves the baby gingerly over, then gets out of bed, stumbling over a baseball bat lying next to it. He picks up the bat...the same Willie Mays autograph bat that was encased in glass in his N.Y. apartment. Frightened, Jack drops the bad, looking down at himself for the first time...he’s naked... ...a mortified look on his face as he sees the kids on the bed... ...he quickly grabs a pair of sweat pants and a yellow cardigan off the chair and throws them on... Kate, still half asleep, reaches out her hand.</context>
      <utterance>C’mon, Dad. Get up! She said “Dad.”</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack turns by instinct. Kate grabs him, drawing him near. A look of fear on his face as Kate opens her eyes... Eye contact...Jack’s certain he’s about to hear her scream...</context>
      <utterance>Jack...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strong coffee, okay? She lets him go as Jack backs out the door...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Ed hugs Jack as best he can with an armful of gifts.</context>
      <utterance>Ed? Lorraine?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lorraine plants a big fat kiss on Jack’s cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Jack you ol’ bird dog. Merry Christmas to ya’...</utterance>
   <speaker>LORRAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk to him, Jack. Please. One day a year away from the Ponderosa. I don’t think that’s too much to ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack, still holding the door open, plotting his escape.</context>
      <utterance>I heard that. This is who I am, woman!  Tell her, Jack! You’re the only one who gets me, for god’s sake!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORRAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need some egg nog...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>‘Course you do. Hell, it’s almost 8 a.m.  Where are my two l’il pardners? Annie! Josh! Giddy up, Bid Ed’s here!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack dashes out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORRAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going, Jack?  Where’s he going?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door flies back open...</context>
      <utterance>Damned if I know... They start to remove their coats, when...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where’s my car?! Where’s my Ferrari!?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you talking about?  What’s he talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, can I just borrow your car?! I promise it’ll be returned!</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Caddy? Why don’t you take your own damn car!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORRAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack spots a set of keys hanging on a hook.</context>
      <utterance>Oh just let him borrow your precious Cadillac, for god’s sake.</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack grabs the keys off the hook...darts back outside...</context>
      <utterance>He’s got a perfectly good mini-van sitting out there in the driveway!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack starts to walk past but Tony blocks the way.</context>
      <utterance>Tony, thank god...</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY THE DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, pal. Entrance is for residents and guests only...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? It’s me, Jack Campbell. Penthouse C. I put you into commercial paper!</utterance>
   <speaker>TONY THE DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Mrs. Peterson walks to the door with her little DOG. Tony opens the door for her...</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little dog starts BARKING ferociously at Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth Peterson!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PETERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tony shrugs his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Who is this man?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at Jack with a raised eyebrow, the dog still</context>
      <utterance>You know me, Betty. You do. Jack Campbell. We’re on the co-op board together. We fought side by side for garbage disposals. Every morning we exchange quasi-sexual witty banter. Think...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TONY THE DOORMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack pleads to her with his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Should I call the cops? I’m gonna call the cops...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PETERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Betty. I know if I can just sleep this off, I’ll be fine...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. PETERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And sleep you shall. Noblesse oblige is not dead. Not yet anyway...Come, let’s get you some help. Surely there must be a shelter somewhere in this city.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Peterson shakes her head at him, a look of pity on her face. Frustrated, Jack turns and runs back to the mini-van...</context>
      <utterance>A shelter?! I’m the richest guy in the building...I’ve got twice the square footage you have!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, whoa, whoa...hold it right there...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank. Where’s Alan Mintz? Is he here yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Mintz?  I don’t think so...building’s closed pal. You’ll have to come back tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don’t know what’s going on here but I am Senior Vice President of this company.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don’t care who you are. It’s Christmas and like I told you the building is closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then he sees it...”ALAN MINTZ - PRESIDENT,” listed plain as day on the building director... Jack looks at Frank, then back to the building directory... A pitying look from Frank...Jack stands there, in shock...</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you’re not hearing me. I am Jack Campbell...  Right here. Jack Campbell, President...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jack turns...sees the DRIVER low in the seat...can’t quite make out the face...</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Watch where you’re walking!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack...still stunned...looks at the car, very familiar...the voice of the driver, also familiar...</context>
      <utterance>You almost dented my two hundred thousand dollar car!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>A look of realization on Jack’s face...</context>
      <utterance>That’s right! My new car’s worth more than your shitty house!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>...it’s Cash, and he’s in Jack’s car... Jack moves over to the passenger window in shock...a smile from Cash...</context>
      <utterance>I feel like I really did win the lottery!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss me, Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s my car! You stole my car!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It’s a callable asset seized in accordance with the acquisition by-laws of your alt-fate contract...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Basically, it’s my car now. Get in. Cash reaches over and opens the door. Jack hesitates...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Cash gives him a reassuring look. Jack gets in...</context>
      <utterance>Look, I don’t make the rules, Jack. This is how it works. Get in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Might wanna fasten your seat belt, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack’s freaking out and Cash is enjoying every minute of it. Cash hands Jack a paper bag. Jack starts breathing into the bag.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is happening to me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash looks over at Jack...he’s really losing it, sobbing into the bag...almost hyperventilating...Cash smiles...</context>
      <utterance>This kinda thing makes a lotta guys throw up. Seen it happen. So if you get the urge, do it out the window.  I don’t want you marring this exquisite leather interior...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don’t know what you’re getting so worked up about, you did this...you brought this on yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brought what on myself?! I didn’t do anything!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No? C’mon, Jack...I’ve got everything I need, I don’t have regrets, that’s just not for me... sound familiar?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash gets a laugh out of Jack’s overreaction...</context>
      <utterance>You mean because you thought I was cocky I’m now on a permanent acid trip?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone else in that store is a statue, they see their lives passing in front of their eyes, but not you. You’re making a business deal...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me my goddamn life back!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You? What about me? I’m working hard for you here, Jack. On Christmas too! Now you did a good thing last night, intervening that way. I was moved...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash turns to Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Please. Just tell me what’s happening to me. In plain English. None of that mumbo jumbo...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It’s a glimpse, Jacko.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I glimpse? A glimpse of what!? What glimpse?! Glimpse!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, eventually, everybody gets one...some of ‘em take a couple seconds...  ...some of ‘em take a lot longer...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look from Cash.</context>
      <utterance>I asked you a direct question! A glimpse of what?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Figure it out. You got plenty of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much time?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As long as it takes to figure it out. Which, in your case, could be considerable.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash looks at Jack, relishing the moment. He flashes Jack a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I just want my life back. Now what’s it gonna take? You wanna talk turkey? Let’s talk turkey! How much money...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I look like I need your money. It doesn’t work like that and I can’t tell you why.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you got to figure it out for yourself.  Are you listening to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash just stares at him...</context>
      <utterance>Figure it out? Figure what out?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s it? That’s all I get?! A glare?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack faces Cash, simmering...with frustration.</context>
      <utterance>Look Jack, in my experience the best way people deal with this is to just relax and breathe through it...let it come to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don’t have time for this right now. I’m in the middle of a deal...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh you’re working on a new deal now...did I mention that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCREECH...Cash slams on the brakes...practically sending Jack through the windshield. Jack recovers, looks up...the car is parked right next to the mini-van. Cash pulls out a small plastic bag, holding it out to Jack...</context>
      <utterance>You know what? I’ve had it with you. I’ve had it with all of this shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks inside the bag, pulls out a BARBIE BICYCLE BELL. He looks at it curiously.</context>
      <utterance>Here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What’s this, a signal? Will you come whenever I ring it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash reaches across Jack and opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>Do I look like I live in a bottle?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks out to the lonely street outside, then back to Cash.</context>
      <utterance>Look Jack I’m late. I’d love to help you out some more but I gotta go handle my business...  Happy trails.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash looks at Jack, the desperation on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you did this to me, you can’t just leave me like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack’s still a little unsure...he sees Cash open the driver side door...</context>
      <utterance>Fine. You want to know everything, I’ll tell you everything. But not here. Let’s get some air...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack gets out of the car...and before he can even turn around, Cash’s door SLAMS shut and the car takes off in a blast of horsepower... Jack stands there gazing down the street, listening to the sound of the Ferrari shifting gears, disappearing... The wind whips up...shivering, Jack looks toward the Lassiter Building, then to the plastic bag in his hand, and finally to the mini-van.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, man...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arnie looks up and sees Jack in the van.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. Do you know where Merrison Street is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeannie! I found Jack!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack takes in the decor – it’s a male leisure time fantasy – old pinball machine, wide screen TV, dart board, and kitschy ‘50s style bamboo bar...</context>
      <utterance>You look terrible...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Arnie notices Jack’s fascination with the room...</context>
      <utterance>Truth is I expected you. Kate called before and asked if I knew where you were.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I moved the Barca-lounger into the corner. It’s throwin’ everybody off. What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A satisfied smile from Arnie, Jack’s approval means something to him.</context>
      <utterance>Great room...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arnie shepherds Jack onto a bar stool and pours a drink out of a bamboo bottle holder.</context>
      <utterance>You and me, buddy. We know how to live...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack doesn’t respond, his eyes drawn to a softball team photo on the bar...Jack and Arnie kissing a huge trophy with the caption, “Plainfield, N.J. Softball League Champs, 1994.”</context>
      <utterance>So Jack, you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack looks over from the photo to Arnie...</context>
      <utterance>I mean you leave the house on Christmas morning, you don’t tell anyone where you’re going...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We’re friends, aren’t we?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arnie makes a fist and gestures to his heart. Jack nods.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I don’t say it enough but you moving in next door to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>A moment of decision for Jack as Arnie stands there, open eyed, ready to listen.</context>
      <utterance>Talk to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m having kind of a bad day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A raised eyebrow from Jack.</context>
      <utterance>I read somewhere that the suicide rate doubles during the holidays...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I saying? You don’t need to hear that...  All I meant was a lot of people have a hard time dealing with all the forced reverie, that’s all. Is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trouble at work?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don’t think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack pauses at the mention of Kate. Arnie’s eyes widen...</context>
      <utterance>It’s not Kate, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, it’s like we’re in each other’s heads...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at Arnie as if he’s seeking confirmation.</context>
      <utterance>Kate’s my wife...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arnie comes out from behind the bar, taking Jack by the arm.</context>
      <utterance>Just keep saying it, Jack, like a mantra.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C’mon, I better walk ya home. She’s mad enough as it is, right...?</utterance>
   <speaker>37	EXT. ARNIE’S YARD - SECONDS LATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arnie walks Jack through his backyard...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you fit the profile exactly. Thirties, house, kids, financial responsibilities. You start thinking...this isn’t the life I dreamt about. Where’s the romance, where’s the joie de vivre? Suddenly, every lingerie ad in the Newark Star Ledger represents a life you can’t have...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A chuckle from Arnie.</context>
      <utterance>It’s just two kids, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They arrive at...the backyard of the Campbell house... cluttered with a swing set, a dog run with chewed up lawn, and a wooden sun deck in the process of being built...</context>
      <utterance>You made a choice, Jack, a promise to your wife. Maybe sometimes it seems like you gave up the world, but look what you got...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack trips over a wayward BIG WHEEL.</context>
      <utterance>Four bedrooms, two and a half baths, and a partially finished basement...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Arnie leads Jack toward the house.</context>
      <utterance>Kids...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>A blank stare from Jack as they arrive at the sliding glass door...Arnie faces Jack squarely, grabbing his shoulders and looking him in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>Okay look, you probably don’t want to hear this right now but remember what you told me last summer when I almost had that thing with Arnie Jr.’s speech therapist.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Arnie gives Jack a comforting smie...</context>
      <utterance>Don’t screw up the best thing in your life just because you’re a little unsure about who you are. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Arnie turns Jack toward the door and slides it open.</context>
      <utterance>God, it feels so good to finally give something back to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Arnie gives Jack a gentle hug...then gives him a little push toward the door...</context>
      <utterance>I’m gonna hug you now...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cups the receiver. Jack looks at her, she’s dressed now, nothing fancy but she looks great.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on a second...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A curious look from Kate.</context>
      <utterance>You cut your hair...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate just stands there looking at Jack, giving away nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Ten years ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a resolute nod, then...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack grimaces as she resolutely hangs up the phone then stares him down angrily.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind, he just walked in...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack watches her vent, the frustration on his face building.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have any idea what you put us through today?! You walk out of here at 7:30 in the morning, don’t tell me where you’re going, or even that you’re going, and I don’t see you ‘til hours later. I had state troopers looking for you! I called hospitals...  ...I was just on the phone with the morgue for god’s sake!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack’s almost to a breaking po INT.</context>
      <utterance>What kind of man leaves his family on Christmas morning without a word about where he’s going?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of man does that!?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him curiously.</context>
      <utterance>I don’t know! Please stop yelling at me!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was in the city.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The city? New York City? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because that’s where I live.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack...don’t even start...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A raised eyebrow from Kate. Jack moves around the room...</context>
      <utterance>Look, you don’t understand. I woke up here...and this is very strange ...this is not my house...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate looks him over, assessing, then...</context>
      <utterance>I’m not “Dad...”. Kate, you’re not my wife...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares him down, expecting an answer. But he has no answer.</context>
      <utterance>You know what, Jack? It’s not funny this time. I’m really angry.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack takes the bell out of the plastic bag that Cash gave him, holds it up in front of her and starts RINGING it furiously. Then...Annie rides into the room on her new bike.</context>
      <utterance>Jack!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack watches as she pedals over, reaches into his hand and takes the bicycle bell...</context>
      <utterance>What’s that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Annie rides excitedly out of the room on her bike. Leaving Jack and Kate alone again...</context>
      <utterance>I like this...  ...thanks, Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack sees the disappointment on her face...</context>
      <utterance>You missed the whole thing, Jack. The pancakes, the presents...you spent six hours putting that bike together and you didn’t even get to see the look on Annie’s face when she opened it...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack looks down, almost ashamed...he relents, giving in to the moment...</context>
      <utterance>You missed Christmas, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m...I’m sorry. Kate looks at him. He seems sincere enough...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, we don’t have time for this right now, we’ll talk about it later. Now get dressed...  You’re not wearing that to the Thompsons’ party. I don’t care how hilarious you think it is...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Party? Oh no, I can’t go to a party...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look forward to this party all year. What’s with you today?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate looks at him a moment, then shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Trust me on this Kate. I really don’t think going to a party is the right move for me at the present time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up the phone, starts dialing...</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Do whatever you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Telling my mother she doesn’t have to stay with the kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate just looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Because you’ll be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks past her...toward a hallway door, Kate watching him... He opens the door...it’s a closet.</context>
      <utterance>I’ll be ready in ten minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ...  Where the hell is the bathroom?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny, Jack. I’m laughing on the inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>39	INT. BATHROOM - MINUTES LATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack walks in, looks in the mirror, determined to collect himself...but something’s not right... He glances around...the bathroom is small and it’s cluttered with Kate’s razors, loofah, skin creams... ...none of this stuff is his... ...he looks in the mirror again, his face revealing a forlorn sense of displacement... ...he stares at himself until...he starts to lose it... anger, confusion...sadness...finally, he begins breaking down... After a moment, he turns on the water, rinsing his face...</context>
      <utterance>The light comes on...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like the dress...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It’s lovely...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack shoots her a confused look...then walks in, trying to catch up with Kate...</context>
      <utterance>I thought I saw you notice it at the kids’ recital.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see Van Horn last night? This kid’s gonna single-handedly save basketball in the state of New Jersey...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick looks at him in disbelief.</context>
      <utterance>The Nets? You’re kidding, right...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>BILL KRAMER, a huge pile of fried chicken wings on his plate, tugs at Jack’s shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Well...they’re certainly due.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL KRAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So tomorrow’s the big day, Jackie...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay...why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL KRAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Triple bypass. I’m going under the knife. I told you, didn’t I?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Triple bypass?  You really think you should be eating all that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL KRAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? I figure I’m going in for a cleaning tomorrow, I might as well load up on the fried stuff tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nick reaches into his pocket and pulls out a packet of Dutch Masters cigars. He shows them to Jack, Jack nods politely. Nick eagerly hands him one... Nick lights Jack’s cigar, then his own...enjoying that first puff...smiling at Jack...Jack dutifully takes a puff of the cigar...nods back at Nick...but it’s an effort... Evelyn Thompson approaches, a tray of MUSHROOM PUFFS in hand...</context>
      <utterance>Good thinking, Bill. Have another drink.  He’ll be lucky if he lives through the night...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finger food...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don’t think so, thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate sees Evelyn and Jack from her position on the other side of the room...Kate watches as... Evelyn holds the puff up to Jack’s mouth, slowly putting it near his lips...</context>
      <utterance>C’mon, as soon as I put them down, you’re gonna grab a couple...you always do...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>He instinctively opens his mouth as Evelyn pushes the treat inside...</context>
      <utterance>Let me. They’ll melt in your mouth...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>On Jack’s face...if freezer burn were a facial expression, this would be it...</context>
      <utterance>Good?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...Evelyn licks her fingers suggestively then hands Jack the entire tray with a sexy smile... A raised eyebrow from Kate, still watching...</context>
      <utterance>They’re great! Thank you!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mushroom puffs aren’t the only thing I do well...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn nods as Jack walks toward the staircase... Kate follows Jack with her eyes as he climbs the stairs...</context>
      <utterance>Well do whatever it is you do well, and just...just do it. Excuse me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Click. A dial tone. Jack slams the phone down...</context>
      <utterance>...what do you mean he won’t come to the phone?!  Do you realize how much money I’ve made for that sonuvabitch in the last eight years?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>He slams the phone again...and again...and again...</context>
      <utterance>Damnit!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jack turns, sees Kate standing in the doorway, watching him take his frustrations out on the phone, concern on her face.</context>
      <utterance>Jack...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A forced smile from Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you’re okay...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I’m fine. It’s just this god awful football phone! Who has a phone like this anyway?!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate notices the tray of mushroom puffs on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Uh huh...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>She turns and leaves...Jack looks at her, confused...</context>
      <utterance>You must really love Evelyn’s mushroom puffs, huh?  You know they’re not real...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack watches as Kate charms the crowd...</context>
      <utterance>...then she asks me to put this sweater on. What choice do I have, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>The guests laugh again. Even Jack finds himself laughing, until...</context>
      <utterance>But as I’m slipping it on I notice she’s misspelled the word “lawyers.”  I had to go through the entire day wearing a hand embroidered sweater that said, “Non-Profit Layers Do It For Free.”</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A chuckle from the group. Kate’s confused.</context>
      <utterance>So you’re a lawyer...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>People are starting to LAUGH.</context>
      <utterance>A non-profit lawyer...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pro bono. You don’t get paid at all. Nobody makes a dime. Well, bravo... Blank stares from everyone, including Kate...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate grabs a leash off a hook and hands it to Jack.</context>
      <utterance>I better go wake my mother...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you go...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You’re kidding me...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She’s your dog, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, she’s not.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, she’s the kid’s dog. Let’s go wake Josh, see if he wants to walk her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it’s twenty degrees outside...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at the dog’s face. Lucy couldn’t be more excited. Finally, Jack shakes his head and takes the leash.</context>
      <utterance>You’re having a bad day, I’ll go with you...actually, there’s no way in hell you’re gettin’ me back out there...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make sure you reward her verbally when she does a number two...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>46	EXT. SUBURBAN STREET - LATE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack, wearing a down jacket, is being dragged down the street by Lucy, his breath condensing in the cold winter air. The dog sniffs at a hydrant and a couple of garbage cans, but isn’t doing her business.</context>
      <utterance>The sound of CRICKETS.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dog stops, sniffing at a manicured lawn...</context>
      <utterance>Figure it out...I’m s crewed...don’t have to be a genius to figure that out...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>But the dog keeps moving, pulling Jack with her.</context>
      <utterance>It’s as good a place as any...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Lucy’s sniffing around someone’s Christmas display but Jack’s too wrapped up in his thought process to notice.</context>
      <utterance>...but obviously not up to your high standards...  Okay...he said you’re working on a new deal now...fine, you’ve done a thousand deals, what’s the first thing you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack narrows his eyes, thinking about that deal...</context>
      <utterance>Triage. It’s your signature. You survey the damage, find out everything you can, you probe, leave nothing to chance. I’m just gonna have to go detective. How did you get Mentadent? You learned everything there was to know about toothpaste and then you pounced...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Resolute, Jack turns to the dog.</context>
      <utterance>That’s our play here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you could take a dump some time in this century, then we could go home where it’s warm... Jack looks around at the unfamiliar houses...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>But the dog ignores him, dragging Jack along...</context>
      <utterance>That is if I can even remember how to get home...  You remember, don’t you girl?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer...</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...my feet are hurtin’...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...that baby’s crying...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...her expression makes Jack turn his gaze from her naked body.</context>
      <utterance>And...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>She closes the curtain and turns the radio back up.</context>
      <utterance>Don’t give me that look, Jack, Tuesday’s your day and you know it. And try to get Josh to day care on time, okay? He missed the macaroni painting last week...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack searches the diaper for the tabs of tape, then gingerly pulls them apart, releasing the diaper from the baby’s bottom, and seeing what’s inside.</context>
      <utterance>Pull tape...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack holds the diaper out away from him, searching for a place to put it. Annie points to a Diaper Genie by the dresser. Jack throws the diaper in, then quickly replaces the lid. Annie points to the container of Baby Wipes.</context>
      <utterance>Holy mother of god!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Annie stares at him a beat. Then...</context>
      <utterance>You must be kidding...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack turns to her. She’s looking back at him with complete earnestness. They stare at each other another moment. Then...</context>
      <utterance>You’re not really our dad, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look of curiosity from Annie.</context>
      <utterance>No, I’m not.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>No response from Annie...</context>
      <utterance>I work on Wall Street, you know with the big buildings...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Annie nods at Jack, still suspicious.</context>
      <utterance>I live in an apartment house with a doorman, I can buy just about anything I want...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn’t my real life. It’s just a glimpse...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where’s my real dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A concerned look on Annie’s face, Jack’s petrified that she’s about to cry.</context>
      <utterance>I don’t know...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Annie approaches Jack, climbing up on a little chair and tugging firmly at his hair.</context>
      <utterance>But don’t worry, he loves you and I’m sure he’ll be back very soon...  ...very, very soon...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They did a pretty good job.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The aliens...In the mother ship. You look just like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annie’s now stone faced, trying to decide about Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Uhh...thanks...slightly better looking though, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>She thinks about it for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>You’re not going to start crying, are you? Because I’m not really sure I could deal with that right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you like kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On a case by case basis...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how to make chocolate milk?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I could figure it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You promise not to kidnap me and my brother and implant stuff in our brains?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Then...a smile from Annie.</context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to earth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stops the van outside the Playland Day Care Center.</context>
      <utterance>Stop here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is day care. It’s where babies go when their parents are at work.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets out of the van...</context>
      <utterance>Check...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have winter camp until four, then ballet until five thirty.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five thirty. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try not to be late because kids don’t like to be the last one picked up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it. Good tip.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bye...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annie turns back toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Annie!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do I go now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big Ed’s.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big Ed’s? Big Ed’s Tires?  Why...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Then...</context>
      <utterance>That’s where you work.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs her shoulders and walks off.</context>
      <utterance>You mean I sell tires...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s what I do. I’m a tire salesman...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Jack, you happen to know the stock number on those new Michelin X1's?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...lemme get back to you on that one...  Tommy...</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack nods amiably then continues into the store...</context>
      <utterance>Thomas, why you bother Jack about that. Look it up yourself...  Okay Jack, we talk later...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stares blankly at Big Ed...</context>
      <utterance>Jack my boy! You are looking mighty worse for the wear...Hey, guess who I played bridge with two nights ago...?</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack considers this briefly.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, you’ll never guess. One Sydney Potter. That’s Sydney Potter, Chief Executive Officer of BuyRite Transport. Only the third largest trucking company in the state. I even let the sonuvabitch win, which wasn’t easy because the guy’s been bashed in the head by Teamsters so many times his brain’s like porridge. Anyhoo, he’s looking for a new parts supplier... we can handle that kind of volume, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Ed makes a gun gesture with his forefinger, winking at Jack, then turns back to the activity at the counter as... Jack spots KENNY, a very young sales associate, walking by. He reaches out and taps Kenny on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I’m gonna have to get back to you on that...Ed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I have a private office somewhere in the building?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...sure Jack...  Right back there...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack walks into the office with his name on the door...</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>57	INT. JACK’S OFFICE - CONTINUOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>bar...it’s small, cramped and cluttered, the walls littered with tire inventory and price lists... Jack takes a slow, sad lap around the office. He makes it to the small wooden desk at the far end of the room and sits down behind it... On the desk are photos of Jack, Kate and the kids, a plastic Michelin Man model, a tire-themed day calendar and a small plastic figurine of a BOWLER, the word, “Bowlers Do It In An Alley” embossed on its base... He surveys the desktop briefly, then opens the top drawer, finding a personal checkbook and looking inside... He sees the bottom line and winces, then puts it back... Jack picks up the “Bowlers Do It In An Alley” figurine and gives it a good look...</context>
      <utterance>There’s no Stairmaster here, no leather sofa or</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He replaces the figurine then opens the bottom drawer where he spots a bottle of Glenfiddich. He lifts it out...</context>
      <utterance>Bowlers do it in an alley?...Non profit lawyers do it for free... what is it with these people? Don’t they realize this refers to sex?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>He takes a paper cup and pours himself a shot. He drinks it down in one gulp and then crumples up the cup, throwing it toward the NET’S basketball hoop/garbage can near the door. He misses... He looks more closely at the photographs...most are family photos, a happy Jack with Kate, with Annie at the pony rides, at Josh’s birth...in every one of them, Jack is smiling...</context>
      <utterance>At least you splurged on some decent scotch...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>He turns his head...spots a small plaque on the wall behind him. It reads, “Jack Campbell - E.F. Hutton 1 Junior Sales Associate, 1988.” Jack raises an eyebrow...</context>
      <utterance>What are you smiling about...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>He grabs it off the wall and looks at it more carefully...</context>
      <utterance>Number one...not bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack’s jarred into reality...</context>
      <utterance>1988...? I was in London in 1988...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>The P.A. system comes to life...</context>
      <utterance>You never went to London...  ...you never got on that plane... He stays there a moment...in shock. Then...</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack to mag wheels...Jack, you’re needed in mag wheels, customer waiting!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I was the number one junior sales associate at E.F. Hutton in 1988. Did you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I didn’t...that’s great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s the kind of thing you can really build on...</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They approach “Mag Wheels” where TOMMY, a slick sales associate, stands with a CUSTOMER looking at the displays...</context>
      <utterance>I mean sales has always been a feeder for M and A, always...</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we are, mag wheels...  Hey Jack, are you sure you’re okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny looks at him nervously.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I’m just a little confused right now about why I work here...</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack nods compassionately. Kenny takes off leaving Jack alone with his thoughts as Tommy approaches with the customer.</context>
      <utterance>Uh...I just started here last Tuesday.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you’re all set on the Skip Shift eliminator and the Brembo rotors. Jack’s our point man on alloy wheels...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know why do I work here...?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The customer nods, impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Because you’re the best damn tire guy in the state of New Jersey...  Jack taught me everything I know about the business...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another nod to the customer.</context>
      <utterance>I taught you the business?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he’s a crack-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy’s confused.</context>
      <utterance>Everything I taught you. I want to hear it all, right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I’m ready to buy here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack grabs one of the alloy rims off the shelf, holding it out to the customer.</context>
      <utterance>I want some alloy wheels.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The customer takes the wheel from Jack, looks at it confused...</context>
      <utterance>Here. These are great. You’ll need four.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don’t like these...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you heard the guy, I’m the best damn tire guy in the state of New Jersey.  Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A satisfied smirk from the customer.</context>
      <utterance>Okay...  Rule number one, the customer is always right...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A KNOCK at the door...</context>
      <utterance>...I have no idea what our inventory level is, that’s why I’m asking you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>He hangs up the phone as the door opens. Big Ed sticks his head in...</context>
      <utterance>Look, just send us what you sent us last month, okay...? And keep doing that until further notice...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a minute, Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Ed walks in, followed by SYDNEY POTTER, 60s, a tough looking man...</context>
      <utterance>I’ve got all the time in the world...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Potter extends a hand, Jack rises from his chair, trying to place the name. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Jack, meet Sydney Potter, BuyRite Transport, one of Jersey’s top businessmen...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands. Potter nods his head at Jack, immediately impressed. Big Ed is beaming.</context>
      <utterance>...and a helluva bridge player. Ed’s told me a lot about you...</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucky in cards, lucky in business, lucky in love. My cup runneth over...  He’s a nice looking boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A smile from Potter, then a serious look.</context>
      <utterance>My daughter’s no slouch either...</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Potter stares Jack down. But Jack’s not about to be intimidated by him. He pauses, matching Potter’s stare. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Let’s cut to the chase, Jack. Big Ed tells me you’re the grease that makes the wheels turn around here. I need a new parts supplier for my fleet. You seem to have the parts. That we know. What we don’t know is why the hell I should buy them from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A surprised look from Potter. An anxious laugh from Big Ed.</context>
      <utterance>I have no idea...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C’mon Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack continues to stare down Potter.</context>
      <utterance>I mean it. From what I can tell, we’re a mom and pop operation, we’re already over-extended in sales, and any price advantage we could offer would easily be matched by a larger supplier...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>The staring match continues. Big Ed’s getting more nervous. Potter’s the first to blink.</context>
      <utterance>So like I said, I don’t have any idea why you should buy your parts from us...</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, you got my attention...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Except for rule number one...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>A smile from Potter. Jack gives Ed a wink. Ed watches, thrilled...</context>
      <utterance>The customer is always right. A clich? Sure. The difference is, we mean it. We’re small, we need our customers. We can’t afford to disappoint them, ever. Yeah, you could go to some leviathan supplier, probably save a few pennies on the price of oil filters, but with us you get more than a supplier, you get a bridge partner...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Potter nods at Jack. Jack moves in for the kill.</context>
      <utterance>You want to bid hearts, we’re right there with you. You feel the need to redouble, you’re not going to get any argument from us...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Potter pauses a minute, then...</context>
      <utterance>The big guys may have the high cards, but you know as well as I do, Sydney, high cards don’t always take the trick.</utterance>
   <speaker>POTTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Ed smiles, letting out a relieved sigh.</context>
      <utterance>I like him...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big Ed and Potter exit the office...</context>
      <utterance>That’s my boy...  C’mon, lemme show you the rest of the ranch...</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG ED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>...leaving Jack there with a satisfied smile on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Nice shootin’, Jack...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>CNBC REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON T.V.</mode>
      <context>The Global Health Systems and MedTech logos appear on a graphic in the corner of the screen...</context>
      <utterance>...advancers led decliners by a nine to four ratio and the closing tick was a mildly bullish plus seventy six. Much of the market’s action today was fueled by the latest round of merger mania to hit Wall Street...</utterance>
   <speaker>CNBC REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D, ON T.V.</mode>
      <context>confident looking Mintz shaking Bob Thomas’ hand at the press conference.</context>
      <utterance>...when Global Health Systems and MedTech Pharmaceutical announced their intentions to join forces in a massive one hundred and twenty two billion dollar stock swap deal. Though neither side expressed significant regulatory concerns at the announcement press conference, it is believed that both the FDA and the FTC will be closely scrutinizing the marriage, the largest ever in the health care industry. When asked about possible anti- competitive implications, Global Chairman Bob Thomas referred reporters to P.K. Lassiter and Company President Alan Mintz, the original architect behind the deal... Jack stares in shock as the image changes to a super</utterance>
   <speaker>CNBC REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D, ON T.V.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ironically, Mintz first met Thomas at a Lamaze class...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Lamaze class...!?</utterance>
   <speaker>CNBC REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON T.V.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...while coaching their pregnant wives, Mintz and T homas struck up a dialogue about the need for consolidation in the rapidly growing health care industry and two months later, the deal with MedTech was born...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! That’s my deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>CNBC REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>ON T.V.</mode>
      <context>Kate comes into the room from the hallway wearing only Jack’s NYU sweatshirt...</context>
      <utterance>In other business news, U.S. Labor Department officials announced today that two hundred and seventy-five thousand new jobs were created last month, twenty-five thousand less than economists were predicting, leading to a mild rally in the bond markets before midday. But as the trading session drew to a close, the profit takers stepped in and the long bond closed at ninety seven even, up only two ticks, the yield inching down to six point zero seven percent...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes over to the window and draws the blinds. Jack looks up at her, nods, then goes back to the TV.</context>
      <utterance>The kids are asleep...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack. I said the kids are asleep...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate shuts off the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Well that’s just great...those little monkeys can be a real handful...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! I was watching that!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we had a deal about you watching CNBC in bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate throws a Kate Bush’s “The Sensual World” into the CD player.</context>
      <utterance>I’m working on a new deal now...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She climbs onto the bed, a seductive look on her face.</context>
      <utterance>Fine, but not tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a second. You want me, don’t you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate starts kissing him...but Jack’s a little uncomfortable with the sudden intimacy...he pulls back, a little nervous.</context>
      <utterance>That is the general idea, yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn’t we grab some dinner first? Maybe a bottle of wine...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It’s ten thirty, Jack. By eleven you’re gonna be sprawled out on the bed snoring your head off. We don’t have time for wining and dining.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts kissing him again...but this time he just goes with it, and as her hands run through his hair he’s brought back to a different time and place... Jack momentarily pulls back and looks at her...it’s like the first time he’s really looked at her in eleven years...</context>
      <utterance>Whatever you say...honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>She smiles at him, almost uncomfortable with the compliment...</context>
      <utterance>God...you’re beautiful...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I’m serious...you’re really stunning...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is good stuff, Jack, keep it coming...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stares at her, entranced...Kate pulls back, reacting to the intensity in his stare...</context>
      <utterance>I mean back in college, you were a very pretty girl, there’s no question about that. But this...  ...you’ve really grown into a beautiful woman...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack freezes. There’s love in her eyes but it’s not meant for him... She kisses him...</context>
      <utterance>Look at me like you haven’t seen me every day for the last twelve years...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>She gets up off the bed and heads for the bathroom... He looks around...not sure what to do...Finally... He turns onto his side and closes his eyes... Kate emerges from the bathroom, she sees Jack on the bed, hears his breathing heavy with sleep... At once charmed and disappointed, Kate sighs. She turns off the CD player and heads into bed. She pulls the covers up over Jack, shutting off the light... She puts an arm around him, kissing him sweetly on the neck...</context>
      <utterance>Don’t move.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Close in on Jack’s face...turned away from Kate...he opens his eyes...looks down at her arm...loneliness on his face...</context>
      <utterance>‘night, honey...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We’re almost done here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Janes, Mom. You promised.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An unhappy look on Jack’s face.</context>
      <utterance>That’s right. Okay, let’s make a quick stop at the kids’ shoe department, pick up my watch from the battery place, then I’ll run into the linen store...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate looks back at Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Why don’t we just go to all the stores?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate gives him a look. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Every single store in this godforsaken shopping mall. We can go to them all.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack glances at the Men’s Dept., sighs and gives Kate a nod. She takes off with the kids...and then he sees it... ...the Zegna section. He’s drawn to the neat rows of beautiful suits like a moth to the light... He approaches the rack, pulls out a dark green suit, gently touching the soft wool.</context>
      <utterance>You know what, Jack?! I’ll go with the kids. Why don’t you just hang out here in the men’s department... okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jack turns and sees a SALESMAN standing behind him.</context>
      <utterance>It’s perfect for your frame...</utterance>
   <speaker>SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to try it on?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jack snaps out of his trance. He sees Kate standing behind him, Annie and Josh happily playing a few feet away.</context>
      <utterance>You look amazing in that suit...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean...wow...off the charts great.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate raises an eyebrow, then looks at the price tag.</context>
      <utterance>It’s an unbelievable thing. Wearing this suit actually makes me feel like a better person.  I’m gonna buy it...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>$2,400?! Are you out of your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She got those shoes...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at her...it’s a moment of decision.</context>
      <utterance>Those shoes were twenty five dollars. C’mon, take it off. We’ll go to the food court and get one of those funnel cakes you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate looks at Jack, a little surprised.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any idea what my life is like?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate just stands here, aghast...</context>
      <utterance>I wake up in the morning covered in dog saliva...I drop the kids off, spend eight hours selling tires retail...retail, Kate.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I pick up the kids, walk the dog, which by the way, carries the added bonus of carting away her monstrous crap...I play with the kids, take out the garbage, get six hours of sleep if I’m lucky, and then it starts all over again...and why is it that I always have to drive everyone everywhere? I spend practically my entire day in that slow as hell mini-van listening to Raffi tapes and trying to figure out how the cup holders work...I’m sick of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate stares at him, shaking her head...</context>
      <utterance>What’s in it for me? Where are my Mary Janes?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It’s sad to hear your life is such a disappointment to you, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate stares at him in disbelief. Then...</context>
      <utterance>I can’t believe it’s not a disappointment to you!  Jesus, Kate, I could’ve been a thousand times the man I became. How could you do this to me? How could you let me give up on my dreams like this?!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate’s words pierce Jack...he has to avert his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I’m sorry. I’m sorry I was such a saint before and I’m such a prick now. Maybe I’m just not the same guy I was when we got married...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at each other for a moment...a stand-off...</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you’re not. The Jack Campbell I married wouldn’t need a $2400 suit to make himself feel better about his life, but if that’s what it’s gonna take, then buy it. Just buy the goddamn suit ...we can take the money out of the kids’ college fund.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it...  We’ll get a funnel cake. It’ll be the highlight of my week...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate just keeps looking out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, I’m sorry about that back in the store. I really don’t want to fight with you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>She turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>But you must sometimes wonder how we ended up here. I mean back in college, did you see us...  ...here...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A glimmer in Jack’s eye...</context>
      <utterance>I’ll give you this, life has thrown us a few surprises...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It really has, hasn’t it? So if you had to...what would you say was the biggest surprise? She glances at the kids sleeping in the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...Annie for one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surprise. We’re pregnant...  Yeah...that must’ve been...I mean that was very unexpected. But what are you gonna do, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it worked out okay, don’t you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. I really like Annie.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, Jack. Maybe we’ll keep her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I love Annie. We had a lot of good times, didn’t we?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were young...  Remember that little place on Charles Street we used to go to?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charles Street? In the Village? When we were living in Greenwich Village...?  Great times. Why’d we ever leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack nods, starting to piece it together.</context>
      <utterance>You can’t really raise a kid in an apartment in the Village...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The trek out to the hospital every day didn’t help either...  You were great. Surviving the heart attack was one thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had a heart attack?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack, stop that. I'm still mad at you...  ...who knows what would’ve happened if you hadn’t stepped in at the store.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look from Kate.</context>
      <utterance>That’s why I work for Big Ed?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack looks out at the road a moment, piecing it all together in his mind.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, that’s why I work for Big Ed...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate looks at him a little strangely.</context>
      <utterance>So we had a baby, Big Ed had a heart attack, we b ought that house, and I’ve been working for him ever since...Sayonara, Wall Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our life in a nutshell...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want to look at it that way...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances again at the kids in the back seat, then at Jack.</context>
      <utterance>How would you look at it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A smile from Jack. He admires her outlook even if he can’t bring himself to share it.</context>
      <utterance>A great success story...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>66	INT. BOWLING ALLEY - EVENING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stands at a lane holding a bowling ball, the nickname “The Hammer” emblazoned over his bowling shirt pocket...He approaches the line and throws the ball down the lane... It’s ugly...The ball caroms off the hardwood into the gutter.</context>
      <utterance>A crowded suburban New Jersey bowling alley...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack turns. Arnie and the BOWLING TEAM are in the scorekeeping area watching Jack make a mockery of the sport. Jack scowls.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Jack, this is a league match, for god’s sake!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where’s your follow through? Where’s your stance?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I’m doing the best I can...  I’d like to see you hit a squash ball after seventeen beers...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You’re right. Why am I so competitive!? Compensation, I guess. Look, just focus, Jack. You can still pick up the spare... Jack retrieves his ball, sets up, genuinely concentrating...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack puts everything he has into the throw, heaving the ball down the lane with as much grace and power as he can muster...hitting the six pin and taking out four others.</context>
      <utterance>You are Jack Campbell. You’re better than this sport. You shot the rapids at Kenai. You ran with the bulls at Pamplona. You jumped out of a plane over the Mojave Desert, for Christ’s sake. You can do this...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>He turns, a fist pumped...But the guys could care less...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Pete, you’re up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment of confusion as he tries to place the face. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Hi Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evelyn, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very funny. I saw you out there on lane five. What do you have the flu or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Need a nurse?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn laughs.</context>
      <utterance>You’re a nurse?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She brushes past Jack, continuing to her lane...Jack follows her with his eyes a moment, then...</context>
      <utterance>If that’s what you want...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a second...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we...?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we what, Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn’s surprised at Jack’s directness. She stands there a beat, then walks back toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Is there something going on between us?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we finally being honest?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would help me if we were.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn looks a little flush...she briefly fans her face.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, you’re right, we’ve been dancing around this for years...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>An intrigued smile from Jack.</context>
      <utterance>God, my heart is racing. Here goes...  When I get dressed for a party and I know you’re going to be there... well, let’s just say I don’t go strapless because my husband likes it...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>She picks a piece of lint off his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>I’ve got six sets of snow tires piled up in my garage and I won’t even drive in the snow...And our kids just happen to be in the same ballet class every year?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>A look of surprise from Jack.</context>
      <utterance>So, if you’re asking me whether I’d like it to be more, the answer is yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack considers this for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>...and Kate would never have to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wide smile from Evelyn.</context>
      <utterance>Do I have your number?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns, leaving Jack standing there, watching her sashay back to her lane.</context>
      <utterance>Steve’s out of town with the kids this week. Why don’t you just stop by...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Jack, you’re all flush. I guess that seventy-one took a lot outta you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just saw Evelyn Thompson.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is relentless.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wants to have an affair with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty much.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah...  What is it about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So could you write down her exact address?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa...whoa...wait a second, Jack. You’re not actually gonna cheat on Kate?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wouldn’t really be cheating...  It’s complicated.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, maybe I’m not as good a consigliere as you are but you have to trust me on this one. A little flirtation’s harmless but you’re playing with fire here. The Fidelity Bank and Trust is a tough creditor. You make a deposit somewhere else, they close your account forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m telling you, those rules don’t apply to me, Arn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at him curiously.</context>
      <utterance>Screw the rules. I’m talking about the choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C’mon, Evelyn Thompson’s got no class. She doesn’t marry Dr. Steve, the woman’s living in a trailer.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, is that really necessary?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arnie takes one last swig of his beer and gets up...</context>
      <utterance>All I’m saying it there isn’t a guy in Union County who wouldn’t give his left nut to be married to Kate...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>He leaves Jack alone, thinking...</context>
      <utterance>I’ll see ya later, Jack...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was the game, honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate turns around, revealing a huge hunk of chocolate cake on a plate in front of her, a bite ready to go into her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Long, boring, and generally pretty sad. Arnie seemed to enjoy it...  Hey, where’s that chocolate cake...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean this chocolate cake?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate takes the bite, a little piece of icing sticks to the side of her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>That’s my piece. I was saving it because I got nauseated from that store bought chicken.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack approaches the counter.</context>
      <utterance>It’s good...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes another bite.</context>
      <utterance>Gimme that cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes a grab for the plate but she holds it out where he can’t reach it.</context>
      <utterance>No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C’mon.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare each other down a moment. Then... He tries to swipe the plate. Kate jumps out of her chair, running out of the kitchen with the cake, laughing... Jack takes off after her...chasing her through the house... just about the catch up to her when... She darts up the stairs, still laughing...he follows her...</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Jack. It’s too important to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...reaches up...grabs her shirt...pulls her down playfully on top of him...</context>
      <utterance>I want that cake!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want the cake!?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, then takes the whole piece in her hand and smooshes it right in his mouth... Beat. Then, Jack starts laughing...</context>
      <utterance>I want it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a big clump of it and smooshes it in her mouth. They stay there a moment, lying on the stairs, feeding each other cake, laughing. Jack leans back on the stairs. He looks at Kate’s face, practically covered in cake, smiling, and realizes... ...he hasn’t laughed like this in thirteen years. Then...</context>
      <utterance>It’s good, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sexy smile from Kate...they start kissing passionately right there on the steps...it’s heating up...</context>
      <utterance>Are the kids asleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C’mon, you know what I like to hear...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, baby, I know what you like to hear...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then say it...just say it to me...!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, you’re a bad girl, baby... You make me so hot...I’m gonna take you to that special place...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks up at her, he can practically see the passion drain from her face...</context>
      <utterance>What...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not it...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice, Jack. You’re sweeping me off my feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up and heads up the steps, disappearing into the bedroom...Jack shakes his head, frustrated. Then, he feels something licking at his hand... He looks down and sees Lucy standing next to him, wagging her tail, looking up at Jack with an “I’ve gotta go” look on her face. Jack heaves a sigh, then...</context>
      <utterance>What? You make me hot...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>He leads the dog toward the front door...</context>
      <utterance>C’mon, Lucy, maybe one of us can get a little relief tonight...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Bill stops playing and looks up at Arnie.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Bill, this thing is an antique. Don’t you even have image stabilization?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL KRAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then...Jack comes into frame, a confident smile on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Four hundred bucks at Best Buy, Arn.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack is jarred by the image of himself on the video... Jack on TV...he smiles as Kate walks into frame, easily putting an arm around Jack...</context>
      <utterance>And everyone knows image stabilization is for the weak...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Jack, it’s your wife’s birthday, got anything to say to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It’s your birthday? Today? What’s your name? Where were you born?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slaps him playfully on the arm...</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. You’re my wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate looks at him expectantly. Then...</context>
      <utterance>I do have one thing I wanna say...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT”D</mode>
      <context>Jack doesn’t have the greatest voice in the world but he’s not the least bit self-conscious...and Kate seems to like it, there’s a twinkle in her eye...some of the guests focus their attention on Jack and Kate. Jack winces, embarrassed, as he watches himself sing...</context>
      <utterance>Oh those fingers in my hair, that sly come hither stare, strips my conscience bare, it’s witchcraft...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Bill Kramer still at the piano, chimes in with the basic chords for “Witchcract,” sounding it out as he goes along...</context>
      <utterance>...and I’ve got no defense for it, that heat is too intense for it, what good would common sense for it do...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>The camera catches the reactions of guests in the crowd... the women, smiles on their faces, wrapped up in the romance of the moment. Envy on the men’s faces as they watch Jack serenade his wife... A musical interlude from Bill as Jack takes off his jacket...some HOOTS and HOLLERS from the crowd...Arnie captures the image of Kate whistling at her husband... Arnie follows with the camera as Jack strolls in front of the gathered guests...</context>
      <utterance>...‘Cause it’s witchcraft, wicked witchcraft...and although I know it’s strictly taboo...when you rouse the need in me, my heart says yes indeed in me, proceed with what you’re leadin’ me to...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack watches himself move gracefully. But it’s no longer embarrassment on his face, it’s fascination... Back in the video, the camera catches Evelyn Thompson watching longingly as Jack moves back toward Kate...Evelyn can’t take it anymore, she abruptly turns and walks toward the kitchen... Jack raises an eyebrow... In the video...Jack approaches Kate, she couldn’t have a more delighted look on her face. He picks up the verse...</context>
      <utterance>It’s such an ancient pitch, but one that I’d never switch, there ain’t no nicer witch than you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>The camera pans across the crowd, even the men are getting into it, focused on Jack as he sings lovingly, unashamed, to his wife...Nick Careli mouths the words along with Jack, almost as if he’s studying him, revering him... Jack watches the TV, seeing Nick do this...maybe he underestimated his alter ego... On the video...Jack staring into Kate’s eyes...</context>
      <utterance>‘Cause it’s witchcraft, that koo koo witchcraft...and although I know it’s strictly taboo...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack and Kate exchange a sexy smile...</context>
      <utterance>...when you rouse the need in me, my heart says yes indeed to me, proceed with what you’re leadin’ me to...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack kisses her on the lips...HOOTS and HOLLERS from the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>It’s such an ancient pitch, but one that I’d never switch...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate brushes a hand across Jack’s face... Smash cut to Jack watching this...seeing the connection, the heat between them...coveting it... Back to the video...the music building...the crowd completely in the palm of Jack’s hand...</context>
      <utterance>‘Cause there’s no nicer witch than you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>The camera closes in on Jack and Kate as the music builds to a crescendo...</context>
      <utterance>...than you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>A little musical flourish from Bill as the crowd breaks out into huge CHEERS and APPLAUSE... Jack, watching this other version of himself in the video, the center of attention, larger than life, focused on Kate... Back on video...</context>
      <utterance>...than you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate leans over, giving Jack a deep kiss...OOHS and AHHS from the crowd...but Jack and Kate are in their own little world... Jack continues to watch himself on the video, his smile fading, becoming a look of realization...then loss... A tear at the corner of his eye... The SOUND fades in Jack’s head as the action in the video continues... He’s left standing there...silent, still...</context>
      <utterance>Happy Birthday sweetheart...I love you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time to get up, honey... Jack obliges without question, getting out of bed, putting on a robe and slippers and exiting, still practically half-asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>73	INT. KITCHEN - SECONDS LATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns on the Mr. Coffee, gets a bottle from the fridge, throws it in the microwave, removes it, and heads upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>Jack walks into the kitchen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Terror on Jack’s face.</context>
      <utterance>Happy Anniversary, honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack musters up a smile, then approaches the gift.</context>
      <utterance>Before you do whatever crazy stunt you’ve got planned I want you to open mine...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I should wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates, then begins unwrapping the package, revealing... ...a suit, similar in color and style to the Zegna suit...</context>
      <utterance>No, open it...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found it at an outlet store. I know it’s a knock-off, but I think it’ll look great on you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack is overcome with emotion...Yes, it’s a ZEENA, but this is probably the nicest thing anyone’s ever done for him...</context>
      <utterance>Zeena...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really are incredible...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at Kate’s expectant face, suddenly remembering how truly screwed he is.</context>
      <utterance>Enjoy it, sweetheart...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He’s sweating bullets...watching as Kate gets a quizzical look on her face...</context>
      <utterance>You’re probably expecting something from me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here’s the thing. I really hadn’t planned on giving you your...uh... anniversary gift until tonight.  You know, anniversary’s good all day...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? You never wait all day. You can barely wait until it’s light out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Kate looks at him like she’s looking into his soul.</context>
      <utterance>I know that, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stands there, silent.</context>
      <utterance>You forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You actually forgot our anniversary.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That didn’t help.</context>
      <utterance>I’ll fix it. I’ll go out right now and get you something. I’ll make it right.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack sees a tear run down her face...a pang of guilt on his...</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Jack...Is this where we are now? Is this our marriage? Suddenly I’m the wife who has to drop hints two weeks before her anniversary so her husband doesn’t fuck it up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate wipes the tear away but they just keep coming.</context>
      <utterance>Please don’t cry...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack approaches her, holding out a hand but Kate pushes it away, gets up and walks toward the bathroom... Jack is left standing alone, holding Kate’s gift...</context>
      <utterance>I don’t want to be that, Jack...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing. Finally, he lifts the bike up in the air, RINGING the bell with everything he’s got...</context>
      <utterance>C’mon...c’mon...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Pull back...Annie in the doorway...looking at him.</context>
      <utterance>C’mon, goddamnit, how was I supposed to know the date of their anniversary!? I never married her!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack turns and sees her, gently lowering the bicycle.</context>
      <utterance>Put the bicycle back on the ground...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad...I shoulda warned you. Dad always does something really special for their anniversary.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One year he had a solar system named after her...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don’t you think that’s a little gimmicky?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack raises an eyebrow.</context>
      <utterance>Mom liked it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe there’s a jewelry store back at the mall. I could get her a pair of earrings or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s good but...you did forget the anniversary.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then...</context>
      <utterance>Right. That’s a major oversight...  So if I’m Kate...I can’t really afford the finer things, my husband’s career is a crushing disappointment to me, I’m trapped in suburbia...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Annie smiles, impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Did he ever take her to the City?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a look of confidence comes over Jack’s face. For the first time, he seems like a man in control.</context>
      <utterance>You’re really gettin’ the hang of this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annie thinks about it for a moment, taking it very seriously...</context>
      <utterance>Which do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate nods. She’s about to put it on when she looks at Annie...</context>
      <utterance>The black one...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fighting’s a part of it, Annie. You know that, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate looks at her with a raised eyebrow, then nods. It’s true. She puts down the dress and holds out a hand to Annie.</context>
      <utterance>I’m not worried, Mom. He’s still learning our ways...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate leads her to the makeup table, then opens a lipstick...</context>
      <utterance>C’mere.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate nods then applies some red lipstick to Annie’s lips.</context>
      <utterance>Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate rubs her lips together, showing Annie how to do it. Annie mimics her Mom, then Kate looks at her – Annie’s beaming.</context>
      <utterance>Now go like this...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Pull back to reveal...Jack standing at the door, watching ...appreciating the kind of mother Kate is...</context>
      <utterance>You’re gonna break a lot of hearts, you know. A smile from Annie...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A charmed smile from Kate as she hands Jack her coat. Jack hands the coats over to the COAT CHECK GIRL...</context>
      <utterance>You look beautiful...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack fakes a SNEEZE, trying to cover up...Kate gives him a pat on the back...</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Catherine...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes Kate by the arm...</context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine... He leads her to the main room. She looks out at the room, elegant tables, French country decor, a PIANIST playing Cole Porter...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack...can we afford all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What’s the difference? I’m taking my baby out for our anniversary, damn the costs...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack’s caught for a moment. Then...</context>
      <utterance>How do you even know about this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack puts his arm around her and kisses her on the cheek...</context>
      <utterance>Arnie...  Arnie. He’ll throw you a curve ball once in a while, that’s for sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>82	INT. LOIRE - A LITTLE LATER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>standing next to them. Jack’s not even looking at the menu.</context>
      <utterance>Jack and Kate sit at a secluded table, a WAITER</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate looks at Jack, a mixture of confusion and awe on her face.</context>
      <utterance>We’ll have the tureen of quail breast with shiitake mushrooms to start, then the veal medallions in raspberry truffle sauce and the sea scallops with pureed artichoke hearts...sea scallops, North of the Caspian...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good, sir. And may I say those are all excellent selections.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate reaches over and pulls down the wine list, reading it upside down.</context>
      <utterance>You may...  Also, we’ll have a bottle of Lafite, 1982.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wince from Jack...for a moment there it was almost perfect.</context>
      <utterance>It’s five hundred and fifty dollars, Jack!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter nods, then walks toward the kitchen...</context>
      <utterance>Just a glass of red wine for each of us...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are so not off the hook yet, slick.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A noncommittal nod from Kate. Then Jack notices her look over at the pianist, drawn in by the music.</context>
      <utterance>But I’m gettin’ close, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>A puzzled look from Kate. There’s nobody else dancing. There isn’t even much room to dance...</context>
      <utterance>You want to dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack gets up and holds out a hand.</context>
      <utterance>I don’t think there’s dancing here, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate looks around again, then she smiles. Kate rises, taking his hand. Jack takes her in his arms, swaying slowly in the limited amount of space, confident and self-assured. The pianist looks up, smiling, appreciating their role in this romantic moment. Kate moves with Jack, following his lead comfortably. They look good together...in sync with each other... People are watching them...some of the men are impressed, others are scoffing, but the women are clearly charmed...</context>
      <utterance>Sure there is...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack flashes her his most charming smile.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty good for a tire salesman from Jersey...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue to dance, in a world of their own...</context>
      <utterance>I have my moments...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack takes a scallop from Kate’s fork.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmm...  ...here, try one of these...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate laughs.</context>
      <utterance>God I missed that taste...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate shoots him a look of curiosity. Jack looks back at her, sees the trust in her face...He puts down his fork.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you laughing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to tell you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hears the seriousness in his voice.</context>
      <utterance>I think it may help us but there’s a slight chance it could make things worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I’m worried...just say it. Whatever it is we’ll deal with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. Jack searches his mind for the right words. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack looks to her, expecting the worst. But she just nods reassuringly. He continues...</context>
      <utterance>I feel like I’m living someone else’s life...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to be so sure about everything, you know? I knew exactly who I was and what I wanted. Then one morning I woke up and suddenly it was all different...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worse, you mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack lets out a small smile. Now he’s the one who’s reassuring Kate.</context>
      <utterance>No. Well, maybe a few things. But mostly just different...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never used to be like this, Kate. I had it all figured out. No doubts, no regrets.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her, staring into her eyes, almost desperate for understanding.</context>
      <utterance>Now...I don’t...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A raised eyebrow from Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Me neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it’s good to be a little unsure about who you are. It’s very human.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you always seem so certain.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C’mon, Jack, you think there aren’t mornings when I wake up and wonder what the hell I’m doing in New Jersey...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s a big one for me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My office is a dump, I answer my own phone...and you’ve seen my pay check.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your pay check is a disgrace to pay checks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean yes, I help people that need it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess...some of them are probably faking.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, right there with her.</context>
      <utterance>God, sometimes I think it would be so nice not to have to stretch ground beef or maybe drive a car with a CD player...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Imagine having a life where everything was easy...where you asked for things and people just brought them to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause, then...</context>
      <utterance>It’s wonderful... Kate laughs, nodding.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It’s as if she’s inside his head. They stay like this for a moment, looking into each other.</context>
      <utterance>I think about it, too, Jack. I do. I think about the kind of person I’d be if I hadn’t married you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops a moment, considering. Then...</context>
      <utterance>And...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack nods.</context>
      <utterance>And I realize I’ve just erased the things in my life I’m most sure about. You, the kids...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good things...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks into Kate’s eyes.</context>
      <utterance>What are you sure about?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate smiles at Jack, a loving, secure smile. It’s been a while.</context>
      <utterance>I’m sure that right now there’s nowhere I’d rather be than here with you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack smiles as he opens a champagne bottle sitting on a silver ice bucket...</context>
      <utterance>This is so beautiful...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know champagne makes me do crazy things.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate smiles, clinking her glass with Jack’s.</context>
      <utterance>I’ll just full yours up to the top.  Happy anniversary, sweetheart.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don’t know how you did it, hoss, but you pulled it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m out of the doghouse?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate saunters into the bedroom, looking at the king- size poster bed, feeling the down quilt. Jack follows her...</context>
      <utterance>Way out...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate kisses him...when their lips separate, we can see the powerful effect it has on him. Jack looks deep into her eyes, stroking her hair, lost in her.</context>
      <utterance>You may even get lucky tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You’re so...beautiful...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They kiss again, a long soulful kiss. Then... Jack pulls back, a look of realization on his face...</context>
      <utterance>I already told you you were gonna get lucky, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My god, all this time...I never stopped loving you...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him, their bodies intertwined...hands caressing ...more and more passionate...then reaches behind her to the light. The room goes dark...</context>
      <utterance>That’s all I wanted to hear...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate lifts her head, turning to face Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmm...Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I feel like I should give you money...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate lays her head back on Jack’s chest, looking at Washington Square through the window.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, my god, Jack you were always good but this...this was... like a porno movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could stay here forever...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate lifts her head and looks at him expectantly. They kiss.</context>
      <utterance>I don’t think I’d fight you on that one...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>89A	EXT. CAMPBELL HOUSE - MORNING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack emerges in his work clothes, putting his coat on, a bagel in his mouth... He disappears from frame, the screen door closing slowly behind him... In a moment...Kate appears at the door, a cup of coffee in her hand...she follows Jack with her eyes as he heads to the car. Then...a smile from Kate... In a moment...Jack returns to frame and heads straight into Kate’s arms... ...a passionate kiss as she leans against the door post...</context>
      <utterance>The front door of the Campbell House...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A smile from Jack as she pats him on the ass and sends him on his way...</context>
      <utterance>Have a good day...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the money, they’re hands down the best radial we carry...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I’ll take them...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, a black ROLLS ROYCE SILVER SERAPH pulls into the lot, its front left tire riding on the rim...</context>
      <utterance>You won’t regret it...  Tommy! Set Mr. Conlin up with four B.F. Goodrich G-Force T/A’s...  ...and give him ten percent off for having the best costume...</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jack turns toward the door, but then looks curiously back at the Rolls...something familiar about it... Then...Peter Lassiter gets out of the car...</context>
      <utterance>Jack, Kate on line two! Jack pick up two!</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kate’s on two, Jack.  Nice ride...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you’re into that kind of conspicuous consumption...</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to handle him? I think I’m ready...</utterance>
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack! Kate still holding on line two...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack walks inside...</context>
      <utterance>Sure...be careful, he looks like a tough negotiator...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ESTELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sounded pretty important.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes his hand away from the phone and walks back outside the store...</context>
      <utterance>I’m with a customer. I’ll call her back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>92	EXT. BIG ED’S TIRES - CONTINUOUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...towards Kenny and Lassiter.</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack approaches, tapping Kenny on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I seem to have had some kind of blow out...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don’t you let me take this one, Kenny?</utterance>
   <speaker>KENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kenny nods then heads back inside...</context>
      <utterance>Okay, chief.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter Lassiter...</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly. I’ve seen you on CNBC.  You look taller in real life...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lassiter, sitting on the little chair across from Jack, an intrigued look on his face...</context>
      <utterance>...truth is, Mintz was so busy timing his wife’s breathing he didn’t see that MedTech needed Global more than the other way around. Ten days, two weeks tops, they would’ve approached you with an offer, and I’d bet anything it would’ve been thirty billion, not twenty nine...  Problem was, Peter, you had a pussycat running the show. What you needed was a rottweiler.</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A smile from Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I’m impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack savors the moment, until...</context>
      <utterance>I really am...</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>He’s jarred back to reality, a little crestfallen...</context>
      <utterance>So, about my car...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lassiter nods, then takes a business card out of his wallet.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. We’re going to have to special order that tire. It’ll be ready in about two days.</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A smile from Jack.</context>
      <utterance>This has my office address on it...  Why don’t you drop it off yourself?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack is shaking his leg anxiously under the desk as he eyes the door...</context>
      <utterance>...I say to her, Margarita, we already have four kids, why do we need more?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack checks his watch...</context>
      <utterance>But she say she want an even number. I say four is an even number! But she say she want six.</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tell her, Margarita, I just got my green card, I like to sit back and rest a little bit...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hector...do I usually listen to your personal problems?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack nods, then...</context>
      <utterance>Sure, Jack, all the time...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I have some business that I have to take care of in the city so I’m leaving early...  My advice to you...follow your dreams.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...we’re really more of a boutique operation, as you can see...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk into...</context>
      <utterance>But you’re not interested in boutique dollars...  I get it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MINTZ’S ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lassiter doesn’t even slow down...</context>
      <utterance>He’s expecting you, Mr. Lassiter...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="43">
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mintz, a confident look on his face, gets up from the desk and goes to shake Jack’s hand.</context>
      <utterance>Alan, this is Jack Campbell...the one I was telling you about...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>Jack, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Mintz.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, call me Alan. We try to cultivate a casual atmosphere around here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A chuckle from Mintz.</context>
      <utterance>I can see that, Alan.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have kids, Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another laugh from Mintz.</context>
      <utterance>Uh...actually, yes. Two... good ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack nods, sits down on the plush sofa, Mintz and Lassiter take the chairs.</context>
      <utterance>That’s great...  Why don’t you have a seat?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack’s a little taken aback by the question, not realizing he was walking into an interview... He crosses his legs, trying to get comfortable.</context>
      <utterance>So, Peter mentioned that you were an avid CNBC watcher but didn’t say whether you had any actual Wall Street experience?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was a sales associate, at E.F. Hutton.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A broker? Really. And now you’re in the tire business?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s right. And auto supply...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack nods...</context>
      <utterance>Uh huh. The retail end, I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...we actually get about sixty percent of our business from automotive service.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind if I ask what kind of sales you did last year? Ballpark...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did one point seven million in total revenue...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack pauses, analyzing the situation...the patronizing questions, the smirk on Mintz’s face...</context>
      <utterance>Uh huh...one point seven. And what do you project for this year?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>As Jack stares into their faces, he realizes the extent of his handicap...</context>
      <utterance>Any thoughts at all on that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>He stops, takes a moment, looking at Mintz and Lassiter then ...a confident smile.</context>
      <utterance>Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Alan, I think we’re gonna have a banner year. Sales are up almost twenty percent in the first quarter and we just landed a major trucking company account.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A gleam in Jack’s eye.</context>
      <utterance>Really. So you’re projecting what, a tad over two million?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mintz and Lassiter follow Jack with their eyes as he crosses the room to the desk, pours himself a glass of water...</context>
      <utterance>That’s right. And that would make us number one in our market...  You mind if I stand? A raised eyebrow from Mintz.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I know our paltry little two million in sales is about what you spend on office supplies in a year. And I know some regional trucking company account is nothing compared to a sixty billion dollar merger...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m not trying to knock the tire business, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack’s confidence is throwing Mintz off, but Lassiter appears intrigued...</context>
      <utterance>It’s okay, Alan. I get it. I’m in your shoes, I’m thinking exactly the same thing...but here’s the thing. Business is business. Wall Street, Main Street, it’s all just a bunch of people getting up in the morning, trying to figure out how the hell they’re gonna send their kids to college. It’s just people...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I know people.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m sure you do...</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mintz covers his embarrassment with a smile...</context>
      <utterance>Let’s let the man have his say...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take you, for instance...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks around the office then back to Mintz.</context>
      <utterance>You drink about sixteen Diet Cokes a day. You’re an excellent father, but you feel guilty about the time you spend away from home. You drink bourbon, but you offer your clients scotch...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>A laugh from Lassiter as Mintz sits there stewing, a caught look on his face.</context>
      <utterance>And your wife decorated this office...</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He certainly has your number, Alan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A raised eyebrow from Lassiter, but he’s game...</context>
      <utterance>You’re a little tougher, Peter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For one thing, you like expensive things.</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s easy. You’ve seen my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lassiter’s impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Okay...you smoke Hoyo de Monterreys. You’re a scotch man, single malt, not because it’s trendy but because you’ve been doing it for forty years, and you stay with what works. You have two great loves in your life, your horses and this company. You wept openly the day the Dow hit ten thousand...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you’re a man who prides himself on finding talent in unusual places...</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Oh? And how would you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Lassiter...nodding his head. Mintz, a plastered-on smile.</context>
      <utterance>Because I’m here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Lassiter returns Jack’s gaze with equal intensity. In a moment, he turns to Mintz.</context>
      <utterance>I’m prepared to do anything it takes to get this job. Start anywhere you need me to start. I’ll park cars if I to...  The biggest part of judging character is knowing yourself. And I know this, I can do this job. Give me a chance, Peter, I won’t let you down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LASSITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alan, why don’t you show Jack around a bit...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’d love to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that’s our war room. We did seven major deals last year, three of them hostile.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn a corner, coming into a deserted section of the corridor. Mintz stops, turning to Jack. Jack returns Mintz’s gaze with a quizzical look.</context>
      <utterance>Seven. Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack’s a little taken aback.</context>
      <utterance>Let’s cut the shit, huh Campbell? What, did you go through his wallet or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No matter. That circus act back there may have dazzled Lassiter momentarily but it doesn’t do shit forme. Even if you get this job, which I highly doubt, let me warn you, Lassiter loses interest in his pet projects very quickly. I’m in the big office because I’ve proved myself to him year after year and nobody is going to come in here and start turning the old man’s head. Especially not some tire salesman from New Jersey. So you watch yourself and stay away from Lassiter, and maybe, just maybe, I’ll keep you on after he gets tired of you. Do we understand each other? Jack stands there, staring at Mintz, silent, expressionless.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Then, a broad smile from Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Do we?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now it’s Mintz’s turn to look quizzical.</context>
      <utterance>God, you really are different, aren’t you...  I mean...wow...I am impressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good for you. Why shouldn’t you protect what’s yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don’t think you’re hearing me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack smiles at Alan one more time, then turns...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I’m hearing you, Alan. That’s not the problem. The problem is that what you think is yours, is really mine. And I don’t care how low on the totem pole I start, I will get it back...  So do yourself a favor and don’t get too attached to that view because sometime soon, maybe very soon, you and your French country antiques, your chintz sofa, and your little play pen are gonna be moving out of that office.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack heads down the corridor, whistling a happy tune, leaving Mintz standing there, bewildered.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, and by the way, you try selling tires for a living. I promise you, you’d starve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The place is incredible...marble floors, architectural lines, high tech fixtures, elegant modern furniture... it’s striking but not at all homey like the Jersey house.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to Xanadu...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty incredible, isn’t it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack nods.</context>
      <utterance>It’s like a museum.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what’s the big surprise? You didn’t rent this place for the weekend, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think bigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack chuckles.</context>
      <utterance>For the week?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place is a perk, Kate.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A perk for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate’s confused.</context>
      <utterance>A company called P.K. Lassiter and Associates Investment House uses it to attract new executives...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You’re talking to their new Vice President of Mergers and Acquisitions.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about, Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack measures her reaction. It’s not good...</context>
      <utterance>I’m going into arbitrage, honey. Turns out I have a knack for it. I’ll be making two hundred grand a year plus a hefty bonus and that’s just to start. And, we can live in this apartment practically rent free for as long as we want.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate just looks at him, in shock. Then...</context>
      <utterance>We can finally afford to move back into the city. In style.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you out of your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don’t think so. This is going to be a better life for all of us, honey. We’ll put Annie and Josh in private schools...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Annie goes to a great school.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m talking about the best schools in the country here, Kate...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack, what could you possibly be thinking? What about my job?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is New York City, it’s like the needy people capital of the world. Those Jersey clients of yours aren’t a tenth as pathetic as the ones you could get here...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can’t believe you want to move back into the city. I thought the reason we left was because we didn’t want to raise the kids here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, this is the center of the universe. If I were living in Roman times, I would live in Rome, where else? Today, America is the Roman Empire and New York is Rome itself. John Lennon.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack’s starting to struggle...</context>
      <utterance>Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack’s back on his heels...seeing his dream picked apart...</context>
      <utterance>Look, I’m detecting a kind of funky tension here...We don’t have to live in this apartment. I don’t need this...I’ll commute...I’ll drive to work...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He’s frustrated...he pauses a moment to gather himself. Then...</context>
      <utterance>In traffic? It’s over an hour each way? That’s almost three hours a day. When are you going to see the kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sad chuckle from Kate.</context>
      <utterance>Kate. You’re not understanding me. I’m talking about a great life. A perfect life. Everything we pictured when we were young. The whole package. You said it yourself, life has thrown us surprises, and so we made sacrifices. But now I can finally get us back on track...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can do that. I want to do that. For all of us. I need to do that as a man...  Think about it. No more lousy restaurants, no more clipping coupons, no more shoveling snow...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack’s taken aback by the intensity of her tone.</context>
      <utterance>Then get a goddamn snow blower!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate stands there, wounded...</context>
      <utterance>Don’t get a new career without even telling me. Don’t take Annie out of a school she loves. Don’t move us out of a house we’ve become a family in...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don’t do that...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Kate looks him in the eye – a deep, piercing look...</context>
      <utterance>Look, you’re making this into something it’s not. This isn’t a referendum on our lives, Kate. It’s a step forward...  Don’t you see? I’m talking about us finally having a life other people envy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate picks up her bag and walks out of the apartment.</context>
      <utterance>They already do envy us, Jack...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very nice. What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary Had A Little Lamb.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Annie starts PLAYING again as Jack looks at the dresser. She has 20 or so family photos lined up and down its sides... Jack studies them...in every one Jack’s face is totally contented. Jack studies them, looking at his own face. Annie lowers the bow, watching him... Jack turns to her.</context>
      <utterance>Ah. A classic...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>She smiles, then starts PLAYING again. He turns back to the pictures...</context>
      <utterance>Please don’t stop...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack turns and sees Kate walking into the doorway, standing there...She sees Jack holding the Pan Am ticket sleeve.</context>
      <utterance>From London to New York...?  I came back... Then...a NOISE...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A quizzical look from Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Our finest moment, right...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>She continues into the room, leaning against a bookshelf.</context>
      <utterance>When you got on that plane I was sure it was over. I left the airport afraid I’d never see you again. And then you showed up the very next day...  That was a good surprise...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack watches her as she lets out a small sigh.</context>
      <utterance>I think about you on that plane, about what must have been going through your mind...you sitting there imagining our life together, our life apart...I think about the decision you made...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate smiles gently as she pictures this.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I was being naive but I believed we’d grow old together in this house. That we’d spend holidays here, have g randchildren visit us here. I had this image of us all grey and wrinkly, me working in the garden, you repainting the deck...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Things change, right? People change...  If you need this, Jack, I mean really need this, I will take these children from a life they love, and take myself from the only home we’ve ever shared, and move wherever you need to go. I’ll do that because I love you... The words are like a warm embrace for Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate smiles lovingly at Jack...she walks over to him, kisses him gently on the forehead.</context>
      <utterance>I love you, Jack. And that’s more important to me than our address...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>She turns and heads out of the room, leaving him there, the boarding pass still in hand, staring lovingly at her as she goes...</context>
      <utterance>I choose us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Jack’s anxious face...</context>
      <utterance>Ringing my bell...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the entrance to the store...the door opens, a YOUNG GIRL, 17, enters, an average suburban teenager... She glances at a fashion magazine, picks up a package of gum... From the POV of the cashier, we see the girl approach the counter... On Jack, crouched down in the aisle. He grabs a bag of salt from the shelf, when...</context>
      <utterance>Four ninety nine?! It’s just salt for god’s sake...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Jack registers the voice...he rises slowly, looking over to the front counter...where he sees... Cash, dressed in a typical chain convenience store uniform, ringing up the teenager... An excited smile from Jack at the sight of Cash...</context>
      <utterance>That’ll be sixty five cents, little angel...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then...the color drains from Jack’s face...</context>
      <utterance>You...!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack moves toward Cash at the counter...</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>The girl eyes Jack curiously, then removes a dollar bill from her pocket and slides it across the counter to Cash...</context>
      <utterance>You’re not sending me back...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash reaches into the register, taking out change for ten dollars...he hands the girl $9.35...</context>
      <utterance>Jack, it’s good to see you...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>The girl looks at the money, realizing that Cash has given her the wrong change...</context>
      <utterance>Thank you darlin’...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>The girl looks at Cash talking to Jack...</context>
      <utterance>What do you got there, rock salt? Look at you, all domestic and shit... You really figured some things out, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl hesitates...Cash turns to her...</context>
      <utterance>I’m not going back...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him, a moment of decision, then...</context>
      <utterance>Everything okay...?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash ignores Jack, watching the girl as she heads to the door, hesitates a moment, then walks out... A look of disappointment on Cash’s face as he reaches into his pocket, pulling out a little notebook... Cash looks at Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Did you hear me...?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a character issue...  ...and for nine dollars? That’s just sad...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash looks at him, compassion on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I’m talking to you! I am not going back, do you understand...?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can’t do this. You can’t keep coming in and out of people’s lives, messing things up...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack throws six bucks on the counter...</context>
      <utterance>C’mon, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’ve got kids, I’m going home...</utterance>
   <speaker>CASH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack walks determinedly toward the exit. He stops and turns at the door...</context>
      <utterance>You know what the word glimpse means, J? It’s by nature an impermanent thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cash follows him with his eyes, a proud look on Cash’s face as Jack leaves...</context>
      <utterance>I’m staying.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it morning yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes her eyes as Jack stands there for a moment looking at her, sadness all over his face.</context>
      <utterance>No, honey. Go back to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Finally, he turns to go...</context>
      <utterance>Take care of yourself, Annie. I’m going back to the mother ship...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack approaches her, sitting on the bed...</context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate nods.</context>
      <utterance>These last weeks, Kate, I know that I’ve done some...some unusual things.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It’s been interesting, that’s for sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I’ve done some good things too, haven’t I?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her arms in his hands and looks her in the eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You’ve been Jack Campbell. And that’s always a good thing... She kisses him on the cheek.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to remember me, Kate. How I am right now, right this very moment. I need you to put that image in your heart and keep it with you, no matter what happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay, Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She’s a bit confused but she couldn’t be more in love with him.</context>
      <utterance>Please, just promise me you’ll do that. You have to promise, Kate. Because if you don’t, then it’s like it never happened and I don’t think I could live with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promise, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise me again...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stands up, heading toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>I promise. Come to bed, honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon...</utterance>
   <speaker>114	EXT. SUBURBAN STREET - LATE NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack with Lucy on a leash, walking side by side, his mind elsewhere... Lucy leads him around a corner...to a large open field... Lucy stops. She looks back at Jack, then out to the open field. Jack removes the leash. The dog bounds happily out into the field, looking for just the right spot. Jack puts his hands in his coat pocket...pulls out a half-eaten roll of PEPPERMINT LIFESAVERS, puts one in his mouth... He looks up at the sky, snow gently falling onto his face. It’s cold, but it’s beautiful...peaceful and still...the air clean and crisp... He breathes in the fresh air, the Lifesaver dissolving in his mouth, watching the dog...</context>
      <utterance>Snow begins to fall...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops the phone...turns back over...let’s his eyes stay closed for another moment...then... His eyes open... He looks around...sees his shirtless torso...then his old apartment...tailored clothes on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...okay, send her up...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack looks at the clock, “9:23 a.m.” He gets out of bed, throwing on pants and a pair of shoes, and leaves the room...</context>
      <utterance>Damnit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Waiting for me by the door, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paula opens her coat – the only thing she has on underneath is a sexy little teddy.</context>
      <utterance>Paula...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s totally see through...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stares at her, totally confused...</context>
      <utterance>Christmas? It can’t be Christmas...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack grabs a leather jacket then walks right by a shocked Paula and heads out the door, practically running down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>It’s whatever you want it to be, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAULA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack?...Jack!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Kate here? Does Kate live here?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack starts rapping his head against the door post, much to the shock of the guy standing there.</context>
      <utterance>Kate? No, there’s no one here named Kate. Is that good enough for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn...damn...damn...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...I’m not...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack shakes his head mournfully.</context>
      <utterance>Is there anything I can do for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, my wife’s in the kitchen. You got a cigarette?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack walks off, beleaguered...</context>
      <utterance>I’m sorry, no...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you can’t park that thing here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It’s me, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don’t care if you’re Tim Allen with your fancy car and all your tools, you still can’t park here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me you recognize me, Arnie. Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How’d you know my name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We bowl together. We’re bowlers ...we won a championship...we’re winners.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arnie peers at Jack through the window.</context>
      <utterance>I never won anything in bowling.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a second...  Jack...Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...Jack Campbell...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Jack Campbell. I went to high school with you...you played baseball, right?  You’re doing well...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, that’s it...yes, we went to high school together.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never really talked to me. I wanted to talk to you, man...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...I guess I just wanted you to know, we could’ve been really good friends...</utterance>
   <speaker>120A	INT. FERRARI - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A curious look on Jack’s face, it’s been a while since he’s heard that sound.</context>
      <utterance>Jack driving...a CELL PHONE RINGS.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Santa, where are you? Everybody’s here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Adelle?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Silence from Jack...</context>
      <utterance>You were supposed to be here half an hour ago...the emergency strategy session? Your trip to Aspen? They’re all panicked here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADELLE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D, O.S.</mode>
      <context>Finally, Jack shakes his head, defeated.</context>
      <utterance>Jack...? Are you going through the tunnel?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’ll be there in twenty minutes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up the phone as all eyes in the room turn to Jack, immediately fixating on how disheveled he looks.</context>
      <utterance>Thank god, Jack’s here. I’ll call you right back...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack, are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What’s going on here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at Alan for a minute.</context>
      <utterance>It’s not good. Bob Thomas has secretly been talking to a European drug company. We’re not sure which one, Julia’s on it right now. Word is they’re willing to let him buy a minority stake and keep running the entire company. The Global people are up in arms. They say we should’ve been prepared for this. We’re in trouble here, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alan looks at him, confused.</context>
      <utterance>You know something, Alan. There’s a much more assertive person somewhere inside of you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I think I like you better this way...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sad laugh from Jack.</context>
      <utterance>Is this another one of those Sun Tzu “Art of War” tricks?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack wallows for another moment in his own sadness...</context>
      <utterance>So what are we gonna do, Jack?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack snaps out of it, turning to Alan and the rest of the group...</context>
      <utterance>Jack...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack leaves the office to the shocked stares of his team.</context>
      <utterance>I’ll tell you exactly what we’re going to do. You’re going to do whatever you have to do to find out which European company he’s been talking to. Then I’m going to clean myself up, fly to Aspen, and drink egg nog with Bob Thomas. His wife and kids will be playing in the background while I spend Christmas day convincing him that the European company is the devil and Global is the answer to his prayers, after all...  Then I’m going to spend four hours skiing. Alone. On Christmas day. Completely and utterly alone. I’m going to do that because that is my life, that is what’s real, and there is nothing I can do to change that...</utterance>
   <speaker>122	EXT. BROADWAY - DAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack’s limo makes its way downtown.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack jots something down on a business card. Then he hangs up the phone, thinks a moment, looks out the window, then turns to the driver...</context>
      <utterance>For Manhattan...Kate Reynolds...I need an address too...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make a right here...</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But the airport’s the other way...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We’re not going to the airport...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you from the shipping company?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman looks at him, then walks back inside...</context>
      <utterance>I’m Jack Campbell...I’m an old... friend of Kate’s. I just called.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Beat. Jack waits anxiously at the door. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Kate! Some guy’s here!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S</mode>
      <context>Jack’s eyes come alive as Kate appears wearing jeans and a white blouse...except for her hair, she looks the same.</context>
      <utterance>Did you call the airline like I asked?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kate...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She searches for a kind word, but he looks terrible.</context>
      <utterance>Jack...God, it’s been so long...You look...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look great.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him another moment, then turns...</context>
      <utterance>It’s good to see you...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate walks inside, Jack follows her in sheepishly.</context>
      <utterance>Lori! Where’s that box?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks up at...a beehive of activity – Lori on the phone, boxes stacked everywhere, TWO MOVERS packing up...</context>
      <utterance>Don’t worry about it, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What’s going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’m moving to Paris...it was right here...  It’s a box marked “Jack.” I put it in the stack for the Salvation Army...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paris?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want me to look for the box or call the airline?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, kind of under a little pressure here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack watches this back and forth.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, kind of giving up Christmas day for my ex-boss here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn’t seem to mind offering to help me on Christmas day when you were unwrapping that Prada bag I gave you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate heads over to some tall wardrobe boxes.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it’s by the wardrobe boxes...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You’re moving...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh. To Paris. My firm has an office there and I’m going to be heading it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To Paris. Paris, France.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That’s the one...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you’re not at a non- profit firm?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not with what they pay me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You’re not married, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Jack, I never got married. You?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly...  Can we just take a minute here? Maybe get a cup of coffee or something...?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I’ll go for a cup of coffee!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A relieved smile from Jack...</context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LORI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack’s smile disappears as Kate hands him a sealed box marked, “Jack”...</context>
      <utterance>Congratulations. The La Guardia flight’s canceled but I got you out of Kennedy on United at nine. Am I good or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack stands here, looking at the box, then at Kate...</context>
      <utterance>Here you go. It’s just some old things of yours...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bemused LAUGH from Kate. Then she sees he’s not laughing...</context>
      <utterance>Do you ever think about us, Kate? About what might have happened...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nod from Jack...</context>
      <utterance>You’re serious...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>One of the movers passes by Jack carrying a box... Jack looks at Kate, flush with the realization that this isn’t the same woman he knew thirteen years ago, or left yesterday.</context>
      <utterance>I’ll tell you what, Jack, if you’re ever in Paris, look me up. Maybe we’ll go for that cup of coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves...</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Goodbye, Kate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate turns and sees Jack, a look of puzzlement on her face.</context>
      <utterance>Kate!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can’t go!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don’t get on that plane!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Let’s just go have a cup of coffee. That’s all I’m asking for. I’m sure there’s another flight to Paris tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack just stands there, unsure...</context>
      <utterance>What do you want from me? You want me to tell you everything that happened was okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate turns her back to Jack, leaving him standing there... He watches her walk to the podium, realizing she’s right... He sees Kate reach the podium...hand her ticket to the attendant... Finally, a look of determination crosses his face...</context>
      <utterance>Well it is. Yes, I was heartbroken ...But I got over it. I moved on. People change, Jack. I changed. I don’t know why you suddenly feel the need to revisit that time in our lives but I assure you, it’s over...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kate turns to him with a look that could kill.</context>
      <utterance>We have a house in Jersey!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he continues...</context>
      <utterance>Don’t do this, Jack...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have two kids, Annie and Josh... ...Kate looks at him, half-mortified, half- interested...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack shakes his head, remembering, fighting back the tears...</context>
      <utterance>...Annie’s not much of a violin player but she tries really hard. She’s a little precocious but that’s only because she says what’s on her mind. And when she smiles...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate’s expression has sifted from annoyance to curiosity.</context>
      <utterance>And Josh...he has your eyes. He doesn’t say much but we know he’s smart...  ...he’s always got his eyes open, always watching us... sometimes you can look at him and just know that he’s learning something new... it’s like witnessing a miracle...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack begins walking slowly toward Kate...the world of the airport going on around him, Jack not caring...</context>
      <utterance>...the house is a mess, but it’s ours...  ...well, after a hundred twenty two more payments it will be...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate raises an eyebrow. It’s something she’s thought about.</context>
      <utterance>And you...you’re a non- profit lawyer. That’s right, completely non-profit. But that doesn’t seem to bother you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack gets closer and closer...Kate’s spellbound now... imagining the picture Jack’s painting...</context>
      <utterance>And we’re in love. After thirteen years of marriage we’re still unbelievably in love...  You won’t even let me touch you until I’ve said it...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack walks into a piece of carry-on luggage sitting by a row of passengers...</context>
      <utterance>...I sing to you...not all the time but definitely on special occasions...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack’s nearly there...</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me...  We made a lot of sacrifices, dealt with our share of surprises, but we stayed together...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Not in this life, and Kate knows it...</context>
      <utterance>You see, you’re a better person than I am...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Kate is perfectly still, Jack’s words echoing in her ears.</context>
      <utterance>...and it made me a better person to be around you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>He’s right in front of her. She can’t take her eyes off him.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it was all a dream. Maybe I went to bed one lonely night in December and imagined it all. But I swear, nothing’s ever felt more real to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Silence. Jack and Kate in their own little world...airport business going on around them...</context>
      <utterance>And if you get on that plane right now, it’ll disappear forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>Jack’s words resonate in her ears. He gently touches a hand to her arm...</context>
      <utterance>I know we can both go on with our lives. And we’d both be fine. But I’ve seen what we can be like together...And I choose us...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT’D</mode>
      <context>She stands there, frozen, staring into Jack’s eyes, searching for the answer.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Kate, one cup of coffee. You can always go to Paris. Just please, not tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Jack...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
