<movie id="121" title="Cell The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's a shy child, yet comfortable with Catherine.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You liked him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward smiles, delighted he made her happy.</context>
      <utterance>He's beautiful...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The boy frowns.</context>
      <utterance>But I thought we were going sailing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A devilish glint in his eye, Edward redirects the mirror. Catherine follows the flicker to a TOY BOAT in the sand.</context>
      <utterance>You promised.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Edward shines light in her eyes, momentarily blinding her, then snaps the locket shut. When her vision clears, Catherine sees a GIANT SHIP perched among the dunes. A craft weighing hundreds of tons just sitting there in the desert.</context>
      <utterance>We can't fit into that!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She walks toward it, but Edward doesn't follow.</context>
      <utterance>That'll do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She extends her hand, but he adamantly shakes his head no.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Mister E.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Undaunted, she... finds herself standing on the DECK.</context>
      <utterance>'s broken.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who says?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mocky-Lock.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no... No you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Mocky-Lock is the bogeyman. Mocky-Lock wants me where I am."</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens a rusted iron DOOR. It makes an HORRIFIC SCREECHING SOUND. Similar to metal-on-metal, but more piercing, more pained. As if made by a living thing.</context>
      <utterance>I bet we can fix it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The boy's FACE CONTORTS, turning into something half-human, half-animal. A monster. Mocky-Lock. He SCREECHES, trying to frighten Catherine, but she cocks her head...</context>
      <utterance>Ed-ward...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We agreed. No more Mocky-Lock. The creature sticks its tongue out and DIVES.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But it's too late! Edward/Mocky Lock slithers into the sand and disappears. Resigning herself to a failure, she opens the palm of her left hand, revealing a SMALL BUMP in the flesh between thumb and forefinger. She presses hard and...</context>
      <utterance>Edward!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN THE PROCEDURE ROOM, there is no reaction from Catherine.</context>
      <utterance>Sing a song of sixpence...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sing a song of sixpence...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pocketful of rye...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Catherine's eyes open.</context>
      <utterance>Four-and-twenty blackbirds.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN THE CONTROL ROOM, Henry hits a switch and Catherine is lowered to the pedestal. Miriam checks Monitors displaying Catherine's vital signs and continuing what must be a routine, presses numbers on a keypad to open the PRESSURIZED AIRTIGHT DOOR separating the two areas. IN THE PROCEDURE ROOM, lights come on and Miriam eases Catherine out of the apparatus. She checks her pupil dilation, pulse, throat, and reflexes. She pokes and prods with a familiarity that would seem rude to an outside observer, but is nothing to them. Getting to her feet, we see that Catherine's BODYSUIT is made of an unusual dark fabric almost liquid in consistency. AT THE CONSOLE, Henry moves to another section and for the first time, we see there are two elaborate neural monitors. And the "brain" pictured here is smaller. Younger...</context>
      <utterance>Baked in a pie...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVEAL A SECOND FIGURE suspended from the ceiling in the PROCEDURE ROOM. A SMALL BOY is lowered to the pedestal and as Miriam records data, Catherine removes the child's "mask," displaying the haunted face of Edward. Clearly, the boy is in some kind of catatonic state.</context>
      <utterance>"Mister E." is doing fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did we go sailing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost. Mocky-Lock showed up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Mocky-Lock is the bogeyman, Mocky-Lock wants me where I am."</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry communicates with them via the intercom.</context>
      <utterance>Mocky-Lock is a pain in the ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine looks annoyed - How could he forget?</context>
      <utterance>Where did that come from again?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine detaches the cables and eases Edward's frail body into a waiting wheelchair. Miriam takes a penlight and examines the boy's eyes... An emotionless void, oddly beautiful.</context>
      <utterance>A nursery rhyme.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BUZZER sounds and ANOTHER DOOR HISSES OPEN... A constantly fretting administrator, BARRY COOPERMAN, is waiting for them in the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Anybody hungry? I'm hungry...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We can see it in Catherine's face - this isn't good news.</context>
      <utterance>Edward's parents are here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He needs a haircut.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell the nurse.  God, he loves when you visit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeing an unfunded future, Henry's ready to disassociate himself from Miriam and Catherine...</context>
      <utterance>My husband wonders if that's true.  He wants to place Edward in a hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are other applications for the scanner, Mr. Baines...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I realize that, Henry...  And I know your work, Dr. Kent, is invaluable to this company...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know about me, though, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catherine, we've waited eighteen months for signs of progress...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's been progress.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine is hurt and vulnerable due to exhaustion and the intensity of her experience with Edward, but feels she must defend herself.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but there is no proof the procedure works. All I have is a belief that your interaction with my son is not a hallucination.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You picked me, remember? And I took the job. Gladly. This is the next wave and I want to be part of it...</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one is doubting your ability.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Introspective and solemn-eyed, Lucien takes a moment, then:</context>
      <utterance>Then what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've invested millions of dollars in this study... And I've convinced others to do the same. I suppose I should feel responsible to them, but I don't. I could care less if they see a profit. I'm responsible to my boy, that's all that matters.  You tell me... Am I doing the right thing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine turns, nods, and tries to smile. Has she been crying? Miriam steps further into the room.</context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hates me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine nods.</context>
      <utterance>Lucien Baines?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't say "hates." Dislikes, distrusts, maybe. Catherine laughs. Exactly what Miriam wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She adores you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She thinks I can bring Edward back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine halfheartedly nods, but her mind is elsewhere, focused on the two apparatuses.</context>
      <utterance>Someday you can. We all believe that...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miriam knows what this is about.</context>
      <utterance>I want to try it. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been over this a dozen times. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? Just once. A trial run. What harm could it do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ever the doctor, Miriam finds herself surreptitiously examining Catherine's eyes, flesh tone, a slight trembling in her fingertips.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miriam reaches for Catherine's wrist and takes her pulse.</context>
      <utterance>Why is it taking so long for us to reach him? Because we've been reactive, that's why. And we need to be active.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miriam...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Miriam examines her, Catherine continues:</context>
      <utterance>Shush.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He creates the obstacles, he decides which games to play.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've heard this argument before. It's not happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could take years for me to get past the barriers he's created.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we reverse the feed and bring Edward into your mind, it could be devastating for him. Imagine the shock of suddenly existing in a whole other world.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do it all the time!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but, you're a willing participant. Picture Edward in a strange place, lost, frightened...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd be there for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he might blame you for terrifying him. That one moment could erase all you've accomplished. And if that happened, the trust he has in you is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miriam takes a penlight and examines Catherine's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine nods.</context>
      <utterance>Besides, I don't know what it might do to you. You're already exhausted.  Have you been sleeping?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Catherine shakes her head no. Miriam shuts off the penlight and looks at Catherine with professional and personal concern.</context>
      <utterance>I can prescribe something...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure? Any more nightmares?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. We need you healthy and relaxed. You're going to eat well, meditate, exercise, and watch mindless television.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She taps Catherine's head.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want you up all night reading Edward's case file of the nine millionth time. Balance, dear girl, is the key. Leave the work here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't bring it home in this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miriam gathers her belongings.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry wants me to try this Vietnamese place he's wild about. Want to come?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to feed my cat. Besides, I want to get to bed early.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miriam exits, but Catherine remains, still curious what could happen if things were reversed.</context>
      <utterance>That's my girl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cole nods at a visibly shaken WORKMAN seated in a patrol car.</context>
      <utterance>Who found her?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak sees a FEMALE BODY wrapped in plastic and bound by wire. Supervising the examination of the woman is FBI PATHOLOGIST DR. THEODORE "TEDDY" LEE, a polite, dapper southern gentleman.</context>
      <utterance>Surveyor for the railroad... 'Bout six this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Teddy gives Novak a friendly, respectful salute - "My pleasure." Novak dons gloves, nods to an FBI PHOTOGRAPHER and assists Teddy Lee in snipping wire and peeling back thick clear plastic. As the photographer reacts to a strong smell, Teddy comments.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for waiting, Teddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEDDY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the man snaps pictures, Ramsey and Cole join them. Sadly, Novak recognizes the face.</context>
      <utterance>Bleach.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We recognize her, too.</context>
      <utterance>Anne Marie Vicksey.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She the one from Santa Cruz?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Teddy expose the bleached flesh of her torso, neither man surprised. Coldly thorough, Novak finds another of the killer's tell-tale signs.</context>
      <utterance>Just graduated law school. Single mom. Had a two-year-old daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>FLASH! Photos are taken.</context>
      <utterance>The semen on her legs and abdomen.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEDDY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone looking after her little girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak looks into the dead white eyes of Anne Vicksey, trying to imagine the horrors she beheld. He moves to the creek and sees only a few inches of water. His eyes move from the drop site to the highway above.</context>
      <utterance>Grandparents. Live over in Davis.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEDDY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLASH! We're up there now, ON THE OVERPASS, with the photographer and Novak, examining TIRE TRACKS in the soft shoulder. Novak peers over the edge at the crime scene, steps back, and focuses on the highway - imagining the killer's truck as it disappeared into the night.</context>
      <utterance>The poor thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TALK RADIO HOST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voice on the radio becomes DISTORTED as we hear it through Stargher's ears...</context>
      <utterance>...complaining about government subsidies for farmers...</utterance>
   <speaker>TALK RADIO HOST</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The host's voice fades into a guttural, monstrous groan.</context>
      <utterance>...but without subsidies, families will starve, and I'm nodd exagggeerrrrr....ayding. Iff id werrrr up tooooo meeeee.....</utterance>
   <speaker>TALK RADIO HOST</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He opens his eyes and watches John kiss Julia goodbye as she returns to work. Stargher looks down and we see what he's been working on - A TOY DOLL. Female. Stripped of its clothes, a single metal ring stuck through its plastic neck.</context>
      <utterance>Meeeee gawwwwwdd Caaaarrrrlll. Mee god cum...  Meeeee....wwuuuuuddunnnnttttt... be spending billions on other countries when we've got problems right here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak checks his watch and the street. Clearly waiting for someone or something.</context>
      <utterance>Well, honey, what's worse? Doing it yourself or asking your mother for help?  Can it wait 'til I get back/  I have no idea, Jeannie.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ramsey snaps shut the cell-phone.</context>
      <utterance>Well all right. Good luck with the Monster. I love you too. Bye-bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Novak is oblivious, pouring over tire-related info.</context>
      <utterance>We call Jeannie's mother "The Monster" because, well... she just is.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you could care less about my personal life, Peter, but I do appreciate the occasional, "How's your wife, Gordon?" He waits. Novak obliges:</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak is distracted by Teddy Lee entering the diner.</context>
      <utterance>Pregnant. Thanks for asking.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramsey assesses the exhausted, lonely, intense man sitting across from him.</context>
      <utterance>Damn, man, I give up. Your partner tells you his wife's gonna have a baby, and all you care about is a coroner's report!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Much to Novak's appreciation, Teddy Lee's arrival provides an escape from answering the question.</context>
      <utterance>I feel for those girls too, Pete. And their families. But it's just a job. Someday it'll be over. And then what'll you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEDDY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives them copies of the AUTOPSY REPORT and FORENSIC ANALYSIS of Anne Marie Vicksey. The WAITRESS sees Teddy, approaches, and offers a menu.</context>
      <utterance>Hot off the presses.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEDDY LEE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chicken fried steak, mashed potatoes, garden salad with Thousand Island dressing and an iced-tea. Thank you darlin'. She nods and moves to the kitchen. Novak and Ramsey flip through the documents.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEDDY LEE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Water in her lungs. Same brand of bleach. Match on the semen. Lots of hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEDDY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramsey checks his copy.</context>
      <utterance>Anne Vicksey didn't own a dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEDDY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TEDDY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak and Ramsey stand over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Complete absence of melanin.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Teddy moves aside and takes another bite of his lunch (chicken fried steak now carry-out).</context>
      <utterance>And that means?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The dog's an albino.  He'd love an animal like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEDDY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, I believe an albino dog is rare indeed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STARGHER'S HANDS COME AT HER FROM BEHIND! One grabs her hair and the other covers her face with a chloroform-soaked towel. He presses so hard, she cannot scream, cannot move. After a brief struggle, he SHOVES her into her car and holds her until she passes out. Stargher pushes Julia into the passenger seat and starts the car. Pulls a dog treat from his pocket and WHISTLES. The Shepherd instantly perks up. Perfectly healthy. And jumps into the car.</context>
      <utterance>God... I didn't see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chatter dies.</context>
      <utterance>Donna Krozin.  Helen Francis, Teresa Manicki...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Every person is solemn and focused.</context>
      <utterance>Antoinette Simms, Natalie Pagels, Grace Cassatt... Anne Vicksey.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He's hooked them. The victims, these women, now mean something to them. With great effect, he holds up grisly post-mortem photos.</context>
      <utterance>Smart, gentle, attractive young women. Just starting out in life. Embarking on careers, going to school, getting married...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Everyone knows this is a real clue and awareness is heightened. Ramsey chimes in.</context>
      <utterance>They were killed. Kidnapped, tortured, and murdered. By a white male. About 30-years old.  Who owns an albino dog./</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak shows them a picture of a WHITE GERMAN SHEPHERD taken from a resource on the Internet.</context>
      <utterance>A purebred German Shepherd.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Breeders typically destroy albino pups, so this animal is truly unique.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nicole Labetzki. Victim seven. Forensics found dog hair in her car, but they had a K-9 unit at the scene and never had it checked.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEDDY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Phoenix office tested that hair thirty minutes ago. And we got the match.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramsey holds up a thick list.</context>
      <utterance>It's his dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The list is long and a few of the cops GROAN. Novak silences them with a fierce look that says, "I will not rest until this man is found and neither should you."</context>
      <utterance>Registered breeders of German Shepherds.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A DESK SEARGENT enters the room and hands a FAX to Ramsey. Novak is curious about it, but continues.</context>
      <utterance>Be thorough, but be fast. This guy's accelerating. He only waited six days this last time. When he started, two months could pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Gravely concerned, Ramsey moves across the room.</context>
      <utterance>This can mean different things. He thinks we're stupid and can't catch him. He's having fun and needs more. Or...  This dog hair thing is sloppy. The body this morning was found in less than three inches of water. He knew we'd find her. He wants to be caught. But if we can't stop him...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...he can't stop himself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DISTORTED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The VOICE echoing inside his skull.</context>
      <utterance>Me god feed on pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>DISTORTED VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pain good. Cumm home to meee...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was still living at home?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HICKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were looking at apartments.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, you came to pick her up when?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight o'clock. We were going out for my birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. HICKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak hides the doll.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you made a mistake. Maybe she... she...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramsey's cell-phone rings and he excuses himself to a corner of the room, leaving Novak alone to deal with this uncomfortable, sad situation, no one saying a word until an emotionally shattered Mrs. Hickson, fingering a rosary, feels compelled to tell him.</context>
      <utterance>No sir. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After three years she remembers what the guy drove?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She remembers because it was her "dream truck." Wanted one just like it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STOCKWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They nod and he directs them to a waiting GMC SUBURBAN.</context>
      <utterance>Ramsey, Novak?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOCKWELL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Stockwell.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>STOCKWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Edison. Just east of Loma Park. SWAT's had the house under surveillance for about twenty minutes.  Suspect is Carl Rudolph Stargher. No registered weapons, no priors. Got a license for his dog, though. Named him Valentine...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have they seen him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak is careful with his answer.</context>
      <utterance>No. There's been movement in the kitchen. But it could be the dog.  You think she's in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We proceed assuming she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's give old Carl a call. Tell him he's got company.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  Can you get a man close?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ERICSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm at the back door.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROCK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ericson maneuvers his way to the kitchen window and uses a MIRROR to sneak a peek. In the REFLECTION we see a motionless man lying on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Check the kitchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a man down. Repeat, man down.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROCK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ericson chances a quick visual check and pops his head up before reporting.</context>
      <utterance>Stargher?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't see his face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERICSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points for someone to secure the animal and MOVES into the KITCHEN, aiming his gun at the man on the floor, finally getting a look at his face.</context>
      <utterance>I've got the dog!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>No problem there. Stargher appears lifeless. As various SWAT team members secure the house, Ericson removes his mask and CUFFS Stargher, startled at the sight of the horrible RINGS piercing his back.</context>
      <utterance>Carl Stargher! Do not move!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERICSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramsey pushes through and Novak informs him.</context>
      <utterance>Paramedics. NOW.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STOCKWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll take him to County General. Reid's already there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stockwell nods and follows the stretcher outside. A stoic Ramsey enters from the living room and Novak can see the disappointment in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Make sure he stays cuffed. Two men on him at all times. I don't want anyone treating him but Reid. Not so much as a thermometer up his ass. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak would give anything for that not to be true.</context>
      <utterance>She's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should come downstairs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>REID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Minimal activity in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex. And here, the anterior cingulate cortex.  It's what helps distinguish between external and internal stimuli.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEDDY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak doesn't like this. Not one bit.</context>
      <utterance>He's schizophrenic.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing here, Reid? Paving the way for his insanity defense?</utterance>
   <speaker>REID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No need. There won't be a trial. This is no act. The coma is real.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa. Wait a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>REID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clearly not.</context>
      <utterance>You ever hear of Whalen's Infraction?</utterance>
   <speaker>REID</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Novak's worry intensifies.</context>
      <utterance>In any schizophrenic, these areas would be affected. But in someone with Whalen's, they're hit hard and hit fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>REID</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stargher's neurological system was infected by a virus in utero. It lay dormant. In his case for about...  ...thirty years. Most likely, he's exhibited symptoms for awhile now, but the infraction - the breach - didn't occur 'til today. You never know when it'll happen, at what age, or why. The triggers vary, but the results don't.  He has no ties to reality. No awareness of this world or the people in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TEDDY LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Thorazine? Or... Desoxyn?</utterance>
   <speaker>REID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The normal psychotropics don't work. He's not just catatonic, he's... disappeared. Like having a dream and never waking up.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This girl. Julia Hickson. Only he knows where she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>REID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak is past angry. He's bordering on devastation. Ramsey attempts to placate him.</context>
      <utterance>Then I'm sorry. For her and for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll go back to his house, Pete. There's still a lot to do. Analyze the videos, track sales of the bleach, go through his records. Maybe he owns property somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramsey backs off, knowing his partner is on the verge of really losing it. Reid thinks perhaps he shouldn't, but sensitive to Novak's pain and anger, mentions it anyway - if only to keep his friend from true hopelessness.</context>
      <utterance>They're in that fucking thing for forty hours, Gordon. Four-oh. He got Julia at seven-thirty last night. You know what time it is now...?!</utterance>
   <speaker>REID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter? This is a longshot. I mean a real long shot. You're gonna think I'm crazy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>AT THE TREE TRUNK, Catherine extends her hand and suddenly Edward is there, quite close, reaching out. Catherine's hand trembles. The boy is startled.</context>
      <utterance>It's fixed!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Her hand tenses and shakes uncontrollably.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not signalling...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sing a song of sixpence...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Edward is frightened by what's happening and runs away. Catherine tries to call out, but her throat constricts, making speech difficult.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not signalling!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sing a song of sixpence.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pocketful of fucking rye.  What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did we stop? Cooperman appears in the window and explains.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked them to.  We have a situation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did he lapse into the coma?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John tries to keep his composure, but Novak's making this tough for him. Novak wants the scientists to see, to understand the boy's pain.</context>
      <utterance>Sometime yesterday morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Each tape is the same. He provides food, drinking water, a toilet. Periodically, a shower starts. It's on some kind of timer - he's clever with machines, building things. I think he wants them to believe this is a simple kidnapping. That there's a possibility of rescue. Of survival. But it's just a form of torture. At the end of the fortieth hour, the drain shuts. The water starts and doesn't stop.  We've already lost more than a day. If she isn't found tonight. She dies like the rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John and Ella Baines - as well as the Sunerset Board of Directors - have given their approval, but the decision is yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the legalities of this...?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stargher is in custody. The functional equivalent of being under arrest. Normally, we'd Mirandize him, and if he didn't lawyer up, we'd interrogate him. But because of his condition, he doesn't have the capacity to waive those rights.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what you're asking us to do is illegal?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not at all.  We're dealing with exigent circumstances. Somewhere there's a kidnapped woman still alive. If we weigh the suspect's Constitutional Rights against the public safety. The Law favors the victim and gives us a lot of leeway. It's called the Public Safety Exception.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what can you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miriam, Henry and Cooperman appear to be onboard. Novak's made a persuasive, heartfelt argument. Only one person still remains uncertain.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty much anything we want. There's a chance to save a human life. Because of that, Stargher has no reasonable expectation of privacy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes turn to her.</context>
      <utterance>What if...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if he wasn't like this? What if he was "normal?" Conscious. How far would you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine nods, analyzes Novak's eyes, gestures, body language, and "interrogates" him.</context>
      <utterance>As far as I needed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John's discomfort is increasing and Novak is sensitive to it.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think he'd tell you what you need to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's always a chance they'll confess.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? I don't work with violent cases, I work with children. But even a kid lies. They love it when they get you to believe something that isn't true. Don't you think Stargher would do the same?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes... Once they've been caught they feel a need for disclosure. They have so much they want to tell. But they've never had a sympathetic ear. They need someone to understand why.  Stargher used to hide the bodies very carefully. It was part of the ritual. Some weren't found for weeks and any physical evidence had been meticulously wiped clean. But these last three... They were still in water - always in water - but  Listen, he wasn't just careless. It went beyond that...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Let's assume he wanted you to find him, that some part of him hated what he was doing... Most likely, that part is dead. Schizophrenics with Whalen's Infraction sever all ties with the real world. I'm sorry, I really am.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it possible?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he came to trust me, yes, but it takes months to build that kind of trust. Someone like Stargher can't distinguish between fantasy and reality. It's all the same. He might tell me she's in Timbuktu and absolutely, one hundred percent believe it to be true, but she's...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They turn to John Tracy. His vulnerable, barely audible voice forcing everyone to listen.</context>
      <utterance>Julia.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Catherine hangs her head. And finds herself looking at photograph of the girl in question. A smiling Julia Hickson looking right at her.</context>
      <utterance>Not "she." Julia. Not thing, or it, or her. Do you know anything about her? Do you know what we've been through? Julia is everything to me. Can you say that about anyone?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FBI TECH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quantico. San Diego Field Office. S.D., L.A., and San Francisco P.D. California, Arizona, Nevada State Police. Nine and ten are open lines.  Direct link to the chopper.  That gets you into the Bureau Database.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Once he's gone, Ramsey takes this moment "alone" to question his partner.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you want to go through with this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else do we do?!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Pete, but for god's sake... This is nuts. Do you really understand what they're going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why jeopardize what we've already done? We caught the sonofabitch. Carl Stargher. That's going to be like Bundy, Gacy, Dahmer. A case that makes careers. But if we push our luck. If this is all bullshit and we come out smelling like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what. If this thing burns us, I take that heat. I give you permission to point your finger at me and say "It was all his idea."</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words are anathema to Novak.</context>
      <utterance>That's not what I'm talking about, Pete. I'm talking about waking up and realizing this girl's gonna die.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cooperman appears in the doorway and informs them...</context>
      <utterance>That won't happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOPERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramsey looks to his partner, but Novak is already on Cooperman's heels. Resignedly, Ramsey follows.</context>
      <utterance>They're ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't we get a catheter in him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(getting him out of her hair)</context>
      <utterance>They took care of that, thank you, Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Proud of his computer, but uncomfortable around strangers, Henry directs Novak and Ramsey to the console.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you give our guests a little tour?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Although he's listening, Novak's eyes never really stray from his prisoner as Miriam uses safety scissors to cut away Stargher's clothes.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, you stand before the one and only Neurological Cartography and Synaptic Transfer System.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Novak observes Miriam as she "undresses" Stargher and Ramsey pokes around the lab.</context>
      <utterance>It provides a highly detailed map of the human mind. Not the brain - any MRI can do that. The mind.  It reads and processes electronically allowing information to be transferred and interrupted.  Let's say your thoughts could be stored on DVD. If someone had the right kind of player, they could watch and listen to what you're thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Miriam needs a moment to fully take in the scars. Henry continues, eager to focus attention back to him, but even he is fascinated by Stargher's skin.</context>
      <utterance>But we can't record or store the data. The connections between nerve cells are constantly being modified.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Miriam gives Stargher an alcohol bath, the clinical procedure taking on the quality of ritual. Her wash cloth moves under Stargher's chin and over his face. She's careful around the eyes and finds herself unable to look at them for long.</context>
      <utterance>It's like the early days of television. The subject sends out a live feed and you receive it during time of broadcast. Whatever happens, happens. All you have to do is "tune in."</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Catherine enters from a dressing area wearing the bodysuit. Filled with curiosity, Novak watches Miriam and Catherine fit Stargher into his suit.</context>
      <utterance>But you do more than tune in... You become part of the snow.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still don't understand why I can't do this... This isn't some "troubled kid" you're dealing with.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I realize that...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine and Miriam try to hide their laughter.</context>
      <utterance>How hard could it be...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first... What? Six or seven times I went in. Remember what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Disorientation, nausea, migraines, hallucinations, insomnia, paranoia.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like a New Year's Day hangover.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak and Catherine roll Stargher onto his stomach.</context>
      <utterance>He needs to be turned over.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This man is deeply disturbed, he...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know the procedure.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a series of EIGHT BANDAGES.</context>
      <utterance>That may be true, but you don't have Catherine's gift. She...  What happened here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miriam peels away a bandage and examines the flesh.</context>
      <utterance>We removed eight metal rings.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine connects Stargher to the SUSPENSION APPARATUS and it HOISTS him off the table.</context>
      <utterance>Then he should like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Henry catches Ramsey poking his nose near a THIRD SUIT AND APPARATUS in the dressing area.</context>
      <utterance>They're comforted by the feeling of weightlessness. Like floating in water.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch that, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miriam prepares a series of CHEMICAL CARTRIDGES and loads them into a container connected to the IV-like tubes linked to the suspension device.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't your responsibility. Remember that. Don't let them use guilt as a tool. If you want to stop, say so.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine focuses on the procedure and makes the necessary connections. Reluctantly, Miriam retreats to the monitoring station. She "locks down" the procedure room and joins Henry, Novak, and Ramsey at the console.</context>
      <utterance>She said convincingly.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the stuff?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About twelve years of research, right Miriam?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't remind me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's like asking her to explain the rules of cricket.</context>
      <utterance>What is it - are they - exactly?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramsey is utterly lost and just sort of nods, but Novak is fascinated. Catherine presses the bump on her hand. A RED INDICATOR LIGHT flashes on.</context>
      <utterance>Psychostimulants, serotonin, stabilizers, meprobamate, Neurontin, lithium carbonate. And my baby. It duplicates and expands upon the effects of a chemical called oxytocin, forcing a break in the neuron connections that hold experience. So new experience can form.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine presses again and the red light shuts off.</context>
      <utterance>There's a touch-sensitive microchip implanted in her hand. If she becomes frightened, disoriented, or simply wants to end the session, she signals us to abort.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine and Stargher are suspended from the ceiling. Henry types and the lights dim to a more somber, tranquil level. Various screens flicker to life, displaying the vital signs of both "feed" and receive." Miriam initiates the injection program.</context>
      <utterance>Although none of what she experiences is real, she can be tricked into thinking it is. The mind is awfully gullible, so she needs to monitor herself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catherine? I'm about to start. If you want me to wait, or...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN THE PROCEDURE ROOM, we see chemicals mix with her blood, then feed the IV. AT THE CONSOLE, as Henry types furiously at the computer keyboard, Novak asks Miriam:</context>
      <utterance>No. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Overhearing, Henry interrupts, pointing at a section of Catherine's "mind map."</context>
      <utterance>You said she has a "gift."</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a gift. A highly evolved area in her cerebral cortex, that's all. A genetic fluke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hopeful, solemn Novak gazes through the window, watching Catherine's body as it becomes parallel to Stargher's... IN THE PROCEDURE ROOM, Catherine takes a deep breath and as the drugs take effect, feels herself losing consciousness. She glances at Stargher, a man who tortures and kills women, then looks up as the CLOTH MASK descends from the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Catherine has a tremendous capacity for empathy.  When we started, there were a number of test subjects - other therapists - who acted as "receivers." All they did was observe and report. Nothing more. But Catherine, she had the ability to feel what was happening. She understood. And the patient responded. Edward engaged her in dialogue, took her places, showed her things. He knew she cared.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Intravenous administration complete.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We follow fibrous wires running from Catherine's mask to Stargher's. Their blood mixing with chemicals in the IV-like containers. The computer system humming.</context>
      <utterance>Initiating connection.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Catherine's eye focuses on the mask. As it comes closer, we see the lining is laced with thread-like wires and microchips forming hyper-miniature circuit boards. Catherine's eye blinks. The mask covers her face. Catherine's eye shuts. Vision fades. Darkness. A faint light. Microscopic veins in the eyelid become wires connected to chips. And we're MOVING, into the circuitry.</context>
      <utterance>Transfer begins 1100 hours, 34 minutes, 12 seconds.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The frightened child retreats into a corner of the claustrophobic room, but the horse does not startle. Surprisingly - to the boy - the horse takes an affectionate step toward Catherine, inviting her to take over. Catherine allows the mare to smell her, then vigorously scratches along the mane and shoulder, much to the horse's delight.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She can see the boy hiding in the corner, stealing glances at her from the shadows.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you like that, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The boy - YOUNG STARGHER - is startled and intrigued by the question - How did she know that?! - but says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Is your name Carl?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The boy reacts to an unusual SOUND coming from the CEILING.</context>
      <utterance>Another little boy I know, he has a horse, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The boy takes a few steps toward her, out of the shadows, but he seems more concerned about something in the ceiling than "connecting" with Catherine. Very anxiously, he looks at the wall behind Catherine and watches an old wind-up kitchen TIMER click down.</context>
      <utterance>His name's Edward. The boy, not the horse...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Again, a sharp SOUND from the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, Carl?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Young Stargher RUNS at her and SHOVES her hard! Catherine FALLS BACK just as EIGHT SHEETS OF GLASS drop from the ceiling! Like oversize razor blades, they slice the horse into four clean sections. They separate and compact the quadrants until four glass-contained sections of dissected horse stand within the room. Catherine SCREAMS, but the mare barely acknowledged what happened. Betraying no emotion, the boy runs. The shaken Catherine takes a moment to collect herself, then gives chase.</context>
      <utterance>What's wro---?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Novak looks at an INTERCOM SPEAKER.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Novak doesn't wait for his just-stirring partner and moves.</context>
      <utterance>She's back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noting Novak's confusion, Henry points to a CENTRAL MONITOR resembling a futuristic V.U. meter, gradiated in sections of white, yellow, orange, and red.</context>
      <utterance>Must've been rather unusual.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't talk about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Theoretically, while she's inside. If she came to believe that Stargher's world is her world, her mind has the power to convince the body that anything done to it is, um, actually done. Novak doesn't like the sound of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why we monitor the use of the drugs so closely. We don't want her getting to that degree of perceptual disorientation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry types a command and Novak speaks into the intercom.</context>
      <utterance>Pump in two liters of pure oxygen, please Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN THE PROCEDURE ROOM, Miriam eases Catherine back to consciousness.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Kent?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When she sees Stargher, Catherine's flesh crawls.</context>
      <utterance>Deep breaths.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it cold in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Incapable of being in the same room as him, Catherine tears out of the apparatus and anxiously exits.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catherine!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Edward Baines, I presume.  Hi, Ed. I'm Pete.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think that's funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine nods. Novak picks up Edward's fallen teddy bear and rests it in the crook of the child's arm.</context>
      <utterance>No. Not at all. From what I understand, he knows I"m here, isn't that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I read about a woman in TExas who was in a coma for seven years. Every time her husband came to visit, her heart would beat faster. Isn't that something? I don't know what name scientists have for something like that...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't have much to do with science.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What then?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The soul. The spirit. Whatever you want to call it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She appreciates his understanding. And finds herself comforted by his presence. Catherine scrutinizes Novak, his intensity, his honesty, his complexity. And asks:</context>
      <utterance>Ah, the part of us that can't be explained.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Novak?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Peter, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The question catches Novak off-guard, but he's willing to answer. Anything to get her talking.</context>
      <utterance>Do you feel there's a side of yourself you don't show people?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.  I suppose everyone does.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like we all have fantasies, right? Things only we know, that we don't share.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine laughs. It helps her relax. If only slightly.</context>
      <utterance>That's what therapists are for, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is difficult for her.</context>
      <utterance>During the sessions. When I'm inside. I see those things. What a person hides, what they despite, what they want to control. With Stargher...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With Stargher I saw things...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses Edward's forehead and exits.</context>
      <utterance>A kingdom. His utopia. Life without consequence or restriction. He's not even Carl Stargher anymore. He's this... idealized version of himself who can do anything he pleases... Without fear. A horrible primitive ugly thing.  I don't want to talk in here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why'd you bring him here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the shrink, you tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak nods. Guilty.</context>
      <utterance>As soon as I met him, you knew I'd say yes. He makes Julia real for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine looks at him with disbelief. "You?!"</context>
      <utterance>It's an old lawyer trick. Target the emotions. Do it right, you get a reluctant witness to testify, a scared kid to confess.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Catherine can see the pain and frustration in Novak's eyes. She gives him a moment and asks:</context>
      <utterance>Before I was with the Bureau, I was an attorney, a prosecutor. Mr. Law and Order. And then... I had a murder case in North Carolina. Charles Gish. Butchered seventeen people in three days. And because of one tiny piece of tainted evidence, he walked.  That's when I quit the DA's office and joined the FBI.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You thought Stargher wanted to be caught.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak's curiosity is piqued.</context>
      <utterance>You were right. There's a part of him that knows the truth. About what he did, about himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Julia?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is going to sound terrible, but... I don't think she matters anymore. Not to him. He never finished her. The others...he was able to make them his.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you can do this, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He might tell me about Julia. The part of him that wants to help, that feels shame and remorse. Who wants to be redeemed.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Stargher we're talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not Stargher, not really. He's split himself right down the middle. Good/evil, right/wrong, merciful/cruel. A monster. And an innocent child. If I could reach the boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa. Hold on. Aren't they the same guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you feel there are different sides to every personality? Maybe even the worst of us is capable of one decent act. We're all human.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hard for me to see Stargher as human, capable of something like "remorse."</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you believe that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe this is a big fucking waste of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak doesn't respond. She prods him.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to Charles Gish?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What difference does it make...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>God, he does not want to do this.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right after the trial, the night after he was released. Mr. and Mrs. Frank Simmons found Charlie sitting in their living room watching TV with their twelve-year old daughter Margaret. He'd cut her right down the middle with a carving knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He can see Catherine doesn't accept that.</context>
      <utterance>Found the girl's heart in the freezer - he thought they might want to keep it.  Luckily, the next thing he did was slit his own throat.  I am convinced of one thing. Charles Gish could've been raised by Ozzie and Harriet and the same thing would've happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A child can experience abuse worse than Charlie's. And grow up to be someone who would never, ever hurt another living thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine realizes that was a confession.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They turn to see Ramsey.</context>
      <utterance>Where the hell you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time, tell me, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramsey shoots him a murderous look, then asks Catherine.</context>
      <utterance>But you looked so cute. All sleepy...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak looks to Catherine for the answer. Through the window blinds, she watches John Tracy lower his head.</context>
      <utterance>Your colleagues want to know what to do with Stargher.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ramsey nods and heads back to the lab.</context>
      <utterance>Tell them to prep him. And that I'll be right there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Briefly, he touches her hand. Catherine looks away from John to Novak's hand, to the photographs on the wall. Stargher's house, Valentine, the pick-up truck. Valentine...</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FBI K-9 AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak signs a document and the K-9 Agent exits.</context>
      <utterance>Sure wasn't like that with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dog picks up a scent from the procedure room and moves it, Catherine and Novak following. IN THE PROCEDURE ROOM, Stargher lies face down on a gurney. Now taped to the wall near Stargher are PICTURES from the basement - his dolls, the hoist, etc. Miriam (in surgical mask and gloves) carefully re-inserts the METAL RINGS (taken from an FBI EVIDENCE BAG) into the eight straps of flesh on his back. When he sees this, Valentine whimpers and hides. Catherine comforts him. Miriam finishes her task and removes her mask.</context>
      <utterance>You're a good boy, aren't you, Valentine?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate to admit it, but there's something perversely satisfying about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine runs to his "sleeping" master and barks at Catherine as if asking for help. She encourages the animal to lick and sniff Stargher's face and hands.</context>
      <utterance>I think that's the whole point.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>IN THE CONTROL ROOM, he scrutinizes the monitor showing the detailed "map" of Stargher's brain.</context>
      <utterance>That's interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>IN THE PROCEDURE ROOM, Catherine readies herself in the "receive" apparatus. As Stargher is lifted off the pedestal, the doors HISS shut and Valentine curls up on the floor beneath his master. As Catherine is lifted, she smiles at the animal, then looks to Stargher.</context>
      <utterance>Increased neural activity in the frontal lobes. Rising dopamine levels in the basal ganglia. Ever since the dog walked in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, Julia Hickson is priority number one. Nothing else matters. Find out where she is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LIGHTS FLICKER. Catherine's eyes shut. FADE TO BLACK...</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>LIGHTS FLICKER. We hear an ELECTRICAL HUM rise and fall. Catherine opens her eyes and the LIGHTS blink on and off in a weird pattern, making it difficult to see clearly.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her suspension apparatus DESCENDS on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Don't kid around, Henry...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Catherine moves toward the electrical panel.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not. It's a power problem. I need you to go to the circuit breaker and check switches six through twelve.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try to stay awake, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she moves toward the panel, everything becomes larger. By the time Catherine reaches the circuit breaker, it is the size of a garage door. Curiouser and curiouser... She turns around to see the LABORATORY IS EMPTY and DEAD QUIET. And she sees herself - Catherine as small as a mouse trapped in a giant walled space. AT THE CONSOLE, Novak, Miriam and Henry observe the procedure room. And Catherine. Suspended in the apparatus. Motionless...</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, yeah. I'm not sleepy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out from the darkness, moving in normal motion, comes the white German Shepherd, but in the thick haze, his face is indistinct and ghostly.</context>
      <utterance>Valentine?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And as she steps toward him, his face DISSOLVES into a STARK LANDSCAPE. An ear becomes a hill, the nose a stone, mouth a path, and the eye a HOUSE. YOUNG STARGHER retreats towards the bleak structure as CATHERINE ENTERS FRAME. Seeing the invitation, she presses on.</context>
      <utterance>Hi sweetie...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Catherine enters the claustrophobic house, the boy hesitantly pushes a towel toward her, but doesn't look. She reaches the counter and starts to dry, much to Young Stargher's relief. As he washes, Catherine hands him a MIRROR LOCKET just like Edward's.</context>
      <utterance>Need some help?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He's hypnotized by the thing, his eyes lighting up.</context>
      <utterance>Carl, I want to give you a present.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She shines reflected light onto the walls. Carl hands Catherine the wet plate and takes the locket. The dish slips from her fingers and SHATTERS on the floor. The boy's eyes fill with dread. The kitchen clock reads 5:30. He PUSHES Catherine toward a broom closet and shoves her inside.</context>
      <utterance>If you need me, or if you feel that I'm around but can't find me, just shine it, like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>With a finger to his lips, he pockets the locket and shuts the door. FROM WITHIN THE CLOSET, she watches the terrified child through a CRACK in the door. IN THE KITCHEN, Young Stargher desperately tries to hide the broken plate. Startlingly, his father, Martin Stargher, is already in the room. Cruel, imposing, manipulative man.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young Stargher backs into a corner, fearing what will come.</context>
      <utterance>What did you do know? You make a mess? I hate a mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>IN THE CLOSET, Catherine pushes, but the door won't budge. She POUNDS. IN THE KITCHEN, we hear no sound.</context>
      <utterance>Don't lie, now, Carl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember what I said about liars? Liars will be punished.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a TOY DOLL. Drunk, she hugs and kisses him. Embarrassed, the boy tries to squirm away.</context>
      <utterance>I got you a present, cutie-pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Martin enters and sneers at the boy.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no. You're not going anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go back to bed, worm.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay, we was just.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman cowers, familiar with his violent moods. The boy hurries to his room, but Martin grabs him by the collar.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, cunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He pulls the doll from the child's hands, turns to the woman, and SMACKS her across the face with it, gashing her cheek.</context>
      <utterance>What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Terrified, she shakes her head "no." Martin sees Young Stargher quietly crawling away, hoping to escape. Martin lifts the boy off the floor with one hand and holds him in front of the woman.</context>
      <utterance>You give him nothing. Whore. Are you his mother? ARE YOU?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The poor boy trembles with fear. And Martin notices a puddle of urine on the floor. He drops the boy and laughs.</context>
      <utterance>You see that? SEE IT? You slithered out one of them. But where is she now, Carl? As far from you as she could get, that's where.  You want a mommy? Is that what you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Humiliated, Carl covers himself and hides in a corner. Martin and the woman LAUGH AND LAUGH, delighting in the boy's humiliation.</context>
      <utterance>Little worm pissed his pants.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and we see Carl is bound to a wooden support beam, a piece of tape covering his mouth. The boy is stripped to the waste, barely conscious, face streaked with tears and sweat.</context>
      <utterance>Only girls play with dolls...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of thing are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She turns, and Stargher is no longer at the sink.</context>
      <utterance>She was the first...</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She turns, where's this voice coming from?! She steps back.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't know what I was doing...</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The bumps into the stainless steel bowl and it topples to the floor, spilling its contents of human organs. Wobble-wobble wobble. The bowl makes its now-familiar noise.</context>
      <utterance>Be careful...</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And she can see him coming out of the shadows. Catherine backs into a corner, fearing what will come.</context>
      <utterance>What did you do now? You make a mess?</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Stargher steps into a pool of light, shooshes the puppy into the hall, shuts the bathroom door, and looks right at Catherine.</context>
      <utterance>I hate a mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>God almighty, what does she say? What does she tell him?!</context>
      <utterance>Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>SCRITCH-SCRITCH-SCRITCH. The puppy scratches at the door and whimpers, but Stargher's not about to let him back in. Moving slowly, carefully, he approaches Catherine.</context>
      <utterance>Don't lie, now...</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Catherine makes a break for the door. "Playfully," Stargher makes a half-hearted attempt to block her, but she evades him and reaches for the knob. But the door's not there. SCRITCH SCRITCH-SCRITCH. She can still hear the dog, but there's no damn door. She turns: No door. No window. The girl's body and bloody remains have vanished. An OVERHEAD LIGHT flickers on, giving the room the look and feel of the cell.</context>
      <utterance>Liars will be punished.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Catherine turns, back to the wall, calm and intimidating, Stargher stands in the center regarding her with great curiosity. Catherine's ready to press the sensor.</context>
      <utterance>Where do you think you're going?</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Don't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>How did he know?</context>
      <utterance>If you go away, you'll never find her.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Catherine stops and listens. She can't leave now. The path to Julia has appeared.</context>
      <utterance>If you never find her, she dies. Like the rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He reaches for her and she flinches. Expecting such behavior, Stargher grins.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, that's why you're here, right? Why you came to my happy little home?</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Catherine cannot show her fear, not now. She composes herself and approaches him.</context>
      <utterance>You're pretty. A pretty, pretty thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His grin broadens to a smile and he almost laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I want to help you, Carl.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine stands her ground.</context>
      <utterance>Help me? That's good. That's a good one.  Liar. Whore. Cunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets close to her face and sneers.</context>
      <utterance>You sound like your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stargher retreats into the shadows, but Catherine persists.</context>
      <utterance>I am not like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then help me. Where is Julia Hickson?</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe, because you want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right? You think you know me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>And when he emerges from shadow, Stargher is STARGHER KING.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna know who I am? You stupid bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine moves to touch the sensor in her hand. He GRABS, LIFTS and SLAMS her onto the floor, the back of her head HITTING HARD. Her vision blurs. Ears are ringing.</context>
      <utterance>Now shud you mouth, priddy thing, or me god slice you from the kunt to the tits.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Stargher King straddles Catherine and pins her arms behind her back. She's unable to touch the sensor. With the tip of the TOOL he traces a line from her pelvis up the center of her suit.</context>
      <utterance>Me god want you stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He shoves the tool through her neck and presses the trigger. A COLLAR CLAMPS SHUT around Catherine's neck and... She blacks out.</context>
      <utterance>Me god mek you beaudiful...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN THE PROCEDURE ROOM, VALENTINE BARKS! Startling everyone. The dog GROWLS and backs away. As if he senses something horribly wrong within his master. IN THE CONTROL ROOM, Novak questions the scientists.</context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we got here, you just topped and pulled her out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mercy. Novak's mind reels.</context>
      <utterance>That was with Edward. She's accustomed to his world. Stargher's mind is unfamiliar territory. She's "lost."  Someone has to go in. Remind her what's really happening. And get her out. Until then, she's at his mercy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Into Stargher. Inside...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak knows who that person will be.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE GLASS, we watch her through one-way glass from the video camera's point-of-view. She looks right at "us," in the mirror, saddened by the dark circles under her bloodshot eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come, thy will be done.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>We drift to the right and see the l.e.d. counters CLICKING AWAY. 01:44:54, 01:44:53, 01:44:52... Less than TWO HOURS to live and she has no idea.</context>
      <utterance>...on Earth as it is in Heaven.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have done this, you know. Been inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miriam nods, knowing he won't accept an opposing argument.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN THE OBSERVATION ROOM, Henry adjusts monitors showing Novak's vital signs.</context>
      <utterance>Deep breaths.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN THE PROCEDURE ROOM, Miriam asks:</context>
      <utterance>Pulse is rapid, pressure's a little high...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nervous?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She loads a MICROCHIP SENSOR into a high-pressure injection gun and IMPLANTS it in NOVAK's HAND. He winces from the brief pain as she loads the chemical cartridges.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to ask you some things... Are you taking any prescription drugs?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prevacid. For my stomach.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any psychiatric medication?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about narcotics?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know your partner's here, but it's very important that you're honest.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am. I'm a pretty boring guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry checks the "maps," Catherine's vitals and reports.</context>
      <utterance>I doubt that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miriam walks Novak through what's about to happen.</context>
      <utterance>We should hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a supportive touch on the shoulder, exits and shuts the door. IN THE OBSERVATION ROOM, Miriam continues via intercom.</context>
      <utterance>The first five minutes will be disorienting. Give yourself time. Let the drugs do the work. If you can see, smell, feel, hear, taste things - you're on the right track. Once you've acclimated, try to get a feeling for Catherine. Instinct plays a huge role in this. Trust it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>IN THE PROCEDURE ROOM, Novak flexes his fingers and sees the little bump beneath his flesh.</context>
      <utterance>You can control how you see yourself - clothes, shoes, that kind of thing - but the rest of it is up to him. Use only what he provides. Don't try to change anything. Or introduce something of your own. It'll only upset him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Novak does and the red light comes on. As Novak is LIFTED, he looks at Catherine, then Stargher. Valentine YIPS and settles beneath Novak. The suspension device clicks into place and the MASK descends.</context>
      <utterance>Agent Novak? Press the sensor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Novak's eyes fix on the clear liquid contained in the IV-like cylinder. A liquid cloud of his blood grows within. Preparing the mixture for injection. The viscosity of the fluid starts to thicken and the CAMERA MOVES INTO THE MIXTURE. As blood and chemical swirls take shape, we MOVE FAST. Deeper into the fluid at a molecular level. We feel like we're SOARING over some kind of liquid landscape. NOVAK HYPERVENTILATES. He's having difficulty making the 98 transition. Flying faster, faster, faster. Through an entire universe. Novak is in the procedure room. Alone. His face contorted as if feeling the effects of tremendous G-FORCE.</context>
      <utterance>No matter what happens, Peter, remember one thing: It's not real.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOTHER ONE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Novak finds the first of the three - VISIONS OF STARGHER'S MOTHER - addressing him. She, like the other two, speaks in a ghostly monotone, nearly devoid of emotion.</context>
      <utterance>Have you seen him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER ONE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As she continues, almost mantra-like, WOMAN TWO BEGINS:</context>
      <utterance>My boy, my little one. His father took him from me. Have you seen him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The women's repetitive "monologues" overlap. Aurual layers now added by THREE.</context>
      <utterance>My child is an abomination. He is damned. He has no soul.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER THREE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak takes a moment to absorb his surroundings. The sights, sounds and feel of the place. Like being within a dream. As he backs away from the odd quartet, SHIMMERING LIGHT dances across his face. Shading his eyes. Novak searches for the source. Opposite him, across the valley, is a SHEER ROCK WALL. A massive cliff face pockmarked with rough "windows." Like a star, the LIGHT sparkles inside one of them, a fragment of MIRROR reflecting a beam away from Novak's face to a PATH cutting across the valley floor to the base of the wall. The light guiding him, Novak follows the path and starts to CLIMB, finding stairs or ladders, passing deep, seemingly infinite passages. Like tombs, or the "drawers" of a mausoleum. Deep within one of them, THE LIGHT FLICKERS. Fades. And Novak crawls into darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Me god me boy. Me god good son.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like an ethereal queen of the damned, she strides toward him, narrowing her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Not real...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She exhibits no recognition of her name. Catherine seductively moves closer to Novak, their bodies almost touching, her hands caressing his hair, lips, neck...</context>
      <utterance>Catherine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She presses her finger to his lips and forces him down, onto the floor, his back to the pedestal. Catherine straddles Novak, and when he tries to stand, she holds him down, forcing him to stay.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Catherine. Listen to me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stargher King's fingers pass over an array of horrific instruments - the throat piercer/collar mechanism, a cleaver knife, a misshapen hammer, a long slender needle...</context>
      <utterance>You're Catherine Young. You majored in Psych at UC San Diego. You work for Sunerset Industries.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Stargher King lifts the blade-like NEEDLE. So far, Catherine looks at Novak like he's speaking gibberish.</context>
      <utterance>Your grandmother raised you after your parents died in a car crash...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Stargher King SLICES through Novak's clothes, exposing the flesh of his abdomen.</context>
      <utterance>When you were twenty-one, you were arrested for possession and got off with community service.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Stargher King cuts his flesh and INSERTS the needle into his stomach. NOVAK SCREAMS! This fucking hurts!</context>
      <utterance>I know this because I work for the FBI. Peter Novak, remember?!?!  Remember. You are Cath-</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Stargher King wiggles the needle, pulls it out, and digs his finger into the wound. NOVAK CRIES IN PAIN.</context>
      <utterance>Help me!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The intensity of Novak's cries hit Catherine like a thunderbolt. There's a glimmer of life, of recognition in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Fucking FEELS real!</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Although we don't see it, we HEAR something awful. Like Stargher King fishing around inside the wound. A pale, sweating Novak tries to stay conscious. He will not go into shock...</context>
      <utterance>Me god gut you like a dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A FEMALE HAND grabs the tool from the tray.</context>
      <utterance>Not real. Not real. Not real.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nod reel, nod reel, nod reel...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she won't listen and he's forced to play catch up as she moves further from the den toward the cliff face. The FLICKER OF LIGHT shines on the entrance to a specific TUNNEL.</context>
      <utterance>Like hell "wait."</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants us to follow. The little boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little boy?! That's him!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He brought you to me, didn't he? If you want Julia to live, trust me. Trust him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He so desperately wants her affection, but fear prevents him from reaching out to her.</context>
      <utterance>Carl...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Scared, he shakes his head "no."</context>
      <utterance>This is Peter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She extends her hand. Oh-so-hesitantly he takes it.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be scared. You're my friend and I would never hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Shyly, hesitantly, he nods. She smiles gratefully and affectionately touches the boy's face. Clasping her hand, Young Stargher leads Catherine and Novak into utter darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Will you take us to her? To Julia?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head and buries his face in her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Carl, do you know? Like on a map...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As a frustrated Novak searches for anything identifying, Catherine comforts the boy and looks deeply into his sad, haunted eyes.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay, it's okay. You helped so much already. I'm proud of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The boy leans against her and she caresses his face.</context>
      <utterance>Carl, I think I can help you. Would you like that? Even if Peter can't find Julia, I want to help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Novak finds himself standing in front of the idealized cell. Mounted beneath the glass is a shiny, perfect metal plaque reading CARVER INDUSTRIAL EQUIPMENT, with a logo. Novak recognizes it from the hoist in Stargher's basement.</context>
      <utterance>I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her to her feet. Feeling betrayed and rejected, the child breaks away from her. THE ROAR OF STARGHER KING shakes the cell. Terrified, the boy searches for a place to hide.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everything happens fast. He and Miriam frantically cease the procedure. Novak and Catherine are lowered and Novak startles them by quickly regaining consciousness. Miriam attempts to inject him with stabilizing drugs, but he's already trying to tear himself out of the apparatus.</context>
      <utterance>They're back.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miriam MOVES into the PROCEDURE ROOM.</context>
      <utterance>Get me out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak is not listening. Fighting off any after-effects- both physical and mental - he moves for the door.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Catherine is coming back and Miriam moves to her. Novak pauses just for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Agent Novak!</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak is already gone.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. But you're going to sit down right now. I have to...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to find something in the basement...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Already there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE FOLLOW Cole as he moves to the machine.</context>
      <utterance>That hoist, with the winch...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cole locates it.</context>
      <utterance>There's some kind of plaque, a metal plate, with a logo. On the base.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carver Industrial Equipment.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dizziness and disorientation again hit Novak. Pale and sweating, he winces as his stomach agonizingly cramps.</context>
      <utterance>Find out the history of that machine. Who bought it, used it, sold it. And check Stargher's pay stubs. I want to know every contractor he worked for. I'm calling you from the chopper in ten minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ, man, you look like hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fighting the pain, he gathers together MAPS, slips on his shoes and grabs gun and holster. Ramsey is apoplectic.</context>
      <utterance>Considering where I've been...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak points to the photo of Stargher's basement, specifically the hoist.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa-whoa-whoa. Mind telling me what the fuck is happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're bettin' the farm on something you saw after they pumped you full of god knows-what kind of shit?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw her. Julia. Alive. I saw everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak is not stopping...</context>
      <utterance>You might've seen Jimmy Hoffa dancing with Timothy Leary. I don't care.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...a pocketful of rye.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four and twenty blackbirds...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT THE CONSOLE, on a security monitor, Henry can see Novak and Ramsey exiting down the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Baked in a pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IN THE PROCEDURE ROOM, Miriam appears concerned.</context>
      <utterance>The FBI has left the building.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine encourages her.</context>
      <utterance>Agent Novak. I didn't get a chance to clear him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Miriam hurries to catch Novak, she tells Henry.</context>
      <utterance>Go. I'm fine. Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, but isn't really paying attention. Catherine turns to Stargher's motionless form, still suspended, still connected to the machinery.</context>
      <utterance>Keep an eye on her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see chemicals flow and computer programs initiate the procedure, but Henry is oblivious.</context>
      <utterance>...there was a moment when we thought we'd lost Agent Novak as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He JUMPS when the door to the procedure room SEALS SHUT and mechanisms HUM.</context>
      <utterance>His post-procedure consciousness recovery was remarkably quick. Never saw that before. Hey, remember that one time...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>When he looks through the window, Catherine is again suspended, the procedure under way.</context>
      <utterance>Catherine?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He types in a command, but nothing happens. He tires again. On another keyboard, but gets no response. When he looks at the "map" screens, he sees something odd. It's a small change, but it makes all the difference in the world.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She changed the codes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would take hours to re-route the system, and even if I did, I shouldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miriam analyzes the situation and regretfully, angrily, worriedly realizes what's happened.</context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's done it. Stupid, stupid girl...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAMSEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Done what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Instead of going into his mind...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's bringing Stargher into hers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The boy turns toward the voice and finds CATHERINE, her hair waving in the wind, skin glowing, eyes bright, cutting a magnificent figure in clothes that make her a warrior goddess. She opens her arms and the boy runs to her, basking in the comfort of her embrace. He shivers and she holds him tightly.</context>
      <utterance>You're all right, Carl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She looks deeply into his eyes and reassuringly explains.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay, honey, you're with me now. You're safe here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promised I would help you, and I always keep my promises.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine is astonished and relieve to hear him speak. A sad, trembling little voice.</context>
      <utterance>Can...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She is touched that he would ask and strokes his face.</context>
      <utterance>Can I stay here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He slowly turns to her.</context>
      <utterance>But what if I told you you could come visit?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Young Stargher's eyes open wide with silent terror. Over his shoulder, she sees a SNAKE slither through the pool. CENTIPEDES CRAWL over her legs and hair. She stands and brushes them off. The atmosphere grows darker and ominous.</context>
      <utterance>I'll make sure it happens, Carl. I'll get them to let me do it. And maybe... maybe we can...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine bristles as STARGHER KING RISES FROM THE POOL like a human serpent. The brilliant colors of Catherine's world fade to GRIM TONES.</context>
      <utterance>He found me...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Stargher King SCREECHES with anger and confusion.</context>
      <utterance>He always finds me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snarls when he sees Catherine.</context>
      <utterance>Where thiisss att?!?! Me god no like id here...</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Young Stargher tightens his embrace of Catherine. She steps back, away from the pond, hugging the boy tightly.</context>
      <utterance>You. Priddy bish-hor-kund. You big trubble-mekker...  And you. You cumm home now, liddle cogsugger worm. Or me god haffa punish you...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.!</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stargher King laughs.</context>
      <utterance>No?!??!?!?!?</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He comes close and reaches for the boy...</context>
      <utterance>Hoo you thing you are?? Himm Muther?</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>For a moment, Catherine appears frightened and intimidated. Perhaps near an emotional breakdown. But that is not the case. She quietly lowers little Carl to the ground and whispers something in his ear. As the boy nods, runs and hides, a ferocity grows within her.</context>
      <utterance>You gimme liddle worm.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like a vengeful Valkyrie, she emits what can only be called a BATTLE CRY! STARGHER ATTACKS! Arms reaching for her. Catherine BLOCKS, PUNCHES, AND KICKS. Stargher King doubles over. Catherine grabs his ears and pulls his face into her bent KNEE, breaking his nose.</context>
      <utterance>I said no.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As blood flows from his nostrils, Stargher King grins...</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to my world.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HE CHARGES. At the right moment, Catherine sidesteps and SMASHES him in the ribs as he passes. Stargher King crumples to the ground and she KICKS an uppercut to this chin. Rising from the mud and muck, Stargher King lands a POWERFUL BLOW to her head, sending her flying. He lifts the stunned Catherine with one hand and pulls her face to his...</context>
      <utterance>You funny. You thing you stop me god?</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Catherine looks into his soulless eyes. Then SPITS in them and BITES his face! She breaks free as he YOWLS with pain. He steps toward her, but his feet don't move. The earth itself appears to wrap around them and turn hard, like concrete. Stargher King HOWLS with frustration.</context>
      <utterance>You cum back wif me god. You be good bish-hor-kund...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SHIMMERING KNIFE seems to enrage from within her forearm, out the flesh and into her hand.</context>
      <utterance>My world...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She SLASHES across his chest, drawing blood.</context>
      <utterance>My rules.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Catherine stops. And turns to see the distraught Young Stargher.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She spins around and sees not Stargher King, but MARTIN.</context>
      <utterance>Don't hurt him!</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Disturbed by the transformation, Catherine backs away. Her vision blurs, the sound distorts. And the earth cracks around Stargher King's ankles.</context>
      <utterance>He didn't mean it. I was bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fighting feelings of disorientation, she kneels before the child and rests the knife on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>He teached me a lesson. I deserved it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches out to him, but the child is JERKED into the air by Stargher King. In one hand, the monster holds little Carl. In the other - a KNIFE. His face and chest red with crimson, Stargher King fixes his eyes on Catherine with a predator's stare.</context>
      <utterance>No one deserves it, Carl. No one.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stargher King raises the blade toward the boy's throat and - SNAP! The strong arms of an adult Stargher breaks his arm at the elbow. Both the knife and boy are dropped to the ground as Stargher King YOWLS like a stuck pig, the good arm cradling the other.</context>
      <utterance>Yer world. My knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me god hurt! Why you do that? Why?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stargher King regards him with disgust.</context>
      <utterance>Enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARTIN STARGHER'S VOICE comes from the belly of the beast.</context>
      <utterance>Enuff?!?!</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stargher and Stargher King square off. The boy stands between them with the knife at his feet.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you what's enough...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carl!</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>the child picks up the blade and stands between them, looking to Catherine for guidance.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up cunt.  Give it here, worm...</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he DRIVES the thing into Stargher King's heart. For a brief moment, Martin's face is superimposed over Stargher King's. Stunned, he slumps and regards adult Stargher with sad, troubled eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stargher TWISTS the handle of the blade and Martin/Stargher King drops dead. Dead. Young Stargher smiles and hugs Catherine.</context>
      <utterance>Why? What'd I do?...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time to go 'way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy runs to adult Stargher who lifts the child into his arms and holds him close.</context>
      <utterance>Carl...?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG STARGHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks to adult Stargher and begins to understand. He descends into the pool, the boy resting his head on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>STARGHER KING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Man and boy disappear beneath the water's surface. Catherine stands and sees that Stargher King's body has vanished. She walks to the shore and sees, deep underwater, Stargher and little Carl floating lifelessly like women in the cell. And FADE FROM VIEW.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Catherine. You did help me. More than you'll ever know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She presses the sensor in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye Carl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine quietly returns to consciousness and is automatically lowered. She pulls the mask from her face, rises and opens the door. Miriam races inside and desperately attempts to revive Stargher. But it's no use. Angry and stunned, she demands of Catherine.</context>
      <utterance>He's in full arrest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But Catherine chooses not to. She knows Carl Stargher will never return to the world of the living.</context>
      <utterance>Help me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Novak? Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cole?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Delano?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. And guess who they hired to seal up the place?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding me.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak locates Delano on the map.</context>
      <utterance>I never kid. My wife hates it. Says I'm too serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pilot grins and pushes the copper to top speed.</context>
      <utterance>The exact location, Cole. Give it to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine nods, but she's more interested in the movie. Miriam deposits prescription bottles onto a side table.</context>
      <utterance>I left the nutritional information on the fridge door. Read it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I refilled the Zyprexa and Atavan...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need them anymore...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she leaves them just the same.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll come by tomorrow after work. With dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks Miriam. Say hi to Henry and...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...give a kiss to Edward.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The women exchange smiles and Miriam exits.</context>
      <utterance>Give a kiss to Edward.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Novak.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Kent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're looking well.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks you. Six weeks off does a body good.  I heard she got the approval to try the reversal with Edward.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak opens the rear compartment of the Suburban and we hear something moving inside.</context>
      <utterance>Federal Bureau of Investigation, ma'am. We know all, see all...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the patient.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awaiting his arrival.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the cat?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miriam's pager BEEPS and she hurries to her car.</context>
      <utterance>Completely unaware.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRIAM</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Novak smiles, waves goodbye, and reaches into the Suburban.</context>
      <utterance>I've got to go. Good luck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine cradles her cat.</context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door and escorts a leashed VALENTINE into the living room. Catherine's cat squirms from her arms and hides under the couch.</context>
      <utterance>Ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That went well.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak unleashes the albino Shepherd and he runs to Catherine, licking her face, wagging his tail.</context>
      <utterance>Give her a minute.  Hello, Valentine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine picks up the cat's scent and sniffs around the base of the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely.  Abigail...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard Julia and John got married.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep. Eloped.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine settles on the floor. Slowly, Abigail's curiosity gets the best of her and she creeps out, sniffing the dog's nose. Patient and sweet, Valentine lies still, allowing the cat to reach an acceptable level of comfort.</context>
      <utterance>Good for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well look at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you. You have to be optimistic. Believe in them...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amazingly, Abigail brushes up against the dog and purrs.</context>
      <utterance>So you say.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catherine laughs. She likes that.</context>
      <utterance>All yours. My boss says it's one of the strangest requests the Bureau's ever had.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He also says that until proven differently, Julia Hickson was found as a result of good old-fashioned detective work.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's painfully clear the thought of it still troubles her.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I think it does.  You know, Catherine... If you ever want to talk about it. What happened to Stargher. That last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Novak doesn't push it. He just takes her hand and gives it a gentle squeeze. The cat dashes into the kitchen and Valentine follows.</context>
      <utterance>Not just yet. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves into the kitchen. In a moment of quiet introspection, Catherine looks at the television screen, at Dorothy accidentally hitting the wicked Witch with a bucket of water, causing her to melt. And she looks away, unable to watch, disturbed by the image. She turns to the kitchen and sees Novak feeding an appreciative dog and cat. He rises and returns to the living room.</context>
      <utterance>I got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOVAK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles and nods, gently resting his hand on her shoulder. Catherine shuts her eyes and leans toward him, comforted by simple human touch...</context>
      <utterance>No. Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
