<movie id="445" title="Private Life of Sherlock Holmes The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WATSON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guards find a battered tin dispatch box with the name JOHN H. WATSON, M.D., painted on it. They remove it from the shelf, set it down on a table. The box is tied with heavy cord, the knots sealed with wax. Strung on the cord is the key.</context>
      <utterance>Somewhere in the vaults of a bank in London is a tin dispatch box with my name on it. It is not to be opened until fifty years after my death.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While one of the guards dusts the box off, the other cuts the cord with a pair of scissors. He then inserts the key in the lock, turns it, raises the lid -- revealing the dusty contents of the box.</context>
      <utterance>It contains certain mementos of my long association with a man who elevated the science of deduction to an art -- the world's first, and undoubtedly most famous, consulting detective.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WATSON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cab draws up in front of 221B. The front door opens and MRS. HUDSON, a plump, motherly woman in her fifties, wearing an apron, hurries down the steps. She greets Holmes and Watson warmly as they alight.</context>
      <utterance>He was the most brilliant man I have ever known -- and I dare say people have envied me for sharing that flat with him in Baker Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cabbie starts to unload their luggage. As Holmes, Watson and Mrs. Hudson proceed inside, CAMERA TRAVELS UP THE FACADE OF THE BUILDING, past the number 221B, to the bay window on the second floor.</context>
      <utterance>I'll grant you he was stimulating -- but he could also be moody, unpredictable, egocentric, and more often than not, completely infuriating -- as our landlady, Mrs. Hudson, can attest -- bless her kind soul.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do wish you'd give me a little more warning when you come home unexpected. I would have roasted a goose -- and had some flowers for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has picked up a dagger, starts opening his mail, which is on the dining table.</context>
      <utterance>My dear Mrs. Hudson -- criminals are as unpredictable as head-colds. You never quite know when you're going to catch one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits into one of the bedrooms. Watson has now taken a magazine out of an envelope.</context>
      <utterance>I'll unpack your bags.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the cover is a colored illustration from the story, featuring in obligatory Inverness and deerstalker.</context>
      <utterance>Here's an advance copy of Strand Magazine.  They've printed 'The Red-Headed League!'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to see how I treated it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can hardly wait. I'm sure I'll find out all sorts of fascinating things about the case that I never knew before.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just what do you mean by that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, come now, Watson, you must admit that you have a tendency to over-romanticize. You have taken my simple exercises in logic and embellished them, exaggerated them...</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I deny the accusation.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have described me as six-foot-four, whereas I am barely six-foot-one.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bit of poetic license.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have saddled me with this improbable costume, which the public now expects me to wear.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not my doing.  Blame it on the illustrator.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've made me out to be a violin virtuoso. Here --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>6.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- a request from the Liverpool Symphony to appear as soloist in the Mendelssohn Concerto.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, really?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fact is that I could barely hold my own in the pit orchestra of a second-rate music hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're much too modest.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have given the reader the distinct impression that I am a misogynist. Actually, I don't dislike women -- I merely distrust them. The twinkle in the eye and the arsenic in the soup.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's those little touches that make you colorful --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lurid is more like it. You have painted me as a hopeless dope addict -- just because I occasionally take a five per cent solution of cocaine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A seven per cent solution.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five per cent. Don't you think I'm aware you've been diluting it behind my back?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a doctor -- and as your friend -- I strongly disapprove of this insidious habit of yours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses the letter down is disgust.</context>
      <utterance>My dear friend -- as well as my dear doctor -- I only resort to narcotics when I am suffering from acute boredom -- when there are no interesting cases to engage my mind.  Look at this -- an urgent appeal to find six missing midgets.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up the letter.</context>
      <utterance>Did you say midgets?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six of them -- the Tumbling Piccolos -- an acrobatic act with some circus.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Disappeared between London and Bristol ... Don't you find that intriguing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Extremely so. You see, they are not only midgets -- but also anarchists.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anarchists?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By now they have been smuggled to Vienna, dressed as little girls in burgundy pinafores. They are to greet the Czar of all the Russias when he arrives at the railway station. They will be carrying bouquets of flowers, concealed in each bouquet will be a bomb with a lit fuse.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. The circus owner offers me five pounds for my services -- that's not even a pound a midget.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. And it sounded so promising --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has crossed to the desk, suddenly notices something.</context>
      <utterance>There are no great crimes anymore, Watson. The criminal class has lost all enterprise and originality. At best they commit some bungling villainy, with a motive so transparent that even a Scotland Yard official can see through it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(even angrier)</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Hudson!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes? What is it? What have I done now?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is something missing from my desk.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Missing?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something very crucial.  You have been tidying up against my explicit orders.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I made sure not to disturb anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dust, Mrs. Hudson, is an essential part of my filing system. By the thickness of it, I can date any document immediately.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She demonstrates with her thumb and forefinger.</context>
      <utterance>Some of the dust was this thick.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He blows the feather away.</context>
      <utterance>That would be March, 1883.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you stand this? Why don't you let me air the room out?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Mrs. Hudson -- he's working on a definitive study of tobacco ash.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure there's a crying need for that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In our endeavors, it is sometimes vital to distinguish between, say, the ashes of a Macedonian cigarette and a Jamaican cigar. Sor far he has classified 140 different kinds of ashes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is now pulling on the rope which lowers the dumbwaiter.</context>
      <utterance>All of which will end up on my rug.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That'll be enough, Mrs. Hudson.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's right. I am suffocating.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me open a window.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not from lack of air -- from lack of activity. Sitting here week after week -- blowing smoke rings -- staring through a microscope -- there's no challenge in that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>contribution to scientific criminology... Holmes has opened his violin case and taken out his fiddle.</context>
      <utterance>Personally, I consider it a major</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How I envy you your mind, Watson.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has tucked the violin under his chin, starts to improvise a nervous pent-up melody. There is nothing amateurish about it -- he plays quite well. Watson resumes working on his manuscript. Suddenly the music stops. Watson looks up apprehensively. Holmes has put down the violin, and is crossing to the sideboard. He opens Watson's medical bag, takes out a bottle of cocaine, starts toward his bedroom. Watson pushes the writing arm to the side, rises from his chair.</context>
      <utterance>It's placid, imperturbable, prosaic. But my mind rebels against stagnation. It's like a racing engine, tearing itself to pieces because it's not connected up with the work for which it was built.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes pays no attention, continues into the bedroom. Watson crosses to the open door. Inside the bedroom, Holmes has put down the cocaine bottle on the washstand, and is rolling up his left sleeve.</context>
      <utterance>Holmes --</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holmes, where is your self-control?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From a drawer he takes a morocco case, opens it, removes a hypodermic syringe.</context>
      <utterance>Fair question.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you ashamed of yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has removed the stopper from the cocaine bottle, and inserting the hypodermic needle into it, starts to draw up the liquid.</context>
      <utterance>Thoroughly. But this will take care of it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only reason you moved in with me is to have a steady supply of stimulants.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts into the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Now, now, Watson -- you mustn't underestimate your other charms.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holmes, I warn you. If you lock yourself in there once more --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the hypodermic out of the drawer in the washstand, starts back into the living room with it.</context>
      <utterance>I intend to do nothing of the sort.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Watson glares at him, the door opens and Mrs. Hudson comes bustling in. Holmes hides the hypodermic behind his back.</context>
      <utterance>Not until you replace this needle. It is getting rather blunt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made you some tea and cress sandwiches.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Hudson, I want you to pack my bags.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going away for the weekend?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And beyond. I'm moving out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(she looks at Holmes)</context>
      <utterance>Moving out?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just as surprised as you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Hudson sighs, exits into Watson's bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>You heard me, Mrs. Hudson. And let's not waste any time.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I be so bold as to ask where you'er going?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know yet. But I intend to resume my practice. I am, after all, a doctor. And quite a competent one, if I say so as shouldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson is glancing around the room, searching for something.</context>
      <utterance>You'll find it very dull -- snipping out tonsils and flushing out kidneys --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're looking for your medical bag, you hid it under the Moorish table.  Which shows a little more imagination than last time -- when it was under your bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will, of course, continue to pay my half of the rent until you find someone to share these rooms with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I going to find anyone who will put up with my rather eccentric habits?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes out three bottles of narcotics, puts them on the mantel.</context>
      <utterance>Here's a fresh needle -- and here's my farewell present to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snaps his bag shut, carries it toward his bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>If you want to destroy yourself, go right ahead. But I won't sit by and watch you doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson disappears into the bedroom, slamming the door. Holmes looks after him, then looks at the bottles of dope on the mantelpiece. He starts pacing. After a moment he stops at the chemistry table, studies the assorted glassware on the shelves above.</context>
      <utterance>Watson...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Hudson takes a clean handkerchief from the open valise, blows her nose.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Mrs. Hudson -- none of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll wash this and send it on to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be at Brown's Hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know how it feels -- I once went through a divorce myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I'm rather looking forward to it. Leading a normal life again. Regular office hours -- nine to three -- and if occasionally there's an emergency call in the middle of the night, I know it's going be appendicitis and not an ax murder. Let Holmes go mucking about in the fog and the sleet, looking for a bloodstained collar-button out on the moors, with some demented hound snapping at his behind -- From the living room comes the sound of a revolver shot. Mrs. Hudson screams and Watson looks off in alarm. Then he races out of the room, diploma in hand, followed by Mrs. Hudson.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson jerks Mrs. Hudson back as Holmes lets go with another shot. The bullet disposes of the third bottle, splattering glass and liquid all over the place. Holmes rises calmly from the stool, crosses to the desk, puts the revolver away in a drawer.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Mrs. Hudson. You're in my line of fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Merely celebrating Her Majesty's Golden Jubilee.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson is looking at Holmes with a little smile on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Look at that mess you made --</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right, Mrs. Hudson. I'll clean it up --  -- while you unpack my things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unpack?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bewildered Mrs. Hudson goes back into the bedroom. Watson crosses to the fireplace, picks up the whiskbroom and the coal shovel, starts cleaning up the broken glass.</context>
      <utterance>You heard him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Holmes. I know how difficult it must've been for you --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really. It was simple choice between a bad habit and a good companion.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've made me very happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've often been accused of being cold and unemotional. I admit to it. And yet, in my cold, unemotional way, I'm very fond of you, Watson.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He notices the violin, which has been splattered with the liquid from the shattered bottle, picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>I know that. But one likes to hear these things occasionally.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this. Covered with that nasty stuff. I'd better dry it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the instrument, and dabbing it with a handkerchief, carries it toward the violin case.</context>
      <utterance>I'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a moment, I was worried that you were going to let me walk out -- that you weren't even going to try to stop me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a side-glance at the busy Watson, he opens the violin case. Neatly stashed away around the edges are the three original bottles of narcotics. The ones he shot up, of course, were substitutes from the chemistry set. He places the violin carefully among the bottles, closes the case, snaps the locks. As he moves off, we STAY on the violin case.</context>
      <utterance>Now, Watson -- you know there's nothing I wouldn't do to keep you here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WATSON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson sets down his coffee cup, picks up the letter and the tickets, rises from his chair. He starts to pace -- addressing Holmes, who is off-scene.</context>
      <utterance>But on one occasion, he did something that was so utterly unforgivable, that I would gladly have murdered him -- had it not been for my saintly disposition.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you being so stubborn, Holmes? Why won't you go? It's the final performance of the Imperial Russian Ballet -- the house has been sold out for months -- He moves towards the door of --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- seats are going for a guinea apiece --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's precisely it. Why should someone send up two free tickets? Anonymously, at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever sent them must be in great distress. The note says --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>19.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Please! You are the only man in the world who can help me.'</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suspect it's some sort of plot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean somebody wants to lure us into a trap...?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody wants to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. It's a plot to bore me to death. I detest ballet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this isn't just any ballet. It's Swan Lake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, of course, Holmes -- that swan isn't really a swan -- it's an enchanted princess.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the stage now, the hunters appear, carrying lighted torches.</context>
      <utterance>H'mmmm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watson nudges Holmes, who has dozed off.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fabulous woman, don't you think so, Holmes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the glasses to Holmes, who focuses them indifferently on the stage.</context>
      <utterance>The great Petrova.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Petrova is making an exit, backwards, on points.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very strong arches, I must admit.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say twelve men have died for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six committed suicide, four were killed in duels, and one fell out of the gallery in the Vienna Opera House.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's only eleven.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man who fell from the gallery landed on top of another man in the orchestra.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson resumes watching the stage through the glasses.</context>
      <utterance>That makes an even dozen -- in a messy sort of way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Holmes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes and Watson start to get up, but he motions them back into their chairs.</context>
      <utterance>I am Nicolai Rogozhin, director-general of the Imperial Russian Ballet. So glad you accept invitation.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Dr. Watson.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pleased to meet you.  You are enjoying?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Immensely.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me, Mr. Holmes, how is your health?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My health? Better consult my doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he's in excellent shape.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Asthma?</context>
      <utterance>Any insanity in your family? Diabetes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you mind telling me what this is all about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly. Madame Petrova, she has problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you be more specific?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly not.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances toward the stage.</context>
      <utterance>A liason with a crowned head? Compromising letters? Blackmail?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The pas-de-deux finished, to a rousing ovation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rogozhin rises, turns to Holmes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After performance, there will be little celebration backstage -- and Madame requests your presence.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd be delighted.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a parting look he exits, pulling the plush curtains closed.</context>
      <utterance>You are invited, also.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There you are, Mr. Holmes. Madame is expecting you in her dressing room. Dr. Watson, you will amuse yourself meanwhile -- we have vodka, caviar, girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rogozhin turns to a group of ballerinas, claps his hands.</context>
      <utterance>No caviar. Makes me break out in hives.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Half a dozen ballerinas descend on on Dr. Watson. They are giggling and chattering in Russian. Rogozhin leads Holmes off, while Watson takes in the bevy of beauties around him.</context>
      <utterance>Dievushki. Siude, siuda, dievushki. Posnakomtes s docktorum Watsonom.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any of you girls understand English?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nyet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not one single word?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nyet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In that case, I don't mind telling you that you all have lovely po-pos. He pats a couple of the po-pos with his cane.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Holmes, I must prepare you -- this is no ordinary case.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is only the extraordinary that interests me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have now reached the door of Madame's dressing room. Rogozhin knocks. The door is opened by an elderly Russian maid.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Because you will find this extra- extraordinary.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame Petrova prinimaet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rogozhin leads Holmes inside. The maid steps out, shuts the door.</context>
      <utterance>Pozhaluista voidite.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ja priviol vam Mistera Sherlock Holmesa, doragaia.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She extends her hand, and Holmes takes it.</context>
      <utterance>Otchen rada.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her hand. Petrova appraises him from head to toe, and back again.</context>
      <utterance>Madame.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vi menshe rostom chem ja ozhidala.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame says you are shorter than she thought.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No eto nie vazhno. Menia interessujut glavnim obra som vashi mosghi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Short, tall, who cares? It is the brains that count.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Petrova rises, crosses to the paravent.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.  Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ja prochia vsie vashi prikliuchenia. Zamiechatelno! Os sobenno sobaka Baskervillei.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame is great admirer of yours. She has read every story -- her favorite is Big Dog from Baskerville.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Petrova is now behind the paravent, undressing, only her head visible.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid it loses something in translation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rogozhin picks up a violin case, opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Nikolai, pokazhite iemu skripku.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes holds the violin up, peers through one of the sound holes.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Holmes, you know about fiddles.  What is your opinion of this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Antonius Stradivarius Cremonesis, Anno 1709.' Well, the label is authentic.  Judging from the shape, the color of the varnish, and the tone, I would say it is a genuine Stradivarius of the best period.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's magnificent.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skazhite jemu chto eto podarok ot menia.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here -- take it. Madame says it is yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For services you will render.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My fees as a detective are not exactly trifling -- but a Stradivarius -- you're not serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Petrova emerges from behind the paravent, in a brocade dressing gown.</context>
      <utterance>I am not. But Madame is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She drapes herself on the chaise.</context>
      <utterance>Nalejte vodki i obiasnite jemu v chom dielo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. I will pour vodka and explain.  Mr. Holmes, what you have seen tonight is last and positively final performance of Madame Petrova. She is retiring.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a shame.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has been dancing since she was three years old. And after all, she is now thirty-eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must say she doesn't look thirty-eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is because she is forty-nine.  So Madame has decided to leave ballet and spend life bringing up her child.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How admirable.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Problem now is to find father.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? Is he missing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's why you called me in?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also correct. We must have father, because without father, how can there be child?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. The whole thing is still in the planning stage --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes' eyes wander slowly toward Petrova. She raises her glass.</context>
      <utterance>Correct again. Madame would like child to be brilliant and beautiful. Since she is beautiful -- she now needs man who is brilliant.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Za zdorovie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Za zdorovie.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Petrova and Rogozhin down their vodka bottoms up. Holmes takes one swallow, then stops.</context>
      <utterance>Za zdrovie.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it taste like?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Red pepper.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While Rogozhin refills Petrova's glass and his own, Holmes takes another tentative sip.</context>
      <utterance>That's what's in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kogda mi smozhem dvinutsa v putj?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame wants to know how soon you can be ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To leave for Venice. All arrangements have been made. You will spend one week there with Madame...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this is all very flattering. But surely there are other me -- better men --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To tell you truth, you were not first choice. We considered Russian writer, Tolstoi --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's more like it. The man's a genius.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too old... Then we considered the philosopher, Nietzsche --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely first-rate mind...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too German... And we considered Tschaikowski --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you couldn't go wrong with Tschaikowski --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could -- and we did. It was catastrophe.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know? Because Tschaikowski -- how shall put it? Women not his glass of tea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pity, that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skazhite jemu chto je otchen dovolna etim resheniem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame is very happy with final choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame mustn't be too hasty. She must remember I'm an Englishman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what they say about us. If there's one thing more deplorable than our cooking, it's our love-making. We are not exactly the most romantic of people --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfect. We don't want sentimental idiots -- falling in love, committing suicide. One week in Venice -- she goes back to St. Petersburg with baby -- you go back to London with fiddle.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An equitable arrangement.  About my medical history -- when you asked me -- I neglected to mention a small detail. There is hemophilia in my family. We're all bleeders.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On govorit, chto v jevo semie stradajut ghemofilijei.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pust nie bezpokoitsa. Ja ostrighu sebe noghti.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame says not to worry. She will not scratch you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's reassuring to know. But --</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pochemu on kolebletsa? On nie nahodit menia dostatochno privlekatelnoi?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Holmes can answer, the door opens and Watson sticks his head in. He is flushed and slightly inebriated, and there is a flower tucked behind his ear. From off comes the SOUND of wild balalaika music.</context>
      <utterance>Madame says you talk too much. You find her attractive or no?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.  What does prokanzik mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means 'You little devil.'</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurries off, shutting the door.</context>
      <utterance>It does? I am? Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I find her most attractive -- for a woman, that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then no problem.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe a slight one. You see, I am not a free man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not free? You are a bachelor.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Five very happy years.</context>
      <utterance>A bachelor -- living with another bachelor -- for the last five years.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it you are trying to tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hoped I could avoid the subject. But some of us -- through a cruel caprice of Mother Nature --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get to point.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The point is that Tschaikowski is not an isolated case.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean, you and Dr. Watson -- ?  He is your glass of tea?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want to be picturesque about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chto on govorit? Pri chom tut Chaikovsky?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On pederast.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kakoi vi idiot!</context>
      <utterance>Jescho odin? Eto stanovitsa odnoobrasno!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits. Rogozhin starts to pour himself another glass of vodka. Petrova slaps the glass out of his hand.</context>
      <utterance>It would have been catastrophe.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETROVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Potchemu vi nie vijasnili eto eto ranshe, prezhde chem posoritj menia!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watson!  Watson, are you coming?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, old boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves goodbye, and goes on swirling dizzily with the girls. Holmes puts on his silk hat and leaves. A shaken Rogozhin comes up to the buffet, pours himself a stiff drink of vodka. As he drinks his eyes follow the dancing Watson balefully. Watson spins off several of the girls, grabs another group. His ex-partners wind up close to Rogozhin. He whispers something to them. Their eyes widen, and they stare at Watson with disbelief. Watson again switches partners, and the first girls now whisper intensely to those who just left the floor. The same reaction. Watson, oblivious to all this, is whirling around with another set of girls. By now some of the girls who are in on the secret are whispering to the male dancers in tights. Their reaction is slightly different. They are seeing Watson in a new light. And before Watson knows what's happening, he has been abandoned by all the girls, and is joined first by one pair then another pair of male dancers, till he is dancing only with gay guys in tights. It gradually dawns on Watson that there is something wrong with this state of affairs. After some difficulty, he breaks away from them.</context>
      <utterance>Home? Not a chance. Not the slightest -- not the remotest chance. Toodle-ooo.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spotting Rogozhin, he crosses to him. The girls shrink away at his approach.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on! Just a moment!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on? What happened to the girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Do you not prefer it this way?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What way?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to pretend. Mr. Holmes told us everything -- about you and him --</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About me and him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come now, no need to be bashful. We are not bourgeois. Maybe with doctors and detectives is unusual -- but in ballet, is very usual.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson looks around at the boys in tights, who are standing in a half-circle, grinning at him insolently. It is beginning to dawn on him. He pales.</context>
      <utterance>Caprice of Mother Nature. Look at Pavel and Mischa and Boris and Dmitri --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROGOZHIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pours himself another vodka. Watson grabs the glass away from him, downs it with a gulp.</context>
      <utterance>-- And Ilya and Sergei --  Sergei -- half and half.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He races up the stairs and across the landing, flings open the door of the flat.</context>
      <utterance>Holmes!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holmes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer from Holmes. We now see -- but Watson does not -- that the chair is occupied by a section of Holmes' smoking machine, with the pipe attached.</context>
      <utterance>There you are, you wretch! You rotter! You blackguard! Of all the vile, unspeakable fabrications. What do you have to say for yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't just sit there -- speak up, man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He approaches the chair apprehensively, shoves it aside -- and there on the floor is the smoking machine, still wheezing slightly. Watson picks it up, and his eyes travel to Holmes, standing in a shadowy corner, working the bellows with his foot.</context>
      <utterance>Holmes...? Are you all right, Holmes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the sound of your footsteps, I gathered that you were not in a particularly amiable mood.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dashes the smoking machine to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>How could you do a dastardly thing like that to me? What the deuce were you thinking of?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watson, you have my most abject apologies. But have you ever been cornered by a madwoman? It seemed like the only way to get out of it without hurting her feelings.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about my feelings? And my reputation? Do you realize the gravity of what you have done? The possible repercussions?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So there'll be a little gossip about you in St. Petersburg...</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These things spread like wildfire. I can just hear those malicious whispers behind my back. I'll never be able to show my face in polite society...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>39.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if it ever got back to my old regiment -- you don't know the Fifth Northumberland Fusiliers -- they'll strike me off the rolls -- they'll cut off my pension...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watson, you're running amok.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dishonored, disgraced, ostracized. What am I to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the flower behind Watson's ear. Watson grabs the flower, hurls it into the fireplace.</context>
      <utterance>Well, for one thing, I'd get rid of that flower.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may think this is funny, but we're both in the same boat. We must take desperate measures. We must stop this talk...  Maybe if we got married...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then they'd really talk...</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obviously, we cannot continue to live under the same roof. We must move apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, we can still see each other clandestinely -- on remote benches in Hyde Park, and in the waiting rooms of suburban railway stations --</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The whole thing is ridiculous. We have nothing to hide.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I've been trying to tell you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let somebody start a rumor -- just one ugly word -- and we'll sue them for slander.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody would dare. After all, you have an enviable record with the fair sex.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer from Holmes. Watson is becoming a little concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Damn right. I can get women from three continents to testify for me. And you can get women to vouch for you, too -- can't you, Holmes?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you, Holmes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts toward his bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, Watson.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holmes, let me ask you a question --  I hope I'm not being presumptuous -- but there have been women in your life?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks into his bedroom, shutting the door. Watson takes a tentative step after him.</context>
      <utterance>The answer is yes.  You're being presumptuous.  Good night.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holmes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you expecting someone?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at this hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe Mrs. Hudson is entertaining.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson crosses to the door, opens it, steps out. Holmes resumes playing Corelli.</context>
      <utterance>I never found her so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, Mrs. Hudson?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a cabbie here -- he says you owe him two-and-six.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the fare, guv'nor. The young lady doesn't have any money.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What young lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches out the door, pulls in the young lady in question. She is in her early thirties, with strikingly handsome features, but at the moment she is somewhat worse for wear. She is wrapped in a blanket, her hair is wet, and there is a bruise on her temple.</context>
      <utterance>This one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. What have we here?  Who are you, miss? What happened to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The violin music stops o.s. Watson has now reached the foot of the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>That's all she keeps saying -- I don't know, I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did she come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes appears on the landing above, violin and bow in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>From the river. I was driving down the Embankment, just below Westminster Bridge, and there she was in the water -- drowning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't easy, guv'nor -- what with the cold water -- and her fighting me --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you bring her here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson examines the cardboard, nods.</context>
      <utterance>Because I found this in her hand --  -- 221B Baker Street -- that's right, isn't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Young lady -- what did you want at this address?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rather perplexing, wouldn't you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rather.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, gentlemen, you want her? -- it's two-and-six -- or shall I throw her back in the river?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Holmes. You can't let him --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson fishes some coins out of his pocket, hands them to the cabbie.</context>
      <utterance>Watson, you'd better accept delivery.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep the change.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snatches the blanket off Gabrielle, revealing that her dress is clinging to her damply.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, guv'nor.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits into the street, shutting the door. Gabrielle hugs herself for warmth.</context>
      <utterance>No extra charge for the use of the horse- blanket.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(he puts his arm around her)</context>
      <utterance>You're shivering, my dear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He settles her in the chair. Holmes comes over, plucks the square of cardboard from Watson's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Sit here, my dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to massage her wrists to restore her circulation. Holmes is examining the soggy cardboard. On one side is their address, written in pencil. He turns it over, disclosing some smudges of green ink on the other side.</context>
      <utterance>She's suffering from shock and exposure.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson is now studying the bruise on Gabrielle's temple.</context>
      <utterance>There was some printing on the back of this -- but it seems to have come off in the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this -- she's had a nasty blow on the head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Holmes fetches the medical bag, Gabrielle looks from one to the other.</context>
      <utterance>No. The blood has already coagulated. So it would appear that she was the victim of a deliberate attack... Get my bag, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Dr. Watson -- and this is Mr. Sherlock Holmes. Do the names mean anything to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you think of your own name?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has now taken some cotton and a bottle of antiseptic out of the medical bag, and is swabbing her wound.</context>
      <utterance>She's obviously had a concussion -- which often leads to temporary amnesia.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So all we know is that she was coshed on the head, dumped into the Thames, and subsequently dumped into our laps.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know a lot more than that. From her accent, we know she is foreign -- from her ring, we know she is married -- and there is one other clue we have... Something I deduced while I was helping her up the stairs. No corset.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances down at Gabrielle's shoe, which has slipped off her foot. Inside, slightly worn away, are the words:</context>
      <utterance>Good work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you French?  Vous etes Francaise?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Non, je ne suis pas Francaise.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can she say she's not French, in French?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vous etes Suisse?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Non.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alors, vous etes Belge.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes reaches behind her, turns back the collar of her dress. Sewn inside is a label reading: BAZAAR MODERN, Bruxelles.</context>
      <utterance>Je suis pas sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vous etes Belge -- de Bruxelles!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Hudson has come in with a loaded tea-tray, starts to put it down on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Bruxelles? Oui... Je pense que oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson takes the violin off the table, and she sets down the tray.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, dash. Will someone remove the violin, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just found out that she's Belgian.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From Brussels.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slips the wedding ring off her finger, picks up a magnifying glass, examines it. It is made of copper, and engraved on the inside is the inscription: Gabrielle - Emile.</context>
      <utterance>If you don't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabrielle?</context>
      <utterance>Your name is Gabrielle, is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your husband's name is Emile?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Emile...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he? What are you doing in London?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did you arrive from Brussels? Where are you staying?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabrielle bursts into sobs.</context>
      <utterance>What happened at the river? Think! Pensez! Concentrez vous!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's enough, Holmes. I will not permit you to question her in this condition.  Mrs. Hudson, put her to bed. My bed.  I'll sleep on the couch.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her arm around Gabrielle, who is still crying, leads her into Watson's bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Come, my dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets a packet of white powder out of his medical bag, and during the following, stirs a spoonful into her tea- cup.</context>
      <utterance>I'd better mix her a sleeping potion.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watson, I think we should arrange to have her removed to a hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Under no circumstances.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She should have medical attention.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She can get that from me. But more importantly, she must be protected -- there has already been one attempt on her life.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This temporary amnesia -- how temporary is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It depends on the extent of the injury. It's like veils shrouding her memory. It could clear up in a few days -- or a few weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watson, this is a very small flat -- we don't want to clutter it up with women...</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holmes, we've never had a case like this. A woman comes to us with a problem -- we don't know who the woman is -- and we don't know what the problem is. Don't you find that challenging?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite. But we can't afford to wait for those veils to lift -- we must break through them as quickly as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really feel it's that urgent?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do. The sooner we solve the case, the sooner we can get rid of her.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up the cup of tea with the sedative in it, carries it toward the door of his bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes looks up as Gabrielle appears in the open doorway.</context>
      <utterance>Emile?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Emile? Is that you, Emile?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Gabrielle.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, Emile. I thought I'd never find you.  Hold me. Hold me tight.  It's been such a long time. So many nights. You know what I did before I left Brussels?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you won't be angry with me. I bought myself an expensive negligee.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pink negligee with maribou feathers. Don't you think that's a foolish thing for a married woman?  Come.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is the negligee?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In my luggage... Come here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where is your luggage?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clearly reflected in the mirror is the reverse image of the lettering on Gabrielle's palm -- the number "301".</context>
      <utterance>What is it, Emile? What are you doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson tries to rise, falls back with a moan.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Watson!  Your porridge is getting lumpy. Hadn't you better get up?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would like to very much. But --  Mrs. Hudson, would you mind planting your knee in the small of my back?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I would.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Hudson tentatively rests her knee on Watson's back.</context>
      <utterance>Please! I'm in excruciating pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Hudson presses down harder, and there is a distinct snap.</context>
      <utterance>A bit higher -- just below my seventh vertebra --  That's good. Put your arms under mine -- fold them behind my neck --</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless you.  That damn couch.  You'd better see if our patient is awake. He seats himself at the table. Mrs. Hudson crosses to the door of Watson's bedroom, opens it, starts inside, then stops.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Watson. She's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jumps up from the table, joins Mrs. Hudson, looks past her. The bed is empty. Gabrielle's clothes are in evidence, but there is no sign of her. Watson strides towards Holmes' bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws the door open, is about to step inside when he sees something that makes him freeze.</context>
      <utterance>Holmes! Holmes! She's gone!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmmm. I smell porridge. Lumpy as usual, I suppose. He sets the suitcase down on the couch, as Watson and Mrs. Hudson approach.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, there you are, Holmes. We were just wondering -- how --</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We certainly were.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Hudson, why don't you go down to the kitchen -- get a towel -- and wipe that look of disapproval off your face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits huffily.</context>
      <utterance>Liberties -- in my house!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't really blame her -- I mean, the way it looks -- if I didn't know you better, I might suspect you'd taken advantage of the young lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact, I did take advantage of her... Would you hand me the butter- knife, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up the butter-knife from the table, suddenly turns back with a delayed reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to pry open the locks of the suitcase with the butter-knife.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holmes, this is reprehensible! Where are your professional ethics? Have you no sense of decency, no shame --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None whatsoever. If you must know, I found her body quite rewarding.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You cad!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Especially the palm of her right hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd rather not hear about it!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well. Then I won't bother to tell you how I traced her suitcase.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's her suitcase?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember that piece of soggy cardboard with our address on it? It was a luggage ticket -- the number rubbed off on her hand. And since she must have arrived from Brussels by the boat train, I concluded that she had checked her belongings at Victoria Station.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By Jove! If you're right, we should find a clue to her identity. Holmes has now forced open the locks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the suitcase, lifts out the top piece of clothing, holds it up -- a pink negligee with maribou feathers.</context>
      <utterance>Or at least a pink negligee with maribou feathers.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Voila!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start sorting through the clothes in the suitcase. Holmes removes a tied bundle of letters.</context>
      <utterance>Let's see - what else is in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he examines the envelope, Watson takes out a framed photo of a rather attractive man of fifty.</context>
      <utterance>Now we're getting somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you suppose this is?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come in, Madame Valladon.  You are Gabrielle Valladon.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is your husband, Emile Valladon?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes fall on the open suitcase.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to have ransacked your valise. But since you came to us for help --</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>221B Baker Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes...  Which of you is Mr. Holmes and which is Dr. Watson?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson, pleased, twirls the end of his mustache. Gabrielle sways slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Watson is the handsome one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He helps her into a chair.</context>
      <utterance>That's the way he affects most women.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hurries over to the breakfast table.</context>
      <utterance>Coffee. You want strong coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all so confusing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's try to sort it out. You came to London looking for your husband...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. He's a mining engineer. We were married five years ago, in the Congo.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where your husband was working in a copper mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks it up from the chemistry table, hands it to her. Gabrielle starts to put it on.</context>
      <utterance>Your wedding ring -- it's made of copper.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last year he invented a new kind of air pump, and was hired by an English company, Jonah Limited.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jonah Limited. Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been writing to each other regularly. Then suddenly, three weeks ago, his letters stopped. I kept writing ... but no answer. Finally I decided to go to that address --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>32 Ashdown Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. It's just an empty store -- nobody there. Then I tried to find Jonah Limited. No such company exists.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How decidedly odd.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame Valladon, can you think of any reason why your husband should have lied to you about theses things?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Emile? Never. He loves me -- and I love him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I gathered.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went to the police -- they said they would send out a missing persons report -- but they didn't sound too encouraging. Then I went to the Belgian embassy and explained the situation to them -- and they suggested that I consult you...</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could have done worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was on my way here -- and suddenly there were footsteps behind me -- and a hand over my mouth -- and the smell of choloroform -- and the next thing I knew I was in the water -- and then a man was wrapping me in a blanket --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame Valladon, somebody tried to kill you last night. Do you have any idea who could have done it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand any of it.  What does it all mean, Mr. Holmes? Where is my husband? You must help me find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll do our best, I assure you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses to the desk, picks up a sheet of paper and an envelope, then leads Gabrielle over to the chair with the writing arm, seats her in it.</context>
      <utterance>Madame Valladon, I want you to send one more letter to your husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To Emile Valladon -- Ashdown Street -- what was that number?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>32. What do you want me to say in the letter?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He folds the blank sheet of paper, and as Gabrielle finishes addressing the envelope, he inserts the paper in it, starts to seal it.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sending an empty sheet of paper to an empty shop?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That empty shop is obviously being used as an accomodation address, or letter- drop. But what gets dropped must be picked up. The question is how? -- and by whom? -- and why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson hands him the indicated tools. Holmes chips away the cement from the top and bottom of the last bar, then using it as a hinge, swings the grill open. He lets himself through the skylight, drops to the floor. Watson now helps Gabrielle through the skylight, lowers her toward Holmes, who puts his arms around her waist, eases her to the floor. For a brief moment he keeps his arms around her. Watson has now squeezed through the skylight.</context>
      <utterance>Hammer... Chisel.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the tools to Holmes, jumps to the floor. Gabrielle is looking around the shop.</context>
      <utterance>Here!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson crosses to the square tarpaulin-covered object. He lifts up one corner of the tarp -- and is greeted by a loud twittering of birds.</context>
      <utterance>It's so strange to think I've been writing to a place like this all these months.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at all these canaries. Do you suppose this could have been a pet shop?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the front window, the silhouette of a postman can be seen approaching. He drops a letter through the slot in the front door, moves on. The letter lands on a section of floor which is solidly covered with dust -- except for a series of double tracks, running to the door and curving back.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe.  Here comes our letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reassembles the three tools, fitting each section into another, to form a cane.</context>
      <utterance>Now we are faced with the most nerve- wracking part of the detective's job -- doing nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Holmes --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how I'm going to pay you for all this. The purse with my money is somewhere at the bottom of the Thames.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could be worse. You could be at the bottom of the Thames -- much to your discomfort -- and much to my chagrin.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand how anybody picks up letters here.  No footprints -- just tracks. What does it mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They become aware of a squeaking noise outside the rear of the shop, growing louder as it gets nearer. The noise stops, there is the sound of a lock turning, then the rattle of a chain.</context>
      <utterance>I would surmise somebody is using ice- skates -- if it weren't for a conspicuous absence of ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do now?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads Gabrielle and Watson toward the rear wall, right next to the door. They flatten themselves with their backs to the wall, just as the door slides open -- concealing them from view. Revealed is the mews behind the shop. In the door is an old BIDDY with straggly hair, sitting in a wheelchair. In her lap are a bulky paper bag and a tin pitcher filled with water. As she wheels herself inside, the unoiled wheelchair squeaks loudly. She stops in front of the cage, pulls on a rope which runs through a pulley in the ceiling -- and the tarpaulin rises into the air, exposing the canaries.</context>
      <utterance>This way.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN IN WHEELCHAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She cackles to herself, glances toward the front door.</context>
      <utterance>Some of you will be going on a little trip soon -- I hate to lose you -- but even an old woman has to live. Although you might well ask, why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WOMAN IN WHEELCHAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to wheel herself toward the front of the shop. Through a crack in the door behind which our three are hiding, we see Holmes' eye watching her. The old woman reaches the letter, picks it up, studies the address. Then she hears something, glances toward the open rear door. A horse-drawn wagon with a canvas top is just pulling into the mews. Two CARTERS jump down from the driver's seat, and one of them takes a small bird-cage from the back of the wagon. As they start in through the door, the old woman drops the letter into her lap, wheels herself toward them.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. You never told me we had a letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning, Duchess.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN IN WHEELCHAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you been doing with yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN IN WHEELCHAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think? Taking dancing lessons.  How many do you want this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door of the small cage, the bottom of which is covered with newspaper, starts transferring canaries into it from the large cage.</context>
      <utterance>Two dozen.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN IN WHEELCHAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they doing with all those canaries? What's going on up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Duchess, we don't know -- and we don't want to know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SECOND CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about that letter? Does that go, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN IN WHEELCHAIR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She chuckles. The carriers exit into the mews, stash the cage in the back of the wagon, mount the driver's seat.</context>
      <utterance>No. That's going to be picked up in person.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really thought we were done for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear what she said? You really think Emile is going to pick up the letter himself?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It certainly would simplify things, wouldn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maildrops and canaries and wheelchairs... And what was all that about Jonah? And what do you suppose they're doing up there? And where is up there?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My guess would be Scotland. Inverness, to be more precise.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inverness?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabrielle glances casually at the letter the old woman left lying on top of the cage, and her expression changes.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't you notice the paper at the bottom of their cage? The Inverness Courier.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Holmes! This letter --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's addressed to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With the saw-end of his cane, he slits the envelope open, removes the enclosure, unfolds it. We see the letter in his hand as he reads it out loud. The letterhead says: DIOGENES CLUB, St. James's, London.</context>
      <utterance>Nevertheless --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Dear Sherlock: I expect you and Dr. Watson to join me at the club immediately upon reciept of this note. According to my calculations, that should be at 11:40 a.m. Your brother, Mycroft.  What time do you make it, Watson?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm rather curious myself as to what is going on in that Machiavellian mind of his.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean Mycroft, I mean Madame Valladon.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the door and they start in.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. She's perfectly safe with Mrs. Hudson.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To see Mr. Mycroft Holmes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>looks around in consternation, sees them hurrying up the majestic staircase, steps out from behind his desk.</context>
      <utterance>Right you are. He's expecting you in the upstairs study. Now if you gentlemen will sign in --  Surname, Christian name, address, nature of business -- He holds out the pen to them, but they are gone. He</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come in, come in, Sherlock -- Dr. Watson... Sit down.  You're looking very fit, both of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how are you, Mycroft? How's your gout?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He brings over two of the glasses of wine to Holmes and Watson.</context>
      <utterance>Under control. Except for the occasional twinge.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a treat for you -- a very old Madeira -- 1814. There are only six bottles left in the world. I have two of them, and am negotiating for a third.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mycroft has moved back to the table and picked up his glass of Madeira.</context>
      <utterance>If you don't mind my saying so, anybody who's susceptible to gout shouldn't be --</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Watson sip their drinks, but not Holmes.</context>
      <utterance>The last doctor who warned me about that was crossing Piccadilly, slipped on an orange peel, and was run over by a delivery van from the Fortnum and Mason. Your very good health.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you wasting this precious stuff on us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I see you so rarely. How long has it been? Not since the case of the Greek interpreter.  Isn't it ridiculous? Two brothers living in the same town...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the same town, perhaps -- but not the same world.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmm. Superb. How old did you say it was?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1814. One year before Waterloo.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One year before Waterloo? Think of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do know where Waterloo is, don't you, Doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Belgium, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite.  And speaking of Belgium, it has come to my attention that you are interested in the whereabouts of a certain engineer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I can save you a lot of trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd be grateful for any suggestion --</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My suggestion is that you pursue it no further.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any particular reason?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it involves the national security. We are handling this matter ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We? Who's we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Diogenes Club, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have always suspected that there was some underground connection between this stodgy and seemingly calcified establishment and the Foreign Office in Whitehall.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's neither here nor there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A YOUNG MAN in morning coat and striped trousers comes in, holding a telegram. Mycroft crosses to him.</context>
      <utterance>It seems to me that The Diogenes Club is here, there and everywhere. When there are rumblings of revolt in the Sudan, an expedition subsidized by your club conveniently shows up to study the source of the Nile. When there is trouble along the Indian frontier, some of your fellow members pop up in the Himalayas, alledgedly looking for the Abominable Snowman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a fertile imagination my brother has. At the age of five, by carefully observing a neighbor's house, he deduced that babies were brought not by the stork, but by the mid-wife in her satchel.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mycroft has taken the telegram, and is coming forward with it. The young man clears his throat.</context>
      <utterance>As good an explanation as any.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Wiggins?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mycroft inserts a monocle in his eye, opens the telegram, moves toward the desk reading it.</context>
      <utterance>An immediate answer is requested, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell them that the three boxes go to Glennahurich, and the red runner goes to the castle.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits. Holmes glances toward the telegram as Mycroft puts it down on his desk. Catching his look, Mycroft turns his telegram face-down, lets the monocle drop from his eye.</context>
      <utterance>The three boxes to Glennahurich, the red runner to the castle. Very good, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you crumple it up and swallow it -- to make sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dear Sherlock, there are certain affairs that do not come within the province of the private detective. They have to be dealt with on an altogether different level.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In other words, you want me to stay within my limits.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do indeed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speaking of limits, what exactly is Jonah Limited?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sherlock, when I said drop this case, it was not merely a suggestion -- it was an order!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By whose authority?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the authority of Her Majesty's government. I hope I've made myself clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In his nervousness he drops his bowler, which rolls along the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Perfectly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now if you'll excuse me, gentlemen --</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Watson retrieve their hats, move toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>A pleasure, as always.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a minute.  You forgot your tool-kit. He tosses the cane to Holmes, who catches it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will be gentle, won't you, when you tell her you're dropping the case?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watson, what does the word Glennahurich suggest to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Absolutely nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Scottish.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And like all Scottish names, it's really a word picture. Glen means valley, na means of the, and Hurich, if memory serves me, means yew tree.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just trying to impress me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He resumes whistling. They start to cross the street, skirting a parked hansom. Feeding the horse is the same cabbie who fished Gabrielle out of the river, and in the passenger seat is Von Tirpitz, the craggy-faced Prussian we saw before. He stares fixedly after Holmes and Watson. Holmes and Watson come up to the door of 221B, and Watson fishes his key out. Holmes is still whistling.</context>
      <utterance>So the three boxes go to the Valley of the Yew Tree.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'll be in Scotland before ye...  You are dropping the case, aren't you, Holmes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson turns the key in the lock, starts to open the door, but is stopped by a chain on the inside. Through the opening a revolver appears, aiming at them point- blank.</context>
      <utterance>Open the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't shoot, Mrs. Hudson -- you're liable to lose two excellent tenants.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, at last. It's been a ghastly experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HUDSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever try doing embroidery with a gun in your hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts up the stairs, followed by Watson.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be relieved to know it was not loaded.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No reaction from Holmes. As they reach the landing, Gabrielle is waiting for them in the open doorway of their flat.</context>
      <utterance>Holmes, you didn't answer my question. Are you planning to disobey Mycroft's orders? He's not just your brother, you know. You'd be defying Her Majesty's government...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any news? Did you find out anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just say I know what the next step will be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to pack your things.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes has put the gun down, and is crossing to one of the book-shelves.</context>
      <utterance>Holmes, let me caution you ---</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At 7:30 this evening, Dr. Watson and I are going to take you to Victoria Station, and put you on the boat-train.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The boat-train?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes has taken a railway guide from the shelf and is consulting it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's better.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sending me back to Brussels? Is that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame Valladon, you must understand...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came here to find my husband -- you were going to help me --</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, my dear. But circumstances have changed --</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The great detective! Well, maybe this case is too small for you --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the contrary. It's being handled at a much higher level --</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I won't go back to Brussels. Maybe you're giving up, but I'm not.  I'm going to go on looking for him. And nobody's going to stop me -- even if they try to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you quite finished? If you recall, what I said was that we're going to put you on the boat-train -- I didn't say you were going to stay on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At 7:30, Mr. Holmes and Dr. Watson will be seen waving goodbye to Madame Valladon at Victoria Station. At eight-twelve, Mr. and Mrs. Ashdown accompanied by their valet John --  -- will appear at Euston Station, and board the Highland Express to Inverness.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. and Mrs.... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(kisses him on cheek)</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I'm sorry for what I said.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hurries off toward Watson's room.</context>
      <utterance>I'll go and pack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes replaces the railway guide on the shelf.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I should do it, since I'm the valet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holmes, what exactly are you up to?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you like to put it in your chronicles, the game is afoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without answering, Holmes heads for his bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>But what game? Are you really that interested in the Belgian engineer?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes, by this time in his bedroom, shuts the door. Gabrielle reappears from the other bedroom, carrying a glove.</context>
      <utterance>Or the wife of the Belgian engineer?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves toward the couch.</context>
      <utterance>You don't like me very much, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By this time Gabrielle has picked up her parasol from the couch, and is obviously searching about.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing of the sort. Quite the opposite... But there's more to this case than meets the eye --</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking for something?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My other glove.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me help you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes up from under the couch with the missing glove.</context>
      <utterance>Here it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slowly starts to shut the parasol.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabrielle's head appears from under the covers of the lower berth.</context>
      <utterance>All right. You can look now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I embarrassing you, Mr. Holmes?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. Would it surprise you if I told you I once spent the night with 121 women?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to climb up the ladder to the upper berth.</context>
      <utterance>On a very interesting case -- in a harem in Constantinople.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is no answer from the monk. Watson picks up his bowler, settles himself in his seat, starts to fan himself with his hat. He turns sociably to the monk beside him, who is absorbed in his Bible.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, father -- I mean, friar -- or is it abbot?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he fans himself the ear-pieces of his stethoscope, which is coiled inside the crown of his bowler, dangle down. He quickly shoves them back inside.</context>
      <utterance>Going to Scotland, you gentlemen? So are we...</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a valet. My master and mistress and I are our way to Inverness. Ever been there? Beautiful country.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The monk doesn't answer. Watson turns away, looks out the window -- but there's nothing to be seen. Then he folds, bored. He glances casually at the Bible in the monk's hands. The Good Book is opened to a page headed: JONAH.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, forgive me. You must be one of those orders that's taken the vow of silence. Trappists, I believe you're called.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls down the shade, closes his eyes, tries to compose himself into sleep.</context>
      <utterance>I see you're reading the book of Jonah. Funny - we were just talking about Johan this morning...  Never mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes raises himself on his elbow, glances down over the edge of his berth.</context>
      <utterance>Women are never to be trusted entirely -- not the best of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't say it -- you did. According to Dr. Watson.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He gave me some back issues of Strand Magazine.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The good doctor is constantly putting words into my mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you deny it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. I am not a whole-hearted admirer of womankind.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not very fond of them myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The most affectionate woman I ever knew was a murderess.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was one of those passionate affairs -- at odd hours -- right in my laboratory. And all the time, behind my back, she was stealing cyanide to sprinkle on her husband's steak and kidney pie.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mustn't judge all women by --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not. Only the ones I was involved with. And I don't just mean professionally -- kleptomaniacs, nymphomaniacs, pyromaniacs. Take my fiancee, for instance --</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your fiancee?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was the daughter of my violin teacher -- we were engaged to be married -- the invitations were out, I was being fitted for a tail-coat -- and twenty-four hours before the wedding, she died of influenza.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the curtain across his berth.</context>
      <utterance>It just proves my contention that women are unreliable and not to be trusted.  Good night, Mrs. Ashdown.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She closes her curtain, as the train whistle sounds.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, Mr. Ashdown.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabrielle removes her parasol, which has been inserted under the straps of her suitcase.</context>
      <utterance>Let's see -- two, three, four --</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you get to Glennahurich? How far is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BAGGAGEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glennahurich?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabrielle casually opens her parasol.</context>
      <utterance>You know -- a valley -- with a yew tree... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>BAGGAGEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about a mile out of town.  Why would you be wanting to go there?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if it's got a view, it might be a nice place for a picnic.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAGGAGEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's got a view, right enough -- but it's no place for a picnic.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>BAGGAGEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it's a cemetary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The three boxes. Is that it, Holmes?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes starts to cut across between the graves, Gabrielle and Watson following. At the grave-site, the workmen are removing the coffins from the cart. There is one large grave, two smaller ones. A couple of grave-diggers stand by respectfully, caps in hands. Holmes, Gabrielle and Watson come up behind a nearby headstone, stop and watch. At the grave-site, the minister is finishing the service.</context>
      <utterance>The two small ones -- they must be children's coffins.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>88.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>resurrection to eternal life through our Lord, Jesus Christ. Amen. The workmen trundle the cart off, the minister following. The grave-diggers don their caps, pick up their shovels. From their vantage point, Holmes, Gabrielle and Watson are watching.</context>
      <utterance>In sure and certain hope of the</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so sad.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The grave-diggers have finished filling in the graves when Holmes, Gabrielle and Watson come up.</context>
      <utterance>Sad -- and rather odd. There are no flowers -- and no mourners.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAVE-DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Working you hard, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAVE-DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really. This is healthy country. Sometimes you sit around for weeks with nothing to do. Then you get three in one day.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAVE-DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An accident. Aye. Father and two sons, they say -- they were found floating in the loch.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Local people?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAVE-DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Nobody around here knows them. The story is that their boat capsized in a swell -- but I don't believe it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you believe?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAVE-DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may think I'm an old fool or an old drunk -- but I've living around Loch Ness all my life...</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you trying to tell us it was the monster?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAVE-DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn right. MacLarnin saw the kids' faces when they were pulled out of the water -- looked like old men -- must've died of fright.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Incredible.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAVE-DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up a white-washed wooden cross, plants it at the head of the grave. The other grave-digger has inserted smaller crosses into the other two mounds of earth.</context>
      <utterance>Is it? Last Easter Sunday my wife and me, we were on our way to services, when suddenly... But what's the use?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you are, Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAVE-DIGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and his partner shoulder their shovels, move off.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you... You look like nice people. If you're wanting a holiday in Scotland, go to Loch Lomond, go to Holy Loch -- but stay away from Loch Ness.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To think that people still believe in that nonsense. Here we are, living in the Nineteenth Century --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm ashamed to admit it -- but I was relieved when he mentioned a father and two boys. It could possibly have anything to do with Emile.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would appear not.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are about to get under way when suddenly Holmes stops them. Coming down the avenue toward them are four small boys, in knickerbockers and caps, carrying bouquets of flowers. Without a word, Holmes draws Gabrielle and Watson back to their hiding place, behind the headstone. The four boys approach the freshly-filled graves. They remove their caps, lay their flowers on each of the two small graves, then kneel down and bow their heads in prayer. From their position behind the headstone, Holmes, Watson and Gabrielle are watching the four boys, who have their backs to them.</context>
      <utterance>However, there still remains the clue of the castle and the red runner -- wherever it may be.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If they're unidentified graves, why are those boys bringing flowers?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because it's their brothers who have just been buried.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their brothers?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they're not boys. They're as tall as they'll ever grow. Hand me some pebbles, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pebbles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are -- how do you say it in English? -- nains.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Midgets.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boys with the faces of old men...</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still don't see --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would it help if I told you they were acrobats?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you remember a tumbling act -- six brothers -- missing from the circus?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes -- that case you turned down -- I completely forgot.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The four midgets have now risen, and putting on their caps, move off down the avenue. Holmes, Gabrielle and Watson emerge from their place of concealment.</context>
      <utterance>Some of us are cursed with memories like flypaper. And stuck there is a staggering of miscellaneous date, mostly useless.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Holmes, is those are not children, then -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite. The question now is -- who's in the third grave?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holmes! She's fainted.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson passes down the lantern, and Holmes slowly shines the beam along the length of the coffin.</context>
      <utterance>Hand me that lantern.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is Valladon, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obviously. What is not so obvious is why his wedding ring has turned green --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a lovely view of the loch from here -- as soon as the morning mist rolls away.  If you've a mind to do any sight-seeing, here's a guide to the local points of interest.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The manager starts toward the door, nodding to Watson.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This way, please. I will show you to your room. Watson picks up his suitcase, follows him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose you're putting me in the basement.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, your room is in the attic.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson grunts as the manager leads him up a narrow flight of stairs.</context>
      <utterance>It's the privy that's in the basement.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I have your wedding ring, please?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just as I thought. There is a distinct difference in color between your ring and your husband's.  Which leads me to believe that the cause of death was not drowning...  I wish you would stop that.  Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it's not easy. But you must remember that we're that nice couple from London, on Holiday in the Highlands.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll try.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's much better.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She manages a tentative smile. Holmes looks at her for a long moment, then --</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, if I may proceed without further interruptions --</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Ashdown!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flings the door open.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Ashdown!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holmes! I saw it! I saw it from the attic! It's out there in the lake!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saw what?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The telescope. Where's the telescope?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The monster!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson fishes a small telescope out of Holmes' suitcase, rushes through the open French window to the balcony.</context>
      <utterance>The monster?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes joins him on the balcony.</context>
      <utterance>There it is! There it is!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the telescope to Holmes. Gabrielle comes up to the window behind them. Holmes trains the telescope on the lake.</context>
      <utterance>Look for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See it? See it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the telescope from Holmes, looks toward the lake.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gone? Maybe it was never there.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear to you -- I saw it -- clear as anything --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watson, as you so succinctly put it, we are living in the Nineteenth Century -- He steps back into the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe that grave-digger was right -- the swell, and the boat overturning --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monsieur Valladon may have been found in the lake -- but he did not drown. He died of asphyxiation.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Asphyxiation.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is only one substance that can turn a copper ring green and bleach the color out of canaries -- chlorine gas.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That may be. But the fact remains that I saw something out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A figment of your imagination. Now let us be logical. The only concrete lead we have is the reference to the castle --  The question is, which castle?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call yourself logical? You're the least logical man I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like some cranberry sauce, dear?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you pass the cranberry sauce, please, John?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he does so, he catches sight of something o.s.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, dear.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some chaps I met on the train. We had a long conversation -- or rather, I had a long conversation -- because they're not allowed to talk -- Trappists, you know. Just study their Bibles. You'll never guess what the one next to me was reading -- the Book of Jonah -- isn't that odd?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he turns back, he notices that Gabrielle is manipulating her parasol in the air.</context>
      <utterance>Quite.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it, dear? What's the matter?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't think we have to bother with this castle. It's just a pile of rubble.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to the sign -- and to a guard coming up the driveway, with a couple of huge mastiffs on leashes.</context>
      <utterance>Then why are they taking precautions?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, indeed?  Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go where?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When rebuffed at the front door, one's only choice is to try the tradesmen's entrance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. No visitors allowed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you the guide here?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. The castle is closed to the public while work is going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's being restored by the Society for the Preservation of Scottish Monuments.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too bad. I particularly wanted my wife to see Urquhart Castle. The tower is one of the most interesting examples of -- about 1400, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me see -- was it built under James the Second or James the Third?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Thrid... If you come back next year, we'll be all done here, and I'll be glad to show you around.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pleasant sort, isn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pleasant, but ignorant. He was off one hundred years and one James.  It's actually 1500 and James the Fourth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he's an official guide, shouldn't he know... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have now reached the wall against which they left their bicycles. Suddenly Holmes stops, attracted by the sound of birds chirping.</context>
      <utterance>If he's an official guide.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen... Do you hear anything, Watson?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Those birds are making too much of a racket.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sulphuric acid?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The more we find out the less sense it makes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To a graduate chemist it makes a great deal of sense. Sulphuric acid, when exposed to salt-water, produces chlorine gas.  Would you mind clasping your hands, Watson?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson has lowered his clasped hands, and Holmes uses them as a foothold to go scrambling up the scaffolding of the nearby wall. Reaching the top, he looks off in the direction of the tower. The workman carrying the canary cage, and the two carrying the crate of sulphuric acid are approaching the tower. A draw-bridge comes down, and the three men cross the moat and enter the tower.</context>
      <utterance>A little lower... Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holmes, I have a feeling we're redundant here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have now observed the castle from the front, from the back, from the side, from land, from water... what now? Are you planning to spend the night out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabrielle glances past them, and her eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to catch your death of cold.  Wouldn't it be ironic if Holmes' last case were a case of pneumonia?  Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes and Watson turn their heads.</context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes grabs his arm, pulls him back into his seat.</context>
      <utterance>Holmes!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs his oar, and Watson belatedly joins in. They strain at the oars, setting a course which will intercept the monster. Gabrielle leans forward in her seat, trying to peer past them through the curtains of mist. The monster is much closer now -- no more than a quarter of a mile away. Suddenly Watson stops rowing.</context>
      <utterance>Quick, Watson. After it!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holmes, what are we doing? We should be going away from it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watson resumes pulling on his oar. As they row, Holmes looks over his shoulder. The monster has started to submerge. Its head disappears beneath the surface of the water, and the wake it leaves behind soon trails off into the mist. Holmes ships his oar.</context>
      <utterance>Keep rowing, dammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've lost it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least you admit there's an it, not just a figment of my imagination.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have your stethoscope with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes his bowler, unwinds the stethoscope from the inside the crown, hands it to Holmes. Holmes plugs in the ear-pieces, leans over the side of the boat, extends the other end of the stethoscope to the surface of the water.</context>
      <utterance>Never without it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We become aware of the faint beating of engines, accompanied by a bubbling sound.</context>
      <utterance>I can hear something...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the surface of the water breaks, about twenty yards away from them, and the head and neck of the monster rear up from the depths. Watson is first to notice it and jumps to his feet, making choking noises. Gabrielle sees it and screams. Watson grabs an oar, throws it at the monster as it comes past. The backwash hits the boat broadside, rocking it, and Holmes, Watson and Gabrielle are spilled into the lake. The monster moves away from them, heading in the general direction of the castle. It disappears into the mist. Holmes is the first to come up, looks around, sees Gabrielle surfacing a few yards away, swims to her.</context>
      <utterance>It's getting closer -- closer --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lost my parasol.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances around, sees Watson's bowler floating nearby, swims over to it.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Watson?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts the hat -- but Watson isn't under it. As Gabrielle hoists herself into the boat, Watson clambers over the other side. After a moment Holmes joins them, and they sit there, sopping wet and breathing heavily.</context>
      <utterance>Watson?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have come face to face with man-eating tigers -- I was once caught in a stampede of wild elephants -- India, you know -- but I wasn't half as frightened. This beast seems to have a personal grudge against us.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just hope it doesn't come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They glance in the indicated direction. There is no sign of the monster. But the mist has momentarily lifted to reveal the castle, and an odd sight greets their eyes -- the wooden scaffolding in front of the tower is slowly rising into the air.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think it will.  Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What strange goings-on.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really. My guess is that the monster, after a hard day's work, has returned home for his supper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes resumes pacing, and Watson becomes aware of his whistling.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know. But would you believe that you can't borrow a decent pair of trousers in this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer from Holmes. Watson turns to Gabrielle.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like to confide in us?</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whenever he starts whistling, I know he's getting close to a solution.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nothing new, actually. We've come across this situation before.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have? Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the ballet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ballet?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a lake -- and there's a castle -- and there's a swan that isn't really a swan -- or, in this case, a monster that isn't really a monster --</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it indeed that feeds on canary birds and sulphuric acid, and has an engine for a heart?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An engine?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The stethoscope is a very sensitive instrument, and water is an excellent conductor of sound. There is no doubt that what we are dealing with is a mechanical monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not only is it equipped with an artificial heart, it also has artificial lungs. Judging from the bubbles on the surface of the lake, it uses some form of air pump.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think my husband was involved in all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Madame Valladon. I'm sure of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why would anybody build a mechanical monster? Just to scare people?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not very likely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did they try to keep me from finding my husband? And why was he buried anonymously?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I have a pretty good notion of what they're up to -- the Society for the Preservation of Scottish Monuments -- better known as the Diogenes Club.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a knock on the door.</context>
      <utterance>The Diogenes Club?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens and the hotel manager enters, holding a magnum of champagne.</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Ashdown, I have a bottle of champagne for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bottle of champagne? I didn't order it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the magnum to Holmes.</context>
      <utterance>No, indeed. You are to deliver it. These are my instructions.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Instructions from whom? Deliver it where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't know, sir. But there's a carriage waiting for you downstairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ashdown?</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you have the right Mr.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and exits. Holmes taps the bottle of champagne thoughtfully.</context>
      <utterance>Quite sure, Mr. Holmes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Watson, I would say the curtain is going up on the last act.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like the sound of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Holmes starts toward the door, Watson reaches into his sporran.</context>
      <utterance>Please be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He produces a revolver, holds it out to Holmes. Holmes ignores it, exits.</context>
      <utterance>You'd better take this with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's minding the castle?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes climbs into the gig, and the guide moutns the seat beside him.</context>
      <utterance>You'd better get on. It's late.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we going? Some sort of party?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't be disappointed in the guest list.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the host?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flicks the reins. The horse starts off at a trot, and the gig turns into the driveway.</context>
      <utterance>Jonah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Ashdown, I presume.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The red runner, I presume.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>114.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't have gone to all this trouble just for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not for you.  McKeller.  May I have the champagne, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1886 -- not a very good vintage, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A black-suited MAN emerges from the ten, and Mycroft gives him the champagne.</context>
      <utterance>Mediocre. But then again, it's not for drinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man moves off toward the tower. Mycroft pulls back the flap of the tent.</context>
      <utterance>Tie it up, will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes passes inside, Mycroft following.</context>
      <utterance>In here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Despite my most emphatic warning, you persisted in meddling. It would have served you right if you'd all drowned.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry to be so unobliging.  E. Valladon... H'mm.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We found them floating in the lake.</context>
      <utterance>I imagine this belongs to the pretty lady, and this belongs to your valet...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speaking about things floating in the lake --</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much do you know -- or think you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Altogether a strange contraption.</context>
      <utterance>I think you're testing some sort of underwater craft -- camouflauged to mislead the gullible. I think it's an experimental model, operated by a crew of midgets. I think it is powered by sulphuric acid batteries, and uses canaries to detect escaping gas...</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not quite that unique. Right now, four countries are trying to develop what we call a submersible. But none of them could solve the critical problem -- how to stay submerged long enough to make it effective.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does the Good Book say? "And Jonah lived in the belly of that fish for three days and three nights."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was our goal. And thanks to Valladon's air-pump, we got a jump on the rest of them. It's a highly complex system of filtration -- so we had a series of trials --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And at least one error.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>During a test run in Moray Firth, pressure caused a leak in the hull. Sea water mixed with the acid in the batteries to produce chlorine gas. Before they could reach the surface, Valladon and the crew were dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you had them buried in unmarked graves, to preserve your secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was essential to keep the information from your client.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You went to all those lengths to prevent Madame Valladon from fiding her husband?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your client isn't Madame Valladon -- it's the Imperial German Government. They were after the Belgian engineer -- or rather, his invention. They knew he was employed by us, but they couldn't find out where -- so they enlisted the best brain in England to help them. You, my dear brother, have been working for the Wilhelmstrasse.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Madame Valladon -- what part did she play in all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Madame Valladon is dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dead?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>117.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mycroft crosses to the trunk, opens the lid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Holmes a small, framed photograph. Holmes looks at it with apprehension, as well he should: the picture is of a somewhat matronly woman, not the glamorous Gabrielle. Holmes lowers the photograph. Behind it, Mycroft is glaring at him with customary arrogance.</context>
      <utterance>The Germans disposed of her three weeks ago, in Brussels. This is Gabrielle Valladon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The woman who was brought to your house in the middle of the night -- apparently fished out of the Thames -- and apparently suffering from amnesia -- is, in fact, Ilse von Hoffmanstal, one of their most skillful agents. Am I going too fast for one of the "best brains in England?"</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Mycroft continues, Holmes picks up Ilse's water-soaked parasol and examines it.</context>
      <utterance>Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They planted her on you quite neatly, I must admit, so that you could lead them to their objective, the air pump. Very much like using a hog to find truffles. And now perhaps you'd care to join me. I am expecting a certain royal personage from Balmoral.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bows. The Queen extends her hand to him, and he touches it.</context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I trust you had a pleasant journey, Ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes.</context>
      <utterance>It was long and it was tedious. And it had better be worth our while, Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A lady-in-waiting and a uniformed equerry have now descended from the coach. Mycroft leads the party up the steps.</context>
      <utterance>I can assure you, Ma'am, it will be.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what is this curious ship we are supposed to christen?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We call it a submersible, Ma'am. It travels under water.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have now reached the top of the steps.</context>
      <utterance>Under water? What a fantastic idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma'am, may present some of the scientists who were responsible for this achievement. J.W. Ferguson, naval architect --</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST SCIENTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Professor Simpson, our leading expert on hydraulics --</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND SCIENTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>W.W. Prescott, co-inventor of the revolving periscope --</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD SCIENTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is Sir Arthur Grisby, our authority on maritime ballistics --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't claim to understand any of this. But England is proud of you, gentlemen. To think that man can now observe fish in their native habitat --</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, not exactly, Ma'am --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and underwater plants and coral reefs --  Young man -- what was your contribution to this project?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid it was rather negligible, Your Majesty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is my brother, Sherlock, Ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes bows, touches the Queen's extended hand.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, yes. Sherlock Holmes. We have been following your exploits with great interest.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you engaged in one of your fascinating cases at the moment?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a manner of speaking, Ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When can we expect to read Dr. Watson's account of the case?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mycroft signals to a bagpiper, who starts playing HIELAN'</context>
      <utterance>I hope never, Ma'am. It has not been one of my more successful endeavors.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, the ceremonies are about to begin.  Now where is this underwater ship of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the dungeon, Ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The dungeon? What a peculiar place to keep it.  Well, let us get on with it, gentlemen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The four surviving midgets appear on the deck, in wool jerseys and navy caps. They start pulling on a chain which slowly raises the detachable head-and-neck of the monster toward the ceiling, disclosing the conning tower and the periscope.</context>
      <utterance>There she, Ma'am. Her Majesty's Ship Jonah.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what, may we ask, is the purpose of that hideous gargoyle?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's merely a decoy, Ma'am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. To frighten away the sharks, we imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SAILOR of normal height appears on the deck of the sub.</context>
      <utterance>Something of the sort... The crew will now demonstrate the workings of the submersible.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAILOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The midgets scramble down the hatch.</context>
      <utterance>Stand to.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't they rather small for sailors?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are. But because of the size of the craft, the Navy made an exception.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is the sound of the engines starting. Mycroft leads the Queen to an open bulkhead in the side of the sub, with Holmes and rest of the party close behind. Inside, all is noise and confusion. Metal rods are dipping into glass jars of sulphuric acid, complicated machinery is driving the propeller shaft, bellows are inflating and deflating, etc. The midgets are at their stations in the cramped quarters, pulling switches, oiling the engines, operating the periscope. Overhead is a cageful of canaries, all chirping away. Mycroft points out the various features to the Queen.</context>
      <utterance>They should make it a rule. It's quite fatiguing to pin on all those medals while standing on our toes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the main engine, which propels it under water at the rate of two knots -- the stabilizing mechanism -- the multi- stage compressor -- the ballast tank trimmer -- the air-pump which filters and recirculates the air --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How charming.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The air pump, Ma'am?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The canaries. Must make the crew feel at home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Ma'am. These are the levers for firing the torpedoes, which are accurate up to as much as 120 feet -- the periscope for scanning the surface of the water --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But where is the glass bottom?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The what, Ma'am?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The glass bottom.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know -- to see the fist --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and the plants and the corals --</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not quite the idea, Ma'am. H.M.S. Jonah is being commissioned as a warship.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At a signal from Mycroft, the sub engines are turned off.</context>
      <utterance>A warship?  Stop that noise. Stop it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma'am, if I may explain --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Admiralty regards this craft as the ultimate weapon in naval warfare. It can seek out enemy ships and destroy them -- with these torpedoes -- while remaining completely invisible.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean in can fire at other vessels while under water?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Without any warning?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is correct, Ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And without showing her colors?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indeed, Ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Holmes, we are not amused.  It is unsportsmanlike, it is un-English, and it is in very poor taste. We will have none of it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exchanges a look with Holmes.</context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon, Ma'am?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes we despair of the state of the world. What will scientists think of next?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's precisely it, Ma'am. At this very moment the Germans under Count von Zeppelin, are experimenting with a dirigible --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A dirigible? And what, pray, is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A rigid balloon, which could fly over London and drop a bomb on Buckingham Palace. It is being developed at the express orders of Kaiser Wilhelm the Second.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nonsense. We refuse to believe that our grandson Willie would do a thing like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have conclusive proof, Ma'am. Our agent in Friedrichshafen, a man named Ibbetson, actually saw the dirigible, and made a drawing of it. Unfortunately, he was apprehended before he could cross the border.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scuttle it! The sooner the better.</context>
      <utterance>Nevertheless, we don't want any part of this beastly invention. Get rid of it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I point out, Ma'am --</utterance>
   <speaker>QUEEN VICTORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts toward the spiral staircase. The equerry precedes her up the stairs, the lady-in-waiting follows, the scientists trail after them. Mycroft and Holmes linger behind.</context>
      <utterance>And don't concern yourself about that dirigible dropping bombs on us. We shall write a very sharp note to the Kaiser.  Now we wish to return to Balmoral.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Mycroft, it seems we have both been undone by a woman.  What a shame.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not necessarily. If the Germans want that submersible so badly, why don't we give it to them?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it to them?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Invite them aboard for the final journey -- seven hundred feet -- straight down.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how are you going to arrange that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O.s., the bagpiper resumes playing.</context>
      <utterance>I'm rather counting on you to do it. Since you are on such intimate terms with Fraulein von Hoffmanstal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts up the spiral staircase. Holmes follows slowly and thoughtfully.</context>
      <utterance>Shall we say goodbye to Her Majesty?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schloss, isn't it?</context>
      <utterance>Sorry about that. But as long as you're up -- what is the German word for castle?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unter das Schlss? Or die Schloss?</context>
      <utterance>And how would you say under the castle?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. My German isn't that good.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Trappist friends are out there waiting to hear from you -- it's a chilly morning -- we don't want to keep them standing around too long, do we, Fraulein Hoffmanstal?  Come now. It's too late to play cat and mouse.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unter dem Schloss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's up to the good monks now. You can consider your part of the mission accomplished, Fraulein Hoffmanstal.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're all wrong about me. My name isn't Hoffmanstal.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's von Hoffmanstal.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stand corrected.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose once they're in the castle... It must amuse you, Mr. Holmes, Trappists walking into a trap.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's more amusing than that. Once in the castle, they will encounter surprisingly little resistance -- it will take but a small bottle of chloroform to overcome the guards.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean you're going to let them have the air-pump?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better than that. We're going to let them have the submersible. They will find it with its engines running, all set to go. I assume they're all expert sailors? And since there is a German battleship cruising off the coast of Scotland, I expect they'll try to sail it out of the lock and rendezvous at sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you say try to?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens her suitcase, which is on the baggage rack at the foot of the bed. Gabrielle watches him for a beat, then crosses to the wardrobe, starts taking her clothes out.</context>
      <utterance>I would suggest you get your things together. Mycroft will be here to take you into custody.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never had you fooled for a moment, did I? You knew right from the beginning -- when the cabbie brought me to Baker Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stretches out on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Let me see -- not quite that soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so funny. I asked for this assignment, you know. I was scheduled to go to Japan, but I couldn't resist the challenge of coming up against the best. I'm sorry I didn't give you a closer game.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just being kind. I failed miserably.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all have occasional failures. Fortunately, Dr. Watson never writes about mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was out there. Now it's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gone?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bottle of champagne?... and a Bible?...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps through the window as a puzzled Watson lowers the telescope.</context>
      <utterance>That's all that's left of H.M.S. Jonah.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It would seem that somebody carelessly loosened the bolts of the submersible. What a fitting end for Trappists -- now they are resting in eternal silence at the bottom of the lake.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fraulein von Hoffmanstal?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. Holmes. I'm all ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's one thing I like about the Prussians, it's their punctuality.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's one thing I dislike about the British, it's their climate. I understand your jails are quite damp -- and your heating facilities totally inadequate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're going back to Germany.</context>
      <utterance>They are. But you're not going to jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Germany?</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will be conducted to the Swiss-German border, and be exchanged for one of our agents -- a man named Ibbetson.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabrielle looks at Holmes, but he avoids her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Don't thank me. Thank my brother. It was his idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frankly, I think we are making a very poor deal. You much better than most operatives working for British intelligence.  Don't you agree, Sherlock?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mycroft signals to his aide, who comes in from the corridor and picks up Gabrielle's bag.</context>
      <utterance>And better than some consulting detectives.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MYCROFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall we?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIELLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and walks out the door, Mycroft following. Watson's bewilderment has now reached monumental proportions.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take that.  Gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Holmes -- you don't have to explain anything to me, if you don't want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate that, Watson.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After all, I'm only your official biographer --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, I don't think she'd care to have this story spread all over Strand Magazine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes crosses to a small window overlooking the courtyard of the hotel, opens it, looks out.</context>
      <utterance>The public has a right to know these things. If she's a German spy, why should we concern ourselves about her feelings?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I promised not to write a word about it, would you enlighten me? As your friend -- as your valet --</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet. I'm trying to read a personal message.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A message?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is she saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Auf Wiedersehn.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Auf Weider---? The nerve!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>H'mmm. A letter from the Diogenes Club.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe Mycroft is putting you up for membership.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has slit open the envelope. Watson watches him curiously as he reads the letter, but Holmes' face remains expressionless. Slowly he puts down the letter, rises, crosses to the window, stands there staring out into the wintry street.</context>
      <utterance>If only to have the distinct pleasure of blackballing his brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holmes doesn't answer. Watson takes a lump of sugar out of the bowl with a pair of tongs, drops it into his coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Aren't you going to finish your breakfast?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="156" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holmes -- I'm terribly sorry about this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is it, Watson?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're getting better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="157" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LESTRADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Watson.  Just happened to be in the neighborhood, and I thought --</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it this time, Inspector Lestrade?</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTRADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've had three rather nasty murders in Whitechapel. All ladies of easy virtue. You may read something about it -- the newspapers are referring to the killer as Jack the Ripper.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I think I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTRADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of us at Scotland Yard were wondering if perhaps Mr. Holmes would be willing to --</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Lestrade. But at the moment, Holmes is working on another problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>LESTRADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... Well, I just thought it was the kind of case that might interest him. I dare say we can solve it without his help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="158" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From Holmes' bedroom comes the sound of a melancholy tune being played on the violin. Watson starts to ease Lestrade out of the door.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm sure you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shuts the door after him, listens to the sound of the violin for a moment. Then he crosses to the wicker chair, seats himself. He takes some sheets of paper out of the rack and places them on the writing arm, dips his pen in the inkwell, starts to write. The violin music continues OVER SCENE, infinitely romantic, infinitely sad.</context>
      <utterance>Good day, Lestrade.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
