<movie id="165" title="Descendants The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Matt looks up at the WOMAN we saw in the speedboat, now lying stiffly on an upright HOSPITAL BED, her head cocked to one side, a feeding tube in her nose, a ventilator in her trachea, IVs in her arm.</context>
      <utterance>For the last 23 days, I've been living in a "paradise" of IVs and urine bags and endotracheal tubes and six-month- old US magazines. Paradise. Paradise can go fuck itself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Elizabeth King, my wife. Twenty-three days ago she was launched from a powerboat during a race and hit her head, almost drowned. Now she's in a coma that scores 5 on the Glasgow scale and 3 on the Rancho Los Amigos scale, scores showing an extremely severe coma. Liz is very competitive. Whatever she does, she does to the fullest.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEUROLOGIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She reacts non-purposefully to stimuli in a non-specific manner, but occasionally her responses are specific, though inconsistent. Her reflexes are primitive and often the same, regardless of stimuli presented...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was exactly what Elizabeth used to accuse me of.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Liz has a living will.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-three days in a coma, and any day now the doctors will give me their final verdict if she's going to come out of it or not. Then I have a decision to make. Wait, that's wrong.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>His CELLPHONE RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Like always, she makes her own decisions. But I know she's going to pull through.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Noe, what's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>NOE</speaker>
      <mode>ON PHONE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Matt, you have a call from Scottie's teacher. She says it's urgent.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure. Put her on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MS. HAYASHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just don't think these photographs are appropriate for Scottie to be sharing with her classmates. Some of them went home quite disturbed, and we got some angry calls from parents.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, she's sort of been going to town with the whole picture-taking thing, but I had no idea --</utterance>
   <speaker>MS. HAYASHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you how my heart goes out to you and your family, but Scottie just hasn't been herself. Principal Cruz agrees with us that it maybe would be better for Scottie to remain at home with you during this difficult time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Home. See, I would think that sticking to her normal routine would be the best thing for her -- you know, keep her occupied. I wouldn't really know how to...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, I've kind of got my hands full. And her sister's away at school on the Big Island. I don't think Scottie would really want to hang out with me when she could be with her friends and people like you who specialize in children.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. THULL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. King, we see this every day -- children acting out at school when something's wrong at home. And your family is facing a devastating crisis. Have you been engaging Scottie in really talking about what's going on? Encouraging her to express her feelings? That's crucial.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah. Yeah. Absolutely.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They look over to see --</context>
      <utterance>This shit is bananas. B-a-n-a-n-a-s. This shit is bananas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Matt stares aghast at this specimen called his daughter. The ladies glance between Scottie and Matt, wondering when, or whether, he'll intervene. Finally --</context>
      <utterance>This shit is bananas. B-a-n-a-n-a-s!</utterance>
   <speaker>MS. HAYASHI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scottie remains oblivious. Ms. Hayashi rises to her feet.</context>
      <utterance>Scottie, that is not a good choice! Are you making a good choice?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Scottie, come on. Knock it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>5.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Descendants PINK Shooting Draft 4/11/10 Draft</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter with you? Showing those pictures of Mom for your art project?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a photographer, Dad, a real photographer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're not. You're overdoing it is what you're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's what I'm doing.</context>
      <utterance>I saw it in a book. Some famous photographer lady took pictures of her mom in the hospital while she was dying, and they're considered art.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First of all, your mother's very sick, but she's not dying. Second, you don't share personal stuff like that with strangers. What's going on with Mom is private.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hungry. Can we get burgers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we get smoothies?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Scottie continues --</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The last time I took care of Scottie by myself was when she was one. Now she's ten, and I have no idea what goes on inside her head. She's insane. And with Elizabeth in the hospital, I think she's testing me. I'm the backup parent. The understudy.</utterance>
   <speaker>6.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Descendants PINK Shooting Draft 4/11/10 Draft</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish you'd stop doing that. And rather than taking her picture all the time, you should talk to her. I'm tired of asking you. You heard Dr. Johnston -- people in a coma can hear you -- you know, well, some of them can. It lets them know they're still loved, might even help them wake up sooner. And it'll help you express whatever feelings and emotions you're supposed to be going through -- you know, make you feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her a story.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a story.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her anything. Tell her what's been going on in school.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She never cares about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe that. What about after school? She's always driving you around the island. You know, gymnastics? Soccer?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't do those things anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ballet? Piano? Hula?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're not going to say anything to your mother, we might as well leave.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about this? Write her a letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would I write?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. "Get well. Wake up. I love you. Don't leave me alone with my idiot Dad."</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's she going to read it? She's in a coma.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddammit, Scottie, stop fighting me on everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it doesn't make any sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what your mother is hearing right now? You refusing to talk to her. Is that what you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes Scottie by the hand and sits her down in a chair next to the bed.</context>
      <utterance>I'm starving. And I'm thirsty. I want a soda.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What do you want to drink?</context>
      <utterance>We're not leaving until you talk to her. I'll even give you privacy. Recite her the alphabet for all I care.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sprite.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, Sprite. Diet Sprite?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not diet. Regular. Do you think I'm fat?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're not fat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not the model.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just that all that sugar makes you cranky.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not cranky!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'll be right back. Talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NURSE JOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. King, how are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, Joy, fine. And you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE JOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Have you made your decision yet?</context>
      <utterance>I see your picture in the paper today.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My decision?</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE JOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your family. About your big land. The other NURSE nudges Joy to be more polite.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE JOY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Me and Mr. King, we're like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's not really my decision. It's my whole family's decision. And furthermore...  ... mind your own business, young lady. As he turns away to continue down the hall --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHOPKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, they all the same cards. You like buy all the same cards?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SHOPKEEPER blinks at the man weirdly accosting her.</context>
      <utterance>These are inappropriate for a hospital gift shop. This girl is underage. Why do you sell postcards like this? This is a hospital. These aren't get-well cards.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOPKEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like buy all the cards? Or you want I put them back?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she rings him up --</context>
      <utterance>Never mind. Yes, I'm buying them. And these two sodas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scottie, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hungry. Can we go?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't talk to her, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you tell her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's private.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scottie fights him as he snatches her phone away.</context>
      <utterance>You're lying. And Jesus Christ, enough with the goddamn texting! Give me that phone! Give it here!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Scottie springs up out of the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Scottie. Okay, you win. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least say goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scottie bolts out the door. Matt takes a last look at Liz, panic and sadness rippling across his face.</context>
      <utterance>Bye, Mom!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My wife -- the sportswoman, the model, the drinker.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you please wake up already? I need you. I can't do this alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this Barb Higgins?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Matt King returning your call. I assume your daughter is a classmate of my daughter's.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see, where to start? It's Scottie. She's been texting some awful things to Lani, and I'd like her to stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For instance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's the latest one. "We all know you grew pubes over the summer." She sends little messages like that for no reason. She even wrote it on Lani's Facebook wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She calls my daughter Lanikai, implying she's like the size of an entire neighborhood. Do you think that's nice?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances out the window at Scottie, who sits on the ground, back turned, POUNDING something with a BIG ROCK.</context>
      <utterance>That's not like her at all. She's usually very sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you may know, her mother isn't well, and maybe this is how she's dealing with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care about the backstory, Mr. King. My daughter comes home from school in tears.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, no, I get it. I'm very sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scottie should be the one who's sorry. I want her to come over and apologize to Lani, and I don't ever want her to write to my daughter again.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANI</speaker>
      <mode>DISTANT O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She can in a good way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Matt draws a long exasperated breath, as if everything else weren't enough already.</context>
      <utterance>If she doesn't apologize, I'm going to tell the headmaster. You can't buy your way out of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See what I mean? Everybody sees me as the rich guy, the inheritor. People resent us. I resent us. Even our last name -- King. How irritating.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need to say you're sorry, and you need to mean it. No dicking around. I have a ton of work to do tonight. Do you have any idea how behind I am? You made her cry. Why would you want to be so mean to someone?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what you text all the time, nasty things?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what then?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I write them with Reina. They make her laugh, and then she shows Megan and Brooke, and they laugh too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should have known Reina had something to do with it. I don't want you hanging out with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, I told Reina she could visit me in the hospital since I'm not in school anymore. Can she?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something outside the window catches Scottie's attention.</context>
      <utterance>We'll make a deal. You apologize to this girl, and you talk to your mother, and then we'll see about Reina dropping by the hospital. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt looks to see --</context>
      <utterance>Dorks!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dorks!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scottie sits back in her seat, laughing. Matt glances in his rearview mirror to see a TEENAGE SON taking off his T-shirt and throwing it to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Scottie, knock it off!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her house is down there on the corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been here before?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yea-uh. She invites me to her birthday, like, every year.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you guys are actually friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Until last year's party, when she locked me out of the house and I had to sit outside all day while everybody was inside. She thought she was so great, but then I became friends with Reina and Brooke and got popular.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you for coming by.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scottie, do you have something you want to say to Lani?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LANI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Come for a swim or a hike or something.</context>
      <utterance>Great. Well, nice meeting you both. Lani, you should come over sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scottie, the things you said were simply evil. Do you realize that? I don't know what's led you to be such a nasty young lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scottie makes a big exaggerated nod.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey. We came over. She apologized. We're dealing with it. Kids are mean sometimes. They grow out of it. It's a kid thing. Here, Scottie, you're going to stop, right? And you're really, really sorry, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think she's sorry at all. She's going to keep doing it. I can tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lani thinks a moment, nods.</context>
      <utterance>No, she won't. It's like the time Lani locked Scottie out of the house at her birthday party and Scottie sat outside by herself. It was a mean thing to do, but Lani here probably did it just to show off, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm not about to declare that one action defines a human being's entire character. She's a work in progress, and like all complex people is a bundle of contradictions.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You brought me cake.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, and Mr. King?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt turns to look at her. So that's what all this was about on some level?</context>
      <utterance>Good luck with the sale.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say your decision will have a major impact on Hawai'i's real estate world, not to mention the whole landscape of Kaua'i. Hundreds of millions of dollars, yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big decision.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My husband's family is from Kaua'i. Hanapepe, born and bred. They hope you don't sell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARB HIGGINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt and Scottie walk away. Barb closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>All the traffic it's going to make.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to act different with Lani?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll try, but it's hard. She has a face you just want to hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Matt looks up, his glance falling on the portraits of Edward and Margaret.</context>
      <utterance>My great-great-grandmother was Princess Margaret Ke'alohilani, one of the last direct descendants of King Kamehameha. She was originally supposed to marry her hanai brother, but she fell in love with her haole banker and estate manager, Edward King, whose parents were missionaries. Between his land deals and her huge inheritance, all of their descendants for generations have watched the past unfurl millions into our laps through leases and sales. Now the Rule Against Perpetuities is forcing us to dissolve the trust, and we're selling the last parcel of undeveloped land.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon my daughters and I can just be normal citizens like everybody else, and these dead people will stop controlling our lives.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Matt's secretary NOE cracks open his door.</context>
      <utterance>Unlike a lot of my cousins, I haven't touched my share of the trust money. Like my father before me, I live only on the income from my law practice. I don't want my daughters growing up entitled and spoiled. And I agree with my father -- you give your children enough money to do something but not enough to do nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. King, your cousins are here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DR. JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt sits very still.</context>
      <utterance>Bad news, Matt. Dr. Chun, Dr. Mueller and I -- we believe her condition, which we call a multi-factorial anoxic encephalopathy, is deteriorating. We see no eye movement, no pupillary response, basically no brainstem reflexes whatsoever. The machines could keep her going, but her quality of life would be... very poor. Basically what you see now. She'll never be like she was, Matt. Never. We know that now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you how sorry I am to have to tell you this. And you have your daughters. There's just nothing we can do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... if we do go ahead and take her off the machines --</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if, Matt. When. I have a legal obligation. You know that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long will she last?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Organ donation? Forgot about that one.</context>
      <utterance>Hard to say. Could be a few days. Could be two weeks. But for planning purposes, you should work off the shortest possible scenario. I know I need to get the ball rolling on organ donations right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth has so many friends, a big life. Last time I was at your house, must have been 200 people. If you're going to let people know to say goodbye, which is fairly typical protocol in these situations, start now. By the time the last day comes, they feel more ready, as ready as they can feel. I'm so sorry, Matt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt and Mark exchange a look -- "Girls."</context>
      <utterance>Oh, she's been looking a little pale lately all cooped up in here, and I just know she'd be mortified if no one had thought to help her out with some lipstick and blush. I know she'll grill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And of course Kai's getting her all caught up on all the latest gossip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt smiles -- he'd been expecting a grim moment alone with Elizabeth, but instead he finds a room full of warmth and life. Even if it's a little creepy.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't want to have to start from scratch later. Oh, and Matt, on the way here we stopped by and left some more meals in your fridge, all ready to nuke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's the latest anyway, Matt? Any updates?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kai nods sympathetically before turning back to Elizabeth. EXTREME CLOSEUP of Liz's lips as Kai applies lipstick.</context>
      <utterance>No, no. Just more of the same -- monitoring the swelling, keeping her kidneys and other vitals working, you know, hoping for the best.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hungry!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else is new? Let's get you something to eat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The food here at the club is so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, they do a good job here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is it called a jellyfish? It's not a fish, and it's not jelly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No idea. You ask good questions. You're getting too smart for me, Scottie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt notices a BUFF GUY and some FRIENDS headed to a nearby table, and his mood sours. Scottie follows his gaze. The guy notices the Kings and feels obliged to mosey over. This is TROY COOK -- athletic and rich.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to find out. Then I'm going to ask Mom when she wakes up and see if she knows. Do you think she's going to know everything she used to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>TROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Matt. Hi, Scottie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Troy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll catch up to you guys in a second. Matt stares so intensely that Troy averts his gaze.</utterance>
   <speaker>TROY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, uh, what's going on? I mean, how's Elizabeth doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same.</utterance>
   <speaker>TROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I visited her last week, you know. I thought she looked pretty good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why'd you ask?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scottie looks up hopefully. Matt notices.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, I just wanted to know the latest. I'm praying for her every day, you guys. Really hard. Seriously. So what I was saying was, when I was there, I talked to her, and her hand moved, so I was pretty encouraged. I thought that was an encouraging sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>TROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really think she heard me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Troy walks away, stops, turns back.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Troy, go to your friends. No hard feelings. Let's just leave it alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, Matt, there were lots of chops and holes that day. I told you a hundred times. Ask anybody. What happened to her could have happened to me. It was a super-hard day on the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't supposed to be driving, Troy. She was supposed to be driving.</utterance>
   <speaker>TROY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wanted me to drive. And she's the one who told me to pass the other boat right before the turn. And just your whole attitude toward me, Matt -- I mean, I feel terrible. I wish it were me and not her. Plus I almost drowned myself when we capsized. And my rotator cuff is never going to be the same, and I'm going to miss Moloka'i.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just because her hand moved, it doesn't mean anything, Troy. Mom twitches at weird times. When you cut off a chicken's head, it runs all around, but it's still a dead chicken.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, sport, don't pay any attention to that guy. That guy's a dope.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I don't want Mom to die.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to say dead chicken.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I know. Hey, let's get out of here. Let's go do something crazy. Like let's drive to the airport and hop over to the Big Island and surprise your sister. What do you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll be fun. She's not expecting us or anything. And we bring her home. I think she should be here with us, don't you? Don't you miss her? I miss her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm out of school. She should be too!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, sorry to bother you. I'm Matt King.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORM SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, hello, Mr. King.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've come to pick up my daughter, Alexandra.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORM SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you call Administration?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't. It's sort of an emergency.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which door? Which door is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scottie, keep it down!</utterance>
   <speaker>DORM SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn down another corridor, and Scottie knocks on a door.</context>
      <utterance>Will you both keep it down? It's around the corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORM SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The door opens, and a girl pokes her head out.</context>
      <utterance>That's the wrong door.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORM SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go back to sleep, Yuki.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dorm supervisor knocks on an adjacent door. A moment later a ROOMMATE opens, groggy from sleep.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Yuki.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORM SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wake your roommate, sweetie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROOMMATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... Alex isn't here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DORM SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROOMMATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she's... outside somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>28.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Descendants PINK Shooting Draft 4/11/10 Draft</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DORM SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girls! What do you think you're doing out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Emily takes off but doesn't get far -- she falls flat on her face, golf club in one hand, BOTTLE in the other.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Alex! It's me, Scottie!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I pay $25,000 year for this crap not to happen. Alex!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This cracks her up even more. Scottie laughs too, though she's unsure why.</context>
      <utterance>Dad?  My fucking dad is here!</utterance>
   <speaker>DORM SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't talk like that here. This is unacceptable behavior!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up, Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMILY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You come out to play a few holes with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We came to get you so you can come home. He took me out of school already. I haven't gone for three whole days.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening? Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexandra hears this, takes a few strides, flings her golf club into the night.</context>
      <utterance>You need to come home and see Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck Mom!</utterance>
   <speaker>DORM SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I say about the language?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>30.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Descendants PINK Shooting Draft 4/11/10 Draft</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like eggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you say so before I made them?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex trudges in and pulls a Coca-Cola out of the fridge.</context>
      <utterance>I thought they were for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning.  Does Mom let you have Coke for breakfast?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now that we get a closer look, we might recognize Alexandra from the postcards at the hospital. We also see a resemblance to her mother.</context>
      <utterance>I'm pretty sure it's after eleven.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shrugging, she plops down near Scottie.</context>
      <utterance>How are you feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hungover, huh? Why am I not surprised? I don't know where to start, and we probably shouldn't in front of Scottie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were supposed to be getting your act together.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have gotten my act together. I was just drinking. I've been doing really well, but nobody ever seems to notice my grades are better, and how I was in that stupid play you guys didn't bother to see. Do you even remember the name of it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>31.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Descendants PINK Shooting Draft 4/11/10 Draft</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I thought. So what if I got drunk on the ONE night you happened to drop in? So the fuck what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey, hey. Watch your language in front of Scottie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyway, it's good to see you. Welcome home. Want some eggs?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long do I have to stay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll discuss that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going swimming.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I'll join you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good times.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt notices all the floating leaves and insects.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go. I'll see you later.  The pool's really dirty. What day does the pool guy come?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He comes... you know, I don't know what day he comes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt grabs a POLE to skim the surface of the water.</context>
      <utterance>Awesome.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid's coming over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Sid?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A really good friend from Punahou. We were in school together for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt wonders his own version of "What am I, chopped liver?"</context>
      <utterance>He wants to be there for me with all this shit happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I know his parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just then, Scottie runs out onto the patio dressed in a BRA</context>
      <utterance>No. He might stay over too. Is that cool?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck? Get out of my underwear, you freak.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ooo, la la! Don't I look divine?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scottie, get back inside and change into your swimsuit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scottie flips him off and runs back inside.</context>
      <utterance>Now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Real good job you're doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexandra slides into the water, swims to the other side and props herself on the edge, floating her lower body. Matt lowers himself into the water too.</context>
      <utterance>That's part of why I brought you here. You have to help me. I don't know what to do with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe if you spent more time with her, she wouldn't act like such a complete spaz. Get her out of town -- go camp on Kaua'i. That's what mom did with me whenever I was losing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Alex, your mother isn't well.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obviously.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex remains silent.</context>
      <utterance>They just told me she isn't going to wake up. It's for sure now. The doctors are going to stop caring for her. Do you understand what I'm saying? Your mom wanted it this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Alex looks at him, takes a couple quick, loud inhalations, then slips --</context>
      <utterance>She has a will, see, saying we have to do it like this. We both do. That's why I got you. We're letting her go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt climbs out and approaches her, arms extended.</context>
      <utterance>Why'd you have to tell me in the goddamned pool?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex... Alex...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt drops his arms, crestfallen. Alex scoffs, walks back into the house.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just found out yesterday. We have to go through this thing together, you and Scottie and I. And I need to go around and tell people what's happening -- our family and close friends. Sometimes I'll want you to come with me. Other times I need you to watch Scottie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to go around with you and tell everyone that Mom's going to die? What's the point of that? Breaking the news, watching them cry, dealing with their emotions. How depressing is that going to be? Just call them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex, nobody wants to do any of this. But we need to tell Grandpa and Tutu, a few friends. They have the right to know and to be able to say goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to talk about Mom with anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever you fought about with her at Christmas, you need to drop it. Grow up. You love your mother. Your mother loves you. Move on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't drop it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whoa.</context>
      <utterance>You really don't have a clue, do you? Dad, she was cheating on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what we fought about. When I was home at Christmas, I caught her with some guy. It made me sick to see her near you. I went back to school thinking that was it, I was done with her. I was going to call and tell you everything. But then the accident happened, and I was waiting until she woke up, I guess. And you, you didn't even suspect. Right?  That disgusted me too. You're always so busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Caught her with some guy? What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brandy and I were on our way to swim in the Black Point pool, and suddenly I see Mom and some douchebag walk into a house. His house, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a guy? It could have been anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He had his hand on her ass. It was gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure it was her.  Then what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then nothing. She went into the house. A few days later I told her I knew what she was doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First she acted like she didn't know what I was talking about. Like I'm blind. Then she got super-mad and started yelling at me and denied it. That's when I decided I didn't want anything more to do with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Some guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt stands up, walks in a little circle -- he literally does not know which way to turn. Then he knows.</context>
      <utterance>Dark hair.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch Scottie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARK AND KAI appear at the top of the stairs looking as though they haven't been downstairs all day.</context>
      <utterance>Hello! It's me, Matt!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hey, Matt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they come downstairs --</context>
      <utterance>You guys weren't sleeping, were you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Want a drink? Want some coffee?</context>
      <utterance>No, we were just fighting. Come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were you fighting about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not stupid. He wants us to throw parties and have people over, which we do, of course, but who ends up doing all the work? Me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they continue their argument, Matt is struck by the pettiness of everyday life. He at once pities it, is impatient with it, and longs for it.</context>
      <utterance>It's work that's totally unnecessary. You don't have to do anything. Nobody's forcing you to clean and buy a new outfit and think of some goddamn theme cocktail. We can just invite people over last minute and drink whatever we have and hang out. It's more fun that way, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what? We can talk about it later. Matt didn't come over to hear us squabble.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, Matt. Is Elizabeth -- is there any news?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In fact there is. I'll tell you in a moment. Who is he?  Does she love him? Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Matt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>seeing.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to put you in this position. But I'm not really the one who put you there, am I? I just want to know who this guy is that my wife has been...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Matt, you're angry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could be a therapist. Very keen powers of observation.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt sits. He's not leaving. No one speaks.</context>
      <utterance>Wow. I think we should talk another time. I think you need to cool it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it Troy? That fucking Neanderthal?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't you even, Mark. Shame on you. You're her friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'd want to know.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Matt's friend too. And this is a very unique and dramatic situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't betray her when she can't even defend herself. Matt, you may not be able to hear this right now, but it's not her fault. Women have needs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you fucking kidding me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your marriage was not... You worked so hard to make partner, and no one can take that away from you. But then you made partner, and you only got busier. And it's not like you were so involved with the girls. She was lonely.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kai looks away. Mark nods.</context>
      <utterance>So you're going to talk to me in clichs about women? Nothing is ever a woman's fault. Was it still going on when she had the accident?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I stayed out of it, Matt. Anytime Kai talked about it, I walked away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you what? You probably egged her on. Add some drama to your life without any actual risk. Whom do you think you're protecting anyway? She doesn't need your protection -- it's over. She's going to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I almost told you yesterday. She's never going to wake up. It's for sure now. You hear me? We're pulling the plug. You were putting lipstick on a corpse.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kai's face dissolves into tears. Mark reaches out to comfort her. Everybody falls back to Earth.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Matt. That's a little intense.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt looks at him blankly, then at Kai. He'd like to know too.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I didn't mean to take it out on you guys. I just... Does she love him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt is stunned but oddly relieved. The truth, once revealed, blows a calming wind.</context>
      <utterance>How can you ask about him when she's going to die? Who cares? Yes, she loves him, loved him, whatever. She's crazy about him. She was going to ask you for a divorce.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt rises to his feet and leave.</context>
      <utterance>You still haven't told me who he is. I guess it doesn't matter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, this is Sid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lanky and odd, a permanent smirk on his face, SID rises from his lounge chair.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Sid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they shake hands, Sid pulls Matt into a man-hug and thumps him on the back.</context>
      <utterance>`Sup, bro?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ever do that to me again.  Get ready, okay? We're going to Grandma and Grandpa's.  Auntie Esther will come over to watch you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid's coming with us, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid, this week, what's going on, is a real family matter. You understand.  Sid's not going to be interested in meeting your grandparents. He'll be bored stiff.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, I told you he was going to be with me. I'll be a lot more civil with him around.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does he know what we're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knows everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dude, your wife is dying and then you find out she's been stepping out on you? That's harsh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get in the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>42.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Descendants PINK Shooting Draft 4/11/10 Draft</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is like reading Korean.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scott, I'll be happy to walk you through it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jibber-jabber.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's an advanced directive -- basically her instructions on what medical procedures she wants or, in this case, does not want. No prolonged mechanical ventilation, no --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares off into space.</context>
      <utterance>I know goddamn well what it says. Says she doesn't want everyone waiting around while she spoils like milk. Says if the doctors can't do squat, she'd just as soon get on with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gramps, are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth had the good sense to write this thing here. Always a thoughtful girl. A strong girl. A hell of a lot stronger than her brother. Barry whines his way through life. Might even be a homosexual, for all I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Scott, I don't think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And she's stronger than you, Matt. She lived more in a year than you did in a decade, sitting in your office, hoarding all your cash. All that money you refuse to use -- what the hell good is it? And now you and your family are cashing in your chips -- what the hell for? Maybe if you'd let my baby have her own boat and bought her some safe equipment or let her go on those shopping sprees women like, maybe she wouldn't have gone in for those thrill sports. Maybe if you'd provided more thrills at home.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Grandpa.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man climbs to his feet and takes a few steps away. Hands on hips, he looks up as though gauging the weather. Then he clears his throat, wipes his face with his sleeve, turns back.</context>
      <utterance>And you, Alexandra. Putting your poor mother through hell when all she was trying to do was instill some sense and drive in you. Shame on you. You should try to be more like her. She's a good girl. She's a good girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As he wanders away toward the kitchen --</context>
      <utterance>You all want a drink?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, do we have guests?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Alice. Good to see you. It's me, Matt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good to see you too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Tutu.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Alexandra.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's your granddaughter. And this is your son-in-law Matt. This is your family. Well, except this kid. I don't know who the hell he is.  Who are you? Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alice, we're going to go to Queen's Hospital today and see Elizabeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid bursts out LAUGHING.</context>
      <utterance>We are? Queen Elizabeth? That's wonderful. I've never met a queen before. I have to put on a nice dress.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is she serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You be quiet, son.  No, Alice. Our Elizabeth. Our baby. We need to go visit her in the hospital. She needs us, just like when she was a little girl. Let's think about what she might want in her room. We'll take it to her and put it next to her bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she's a queen. I have to look good for a queen. Don't you want me to look good?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>45.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Descendants PINK Shooting Draft 4/11/10 Draft</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Alice.  Sorry, old gal. You go ahead and say whatever you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Sid snickers again, Scott Thorson approaches him and glares.</context>
      <utterance>I've never met a queen before.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, man. I was just laughing. It's funny. I think she knows she's being funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott POPS HIS FIST into Sid's face. Sid FLIES BACK.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to hit you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the backseat, Sid holds a package of FROZEN PEAS to his puffy blue eye.</context>
      <utterance>How's the eye?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was unreal. I mean, how often do old people just haul off and fucking cold-cock you in the face?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's hit me a couple times over the years. And watch your language.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, let me kiss it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, could you two just cool it around me? You know, stop... touching each other so much?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLAMMING ON THE BRAKES, Matt turns around, points a menacing finger. Even Alexandra realizes Sid went too far.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Maybe that's why your wife cheated on you, if you're so against touching.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You little fuck. Do you get hit a lot?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I've had my share.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You know that, right?</context>
      <utterance>Your friend is completely retarded.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt looks at him. Given who Sid is, there's no reason to think he wouldn't have a retarded brother.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, my little brother's retarded. Don't use that word in a derogatory fashion.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Psych! I don't have a retarded brother!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You suck, Sid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rather than lashing out again at Sid, Matt turns around and lowers his head into one hand, squeezing his temples. It's all getting to be too much for him.</context>
      <utterance>Speaking of retarded, do you ever feel bad for wishing a retarded person or an old person would just hurry up? Sometimes I wait for them to cross the street, and I'm like, come on already! But then I feel bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt thinks a moment, then --</context>
      <utterance>Don't forget -- I know where he lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get in the front seat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been doing any surfing over there on the Big Island?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't surfed in years.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, how come? You were so good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At first I stopped because I got my period and didn't know how to use a tampon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't want to attract sharks, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I wouldn't go for, you know, five days or so, and then I guess I just stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you ask Mom to show you or teach you or whatever?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't even tell her I got my period for like a year. She was always pushing me to look older and act older, so I just...</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even I know how to use a tampon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first time I got my period I thought I shit my pants.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ew, maybe you did!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid, shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure he knows what's going on with our family? Because he sure doesn't act like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know anything about him? Like what he does or if he's married?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just his name. Brian Speer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you ask Kai and Mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't want to get into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt pulls over opposite a supremely average-looking house.</context>
      <utterance>We'll google him later. Okay, there it is. Stop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There? He lives there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I can't say for sure he lives there. That's just where I saw them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you just happened to be driving by.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all observe closely, very focused. Nothing happens. It's just a house.</context>
      <utterance>Sadie was driving. We both saw it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That house is a piece of shit. At least go after a guy who's got a mansion. And do you think he's married? That'd be pretty cold-blooded to do it in a house where you're married.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid, please be quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all think a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I'm just showing you the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I go ring the bell?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one moves.</context>
      <utterance>No, wait, this is stupid -- this stalking, or whatever the hell we're doing. We came, we saw. Whatever. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not like we're stalking him exactly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would you do if you saw him, anyway? Talk to him or punch him or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I just want to see him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I know is, someone messed with my girl, all hell would break loose.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever, Sid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, you'd never do that to me, would you? You know, if we ever got married. Fuck around on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends on how you treated me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's enough now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we're not getting married. Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, that's enough. We're getting out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt does so, checking that the coast is clear.</context>
      <utterance>Just go back a couple of houses.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There who is?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt and Sid look toward a HOUSE FOR SALE. At first they don't get it, but soon their gaze drifts to the --</context>
      <utterance>Look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now we know what he looks like.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexandra climbs out of the car to grab a FLYER and take a photo of Brian Speer with her phone.</context>
      <utterance>Must be pretty handy for a dude having an affair to have some empty houses at his fingertips.  I'm just saying. That's how I'd do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Looking as though he's about to vomit, Matt hangs up, regards the flyer on the coffee table before him.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, this is Brian Speer at Kaimana- Prudential Realty. Sorry I missed you. Leave a message with your name, number and time of call, and I'll get back to you just as soon as I can. Mahalo.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Matt looks up to see Sid in his boxers.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, boss.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you call him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of your business. And put some clothes on. And you're not sleeping in Alex's room. In fact, you should really go home, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alex wouldn't like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guest room. Take it or leave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to do what we're going to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to make it easy for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just fooling with you, man. We're not like that. Guest room's awesome.  Just call him. He's nobody. Raise hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Matt rises, looks at her motionless face, exhales, gets himself together.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy's little girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He slides the curtain open and lets the girls in.</context>
      <utterance>I'm bringing in your daughters now. Alex is home from school. Try to be nice, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexandra approaches the bed slowly, startled by the changes in her mother's appearance and knowing the end is near.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Mom! Look who's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say something, Alex. People in a coma can hear you. You're supposed to talk to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her how you were drunk the other night. Tell her maybe you're an alcoholic.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess it's in the genes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Girls, be serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Mom. Sorry for being bad. For wasting your money on expensive private schools. Money you could have used on facials and massages and sports equipment. Sorry for everything.  Sorry we weren't good enough for you -- especially Dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop it. That's out of line.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You going to give me a "time out?"</context>
      <utterance>Or what? You going to ground me? Or ship me off to another boarding school?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unable, in front of Scottie, to remind Alex that Elizabeth is dying, Matt grabs his older daughter and SPANKS her.</context>
      <utterance>Goddammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got served!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scottie, out in the hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's the one out of line.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go find Sid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's smoking. I shouldn't be around second-hand smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Scottie runs outside --</context>
      <utterance>Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you just spank me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have no right to talk to your mother that way. She's going to die in a few days. What if those were your last words?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt considers this. Of course she didn't see his recent outburst, and he's not about to let on.</context>
      <utterance>I have every right to speak this way. I'm mad at her. How can you be so forgiving?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be angry later. For now let's just think about the good parts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And don't say that stuff in front of your sister. Don't ruin her for Scottie. Say something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Mom, I know we fought a lot. But I always wanted to be like you. I am like you. I'm exactly like you. God, that came out so dramatic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid saunters inside with Scottie in tow.</context>
      <utterance>You are like her. Mostly in good ways. Maybe some bad ways. Remains to be seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt squints at Sid. Is he stoned?</context>
      <utterance>I hear you got spanked. I hear all hell's breaking loose in here.  Hey, Mrs. K., howzit? I'm Sid, Alex's friend from Punahou, remember? Nice day outside. No clouds. Not too hot. You know what I think? Tough lady like you? I think you're going to make it. I mean, I'm no doctor. What do I know? But that's what I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Sid turns back for a long look at Elizabeth.</context>
      <utterance>I'm staying at your place to help Alex out. Don't worry, Mr. K.'s got me on lockdown at night. And I met your dad - - he packs a mean punch. Look at this.  Wow. You're beautiful.  If you look anything like her when you're older, you're lucky. I mean, you know, not exactly like she is now. I mean in general.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reina just texted me! She's here visiting her grandma! Can she come visit?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dammit, Scottie, no Reina.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you said Thursday, and it's almost Thursday. I don't get to see her in school anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt looks at Alex, who in turn raises her eyebrows -- what harm could it do?</context>
      <utterance>I need her. Alex needs Sid. I need Reina.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, this is Reina. Reina, that's my sister and Sid, and that's my mom on the bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>REINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex and Matt look at each other, bewildered. Scottie leads Reina to the bed and touches her mother's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>REINA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this is your mother? I guess it's true. Should I shake her hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>REINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, Reina, I hear your grandmother's not feeling well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>REINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It's pretty bad. She got her stomach operated on and then got some stupid infection or something. It's pretty gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Reina, thanks for stopping by, and, here, Scottie, let me give you some money, and you two can go get an ice cream or something...</utterance>
   <speaker>REINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too many carbs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carbs. Well, you could go to the cafeteria and get some lettuce.</utterance>
   <speaker>REINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's okay. I'm done.  You aren't a liar after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you want to hang out?</utterance>
   <speaker>REINA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Exit Reina.</context>
      <utterance>No, I should go. I'll see you at the club. Hope your mom gets better.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scottie, what'd she mean by "You aren't a liar after all?" What'd she think you were lying about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't believe Mom was sleeping.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you had to prove to that twat that Mom's in a coma? What the fuck is in your skull, a bunch of stupid pills?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, you motherless whore!</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, whoa, easy there, half-pipe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex listens. Scottie has no idea what's going on, but it sure is fun.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? No, you've got the right number. This is his assistant Sharon. How may I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexandra hangs up, proud. Matt's proud too.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I see. And for how long? Uh-huh. Okay. So one or the other. I'll tell him. Mahalo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was Bonnie Tanaka, a realtor. She says Mr. Speer is on Kaua'i till the 18th, but she'd be happy to show you the house or you can stop by the open house on Sunday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Mr. King.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Buzz.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about Mrs. King. Hope she gets better real soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt nods, swigs his drink. Buzz now feels emboldened to reveal the cocktail concealed behind his back.</context>
      <utterance>It really blows.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please don't tell my mom I'm drinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUZZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I steal beers from your outdoor fridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buzz slinks off.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>PRE-LAP - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've all been asking about Elizabeth, and I've given vague answers. But the reason I've asked you all to come over today is to tell you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that her coma is permanent. She's not going to make it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This week -- tomorrow, in fact -- as per her wishes, we're going to unhook her from life-support.  You all know Elizabeth -- she always likes to do things on her own. Goddammit.  I wanted to tell you all in person. You're all our dear friends, our best friends. And the girls and I appreciate so much all the ways you've helped these last few weeks -- bringing food, calling...</utterance>
   <speaker>ONE GUEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we see her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, for God's sake, yes. That's the whole point. Go see her as soon as possible. That's what I wanted to tell you. It should be now, not after. Everyone who loves her deserves a chance to say goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean him? Tell him to say goodbye?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll only be gone a day or so. I'll leave in the morning, and be back tomorrow night. If it takes another day, fine -- I'll give it two days tops. If I don't find him, at least I tried.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drop it, Dad. You've got way bigger fish to fry than confronting fucking Brian Speer. Are you recording this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm summarizing a deposition.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you work?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you go to a movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To get Scottie out of the house. And you're going to tell him to come back and see Mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think... I just think she would want him to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just call his office and say it's an emergency.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexander senses his resolve -- it's kind of refreshing, actually -- then breaks into a wicked little smile.</context>
      <utterance>On the phone he can escape. In person he has nowhere to go. I want to see his face. I want to change his life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I want to go too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you stay with Scottie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck that. Let's all get out of town.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COUSIN RALPH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Matt turns to see COUSIN RALPH loping over, briefcase in hand. Like Matt, he wears the island businessman's uniform -- Khakis and a Reyn's Spooner shirt. Grinning and nodding, Cousin Ralph gives Matt a back-slap hug and greets Scottie and Alexandra, whose names he clearly forgets.</context>
      <utterance>Yo, Matt King!</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN RALPH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatcha doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just came over for a day or two.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I just got back from Kahului. A little business over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt's smiles to cover the fact that he hasn't actually been thinking about this stuff.</context>
      <utterance>All right. So you here to talk to some of the cousins? Make sure everybody's happy with your choice? Pay your respects to Cousin Hugh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, nothing like that. Just a little holoholo. Get the kids out of town.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it is Holitzer, right? We all know it's Holitzer. Cousin Hugh wants him, they go way back. I got my misgivings, though. It's not the highest bid by a longshot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COUSIN RALPH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's an argument to be made for maxing it out. We only do this once in a lifetime. And in this economy --</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, no, I know. I want to work with you guys, Ralph, I really do. Whatever the majority wants, I'll go along with it. Let's just get it over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's Elizabeth doing? She going to be okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The same.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she's a tough gal. She'll be okay. Yeah. Say, where you going, Hanalei?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Princeville.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. I'll give you a ride.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Ralph.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn off over here. Let's go see the land.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a last look, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got time?</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got nothing but time.</utterance>
   <speaker>65.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Descendants PINK Shooting Draft 4/11/10 Draft</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you shitting me? You guys own all this land?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not personally. It belongs to a trust. But yeah, it's ours for a few more days.</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The other side of that ridge too. You can't see it from here. It's like this, but a little flatter and doesn't have as nice a bay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is outrageous.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All continue to ogle this awe-inspiring sight.</context>
      <utterance>Yep. Big resort there on that point. Commercial area over there, houses all through there. I think they should put in a big zip-line. Hell, we should have put in a zip-line.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, part of me agrees with the cousins who don't want to sell. They're going to make a pretty big stink at the meeting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but we have to sell. The trust has to dissolve in seven years, and if we haven't sold, it'll be a huge mess. Selling now and distributing the cash is the only clean way to do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RALPH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's a shame, yeah? On the other hand, hey, it's just sitting there. No one's using it. At least this way the whole world will be able to enjoy it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With them, we look across this land, vivid and verdant.</context>
      <utterance>Take a good look, girls. In the old days, this was part of your great-great grandmother's inheritance going all the way back to Kamehameha I.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down there is where Mom and I would camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all did, all our lives. A lot of memories.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about me? I want to camp. I wish we lived in the old days.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do. We still do.  Do we really have to sell?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doing anything else would get extremely complicated. A lot of your cousins just want the money. Everything has its time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want us to keep it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not showing anyone by that name.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt hangs up, blinks a few times, spaces out a moment. Then he slides open the glass door to the --</context>
      <utterance>No, I understand. Okay. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex shoots him a look, then stamps out the butt on the bottom of her shoe.</context>
      <utterance>Put that out, will you please?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could at least smoke lights. Like Sid.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just got off the phone with Dr. Johnston. They did what they had to do a couple hours ago. They've moved her to another floor. They say she seems comfortable, still breathing on her own. She's doing okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how are you doing, Alex?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? You mean considering Mom's... circling the drain?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean other than that. In general. You haven't been using, have you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Jesus, I'm not using.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all? I smell pot all the time on Sid.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Sid.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you just stopped? Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Dad, it's no big deal. Kids do drugs and they stop. Unless they're like super-ghetto. And you sent me to boarding school, remember? I couldn't get anything anymore. So no, I'm not doing any drugs. But I still think they're fun. Okay, maybe a little pot once in a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can't deny that.</context>
      <utterance>And a little drinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you being so honest?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom's dying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, I'm proud of you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much to be proud of.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thanks.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, there is. We shipped you off. Let them handle it. And now you're here, helping with Scottie, helping me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to know what really pisses me off? That she wouldn't end it. Not even when she knew she was busted. How are we supposed to feel about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess she really liked him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how are we going to find this guy, Sherlock?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Well, why don't you two take Scottie to the beach? I'm going to call around a little. We're on an island, for Christ's sake. Everything's just one degree of separation.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll find him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's in your suit?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're my beach boobs.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lying on her stomach, Alex lifts her head.</context>
      <utterance>Take that out. Right now. Alex, Jesus, why'd you let her do that? You too, Sid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Take them out, stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scowling, Scottie gets up and starts pulling the sand out of her suit as she stomps toward the water.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Scottie. Honestly. Big boobs look kind of fatty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any luck?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hotels were a dead end, but I took another shot with his office. He's definitely in Hanalei renting a house somewhere -- probably one of those cottages around the bay. Who wants to go for a walk?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt grimaces -- not whom he was hoping for. Alex ties the straps of her bikini and flips over.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, let's go. Scottie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we swim with the sharks? I read in the hotel magazine how they put you in a cage in the ocean and throw shark feed in the water and sharks swim right up to you. Can we do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scottie, we're not really here to do stuff like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you and Mom meet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was with a law school buddy from the mainland, and I took him to the club. We were just coming in from paddling, and your mom was on her way out, and she looked at me and said, "Do you think it's going to snow today?" We all got beers when she came back in. I had already seen her around. That was it. I got her number.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you think she was pretty?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She knocked me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you love about her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love... I don't know. The way we are with each other, most of the time, anyway. I love how she's more capable of feeling joy than anyone I've ever known. I just like being with her, just riding bikes or going out to dinner, even if it's just a plate lunch at Rainbow's. Years ago we used to do a lot of paddling together.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we drop this? Jesus.  "What do you love about Mom, Daddy?" Shut up, already.  And stop babying her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy, Alex. We're just talking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Very close call.</context>
      <utterance>Your mom got chased by a shark once.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were on Moloka'i with Mark and Kai, and your mom was out surfing and saw a shark right beneath her on a wave. Like right beneath her. She got down on her stomach and started paddling like crazy, and this big fin kept following her. She even paddled up onto the nearest rocks instead of all the way to shore. Got cuts all over her legs and hands. Only time I ever saw your mother scared, and she was really scared. She even threw up. Crying and shaking. I had to hold her for a long time. She really thought she was going to die. Of course she hid all that from the Mitchells, turned it into a funny "Me-versus-a-shark" story. I told her...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue in silence a few moments.</context>
      <utterance>I told her it wasn't her time yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish Mom was here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll ask you that same question, Scottie. What do you love about Mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lots of stuff. She's not old and ugly like other moms.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like her stories -- like how she streaked at the wedding and the time she beat a wild pig with a shoe. How about you, Alex?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are we still talking about this?  I like how she's not afraid of anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's watch one of these!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not watching porn.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reina's dad watches pornos. Reina calls them masturbation movies. Her dad has some. She plays them when her parents aren't home and one time invited boys over to see if they grew down there. One did.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reina's awesome.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you there? Have you seen any of those movies?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've got to watch her with the internet. And Reina's dad. Scottie, Reina is a fucked-up ho-bag, and you need to stay away from her. Do you want to end up like me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean the earlier me, when I was mean to you and yelling at mom all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Reina's going to be a meth-head, and she's going to get used by stupid guys. She's a twat. Say it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's a twat.  Twat, twat, twat, twat!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop that!  I don't get it. I don't know what to do... these things she does. What goes on in her head? You weren't like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex looks at him -- authority?</context>
      <utterance>I'm not so sure. I mean, look how you kids talk in front of me. It's like you don't respect authority.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sheepish look on his face, Matt takes a seat on the edge of the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Checking on me or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't, uh... I haven't been sleeping very much lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Understandable.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm worried about my daughters. I'm worried there's something wrong with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to do some messed-up shit when I was a kid. Still do. It's going to get worse after your wife dies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does Alex really think about this stuff that's going on? What does she say?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean? I thought she talks to you all the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't really talk about our like "issues." We just, I don't know, we deal with our shit by talking about other stuff and having a good time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt can't believe what he just asked, but he's desperate for clues from even the unlikeliest source.</context>
      <utterance>What would you do if you were me? How would you handle my daughters? How would you handle... the situation of this guy we're trying to find?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt questions his sanity at having asked Sid any advice.</context>
      <utterance>I told you what I'd do -- I'd lay his nuts on a dresser and hit `em with a spiked bat. With the daughters, I don't know. I'd take them on a trip. Or no, I'd buy `em a bunch of shit. Like with all the money you're going to get when you sell the land -- you're going to make stupid money, right? -- dude, you could buy them anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want some of it? Some money?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I gave you a lot of money right now, tonight, would you leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would I leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Sid, I'm asking you a favor. If I give you money, will you leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You want me to go?</context>
      <utterance>Oh. I get it. Is that what you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Exchange them for sons, I guess.</context>
      <utterance>Look, dude, you're right. If I had daughters, I wouldn't know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I might wind up with something like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not so bad. I'm smart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're about a hundred miles away from Smartville. No offense.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're mistaken, counselor. I'm smart. I have good hygiene. I'm an decent guitarist, a good cook. I cook food all the time. I'm vice-president of the Punahou chess club. And I always have weed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure your parents are proud.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's possible. My mom's sort of busy right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does she do, your mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At first refusing to fall for it, Matt sees this is no prank.</context>
      <utterance>She's a receptionist at a pet clinic. But mostly she's been getting the house together after my dad died. My dad died a few months ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Sid smiles and nods as though to make Matt feel better about the sad news he just shared.</context>
      <utterance>November 24th. Drunk driver. Actually both drivers were drunk. Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Sid. I'll see you tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, boss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay in the zone, please! That means you, Skylar. And you too, Colt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Skylar and Colt?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like you got yourself a handful with those two.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must keep you pretty busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're pretty non-stop, but they're at a really fun age.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eight and ten.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have two girls. Ten and seventeen. That whole non-stop thing. That never changes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys live here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We live on O'ahu.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JULIE SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, so do we.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm just getting my girls out of town for a couple days. Their, uh, their mother is in the hospital, so I thought I'd give them a little break.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong? If you don't mind my asking.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Does Julie recognize any of this, or even recognize him? Doesn't seem like it.</context>
      <utterance>Just a little boating accident. Hit her head a little too hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A sailboat? Or one with a motor?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's actually sort of charming, this Julie Speer.</context>
      <utterance>One with a motor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, good luck with that. I wish her well. Skylar, don't go so far!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys staying in one of the cottages over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, my husband had to come here for work, so we thought we'd all make a little vacation of it. He knows the owner, so --</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hugh King.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's my cousin.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That hangs there a moment. Matt suppresses the sudden desire to spill the beans.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Then you probably know my husband. Brian Speer?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, can't say as I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I just assumed, since he's been --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt looks over to see Scottie very agitated about something.</context>
      <utterance>Dad! Dad, come here! Something bit me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. Nice talking to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt trots off.</context>
      <utterance>You too. Take care.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>yucking it up at the BAR with other REGULARS.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Order me something.</context>
      <utterance>There's Cousin Hugh. Get us a table.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks over his shoulder to see whom Matt might have come in with.</context>
      <utterance>Heeey! Mattie-boy! What are you doing here? I didn't expect to see you until the meeting.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Scottie and Alex.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big girls now! So what are you doing here, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just getting the girls out of the hospital for a couple days, you know, change of scenery.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, boy, what you've been going through. That's a tough deal.  But Elizabeth, hey, she's, she's a tough gal, I'll tell you that. A fighter. She'll make it. Get you a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, what're you having?</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barney, an old-fashioned for my cousin here. Nice to see you, Matt. How you been otherwise?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much otherwise. Between our business and the hospital, you know, I've just trying to keep my head above water. So listen, I see you have some people staying in the cottage.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hey, Mattie, if I'd known you were coming, I coulda --</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no, I'm just wondering about the guy you're renting to. I think his name is Brian Speer.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, real determined son-of-a- bitch. He's Lou's sister's... No, wait. Lou has a sister, and the sister's husband... Lou's brother-in- law is cousins with that guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh? Who's Lou?</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, wait. You mean the cottages on the bay or the cottage back by the trail?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bay. The guy with the wife and two boys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's right. Determined son-of- a-bitch. Anyway, the point is the guy we're doing business with is that guy's brother-in-law. Works for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian Speer.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, the guy we're doing business with?</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you think? Don Holitzer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holitzer.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm saying. That's Don's brother-in-law in the cottage. You don't know him? I would have thought you'd know him. He's a realtor over by you. So if we sell to Don -- and that's what we're going to do, right? That's what you want too. Nice guy, Don. He'll do right by us. Then when Don develops and re-sells and leases and all that --</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah --</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes a moment for this stone to drop to the bottom of Matt's well.</context>
      <utterance>He's letting this brother-in-law in the cottage handle the transactions. A lot of them, anyway. Big score for that guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he like?</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian Speer -- what else do you know about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much. He's lucky. The bugga's lucky. His sister is married to the guy. Son-of-a-bitch is going to make a shitload of money on commissions.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cousin Hugh's eyes emerge momentarily from their drunken fog to give Matt a firm, steely warning.</context>
      <utterance>Not if we don't go with that bid.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You've said as much.</context>
      <utterance>We all want Don. You do too, Matt.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well. Good to see you, Hugh.</context>
      <utterance>No, I know. You're right. Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you at the meeting.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place rocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Totally.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ordered you mahi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, guess what. Turns out Brian Speer is connected to Don Holitzer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Don Holitzer?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The guy we're going to sell to. And that woman today at the beach. That was his wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose wife?  The hottie with the hat? You sure?  So he's married. Nice. Why didn't you say anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's him I want to talk to, not her. I know where their cottage is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let's go knock on his door.</context>
      <utterance>You do? So let's do it right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alexandra quietly exults.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm saying.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do that. Don't be excited. This isn't fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's what we came here to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you to talk to his wife while I talk to him. And figure out some way to distract Scottie and their kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it. Sid, come here!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Dad and I are going to go talk to some friends while Sid takes you back to the hotel, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to come too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't. Who wants to sit around talking in some house? Let's ditch these losers and go watch some serious</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they walk away --</context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give `em hell, boss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. What should I say?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll think of something. You're a lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry for sucking you into this. I should be doing this alone. It's selfish of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as they are round the house toward the lanai, Julie Speer backs out of the screen door with a plate of hamburger patties. Alex nudges Matt.</context>
      <utterance>I'm the one who sucked you in. I'm the one who knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be a pussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The screen door slams. Julie looks over.</context>
      <utterance>Hi there!</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the guy from the beach today.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, hey, I'm such an idiot. I just figured out I do know your husband. My daughter and I were on our way back to the hotel from dinner, and we thought we'd drop by and say howdy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Howdy?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Come on up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Matt King. This is Alexandra.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Julie Speer. Yeah, I thought that was you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been in the paper so much lately. I figured you had to know Brian. He's been pretty involved.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, no, I know, yeah, super-involved. Maybe I've met him in passing. I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, I guess you guys are deciding really soon. A couple of days, right -- you and your family meet? I'm sorry. That's probably a conflict of interest or something.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's okay. You're right -- it'll all be over in a couple of days.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys want a burger?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just ate, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Alex and Matt agree, a figure appears at the screen door. BRIAN SPEER emerges, a bag of BUNS in one hand.</context>
      <utterance>A drink then.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Brian.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian's big GRIN WILTS.</context>
      <utterance>Brian, we may have met before. Matt King. My wife is Elizabeth King. I think you may have met her too. Our daughter Alexandra.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just going to get drinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt nudges Alexandra, who suddenly remembers her duty.</context>
      <utterance>Good, good. Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you need help?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex is glad to keep her ringside seat for the moment. All buckle their mental seatbelts.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, I got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth is dying. Oh, wait. Fuck you. And she's dying. We unhooked her from the machines this morning. She'll be dead in a few days.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they've plotted, Alex and Matt study Brian's paralyzed face. They exchange a glance, then look back at him.</context>
      <utterance>We're not here to hurt you. We just thought she'd want you to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is him? Why would she go for him?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beats me. Well, he's very articulate.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't... I'm sorry. I never thought it would come to this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sorry my mom's going to die? You're sorry you fucked her? You're sorry you fucked over my dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry for all of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, pal, like she said, I'm not here to wreck your life. I just came to give you a chance to go to the hospital. I don't know how long you're planning on being here, but I'm sure you can think of an excuse to leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be good at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can be alone with her to say goodbye or whatever you want. Do you hear what I'm saying?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie returns with wine for Matt and a soda for Alex.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, look, I can't have you here. You understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we go.  Everyone's so serious. Please don't tell me you're talking about business.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're talking about love.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's nice. Brian, call the boys in for dinner.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all stand there a moment. Matt's unsure how to play this out. He shoots a quick panicked look at Alex, who scrambles to keep the ball rolling.</context>
      <utterance>They're fine. Let them play a while longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awesome cottage you're renting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, say, prime Hanalei location. I used to come here as a kid before it was a vacation rental. Alex, your great-uncle Warren and Aunt Lillian built it back in the 20s. Haven't been inside in years.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. We'll give you a tour.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or, Brian, maybe you could give my dad a little walk down memory lane, and Julie and I can chat out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just a quick look.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'd like that, if you don't mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt walks up to the door, making a point to let Brian open it for him.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. But it's not like I live here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For a moment Brian looks tricked, as if Matt really did just want a tour of the house.</context>
      <utterance>How did you meet? I'm curious.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither can I. How did you meet?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you said you came here just to tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I changed my mind. And I can't very well ask her the details. How'd you meet?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At a party.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What party?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Super Bowl party.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the Mitchells'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that help? Does that make it better?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian drops his head, rubs his temples.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm doing you a favor here. I could go out there right now and fuck you up, so get a better attitude. Then what? How'd you get the nerve to ask her out?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to know what makes a person cross that line. Was it about the deal? Is that when you decided she was for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. It's not what you think. It just happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing just happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything just happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was she going to leave me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She would have. But I, I, uh... I didn't want that. That wouldn't have happened. I love Julie.  Please don't tell her. Please. I don't know what I've done. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian nods slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Did she say she loved you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Brian looks down.</context>
      <utterance>Do you love her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't love her. You don't love her. You just used her to get to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I told you. I wasn't trying to get to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was an affair, an attraction. Sex. And she got sort of... carried away with the whole thing, and I guess I went with it. I mean, I didn't exactly say no to things. I should have. I love my family.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I guess it's all working out. Her lips are sealed, and you don't have to go through the trouble of dumping her.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's a wonderful woman.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, hey, that's really unfair. I had - - have -- a lot of respect for her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Have you ever been inside my bedroom?</context>
      <utterance>Too bad her husband found out. You can't win `em all. One more question.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That really is all I came to say.</context>
      <utterance>You could have had the decency to lie about that one. Well, she's in Queen's Hospital if you want to say goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN SPEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt's face slackens into overwhelming sadness.</context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't you be with her?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, great, all remodeled, new appliances. Nice. Alex, we should be getting back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hey, thanks for stopping by. Really nice to meet you both. Maybe we'll see you at the beach tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So when do you think he'll show up?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid leans forward from the middle seat.</context>
      <utterance>I have no idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was he sorry? I hope he was sorry, man. You could have told his wife, and you didn't. I hope he knows how lucky he is. I would have told her everything. She deserves to know. Or else she's going to be a dumb bitch the rest of her life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No need to get creepy. Anyway, doesn't matter. That's all behind us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, the one we have to worry about telling things to now is Scottie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've asked Dr. Johnston to help us break the news tomorrow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DR. JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, everyone. Matt.  This is Dr. Herman, whom I told you about. She works with us in counseling.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The adults exchange glances. Dr. Herman approaches Scottie.</context>
      <utterance>How come Mom isn't on any more machines? Is she getting better?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Herman hands her a little squeaky RUBBER OCTOPUS she pulls from her pocket.</context>
      <utterance>You must be Scottie.  Scottie, I have a present for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DR. HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. It's an octopus. Such a funny creature with its eight legs. But did you know octopi are actually extremely intelligent, like dogs and cats? They have unique personalities, and just like us they have a lot of defense mechanisms. I'm sure you know about the ink sac. She uses ink to confuse her predators. She can camouflage herself. She can emit poison, and some can mimic more dangerous creatures, like the eel. I keep her to remind me of our defense mechanisms -- our ink, our camouflage, our poison, all the things we use to keep away hurt. The reason Dr. Johnston invited me here today is to meet you, Scottie. I've heard a lot about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Herman shoots a look at Matt before continuing.</context>
      <utterance>I've heard that you're a wonderful and unique and spirited girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>All watch Scottie react to this news.</context>
      <utterance>And I've heard your mom's not doing too well and that she's going to die very soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, is that true?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Scottie. It's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. HERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to have to be a very brave girl right now, and you're surrounded by people who love you. I came to meet you and tell you that if you ever want to talk about what you're feeling, I would like to talk to you too. I can help you face what's going on without all the silly defense mechanisms that work for an octopus but not for us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>DR. JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Herman looks at everyone with great sincerity before leaving. Scottie is left holding the octopus. She drops it, and it squeaks a little.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Thank you, Dr. Herman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, well, they say she's very good one- on-one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Mom's going to die for sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. We worked really hard with her, but three other doctors and I agree she's in what we call an irreversible coma. Do you know what that means?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means she doesn't have a brain anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly, but... yes, that's the general idea. So we're doing exactly what she wanted us to do if that ever happened. That's why she's not attached to the machines anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's for the best, Scottie. Look at her. She's not happy like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The purpose of medicine is to heal, and we can't do that now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Johnston looks to Matt for this one.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. What will we do with her body?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First Mom's going to give some of her organs to other sick people, so she can help save their lives. That's a really neat thing she's doing. Then we're going to... we're going to scatter her ashes in the ocean. You know how Mom always loved the ocean.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scottie looks at her mother, picturing her as ashes.</context>
      <utterance>Her ashes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When will she die?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any day now, I'm afraid. But you still have some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. Let me know if you have any more questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor leaves, and the room is quiet. Scottie is in a sort of trance.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Sam.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scottie goes to her sister, who takes her in her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Come here, Scottie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do eyeballs burn?</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Scottie. Don't think about stuff like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cheerful Alice doesn't really get what's going on. An emotional Barry hugs Matt and the girls.</context>
      <utterance>Here we are.  Hi, Bingo. Alex.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Matt and Alex maneuver seats for the Thorsons to sit near the bed. Barry gets his mother situated, then takes a seat himself. Remaining on his feet, old Scott surveys his daughter from a distance.</context>
      <utterance>There you are again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what did you decide?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's not much left to decide. We're just sort of playing it by ear and making sure she's comfortable.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even Sid and his daughters perk up at this question. Matt is taken aback.</context>
      <utterance>I mean what did you decide about the buyer? Who's your buyer?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much are you getting?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad, I'm sure you'll be able to read about it in the paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need to read about it. I can hear about it right now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's not the time for that.</context>
      <utterance>Scott, let's not talk about that here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>sheepish look imply he buys into his father's propaganda.</context>
      <utterance>All the same to you, I guess. A million here, a million there. Just ironic, that's all -- Elizabeth coming into this misfortune just as you're coming into a fortune. She gave you everything, Matt. A good, happy home, two beautiful daughters. Matt looks to Barry for help, but Barry's silence and</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scott, what's your point?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wanted her own boat. She should have had her own boat, one she would have been familiar with.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wasn't even driving! Her boat, someone else's boat -- it wouldn't have made any difference. You're not going to blame me for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Why fight it?</context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure, quibble about the details. She was a faithful, devoted wife. She deserved more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right. She deserved more.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott turns to Sid like he's about to pop him again.</context>
      <utterance>For Christ's sake, take it easy on the man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His point made, Scott looks at Matt and the girls and shuffles to Elizabeth's bedside, puts his hands on Alice's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>My father has been doing a really amazing job under the circumstances.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we ready to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARRY THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Mom. Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt, Sid and the girls quietly go into --</context>
      <utterance>Girls, Sid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man, that guy's a prick. Was he always like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scottie has stayed behind to peek through a crack in the door. Noticing, the others join her.</context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he praying?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT THORSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say goodbye to Elizabeth, Alice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man puts his hand over his mouth and squeezes his eyes shut. Then he opens his eyes and places a hand on her forehead, smooths her hair back.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Goodbye, Elizabeth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth's not doing well.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll be okay. She's a fighter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, no surprise. Other than the holdouts who don't want to sell at all, it's Don Holitzer. Chicago group a distant second. Feels good. We're doing the right thing, Mattie. At least there ain't going to be any Wal-Mart. Now it's your call, and we're all behind you, most of us anyway.  Go ahead, Captain. Make it official.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's strange, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's strange?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hugh and Six exchange a concerned look. For a moment we go VERY CLOSE on Matt's eyes. Then --</context>
      <utterance>We didn't do anything to own that land. It was entrusted to us. And now we're just...</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do it. I won't do it. I'm not going to sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing, Matt? I mean, we know you have a lot on your plate right now, but you're not going to fuck this up for us. It's over. If we don't sell now, it'll be a mess when the trust dissolves. Just sign, go to your wife, done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want it to go to Holitzer. I don't want it to go to anyone. I want to keep it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN SIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For Christ's sake. We can't move without your approval. And we don't want to. Hugh tries forcing Matt's hand. Matt resists.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your head's not right, Mattie. Your head's not right. You want a couple days to think it over? Take a couple days.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need a couple days. I have the authority, and this is what I want. I haven't wanted something in a long time. We have other businesses we're converting to corporations. We can figure it out.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN SIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's utterly unproductive land. It doesn't generate enough income to pay the goddamn taxes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the trustee. You know better than anyone we only have seven years left.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cousin Hugh draws a long breath, looks up at the sky, then back at Matt.</context>
      <utterance>Then I have seven years to figure out how to keep it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're family.</context>
      <utterance>We'll come after you. Just because you're a lawyer doesn't mean the rest of us would be afraid to come after you. But nobody wants to do that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cousin Hugh releases a long breath more like a belch, quickly picks his nose, exchanges a look with Cousin Six. Then he brings his fingers to his mouth to WHISTLE.</context>
      <utterance>People will be relieved, Hugh, the whole state. I sign that document, it's over. End of the line. Something that was ours to protect will be gone. Even though we're haole as shit and go to private schools and clubs and can't even speak pidgin, let alone Hawaiian, we still carry Hawaiian blood, and we're still tied to this land. And our children are tied to this land. It's a miracle that for whatever bullshit reason 150 years ago, we own this much of... paradise, but we do. And for whatever bullshit reason now, I'm the trustee. And I'm not signing. And if you sue me, it'll only make us closer.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUSIN HUGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rising to his feet, Matt scans the faces of his relatives.</context>
      <utterance>All right, everybody, listen up. Cousin Mattie has an announcement. Get ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises to help her find a spot to put the flowers. She nods to the girls.</context>
      <utterance>Julie. What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know we just met, but I was thinking about you guys these past few days, and I knew your mom was here. I don't know. I just felt I should stop by.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sid. This is Mrs. Speer.</context>
      <utterance>You remember Alex. This is Scottie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Julie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you friends with my mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they now do often, Matt and Alex exchange a look.</context>
      <utterance>No, we never met. But I know a lot about her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flowers are lovely.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we appreciate your coming by.</utterance>
   <speaker>SID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls follow Sid's prompt, leaving Matt alone with Julie, standing, a dying woman between them.</context>
      <utterance>Scottie, Alex. Let's go to the cafeteria.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, uh, I'm not sure how much you know about my wife's condition, but she's going to die very soon. Any minute, really. That's sort of why we're all here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wow.</context>
      <utterance>I know. That's why I came. Because I know. I came because my husband wouldn't. And that just didn't seem right. I thought someone from my family should come.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I came to your house like that. Just barged in on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Of course you are. I'm angry too.</context>
      <utterance>It's all right. I assume you're angry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So he told you, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After you left that night, he was acting really weird. Then I started smelling it all over him. I'd already smelled it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I finally got it out of him. We've been going crazy ever since. Not easy with the kids around. It's all something I never could have imagined. And then your family's decision about the land. I think you're doing the right thing, but Brian is -- well, it's all so complicated and confusing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian told me everything. Well, how can I ever know it's everything? When did you find out? Have you known for a while?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a few days ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt is unsure but what else can he do? Julie approaches the bed.</context>
      <utterance>I'm angry, but I'm just so sorry. I can't imagine what you're going through. Do you mind if I say something to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, I'm Julie. Brian's wife. I just want to say I forgive you. I forgive you for trying to take Brian. I forgive you for almost destroying my family. I have to forgive you. Even though I want to hate you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt walks to the door and opens it. Alex and Sid -- who've clearly had their ears against the door -- scamper away, unnoticed by Matt and Julie.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. All right. That's enough, Julie. I think... I think that's enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He didn't really love her.</context>
      <utterance>He didn't love her. Just so you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JULIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Julie heads to the door. At the door, she looks at Matt. Matt looks at her. She leaves. Matt is left alone with his wife, and he realizes suddenly that this is his moment. He walks to the bed, takes her hand, rubs his palm over her hair. He says something to her as though silently praying, then realizes he should say it aloud. He presses his lips to hers and puts his hand on her stomach.</context>
      <utterance>That's why I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goodbye. Goodbye.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Elizabeth. Goodbye, my love, my friend, my pain, my joy. Goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PADDLES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>in the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>A BOX ENCIRCLED BY LEIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>sits tied to the seat of a small outrigger CANOE.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT AND THE GIRLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>navigate the canoe through the surf.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far do we have to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that far. Just past the break.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Steer straighter, Dad. And a little faster, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Alex passes the box and scooper to Scottie.</context>
      <utterance>Scottie, you're next. Go ahead, it's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scottie looks at Alex and scoops out a pile, holds them at eye-level, and pauses.</context>
      <utterance>Just say goodbye.</utterance>
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Scottie. It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sad Scottie pours her scoop into the water. All look down as the ashes descend.</context>
      <utterance>Bye, Mom.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MATT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One scoop strawberry, one scoop mocha chip.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTTIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Matt gets under the quilt with her. Moments later Alexandra wanders in, notices what they're watching, sits next to Matt, pulls the quilt over her legs.</context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I have some?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
