<movie id="148" title="Crow Salvation The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are there so many?</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THROUGH THE WINDSHIELD--a Protestor's poster visible. "Remember the Victim." With a picture of LAUREN RANDALL, the deceased, who bears a striking resemblance to surviving sister Erin. And another sign--"Happy Birthday Alex."</context>
      <utterance>Just hold on to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a deep breath, they get out of the car and... WITH THE RANDALLS as they make their way through the throng toward a special entrance marked "WITNESSES," nearly within reach when WHOMP. Erin shields her face as a BRIGHT LIGHT comes on. OVER TV REPORTER BARBARA GONZALEZ Action Newsteam addressing the Nathans. Speaking into a mic.</context>
      <utterance>It's because they're doing this on his birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONZALEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nathan pushes past Gonzalez, taking Erin's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Randall. Sir. Do you think this execution will bring you a sense of closure?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONZALEZ</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin. Your sister...</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Reporter TURNS to the camera, not missing a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Leave us alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>GONZALEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A difficult time for everyone involved.  Interesting fact. It will take about twenty-one cents of electricity to execute Alex Corvis tonight on this, his twenty-first birthday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't order that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despite himself, Alex looks up. Mercer gestures at... THE CAKE in the middle of the candles, an arm made of frosting with a large ZIGZAG marking on the forearm, also frosting. FAVORING ALEX looking from the cake up to Mercer, who nods at the candles.</context>
      <utterance>We found the man with the scar.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. Make a wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex focusses on the chess board. Tries to anyway.</context>
      <utterance>Get it out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I've come to a lot of these over the years, but this one has many unique aspects. Youth of the condemned. That's unusual. Fifty three stab wounds. Kind of a record.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONZALEZ'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Corvis still maintaining his innocence.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, they all say that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex gets up, crosses to a small ledge on the other side of the cell that holds a few books and pictures. He finds... A PICTURE OF LAUREN AND ALEX In a grove of tall trees. A self-portrait by autotimer. Arms around each other. Her head on his shoulder. Happy. RESUME Alex staring at the photo, taped to the wall.</context>
      <utterance>You ok?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's been holding me together is the hope that maybe you do go someplace. And I'll be seeing her again soon. Only what will I say? That I was too stupid to find the guy who killed her? That he's down here laughing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her... we'll get him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll find the guy with the scar.</context>
      <utterance>Someday he'll surface and I'll get him for both of you. I promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We couldn't find him. And, obviously, the jury didn't buy it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONZALEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some people here seem to.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look around. He's right.</context>
      <utterance>People here are protesting the execution of a kid just turning twenty-one. A kid who had a tough life. No parents, no dough. Always had to fight for everything. It's a tragedy, it really is. But I don't see a single sign telling me Alex Corvis is innocent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look up as Mercer appears outside the barred door to the cell, starts to unlock it.</context>
      <utterance>I was facing the hot seat, I'd want my attorney banging down the door of the Supreme Court, not playing board games. But maybe that's just me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your move.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It really is. Other prison personnel arrive outside the cell in various uniforms: A MINISTER with clerical collar, the WARDEN, two GUARDS. Waiting. Walsh crosses, very emotional how. Gives Alex a huge hug.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two friends exchange a long last look.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to watch. I don't want to give them the pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ok. C'mon now...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A thick silence. Alex looks unprepared, uneasy as he scans a sea of hostile faces, settling on Erin and her dad.</context>
      <utterance>Alexander Frederick Corvis. Do you have any last words?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin shakes her head, disgusted. Looks away. ALEX'S POV - THE LAST SECONDS OF HIS LIFE SLOWING in his inner perception, movement ramping down as Alex scans the disbelieving faces. The Phone. Silent. No reprise. The Observation Room witness door opens. A Guard in the back row deferentially offers his seat to the NEW ARRIVAL, a man in dark clothes, his face obscured by REFLECTIONS in the plexiglass. As he UNBUTTONS his shirt cuff... The warden steps to the side of the room, nods to the executioner who lifts a COVER off a large switch. The New Arrival pulls his shirtsleeve back over his forearm, exposing a scar for Alex, THE SCAR, an odd zigzag pattern of raised welts, a pattern deliberately formed of skin. The Executioner throws the switch. ON ALEX SHAKING violently as he fights to stay alive, time extremely subjective now as he chokes out...</context>
      <utterance>I loved Lauren. I still do. I'm innocent.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The word bubbles up as if from underwater, audible only to Alex. Alex wrenches his head, a superhuman act of will trying to ID the Scar Man through the reflections.</context>
      <utterance>Murderer!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUARD ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this. Goddamn helmet melted down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They WIPE past, Alex's charred remains visible a moment, parts of the helmet fused on his face and head, his body convulsed in a pugilistic attitude.</context>
      <utterance>That, my friend, is a deterrent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALEX'S INTERNAL POV A pop of Mercer bringing the birthday cake. A wash of flame, twenty one candles. A blip of Walsh. Of a White King. RESUME Alex perplexed, looking at the cake still littering the floor of his ex-cell, candles melted down. Mercer works his way through the double-barred doors onto the row.</context>
      <utterance>Get me some backup. We got one loose on the row.  Now who the fuck are you? Alex looks up, sees Mercer and FLASH...</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The INMATE occupying the cell next to Alex's peers out through the bars, vanishes again as Mercer WHOPS the bars once with his nightstick.</context>
      <utterance>And what have you done to your face there beauty queen?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my birthday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHOOSH. Mercer swings his NIGHTSTICK at Alex's head. Alex catches it, instinctively in one hand. Mercer reaches for... A RED PANIC BUTTON hanging off his guard belt. Mercer slams it. FAVORING ALEX lets go of the stick, looks at his own hand, surprised. WHAM! Mercer broadsides Alex's head with the stick. Alex goes down shocked, not from pain, from the fact that someone would attack him. WHAM WHAM WHAM. Mercer brutalizes Alex, collapsed at his feet as... TWO GUARDS enter the far end of the Row, race toward Alex's cell, one holding a TASER. Its LASER SIGHT finds Alex, crumpled in front of Mercer.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well... here's a present for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Looks like it's over. The guards relax. ALEX suddenly looks up at Mercer. Zero damage from the blows.</context>
      <utterance>It's ok. Man. Had me going there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. Make a wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex wheels around as Guard One squeezes the trigger. CROWVISION The Taser Darts speed toward Camera. RESUME Alex shunts himself to the side and the TASER DARTS impale themselves in Mercer's thighs. He drops fibrillating. A CHEER goes up from the men in their cells, who become progressively rowdier as the guards BOLT and Alex follows, strength in his stride, nightstick in hand. Pieces of FLAMING TOILETPAPER flung now from the cells of Deathrow. AT THE FAR ENTRANCE the two Guards scramble to get the door closed behind them before Alex catches up. They'd make it except Alex hurls... THE NIGHTSTICK flying end over end like a throwing knife, catching the trailing guard in the back of the head, dropping him in the door, propping it open. ALEX enters the cage entrance to Deathrow, sharing the space with the Guard still standing.</context>
      <utterance>Taser!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keys?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RADIO GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another LIGHT goes on. They're starting to make a line. Buzzers going off now. A general ALARM sounded.</context>
      <utterance>Unauthorized movement in B five, B six, C three, four, five...</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO GUARD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Escape in progress. Heading for the roof.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BULLHORN VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if in defiance, the Crow hops toward the fence, old chain link topped with razorwire along the perimeter of the roof. BULLHORN VOICE CONTINUES as Alex follows... ALEX'S POV through the fence, down fifty feet to the pavement.</context>
      <utterance>Do not proceed. Back slowly away from the fence.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex turns, sees... A HALF DOZEN GUARDS emerge from the stairwell to the top of the roof, level weapons at Alex.</context>
      <utterance>Damn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RADIO GUARD VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mercer moves the radio away from his head.</context>
      <utterance>Physical head count shows all inmates present.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then who was the fucking Houdini?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Look. I like what we've got going here. But I can think of lots better to do with it than fighting crime. Know what I mean? The Crow makes its way to a file cabinet, the top drawer marked "Cl-Cr." Alex lingers a moment at the desk, eye on the spike. WHOP. Alex drives his hand onto the SPIKE. Looks up, delighted. CAW. The Crow gives Alex an admonishing look. Alex pulls the spike from his hand. Instant healing.</context>
      <utterance>Police? Evidence?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Alex opens the top drawer. Looking for... he's not sure what. Glibly goes through folders.</context>
      <utterance>Ok, ok... what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He stops. Pulls out the first FILE out in a thick section marked "CORVIS, ALEXANDER F." Having caught a glimpse of... IN THE FILE - ALEX'S MUG SHOT And rap sheet. X-CLOSE. We see "Murder 1st degree," "Penalty Phase: Find for Execution."</context>
      <utterance>Nothing under "Crow."</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>But even this has little interest for him as the finds the words "Lauren Randall" on the page.</context>
      <utterance>Execution?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ALEX rips the drawer out of the file cabinet, dumps it CRASHING on the ground. He drops to the floor with a growing sense of dread, feeling with both hands, finding... A SPLAY OF PHTOGRAPHS encased in plastic -- the prosecutions' background presentation on Alex and Lauren. The first photo shows LAUREN Posing jauntily, her arm around a Snowman. She and the Snowman wear matching Boston Red Sox caps. ALEX'S INTERNAL POV On Alex, anticipating...WHAP! A snowball nails him square in the face. WIDE to reveal LAUREN running for cover as Young Alex scoops up snow for ammo. He lobs a snowball at Lauren, just as she slips to the ground. she doesn't get up right away. Alex is just a shade concernec as he runs over to her. He reaches the spot to find LAUREN in the snow, waving her arms and legs to make a snow angel. She looks up at him and beckons him to lie on top of her.</context>
      <utterance>Lauren...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you, an Angel?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RESUME Alex's pained smile at the memory, until he finds: THE MURDER WEAPON A rough looking hunting knife bagged and tagged as "AC-005: Murder Weapon." ALEX frantic now, spreading out the file contents, finding... CRIME SCENE PHOTOS In a Grove of tall trees, Lauren Randall's stabbed and mutilated body, her neck slashed, head lolling sideways, melds with...</context>
      <utterance>I'm your Angel. Come here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His knife. Corvis.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lie!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex fishing through the detritus around him, finding... "THE LIST" A list of witnesses by category with contact numbers, addresses. Alex's finger finds Eyewitness Thomas Leonard.</context>
      <utterance>You lie, you lie, you lie...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>THE DOOR TO THE EVIDENCE ROOM opens. A YOUNG COP enters, walks slowly past rows of file cabinets, looking down empty aisles until finding the file drawerful Alex dumped. But Alex is gone. The Young Cop looks up as the Crow departs through the window and two other cops arrive. One of them Dutton.</context>
      <utterance>Thomas Leonard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dutton walks to the mess on the floor, curious. He squats. Picks up a tag marked "Murder Weapon AC-005" staples ripped out, nothing attached to it. Takes in the crime scene photos of Lauren. Off the PIX...</context>
      <utterance>What the hell was that?  Shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RESUME Camera continues to circle Alex at the grave.</context>
      <utterance>Your Shaolin style is no match for my kung fu. As Alex wipes by...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALEX'S INTERNAL POV More goof kung fu, the circle closing. Lauren laughing more, searching for words.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not dead. And I'm not alive. And I'm remembering. And it hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RESUME Resolve strengthening.</context>
      <utterance>Your... flying crane style is no match for my... drunken tiger kick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALEX'S INTERNAL POV Lauren's starting to crack up, trying to think of what comes next.</context>
      <utterance>I can't be alive. Not without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other a long moment. As they kiss...</context>
      <utterance>Your... mad monkey... love ... is no match for...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALEX'S INTERNAL POV Lauren in his arms as the kiss ends, and she answers a question we never heard.</context>
      <utterance>I want to be with you forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RESUME OVER THE CROW. Camera stops circling. Alex looks up at the headstone, silent tears in his eyes as...</context>
      <utterance>Only forever?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to us?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nathan looks over. Sees she's holding the Locket.</context>
      <utterance>Dad...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She'd want it.</context>
      <utterance>I want to take this to Lauren.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey. I just can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay in the car. I'll only take a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin. I know you think she's been talking to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off her dad...</context>
      <utterance>It's not that. Really. It's just... now that he's gone, I think it's time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds his hands up, compliant. She doesn't bolt. But she's ultra-cautious. Like with a snarling dog.</context>
      <utterance>Don't come near me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was a friend of your sister's.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know her friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lifts the Locket around her neck. Visible to anyone.</context>
      <utterance>That locket you're holding. You have one just like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, no kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father gave them to both of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And he's right over there by the way.  What did you do to your face?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone else did it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a friend of the guy who killed her, aren't you? You almost sound like him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't kill her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'll prove it to you.</context>
      <utterance>I know everything about your sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>OS, the car door opens. Then SLAMS shut. Nathan approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Stay away from me! Dad! Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>22.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She whips around, points at... Alex is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were you yelling about?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy said he was a friend of Lauren's. He had like paint all over his face.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you ok?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head, confused, then, looking around spots... THE HEADSTONE. The track from the RED TEAR indelible even in the downpour. Off Erin, as she touches the angel's stained cheek. And her dad, soggy in the rain...</context>
      <utterance>What's that supposed to mean? He was right here. He was!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sssshhh. She's resting.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the fuck did you come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy starts toward Alex, who pulls the KNIFE from the Evidence Room.</context>
      <utterance>Big bang, primordial ooze, divine hand of a benevolent creator? All possibilities. Although recent events have given me doubts about the benevolent creator.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lied at my trial.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know you, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHAM. Alex pins what looks like Tommy's arm. It's just his jacket, but it immobilizes Tommy.</context>
      <utterance>Capital case nine nine dash C one one five. Alex Corvis.  Exhibit A.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. I said what I saw. Two kids arguing. A guy and a girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you saw me with this. I never held it until today.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex HEAVES Tommy crashing into the window, smashing the glass and cheap aluminum frame. Tommy hanging halfway in, halfway out. Four floors above the alley. Alex rips Tommy's shirt where the knife already cut it. JACKS the sleeve down. No scar there.</context>
      <utterance>What's your damage, man? Corvis hacked up that girl like a motherfucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One chance to tell the truth, Tommy. Who is the man with the scar? He planted this in my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no scar. Corvis made it up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong. Answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY'S WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TOMMY'S WIFE enters from the bedroom, SCREAMING. Heavy eye makeup, looking like she just woke up. OS, a TODDLER CRIES as she throws herself on Alex and they spill back inside.</context>
      <utterance>Tommy!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY'S WIFE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him go! Let him go!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she doesn't leave. She pleads in wrenching SOBS that seem to affect Alex. The Crow lands in the window.</context>
      <utterance>Honey. Take the baby. Get out of here now!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY'S WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her MASCARA runs down her cheeks, a facsimile of Alex's mask. They share a long look, connected by pain. The Crow cawing a warning, hopping in the window as...</context>
      <utterance>He's all I got. Tommy and the baby. Don't take him. The baby needs a father.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy nods at his wife, who heads off to the bedroom. The Crow gives Alex an admonishing CAW, then takes flight.</context>
      <utterance>Your baby is crying. Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did they give you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They showed me pictures, what he did to her. Evidence. Said all I had to do was stand up there and not my head "yes."</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did they give you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A job. Construction. Twelve an hour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Tommy takes a look at "The List" and flips it over... "THE LIST" Tommy points to the Police Witness list. Dutton, Erlich, Larkin, Toomey.</context>
      <utterance>Write down their names. All of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALEX drops his head. All clear now. He laughes gently at the sound of SIRENS approaching, still blocks away.</context>
      <utterance>You already got 'em. Right here. These cops said the needed an eyewitness, or Corvis would walk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She jostles her friend JANNIE, passed out in the front passenger seat, trying to rouse her. No luck. DUTTON motions and Tracy buzzes down the window.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy tries hard to keep her smile going as she looks through her purse. Not finding anything.</context>
      <utterance>Let's hope not. License and registration please.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with your friend there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's... sick.  Actually she never had Mai Tais before.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you, you've had them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy paws through her purse some more. Vamping.</context>
      <utterance>Not tonight. Honest.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you had a license, I bet I'd have seen it by now. How old are you? Fifteen?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dutton leaves that dangling. Circles around to the passenger side...</context>
      <utterance>Look, I'll tell you the truth. Jannie drove us and was supposed to drive us back, she has a license, but I mean... look at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get up, get up...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CROWVISION High overhead. Tracy steps out of the car. Dutton shuts the passenger door, points. Tracy moves behind the Seville. RESUME Dutton closes in. She's getting very nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to walk a straight line?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you... to bend over.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, can I just call a cab?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tracy bends over the car trunk. Dutton eases her feet apart with the tip of his boot then pulls out his NIGHTSTICK, uses it to lift her tiny skirt slowly up over her butt. As he does, she stands back up, shakes her head "no."</context>
      <utterance>What did I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tracy's frantic, about to call out as Dutton moves to the passenger door, opens it and... OVER DUTTON - ALEX sits in the passenger seat now. Jannie shunted inward.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'll ask your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dutton pulls his 9MM BARETTA on Alex.</context>
      <utterance>I want you... to bend over. Officer Dutton.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With insolent slowness, Alex finishes writing... "THE LIST" a red line drawn through Dutton's name. ALEX gets out of the car. Dutton SLAMS the door and Janie stirs, coming to. At least a bit.</context>
      <utterance>Where'd you come from? Out of the car. Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hands on the car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex advances on Dutton.</context>
      <utterance>Question. These hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE. Dutton's finger squeezes the trigger. BAM! The shot blows Alex back at the Seville passenger window. Slumped face against the car.</context>
      <utterance>You're dead, ditch weed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jannie's head pops up inside the car. She SCREAMS at... JANNIE'S POV Alex right in her face, nice and dead. Dutton lowers his gun BG. Tracy in a panic. Suddenly, Alex opens his eyes, smiles. Face distorted against the glass. She screams again.</context>
      <utterance>Omigod, omigod...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ALEX wheels around, wrenches Dutton's wrist, vise gripped. Dutton's gun falls to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>You're up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tracy rushes to the driver side.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies. Drive carefully.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Tracy SCREECHES off leaving Dutton in shock.</context>
      <utterance>You might want to call 911. Report an officer down.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a fucking hollow point!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex draws the KNIFE--the murder weapon--from his costume.</context>
      <utterance>I guess it's true. Guns don't kill people...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think maybe knives do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep that thing away from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not just some "thing." It's A C zero zero five.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLASH. The knife moves and RIP! Alex yanks the sleeve off Dutton's uniform, revealing a SCARLESS FOREARM.</context>
      <utterance>You're the skel broke into the evidence room.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck! What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A scar. On the arm. Of the man who planted this in Alex Corvis's car.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex glitches, hearing this a second time, then RAMS Dutton into a wall with a great CLATTER of trash cans. Alex all over him, holding Dutton's head firmly in his two hands, like he could crush it in an instant.</context>
      <utterance>There's no scar, you freak. The Corvis kid made it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex's thumbs inch toward Dutton's eyes, grazing Dutton's eyelids now and a wild thing happens. FLASH! ALEX'S INTERNAL POV Dutton's Nightstick lifts Lauren's skirt. Then flashs of a bloodsoaked struggle, Lauren's death. And the surprise BAM! of a shot fired. RESUME Alex thrown by this. Relaxes his grip on Dutton.</context>
      <utterance>He was innocent. You framed him. You. And Erlich. And Larkin. And Toomey. What do you think, Officer Dutton? An eye for an eye?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dutton kicks him off, smashes a garbage can over Alex's back then pulls a SMALL SEMI-AUTO from an ankle holster.</context>
      <utterance>You were there. All four of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You killed her. I saw it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUTTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BAM! Alex barely slowed by the shot, advancing, Dutton starting to panic. BAM!</context>
      <utterance>Bitch killed herself when she shot a cop in the leg. If she' just acted like a girl nothing would have happened.  So you're right, spooky. Happy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment of panic as the guys bent over the machines freeze. Raise their hands, slowly turn. Then lower their hands.</context>
      <utterance>Police!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's Erlich, Larkin and Toomey. Three cops we met at the execution. Erlich's cane nearby.</context>
      <utterance>You fuck. Don't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the month end?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes. Never been better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Dutton?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably parked near some high school with a hardon. Fuck never showed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erlich, Larkin and Toomey exchange a look. Madden goes to one of the money counters and grabs... A STACK OF TWENTIES tossed violently at the ceiling. Larkin and Toomey scramble as the bills flutter down like leaves, picking them up.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone at all curious why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You leave the door open with two hundred strangers out there! What's it take for you guys to learn a goddamn lesson?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOOMEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one saw anything, Mad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Three exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>You know why Dutton's not here? Rigor mortis! He's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One shot to the head, then fifty three stab wounds with a six inch blade. Any deja vu here? Think Corvus knife, missing from the evidence room.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOOMEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since last night. As usual, you're right on top of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was supposed to end when Corvis died. Remember? The kid no one would miss?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look at me, asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I didn't kill anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back off. I mean it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Erlich and Larkin settle down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crime scene's a goddamn clusterfuck. Every reporter in town's trying to get a look at Dutton's body. I suggest we get a line on this before someone else does.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who'd give a shit about Corvis at this point? Kid didn't have a friend in the world even when he was alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erlich and Madden share a look. On the same wavelength. Erlich picks up his weapon off the table.</context>
      <utterance>I can think of one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GONZALEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gonzalez CONTINUES UNDER as...</context>
      <utterance>... rumors multiply as officials refuse to confirm or deny reports of multiple, multiple stab wounds...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SOUND of footsteps racing down the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Dad! Come in here!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Randall riveted by the TV now.</context>
      <utterance>The cop who found the knife in Corvis's car.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONZALEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>covered. It would appear that thirty seven year old Phillip Dutton is dead in the line of duty... ON THE TV the Newsteam and Gonzalez SHOVED back by COPS running defense for the stretcher. Gonzalez grabs for the sheet covering the body and... NEWSCAM TIGHT on Dutton, as the sheet pulls down, partially uncovering... DUTTON'S HEAD: Comb-over hanging to the side. Blood dripping from crude letters carved in his bald pate--the word "DAISY." Quickly covered by a COP who yells at Gonzalez...</context>
      <utterance>They're moving him now, body</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... but through a digital miracle the "Daisy" frame has been grabbed, and appears as a still now behind Gonzalez. RESUME - FAVORING ERIN struck dumb by this.</context>
      <utterance>Out of here! Now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GONZALEZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gonzalez FADES UNDER as Erin backs away from the TV.</context>
      <utterance>Shocking even for these mean streets, the word "Daisy" apparently cut into his head by the perpetrator, still at large. A name. Perhaps a message...</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lauren called me that when we were little. Daisy. No one knew but us.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's not a message.</context>
      <utterance>Honey. It's doesn't mean anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That guy in the cemetery today said he knew everything about Lauren.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It still doesn't mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Randall, as he sits on the bed, thoughtful...</context>
      <utterance>He said he'd prove it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know about any knife. I'm trying to forget that case.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well someone isn't. They killed Dutton.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erlich flips through a Rolodex, knocks it to the floor, then picks up a PHONE LOG off the desk.</context>
      <utterance>No shit. You couldn't get close to him. But I'm betting you know who did. Who's into Corvis? Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He tosses the phone log out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Not a lot of calls. Business slow?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ERLICH'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the only one gave a flying fuck about him when he was alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lauren Randall did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"THE LIST" The name "Erlich, Vincent" crossed off now by Alex.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Bitches are crazy. Richer they are, crazier they get.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe if you hadn't fried an innocent kid...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erlich violently tosses Walsh crashing back toward the window, falling by the chess board.</context>
      <utterance>How about the real killer. You think of that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erlich exits, slamming the door behind him. Walsh starts to get up, stops. Looking at his own eye level... ALEX'S CHESS BOARD set up identically to the game in Alex's cell, a piece of FOLDED PAPER protruding from under the board. Walsh pulls it out. It says "Q-->B5" WALSH makes the move, Queen to Bishop Five. Smiles. Looks at... THE PAPER UNFOLDED says "Check." Walsh sets it down in the Chess Box next to... THE PICTURE OF ALEX AND LAUREN arms around each other in the woods, smiling. WALSH sensing something, a presence.</context>
      <utterance>If you're covering for someone, that's jail time. I got my eye on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walsh moves cautiously to the curtains, draws them back. Nothing. He leans out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Alex?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The bum is giving the driver side window the same treatment. Hard to see anything now. Erlich throws up his hands in disgust, reaches for the door handle just as... SMASH! The driver side window SHATTERS as something enters at high speed KICKING Erlich across the car... Erlich's head bounces off the passenger window, leaving a BLOODY SMEAR. Alex in the driver seat now.</context>
      <utterance>No! Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LOW ANGLE ON THE PORSCHE wheels spinning as it peels out.</context>
      <utterance>The Germans really know how to make a car, don't they?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard you were looking for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the guy killed Dutton.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erlich pulls a .380 SEMI-AUTO stashed between the two seats. Points it at Alex.</context>
      <utterance>I want you to think of me as the guy who killed you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erlich blows a hole through Alex's LEFT ARM, a yawning aperture through which Erlich watches the passing scenery a few improbably seconds.</context>
      <utterance>Stop the car. Alex FLOORS it and... BAM.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow. The WOUND closes. Knife still in Alex's hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck. Me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHOP. In one swift move Alex impales the knife THROUGH ERLICH'S WRIST, into his thigh. Erlich SCREAMS, tries to remove the knife, but Alex keeps a firm grip on the handle.</context>
      <utterance>What happened to your leg there Officer? Hunting accident?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Erlich tries to stay steely, yells louder as...</context>
      <utterance>Lauren Randall shot you trying to get free. The fifty three stab wounds she died of came from you. Am I right? Ballpark?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLASH. Alex yanks the Knife out and FLASH, slices through the left arm of Erlich's jacket, sawing into the FLESH. Erlich's arm bleeding.</context>
      <utterance>In Saudi Arabia they cut off the hands of petty thieves. What price for a life? Two lives?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not my arm! What you fucking want?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I want... to know why.</context>
      <utterance>I want Lauren. I want my life back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex grimaces, then RIP, he yanks the sleeves off Erlich's arm. Erlich looks down, surprised to see his arm intact.</context>
      <utterance>Why? Why's anything happen? It's all money, man. Money. The girl just got in the way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The scar. Which of you has it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex poises the knife for another descent.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>This gives Alex pause. He shakes his head, clearing the reality glitch, looks up... IN THE REARVIEW MIRROR Cop cars, lights flashing.</context>
      <utterance>I swear. It's a bullshit fucking story the loser boyfriend made up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're going to die.</context>
      <utterance>Are you out of your fucking mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you die if you're already dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERLICH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're him. Corvis.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex smiles as the CIGARETTE LIGHTER pops out. He grabs it and the GLOW vanishes as he closes his fist around it. Erlich turns front in horror. The microsecond of terror realized as Elvis climaxes, the retaining wall zoomes in...</context>
      <utterance>I was talking about you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daisy. How did you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I knew your sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You killed that cop Dutton.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex points at the distant crash site, the vague flashing lights.</context>
      <utterance>And another one. There. Erlich. Took a wrong turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who you are.  That's why you paint your face. To hide.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not hiding. I'm right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin shakes her head, trying to absorb what's going on, then RUSHES ALEX, screaming, beating on him, fists of fury.</context>
      <utterance>You killed Lauren! You killed her!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex tries to handle her flailing arms but she's too manic. He's getting hit in the face, the chest, and it's hurting. He grabs her roughly, gets her to stop.</context>
      <utterance>Not me. Dirty cops killed her. Dutton, Erlich...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been shot, and stabbed and thrown from a car and none of it hurt. But what you're doing now, does. I don't know why.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dad was right! He said you'd ruin her life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up a Card, the Registration from the Corvette.</context>
      <utterance>No. Listen to me. Lauren found out something they didn't want her to know.  This.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the bonfire over there. Look at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Why are you haunting me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to give it to her one more time, then flips the card through the air. She turns, watching its flight all the way to the landing by the front door...</context>
      <utterance>Because you need to understand. And you need... to be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He's gone. Erin walks to the door. Despite herself reaches for the Card on the landing. It's... THE CORVETTE REGISTRATION which we see clearly for the first time. Owned by a company called DELT. The address is 4201 Forestview Drive. ERIN spins around horrified, holds up the Registration.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. Your father wasn't right. She turns back and...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SERGEANT#2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walla responds "no shit"--and CAMERA BOOMS UP, moving to the back of the room over a nervous sea of blue uniforms.</context>
      <utterance>Listen up! Yo! We got a cop killer out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT#2</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>FAVORING LARKIN, TOOMEY AND MADDEN huddling together at the back. Urgent whispers. Larkin and Toomey try to contain their panic.</context>
      <utterance>Til we get an I.D. treat everyone like a suspect. Patrol assignments are posted by the door. Read them. No singles, it's the buddy system til we catch this asshole. Sergeant 2 CONTINUES UNDER as CAMERA FINDS...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knows. I saw him. Fucking zombie mask.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larkin takes out "The List" from the crash site.</context>
      <utterance>You calm down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARKIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose name's fucking next? Not yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOOMEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't testify. You're not on the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pockets "The List." Then looks up as...</context>
      <utterance>Scary guy. Not only survives that crash, but takes time out for art.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SERGEANT#2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The entire room looking back at the three renegades.</context>
      <utterance>Madden! Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT#2</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Madden shakes his head like this is bad news, rises and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>The old man's requested the pleasure of your company.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad I'm not you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She checks out Madden as he moves past her, then puts the eyelash curler away in a NAILIT containing a couple of razor sharp SCALPELS.</context>
      <utterance>Right back at ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madden sits.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we had an understanding. I thought we understood that discretion is paramount.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madden does. The Captain begins and intense slow burn.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erlich gimping around in his goddamn hot rod is not discreet. I've got reporters asking me how much he made. I've got the entire force looking at this case now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madden produces "The List," flips it over to show the Crow doodle in blood.</context>
      <utterance>I know the guy leaves a sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Captain slaps down a crime scene photo--the Crow emblazoned huge on the top of Dutton's cruiser.</context>
      <utterance>No shit he leaves a sign. He's a goddamn Picasso.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Captain SLAMS a file down in front of Madden, who lets things cool out a moment before looking at it.</context>
      <utterance>What else do you know? Do you know this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy Leonard. The eyewitness in the Corvis case.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some hooker phoned it in. There was a riot at his apartment yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guy dressed for Halloween?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look up as the Secretary enters, holding the door open, like it's time to leave. Madden starts to speak and...</context>
      <utterance>Good for you. You do know something.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Secretary gives Madden a look as he exits, then joins the captain who's standing...</context>
      <utterance>Don't say. Just do. Before it all comes tumbling down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Idiots.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sssshhhh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he turns toward her embrace, CAMERA ADJUSTS to point up something we may have noticed... IN THE CASE - A STUFFED BIRD, on one of the glass shelves.</context>
      <utterance>You're the only one who makes it go away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin's a terrible liar, spooked as he approaches.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I dropped an earring.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She jumps up as her father reaches the desk, keeps her distance. He spots the empty DELT folder, closes it.</context>
      <utterance>Looks like you have them both on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>Alex Corvis didn't kill Lauren. Cops did. Didn't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not what you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You killed her!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay away from me! Stay away!</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin SCREAMS, runs out the door with her hands over her ears. He misses a beat, then RUNS after her.</context>
      <utterance>Erin. It wasn't supposed to happen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They killed her because she found out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ACROSS THE STREET, A PORCH LIGHT comes on. Erin hits a button on the key ring, CHIRP CHIRP. It stops.</context>
      <utterance>About them. You've got to leave it alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweetheart...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't call me that! Don't call me anything!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Never. Believe me.</context>
      <utterance>I would never hurt you or Lauren.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Come inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He edges away from the car, reluctantly. She starts to get in, anger giving way to extreme sadness.</context>
      <utterance>I'm never going back in that house again. Get away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TOMMY'S WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larkin backhands her sprawling to the floor, where she crawls to the WAILING BABY, takes him in sheltering arms.</context>
      <utterance>Please! Leave him alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not making this up. He had a crow with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Caw, caw, that's what you're telling me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said I lied at his trial. It's Alex Corvis.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LARKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy nods.</context>
      <utterance>So we're talking... a ghost. With a pet bird.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARKIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The baby's gets quieter as the mom rocks it.</context>
      <utterance>Turn down that fucking baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARKIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Larkin helps Tommy to his feet. Places "The List" on the table. Then RAMS Tommy's face down on top of it.</context>
      <utterance>Get up, Tommy. I want to show you something.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARKIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Larkin hauls Tommy back upright. Dazed.</context>
      <utterance>You see that? My name's next on his list. It's fucking next.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARKIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So who is the guy, Tommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Corvis. It's...</utterance>
   <speaker>LARKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KA-CHUNK. Toomey cycles his 9mm. Everything dead silent.</context>
      <utterance>Take your time. Think before you speak. Cause at this point I got to hear something besides the crap you're been spewing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larkin grimaces. The only question is how to end this.</context>
      <utterance>He said the whole trial was a setup. That I caused an innocent kid to die. Is that true?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks out the window a second. Then scans the room again.</context>
      <utterance>Alex?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Walsh goes back to the board, makes a move.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon. I'm talking to my myself here. It's humiliating.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check and mate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walsh looks up. Nothing. Then Alex steps from the shadows. Walsh looks at him a long moment, sees through the makeup.</context>
      <utterance>Dream on.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two guys look at each other a long moment, cross the few steps to hug. Walsh blown away.</context>
      <utterance>My God. It's really you under there.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Walsh leans in, examines Dutton's BADGE on Alex's costume.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to say you're looking good, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two down. Two to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Down?" Wait, don't tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cops from my trial. They killed Lauren. The whole thing was fixed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walsh sits down. Disturbed.</context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking... that explains a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lauren's father's involved. He bought the cops fancy cars, I don't know what else. It's a company called D-E-L-T. I think Lauren found out.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do they do that they had to kill her?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hoping you'd find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both turn as the Crow lands in the window, CAWS.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I sure will.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Crow flies off. Walsh goes to the window and looks out.</context>
      <utterance>Boo!</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He turns toward Alex, who's gone. A double take as Walsh gets it, whips around, looks out the window again. CUT TO:</context>
      <utterance>What's the deal with this bird. It's been hanging around. Alex?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is where it happened. Right over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stays where she is. Alex quiet, affected by the place. Erin's about to lose it.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you ok?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When Lauren was missing the police came to our house. They said they were looking for her, right?  But I know now they had her, and the reason they brought her here and knew the could blame it on you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's crying softly. He draws nearer.</context>
      <utterance>... is that I sent them here. I told them she came here sometimes. With her dirtball boyfriend. That's exactly what I said.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin. It's not your fault.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all my fault. Oh God. I wish I were dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeming to lose patience, Alex lunges at her, like an attack.</context>
      <utterance>Yes I do, I really do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There were four of them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's holding his hands over her eyes, transferring IMAGES that shake them both. ALEX/ERIN'S INTERNAL POV Jolting FLASHES. A Plainwrap stops where the Mercedes is now. A hand slams the car into Park. Doors open. Four men get out, seen dimly, but they're Dutton, Erlich, Larkin, Toomey. Erlich reaches back in to drag Lauren out of the back seat, her hands cuffed in front of her. Dutton flips up her skirt with his nightstick.</context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lauren stumbles into Erlich, grabs and BAM! FLASH! He takes a shot in the leg from his own, still holstered weapon.</context>
      <utterance>Four large men. And still...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>RESUME - PRESENT Erin's covering her face, like trying to avoid seeing some horrible thing.</context>
      <utterance>She grabbed one of their guns. Got off a shot, then ran, ran for her life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex grabs Erin, forces her to run with him, awkwardly, like a three legged race. Tracing the path Lauren covered.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin stumbling as Alex pushes, cajoles her, the two of them running toward a large tree, MATCHING to... ALEX/ERIN'S INTERNAL POV Lauren stumbling, her cuffed hands hindering, tree limbs hitting her face. Her own panting subsumed in the panting of the cops on her heels.</context>
      <utterance>She ran. Them breathing down her neck...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RESUME - PRESENT Erin still trying not to see. Alex forcing her.</context>
      <utterance>... all the way from the road to this tree...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This tree. Here's where it happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex spins her up against the tree and we MATCH to... ALEX/ERIN'S INTERNAL POV Lauren an adrenaline crazed fighter destined to lose. Her movements UNDERCRANKED, strobed. Discontinuous and jarring.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to see!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The brutal cops overwhelm Lauren. She drops to the ground as... RESUME Erin drops to the forest floor, convulsed in sobs.</context>
      <utterance>She turned and faced them and went down kicking and punching and fighting them, fighting death as they stabbed her and stabbed her. Fifty three times.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex panting. Fierce.</context>
      <utterance>She fought for her life because life is worth living.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Off Erin, sobbing, heartbroken. Alex's fury waning as he looks at her, wonders if he did the right thing.</context>
      <utterance>Think about that. And then tell me how much you wish you were dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wasn't the incident reported?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing to report. All inmates were present and accounted for.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you pretended nothing happened.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Corvis fried. I don't really see how it could be him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all enter...</context>
      <utterance>No. I wouldn't expect you to.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The all look inside. The locker is empty. Mercer's the only one shocked. He noisily opens and shuts the other lockers looking for Alex.</context>
      <utterance>Be forewarned. Nature takes its toll.  Bon appetit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mercer stops, backs off, gives the power trio some space.</context>
      <utterance>You lost him! Now lay off the fucking doors!</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They botched the execution.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ. It was Corvis. Tommy Leonard was right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They watch now as the Secretary moves, drawn to the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you were a little harsh on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>HE FRACTURED MIRROR. Shards of glass selectively removed forming, we see now, a CROW.</context>
      <utterance>Babe? She's looking at... T</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fucking crow.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madden turns, not comfortable with the concept.</context>
      <utterance>Sign of the dead come back to life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about sign of a big black bird?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The dead can return, given sufficient motivation. And Corvis has that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This guy David Jenkins came back as a ghost because my uncle owed him four dollars. Followed him everywhere. Ruined his life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Secretary nestles into the Captain, who whispers in her ear. He nods.</context>
      <utterance>Time out. You really saying he's back from beyond?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause if you're losing your mind, I got a right to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's looking for something. Won't stop until he finds it.  Sometimes the best way to get rid of someone is to let them have what they want.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... with the scar...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... took everything I ever cared about. Left me with nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're going to kill him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes his eyes. Pained at a memory.</context>
      <utterance>Have to find him first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what Lauren and I were fighting about that night? She had a secret, wouldn't tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It made me crazy.</context>
      <utterance>All I knew, she was pulling away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She fights back tears. Gains strength.</context>
      <utterance>I used to be so proud of him. My big deal daddy. And now, he's just a crook. Worse even. And the weird thing is...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>I'm going back.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I could hate him but I can't. He said he'd never hurt either of us, and I know it's true and...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin nods, takes the Locket off her neck.</context>
      <utterance>It's what Lauren would do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She winds up to toss the Locket away and Alex hops down off the hood. Stops her. Takes the Locket. ALEX</context>
      <utterance>I want to forget. Forget what I know. Forget myself. Forget everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He fastens the Locket back around her neck. A covenant.</context>
      <utterance>Keep it. Because it connects you to Lauren. And it connects you to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>CLOSE. Erin pulls some makeup out of her jacket pocket. Dumps it on the ground. Finds a pot of dark eyeshadow among the containers.</context>
      <utterance>No matter what happens I'll make sure everyone knows. That you're innocent. That you loved her. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Make me like you.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to be me anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nathan gets up. Tries to subtly herd the Captain off.</context>
      <utterance>You know it doesn't work this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm out of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Friendships don't.</context>
      <utterance>Partnerships don't end like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Captain circles to the desk now, past Nathan.</context>
      <utterance>Our friendship ended when Lauren died.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe in ghosts, Nathan? Because there's a ghost threatening us.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean Alex.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Captain flips through some of the papers on the desk. Frowns. He closes a file folder.</context>
      <utterance>I mean Lauren.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you never accepted that what happened to her was an accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You killed my daughter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An accident, Nathan.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nathan furious. The Captain keeps a preternatural calm.</context>
      <utterance>She was eighteen years old! There were four of them. They stabbed her fifty three times! Where's the fucking accident?! Huh?! Where is it?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I watched her grow up. Just like you. I know how her mind worked. She kept snooping around because she was worried about you. What you'd gotten yourself into. So stop blaming me. And blame yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do. Every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This catches Nathan off guard. He starts to say something.</context>
      <utterance>Erin knows, doesn't she?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Captain flips through the papers on the desk again.</context>
      <utterance>Don't even bother. You never were a good liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this. Everything we worked for. You tell me... what are we going to do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex picks up the BLACK KING.</context>
      <utterance>It's like a bowl of spaghetti. D-E- L-T is owned by Westwind Builders, Nathan Randall's company. But DELT in turn owns a dozen other corporations. A big mess to wade through, so I checked out Tommy Leonard.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leonard, Dutton, Erlich. They don't matter. I want the King.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're getting there. Because in his so-called construction job, Tommy makes a daily delivery to a place called "The Hole."</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The strip joint?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe they call it a connoisseur's club. Owned by DELT.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walsh opens the door and Erin enters, wild and blood smeared, remnants of the Crow mask around her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Alex!</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>It all catches up with her now, the flight, the exhaustion. She throws herself into his arms.</context>
      <utterance>They killed my dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's ok, it's ok...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not. I can't take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin. Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex immobilized by this. He turns to Walsh.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I found him lying there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is it? This place?</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we should get some support?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Call the police?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex waiting for an address. Finally...</context>
      <utterance>What is this? Where are you going?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1315 Berkeley Street.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex turns to her, comforting. Holds her face in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Don't leave me. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads off and we PRE-LAP sexbomb death metal POUNDING...</context>
      <utterance>It will be over soon.  Watch out for each other.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Two Bouncers give each other a look. One points to a SIGN on the wall: "You must be 21..."</context>
      <utterance>Toomey and Larkin. They're expecting me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Other Bouncer grabs Alex as he pushes past. Alex heaves him into the line of WAITING PATRONS. As they go down like dominoes... the First Bouncer pulls a</context>
      <utterance>I need to see some I.D., pal. Circus in town?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's looking elsewhere, at the door that has quietly opened. The Captain stands there. Somber reptile. Holding a sheaf of papers in one hand.</context>
      <utterance>We'll be safe in my car. Nobody will recognize it. Let's move yours in back, no, down the block. Hope it's nothing fancy. There's a chop shop around the corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You followed me here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him expressionless.</context>
      <utterance>No... Erin, I put out a bulletin on your car because... there's bad news. And I thought you should hear it from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She talks with great difficulty.</context>
      <utterance>Your father got involved with some bad cops. On my force, so I take responsibility.  He killed himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods.</context>
      <utterance>How did he kill himself?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With a gun. Is that what you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a step toward her. She pulls out the Blood Pistol. Seems crazy enough to use it.</context>
      <utterance>No. I mean... how did he kill himself How do you figure he killed himself--with a gun, right--when it wasn't anywhere near where you found him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You killed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Erin. Don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Captain stops, gently tosses the sheaf of papers toward her, onto Walsh's desk. The papers Nathan was preparing. Walsh looks at them while...</context>
      <utterance>Back the fuck off! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He left this. Names, addresses, a note to you. These people he was involved with killed Lauren. He couldn't bear it anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>WALSH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God. He's right, it's all here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Erin has one eye on the papers now, recognizes her dad's hand. The Captain inches forward.</context>
      <utterance>The note. Show it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Captain steps forward, right to the desk. Erin backed into a corner now.</context>
      <utterance>Not you!  Show it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds a hand out for the note, taking her eye off the situation for one second as she reads...</context>
      <utterance>It's right there, under that paper.  Here. Look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She fights as the Captain wraps his own hand over hers, wrestles her arm toward Walsh, in the sights now. BAM! WALSH blown backward, collapsing by the Chess Board. Trying to pull himself up. Erin struggling. As... MADDEN enters from the hall, in a hurry, gun drawn.</context>
      <utterance>You were always the stupid one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods toward Walsh, who is moving, barely.</context>
      <utterance>You need help?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BAM. A shot from Madden drops Walsh for god. As Madden drags Walsh toward the door, the Captain grabs... THE PICTURE OF ALEX AND LAUREN pulled off the lid of the Chess box, one of the pieces of tape left behind. The Captain exits.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry. We don't have much time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She listens as he unlocks the cuffs.</context>
      <utterance>How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have one chance to value your life. Take it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look up and... BAM! Alex DROPS LARKIN with a shot to the forehead. BAM! He MISSES TOOMEY as bullets from below EXPLODE all around him. Alex scampers across framing as... The BARE BULBS burst, all but one, plunging us back in to near darkness as Alex drops to the ground near Larkin's fallen body. Jacks up the sleeve. No scar. Alex spots Toomey, rolls out as... THREE COPS pump rounds into Alex. BAM! Alex takes the middle Cop out, a TOONEY-LIKE GUY who falls onto Toomey, behind him. ALEX turns, forced to defend himself as FULL AUTO FIRE breaks open, the other flank, more advancing cops. While... TOOMEY crawls out from under the fallen copy, then backs out the door on hands and knees while... A FINAL EXPLOSIVE FUSILLADE leaves only Alex standing. As the echoes dissolve... Alex Alex moves to where Toomey was, bends down to check the body... THE NAMEPLATE - "TOOMEY" But the pin isn't fastened properly. The badge askew. RESUME - ALEX rolls the body over, finds another nameplate underneath. "Hauser." Heads off in search of...</context>
      <utterance>Cheers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toomey!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>WAM! Alex swings Toomey's pipe HARD at a much bigger GAS LINE right behind the gas heater, leaving it badly cracked. The hiss magnified 100% nos.</context>
      <utterance>Spark, gas... bad combination. And it's not this leak here, that's the least of your worries.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to play a little game called "Who's got the Scar."</utterance>
   <speaker>TOOMEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What Scar? What fucking scar?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOOMEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're him! You're Corvis! We fried your ass. You're dead, man!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We pick up...</context>
      <utterance>Good thing in a situation like this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TOOMEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fucking Zombie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The scar.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOOMEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Madden moves toward the conversation, his face registers the slightest of smiles. MADDEN'S CREEPING POV MONITORS obliquely visible as he reaches the end of the hall by the Fantasy sets. The "Shower" monitor shows Alex and Toomey, visible through the trashed set, updated every six seconds. MADDEN SNIFFS gas. The HISS now audible along with Alex's voice. Madden smiles. Pulls out his 9mm. And BACKS UP, away from the Fantasy Sets toward the back room. Madden takes aim at... THE FIRST MONITOR The images is Alex threatening Toomey. Updating now--LOSING ALEX on the Monitor as he steps into frame in person, looks up and BAM! CROWVISION a speeding bullet passes narrowly by and... ANGLE - GROUND ZERO as the bullet hits the monitor in a shower of sparks, followed by... BOOM! A ROILING FIREBALL Seems to vaporize Alex before flying down the hallway right at CAMERA. Madden manages a couple steps in retreat before it blows him into the back room with a deafening roar.</context>
      <utterance>There is no scar. I'm telling you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her Bruce Lee "Oooo" a siren call. RESUME Alex moving slowly forward on the street, drawn toward the girl who watches with horrified fascination.</context>
      <utterance>Your witness list is no match for my kung fu.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm losing you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lauren and Alex drawing very close now when... RESUME WAM. A FIST clocks Alex in the face, dropping him hard onto the pavement.</context>
      <utterance>Your zigzag love scar is no match for...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you have to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOYFRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about "thank you."</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's bleeding.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't bleed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOYFRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And delirious. Better steer clear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate that picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I get you something? A glass of water? A transfusion?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are they? Last chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Captain rises.</context>
      <utterance>Or what? You'll bleed all over my carpet?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know crime was actually down until you showed up, or stuck</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>around, or whatever the hell you're doing here.  What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for my friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I heard you were looking for some guy with a scar. How's that going? You find him? Yes? No? Alex tenses as the Captain starts toward him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Alex draws the knife from his clothes.</context>
      <utterance>You are like the guest who would not leave, you know that? And judging from your condition, maybe you've overstayed your welcome. That's not a criticism. Just an observation.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Enraged, Alex SWIPES the knife. The Captain grabs his arm right at the blood soaked necktie, squeezes hard. Alex writhes in pain. In each other's faces now.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think you're going to use it. That's Lauren's knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>THE KNIFE starting to fall from Alex's hand as the Captain continues to clamp down on his wound.</context>
      <utterance>You come in here al lfull of righteous indignation, but what have you got to be righteous about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many innocent people did you leave dead back there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sent them. I had no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Captain snatches the knife, RAMS it into Alex's midriff.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. You're a killer, that's all you are. A clown with a bird and a rising death toll. You think the world did you wrong?! You did the world wrong.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He grabs for her. She pulls violently away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was one thing her dad rejected you. But when she did you lost it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLASH ALEX'S INTERNAL POV Alex back at the inferno, cowering from flames. RESUME The Captain full of righteous conviction.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? I see doubt oozing out your arm. Where do people go when they kill their girlfriends?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Captain bent over Alex, stabbing him.</context>
      <utterance>Screwed up kid stabs her fifty three times. Where would he end up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Porsche explodes.</context>
      <utterance>That's who you are!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Alex blasts Dutton. BAM!</context>
      <utterance>You sick fuck! Look at it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Alex escapes the taser. Mercer drops.</context>
      <utterance>Every loser name anyone ever called you was true!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Time SCREECHING to a halt, all the movement converging on a single, quiet image. One we've seen before... Alex in the chair. But his last words are different.</context>
      <utterance>Are you looking? Answer me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZAP. Electro-spasm as the switch is thrown. No scar, no meltdown, just violent fibrillations that moderate, finally as we MATCH TO... RESUME - THE CAPTAIN'S OFFICE The Captain shaking Alex, holding something in front of Alex's face.</context>
      <utterance>I loved Lauren. I never meant to hurt her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex's eye's gone dead, no longer seeing... THE PHOTO - LAUREN AND ALEX IN THE WOODS arms around each other. Familiar, but on second take, it's like the crime scene photos... Lauren's NECK is SLASHED, her body riddled with stab wounds. Alex has a big smile on his face, his arm around her, her head on his shoulder. 100% sociopath. RESUME</context>
      <utterance>You see it? Huh? Did you see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Captain drops Alex lifeless and bloody to the floor. Only the sound of the Captain panting now, then... The sound of slow clapping. Madden walks into the room from behind perimeter curtains.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I think you fucking saw it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madden kicks Alex lightly, nudging him. No life signes. The Captain rips the picture in two. Tosses it in the trash.</context>
      <utterance>You were right. Picture's worth a thousand words.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just don't believe everything you see.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doubt is a motherfucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a hand with this sack of shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVEAL, this is the Secretary's POV through the window. She's bent over someone's toes, painting them BLUE. WIDE. The Mystery Room revealed. Taxidermy specimens line the wall and the table. Erin stands in PROFILE in the middle of the room, strangely silent, hands tied overhead by a rope that runs to the ceiling. The Secretary brushing polish on Erin's toes.</context>
      <utterance>He's cute. Was cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Secretary applies a last flourish of polish, then stands, kisses Erin gently.</context>
      <utterance>But the face, well, makeup can work for you or against you. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ERIN'S FACE MOUTH SEWN shut in a rough zigzag stitch, like the scar. Her eyes dart as... THE DOOR opens. The Captain and Madden carry Alex in. Madden sweeps the TAXIDERMY SPECIMENS back with his hand, clearing a space for Alex on the table. Among them...</context>
      <utterance>All done. Very nice.  You're a good listener. The Secretary moves off REVEALING...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Secretary puts her ear to Alex's lifeless lips.</context>
      <utterance>So was he dead? Or alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This reminds him... he looks at the Crow on the stand. Lifeless, stuffed. As it should be.</context>
      <utterance>I've seen birds stuffed and mounted so lifelike you'd swear you saw them breathing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we had a case of that here.  Get me my kit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Secretary steps off to grab thekit, leaving Alex's lifeless open eyes pointing toward Erin, reflected in his eyeballs first before... ANGLE - ERIN looking up at her own hands, bound above her as she eases them apart and... The HEART SHAPED LOCKET slips from between her palms and she closes them again in time to catch the chain, the locket swinging. ON THE TABLE X-CLOSE. The locket reflected in Alex's lifeless open eyes a second before... The Secretary returns, blocking the sightline. Lays out the Kit, nasty looking tools left over from the Inquisition. Then unbuttons Alex's tattered shirt, undressing him for the procedure. Stab wounds everywhere.</context>
      <utterance>You two are majorly demented. Anyone ever tell you that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty three?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A large KNIFE, the Lauren murder weapon, angles in at the base of Alex'sneck where the Secretary's head was.</context>
      <utterance>In all the excitement I kind of lost count.  I think I'll mount him with his head up his ass.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>THE LOCKET - OVERCRANKED Snatched in midair by the Crow from Erin's praying hands.</context>
      <utterance>Grab it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... it connects you to me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RESUME Alex BLINKS. The Captain reacts--oh shit--starts to bring the knife down, a hurried strike at Alex's chest. WAM! Alex grabs the Captain's arm in his hand, stopping the movement on a dime.</context>
      <utterance>No matter what happens... you're innocent... I promise... FLASH. Alex painting her face.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MADDEN pulls a gun, points it at Erin. ALEX jumps up, flying INTO the gun as it goes off. CRASH! They tumble THROUGH THE WINDOW into the Captain's office while... THE CAPTAIN cuts down the rope holding Erin. She collapses... ON THE TABLE strewn with blades, secreting one between her hands, in the second before... THE CAPTAIN drags Erin off. The Secretary flails at the Crow with a metal ROD, while... IN THE CAPTAIN'S OFFICE Madden has the gun on Alex now. BAM! No effect. BAM!</context>
      <utterance>All lies. Everything you ever showed me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON ERIN face pressed against the elevator wall, intent.</context>
      <utterance>You brought him back. Good. He owes you. We'll stick together, you and I.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>THE BLADE emerging from her sleeve as she tries to hold it with her two bound hands. DING. The elevator jerks to a stop. THE CAPTAIN grabs her off the floor and she RAMS the blade into his abdomen with the force of the entire body. Twists it. The elevator doors open. ERIN pulls out the blade, claws her way out the door, the Captain hanging on to her, finally getting free as she swipes at him again, drawing fresh blood. Running now, into...</context>
      <utterance>Seen but not heard. They ought to make it a law. Erin winces, looks down...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>sitting on the floor, painting her own toenails BLUE, leaning up against the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Alex eases the Secretary to her feet with a hand around her neck, her back to the wall. She looks UP, smiling at... WALSH - RIGHT ARM MISSING hangs high overhead from some kind of hook. His arm has been crudely removed. Underneath him, on the table, a BOX of 2" surgical stainless steel rods sits by a pool of blood. ALEX yells, reeling, as... The door flies open. A half dozen cops in, all targeting Alex as... THE SECRETARY plunges the Lauren KNIFE in Alex's back. He spins violently THROWING her HARD against the wall. WAM! Surprise!-she sticks. REVEAL, she's impaled on ANTELOPE ANTLERS, hanging off the wall. Her head drops, looking down as a stream of blood flows down her legs, drips off her toes...</context>
      <utterance>Where'd they go?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BAM BAM BAM. The new arrivals open fire. Alex reaches over his shoulder, yanks out the knife with an odd slurping sound as...</context>
      <utterance>My nails.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>82.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HER OBSTRUCTED POV between stacks of tires, the Captain, Glock at ready, PASSES BY, moving out of sight. Footsteps RECEDING. Then silent. ERIN Listening, neurons firing. Cranes her neck to see. Nothing. WIDER the Captain appears BEHIND ERIN, over the stacks of tires. She's oblivious, then... Erin wheels, slashes across his wrist. The Glock falls, Erin grabs it, levels it at the Captain. Her finger tense on the trigger.</context>
      <utterance>The Captain's FOOTSTEPS audible.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you too well. You won't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BAM! She pulls the trigger, simultaneously wrenching the gun, aiming just enough off that... THE CAPTAIN yells in pain, rushes his hand to his ear, a bloody mess. He starts advancing again toward her and Erin pulls... THE TRIGGER again, again, again. No click, no blast.</context>
      <utterance>You don't know me at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ALEX'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FIND ALEX'S FACE in the darkness. Moving as he performs some unseen task. Intent, focussed.</context>
      <utterance>The Jolt, eight amps at two to three thousand volts. It lasts a few seconds. The current surges and is turned off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>FIND ERIN, in the darkness, listening to Alex's voice. She touches her mouth, little drops of dried blood where the wounds are already healing.</context>
      <utterance>They wait for the body to cool, then check to see if the heart is still beating.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>SLOW FADE IN as our eyes adjust to the dim light.</context>
      <utterance>If it is... ba-boom, ba-boom... another jolt is applied.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The only light a few panel indicators and spill from the door open from the adjacent observation room to the outside. Alex looks at the phone on the wall. Silent.</context>
      <utterance>Experts say unconsciousness occcurs before pain has time to register. They agree electrocution does not "hurt," could not hurt. But it does. Unimaginably. Believe me. We're in the death chamber. Dark. Claustrophobic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVEAL the Captain in the chair. A private execution. Erin slumped along a side wall. Totally inscrutable. Intense.</context>
      <utterance>I don't expect a call from the Governor. Any last words? Captain, my Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat of silence.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was that it? Well, ok.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Figure wipes through frame moving toward the switch. The Captain's voice rising as he senses time running out.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not dying for your goddamn illusions. You got that? You think you and your girlfriend had some rosy future ahead of you? Bullshit. She was already bored, why do you think she was looking around? You're nothing, Corvis! Less than nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>CLOSE. The switch thrown. ZZZZZTTT. PAN UP off the switch to...</context>
      <utterance>You can't do this to me you little fucks! I'll come back, just like you, a big fucking shit spewing bird and three guesses what little bitch I'm taking out first...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at the Captain, fibrillating in the chair, starts to move off. Then stops, near Alex, looking with him at... THEIR POV - THE ZIGZAG SCAR fibrillating, as we PUSH into seething detail. Writhing bodies, human suffering, a hellish miasma that draws us in until we turn our heads away, released.</context>
      <utterance>You are so dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops, face to face now.</context>
      <utterance>You want to get some breakfast?  What I mean is... I don't know how this works, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the woods you said you had nothing. But you wouldn't, and I wouldn't if there's some way you don't have to go. Please. At least not right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LAUREN Smiling. Sublime. She kisses him. As the break off, it's... ERIN AGAIN She hangs on a long moment before letting go. Then she spots something... ON THE GROUND - A SIGN carried by one of the protestors. "Remember the Victim." With a picture of Lauren. Someone has written a bold "s" after it. "Remember the Victims." ERIN picks up the sign.</context>
      <utterance>Erin. I'll always be with you. For a split second, she's...</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to Alex. But he's gone. She tries to keep it together as... CAMERA BOOMS up leaving her alone outside the prison walls, with her memories, and her conscience, and her hopes, which is alot. As a DUSTDEVIL whips up in the parking lot, she drops the sign, and starts to CRY.</context>
      <utterance>Alex. Look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In that moment when Alex went... wherever he went... when he made that choice, I knew I was making a choice too. To be alive. In the world. And it made me cry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ERIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVEAL... Erin is writing the journal, but she's a radically transformed wild child. A shock of vividly colored dreadlocks, some of the holes that stitched her mouth shut kept permanently open by studs.</context>
      <utterance>When I think of Lauren fighting and dying, it tears me apart, but it also reassures me. That Lauren and Alex were meant for each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>ERIN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>"Alex Corvis 1981-1999 Always With Us."</context>
      <utterance>That they're together now. Fighters. United by love. And anger. That they've given also to me. She's leaning up against a new headstone.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
