<movie id="129" title="Cincinnati Kid The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The player nearest the window shuts it. The Dealer, who also owns the restaurant, is the talkative type of poker player. Except for THE CINCINNATI KID, the other men at the table look like hoods of one sort or another: gunmen, labor spies, extortionists, what have you. The man who fancies himself the toughest of them all is named DANNY, and he and The Kid have almost all the money on the table between them, about a hundred dollars in front of each. No other player has more than a few dollars left, and now, as fifth cards are dealt, there is about forty dollars in the pot. Only four men are left in the hand.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody shut the goddam window. Let a man think.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Possible straight gets a --  -- lovely little four.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST PLAYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the last hand even, you couldn't give me a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I put the brakes on your straight, didn't I?  There you are, son, a gorgeous deuce.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And our lucky friend from Chicago gets a queen with his pair of sixes. Little lady make you happy, Buster?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deal to yourself, clown.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dealer gives himself a --  I might have known.  Bet your sixes, Buster.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you not to call me that.  Cost you --  Ninety-four bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Biggest pot of the whole game, I got to drop.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interested?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST PLAYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns over his cards, leaving it up to The Kid.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't call you if I had a pair higher'n sixes. Which I ain't.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He counts out the money, which is almost all he has.</context>
      <utterance>Don't seem like he'd bet out without something better than the sixes, does it?  Cost me every cent I've won since yesterday afternoon.  But I tell you, I got this stubborn streak. Call the ninety-four dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't have better than a pair of kings!</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm not claiming anything that fine.  Just enough to beat the pair of sixes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Attending to first things first, The Kid has been pulling in the pot, adding it to his own stake, and pocketing the total. Now as Danny accuses him again, The Kid looks him squarely in the face.</context>
      <utterance>You seen my hole card, you bastard!  He was dealing them high.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stole that dough.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands up.</context>
      <utterance>You better watch those loose lips of yours, you want to have any teeth left behind them -- Buster.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't of shelled out ninety- four bucks --</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks off, disappearing through a door marked "MEN."</context>
      <utterance>I called you on account of I didn't think you had another pair or another six and I know a punk like you would get greedy and try and buy the last hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you looking for, mister?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I have to be looking for something?</utterance>
   <speaker>HACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can pretty much tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can pretty much tell what?</utterance>
   <speaker>HACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some guys come to town, I can tell if they're looking for something.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think I'm looking for?</utterance>
   <speaker>HACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're looking for girls, I can fix you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I strongly doubt if you could fix me up. In that department.</utterance>
   <speaker>HACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well what are you looking for?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're looking for a clout in the head if you don't keep your face to the road.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SECOND HACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you know who that is?</utterance>
   <speaker>HACKIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the second hackie has followed Lancey into the hotel.</context>
      <utterance>No. Who?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Kid know?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody sure as hell ought to tell The Kid.  Lancey Hodges is in town.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BARBER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ask me, The Kid'll go after him as soon as he hears.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUSTOMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's got a better right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going to tell The Kid, Shooter?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, I can't not tell him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid enters the place through the front door, still a little dishevelled from his escape.</context>
      <utterance>It's where he's been headed for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you say, Kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Hoban.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you been? Boys been holding a chair for you in back.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Business opportunity come along. Something too good to pass up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn a profit?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, did okay. Except I almost had it took back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, one of those.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been in too many rough ones lately, Kid. You can't go on forever, coming out in one piece.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got to build my stake, Aren't enough chances in this town to let one go.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're too good, that's your trouble. People who know you're the Cincinnati Kid, they don't want to sit down with you --</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For nickels and dimes... Thing is I've about used up St. Louis.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The streets are getting full of guys you've hustled.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been thinking about Miami. There's nothing to keep me here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell there isn't  Lancey Hodges' in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?  The Man himself, here in St. Louis -- I might just stick around Shooter.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Schlaegel? How are you? And your enchanting wife?... Tomorrow is quite convenient... I generally prefer stud but you name it... Your stakes are my pleasure, sir... Thank you, why don't we make it after lunch? My diet these days is enough to spoil anyone else's appetite... A pleasure, sir. Please remember me to your charming wife. He hangs up and some of the strength seems to go out of him, as if he had been through too long a sustained effort. His eyes show that he is feeling pain and he breathes deeply.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been seeing it coming for a long time, Kid. Long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't exactly been hiding it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you ain't been hiding it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I got to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, you got to know. We all got to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometime or other we got to find out how much juice we got.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why I had to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever sit down with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk along, The Shooter pursing his lips thoughtfully.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Nothing at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't lose. I'm too good to lose when I set my mind to it. I play poker a certain way, Kid. I've had my Lancey Hodges. Only with me it was Whistling Sam Magee to New Orleans.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well then you know it all... about 20 years ago it was, maybe more.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, I lost it. It dried me up on the inside for a long, a very long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid nods as they come to where an old wooden pier extends into the river. Along the river bank can be seen a small portion of the mile-long Hooverville that stretches up and down the Mississippi.</context>
      <utterance>I been where I'm going, know what I mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="44">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid, I don't think you're ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're not going to take my word for it, are you? Are you now?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I ain't. I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, I know. You got to find out for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't figure to take him right away. But if I can hang in there long enough, I can outlast him. If I can outlast him, I got a chance. You admit that, don't you, that I got a chance?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already said I didn't think you were ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you think you were ready when you sat down with Whistling Sam Magee?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid, I thought I was the best stud poker player in the world. I'm telling you now, I thought I was the best.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't think I'm just a cocky square with a fair hand with cards. I got something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you ain't no cocky square. And you probably got something.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. And I ain't saying that you was either when you sat down with Whistling Sam Magee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you got the stuff, being a little cocky don't hurt you none.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, would you say if I got any chance at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This much of a chance. If Lancey is not right. If he's got a cold, or his stomach ulcer is acting up, or something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But then everybody'd see he wasn't right and it wouldn't prove nothing. Listen, we got to have it understood. If he's not right, we call it off till he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start back off the pier.</context>
      <utterance>You're set on a real showdown, aren't you? Your mind's all made up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got to. You said yourself I got to. I'm overdue.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you been around a long time -- I was a lot younger than you when I went up against Whistling Sam -- But you'd be kinda young too, to be The Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want me to set it up?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish you would, Shooter Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what if he turns me down?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He won't, the way I'll spread the word. He'll have to take you on, someone in your class. If he ducked it, that'd make you The Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think he knows I'm around?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ahead, on the levee, CHRISTIAN is seen waiting for The Kid. She has not yet seen them as they approach off the pier.</context>
      <utterance>He can smell meat like you a mile and a half up the river. He knows you're around and he'll sit down with you. You want to butt heads with The Man, I'll set it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's your woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't want to wait around too long. I want to get in and get it over with.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He must of come to St. Louis for a big money game. I'll probably get asked do I want to deal it for them. And however long that takes, he'll have to rest up for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, well, if he's tooling a dollar, I can understand that. Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got much of a stake?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close to three grand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christian sees them and moves toward them.</context>
      <utterance>Work on it. But three grand will give you a ride and even if you don't win, why you'll come away with a good idea of what you're made of. But once you go in Kid you can't quit. You get that straight right now. Two of you go in and only one of you can come out.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, school's out. I damn sure don't want no lessons. I want everything he's got.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shooter turns away abruptly as Christian arrives, giving her a brief nod.</context>
      <utterance>It's the only way to be, Kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid takes Christian's arm automatically; he watches The Shooter walk way down Harold Street. He and Christian head in another direction. She is humming a mountain tune.</context>
      <utterance>See you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we leaving town, Kid? This week?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I won't be ready. Not for a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought --</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is surprised by this and, in her own hesitant way, curious.</context>
      <utterance>Might even turn out we don't go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her fondly and, for one fleeting moment of weakness, is actually tempted to tell her about Lancey. But it is too sharp a break with tradition.</context>
      <utterance>You must feel different about it than you did Saturday.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm feeling a little different.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right. You don't have to act like a cat. You're not bothering me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to turn out the light?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm overtired, that's why I can't sleep.  Why can't you sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Undertired, I guess. If a person rests all day, she doesn't have much to rest up from at night.  Why don't you have a nice hot bath? I could give you a rubdown and then you could have a nice hot bath, and then maybe you could sleep. She waits at the foot of the bed for him to come slowly to a decision.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes into the bathroom, where she turns the water on gently so the tub will take a long while to fill. Then she takes a bottle of alcohol from the medicine chest and returns to the bedroom with it. She stands in front of him waiting for him to move, but The Kid is singularly listless. Not till she sets the bottle down does he respond by turning his face to the pillow. She goes right to work on his shoulder muscles, and she seems to know what she is doing.</context>
      <utterance>'Kay. Can't hurt to try it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do with yourself this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last night I went to a movie with The Shooter's woman. French movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In French?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They had the words in English at the bottom of the picture. But The Shooter's woman knew what they were saying without it. Pig's woman or somebody told me she went to college.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Majored in man-eating.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think maybe she really did go. But I never quite dared to up and ask her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't know you ran with The Shooter's woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got to be kind of friendly when you both were in that three-day game down to Cairo. 'Course she's older'n me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And been around more. A lot more. What was the movie like?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weird. It wasn't a straight story where you knew whose side you were on, the way you do in regular pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>American pictures.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. There were lots of things I didn't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was it about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's this town in Europe a long time ago where they get a message from a Spanish general he's coming to spend the night with his troops. So all the men are scared silly about what the soldiers will do to them.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing weird about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But all the wives and daughters tell the men to go hide somewhere and let them bargain with the enemy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That don't make much sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. The way they handle it is they go to bed with the Spaniards. And the next morning the soldiers go off peacefully and everybody's happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Including the husbands and fathers? Don't they suspect?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's part of what I wasn't sure of. I guess they know what went on but they care more about their safety and their money than they do about their honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then they got their heads screwed on straight. Honor's just an idea. You can't see or feel it and you can't eat it and you sure as hell can't get any mileage on it. She slaps him on the rump and straightens up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't move but just stays relaxed and closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'll just turn off the bath water.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phone for you. I always seem to be the one to answer it, no matter who it's for.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you'd rather we put it in my room --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Shooter picks up the phone but before he speaks into it, he pantomimes to her that he won't be able to hear over the radio. She seems to regard the request as an imposition but she does go grudgingly to the radio and turns it down a little before she returns to her bed and her cosmetic chore.</context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?... Well, hello. What brings you to our fair city? Little action, maybe?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could you guess, Shooter? I was invited by a Mr. William Schlaegel --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CAMERA PULLS BACK to include Christian and Melba looking at the display.</context>
      <utterance>Would you wear it in public?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start walking.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't be much point wearing it in private. Sure, why not, as long as you don't have a bulge to hide?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, Melba.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My guess is there isn't anything about you needs hiding. But I'll give you a more definitive opinion at the bath.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turkish Bath. After we're through shopping. I'm treating you, Christian.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never been. I'm not even sure what you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't do anything. That's what's so marvelous. They do it to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The third time I stayed. Never went back to the boarding house except to pick up my things.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that side of it's held up? No complaints in the bed department?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, just one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The nights he isn't there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He really does that to you, does he? You got one of the rare ones.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You find a guy, you love him, and that's it. It's supposed to just go on like that for life. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to the propaganda, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it isn't my life, it's his life, with me tacked on. You have any idea what it's like to be a hash slinger in a cheap restaurant?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, honey, the stock crash wafted me right from the daisy chain into unmarried bliss.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hell, if you'll excuse the word. But I didn't want to quit. The Kid made me. I felt I ought to hang on to something that was me away from him. You know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Some girls solve the problem by taking on an extra guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm serious. Having children might take care of it, I don't know. Or -- this is really a terrible thing to admit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your most sordid secrets are safe with me. Confess.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he was rich, or famous --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you give him both?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not? Well, if he was rich and famous, maybe I wouldn't mind so much just being -- just a woman to him. Do you think that might make it seem more worthwhile somehow?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somehow! Are you sincere, sweetie?  Oooo -- divine.  Isn't this heaven?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure. In a way it seems soft of -- She is at a loss for a word.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christian looks blank.</context>
      <utterance>Decadent? Depraved?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wicked?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I meant by heaven.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still queens -- possible flush -- no help -- possible flush.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST WEALTHY TYPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Queens check to the possibles.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND WEALTHY TYPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill silently tosses in two of the rarest and highest ranking chips on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Check.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST WEALTHY TYPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fold.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And up two.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND WEALTHY TYPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fold.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD WEALTHY TYPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A phone RINGS and the Third Wealthy Type answers it.</context>
      <utterance>Biggest pot yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call the two thou.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Queen high.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack high. Can you beat that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST WEALTHY TYPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just did.</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD WEALTHY TYPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your office.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECOND WEALTHY TYPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dallas or Tulsa?</utterance>
   <speaker>THIRD WEALTHY TYPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Third Wealthy Type takes the phone and speaks on it during the ensuing. The Second Wealthy Type crosses to the bar and fixes himself a drink. Lancey takes in his winnings. Bill hasn't recovered from the blow. There is a hiatus in the game.</context>
      <utterance>She just said office.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the bloody hell did you figure out I didn't have the king or the ace?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I recollect a young fellow putting the same question to Eddie the Dude. It was a game in the grand lounge of the "J.M. White, Third," the largest paddle-wheeler ever built. "Son," Eddie told him, "All you paid was the looking price. Lessons are extra."  First time I heard of this Cincinnati Kid was in New Orleans, at Yeller's. I knew right away I'd have to play him someday.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll enjoy his game.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I may admire it. But if he's all that good, I doubt if I'll enjoy it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The tougher the competition, the better you used to like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've learned to take everything in moderation.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a drink with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better not. Shooter said they'd break at seven, and he has to have his food first, then his nap.  You know, there's a day in your life I'm looking forward to.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In my life?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at them both and goes off. They move to enter the restaurant.</context>
      <utterance>The day The Kid becomes The Man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you sleep Kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I slept okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you don't mind my not being there when you woke up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I don't mind --  What she was talking about, Shooter's woman -- I'm going up against a big game soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She told me. It's a very big game, I hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will it be long?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?  What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought --</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd go home and see Mama.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't be able to spare you much change.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I wouldn't want much. Bus is really the best way to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would a hundred fish do it? For the bus and something nice to bring your Mama?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be fine, Kid. Just fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When would you want to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She lowers her eyes, finding it hard to say the words.</context>
      <utterance>There's no reason for not going right now unless --</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless you wanted to go to bed first.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to? Would you like it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Un-huh. I'd like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want dessert?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks o.s. raising a hand to summon the check.</context>
      <utterance>Neither do I.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="44">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still haven't said it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Said what?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christian abandons the process of dressing herself and sits down in the easy chair to answer this question.</context>
      <utterance>If you're coming back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I ought to stay with Mama and Papa a while, and see.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's to see?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never did like city streets.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. The promise didn't fulfill itself for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come to the city and all. Electric lights and flush toilets. All the pretty dreams -- it was all promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know if you do or not Kid -- You're city -- and I'm country -- You grew up with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't comment one way or the other, nor does he press the point.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think that's why you're going -- because you like it so much better in the country.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What will you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I've got that big game.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard he's The Man for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. If I won, there would be a lot of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll win. You been coming on strong a long way. This is your time.  Come home with me to Mama's Kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go down to the bus with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go down with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid --</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is going to sound kind of funny to you, but I want to ask it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think there's any chance, if you do win this big game, that you might do something else besides cards?  I don't mean never play poker. I just mean not have it be the only thing you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, it's the only thing I know how to do. What else is there for a guy never finished school? College graduates are walking the streets looking for jobs -- trained people, engineers, scientists!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I realize --</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you're The Man, you don't have to hustle -- When you're The Man, The Best, the Big Money comes around on their knees just beggin' to hustle you. I'm not goin' to quit. I'm goin' to win.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I can see that. Of course I didn't say quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you see how it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christian, you aren't doing this to be off my back, in case I lose?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been thinking about it a long time. I been planning to go home and see how I felt about things.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this just helped you decide.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then don't go.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish it could be more.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't actually hand her the money. He leaves it on top of the dresser and she goes over and takes it, folding the bills and putting them in her change purse. The Kid picks up her suitcase, and she leads the way into the other room. At the front door she stops and looks back at the little apartment for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>That's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't guess I'll ever forget these rooms, Kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't guess I will either.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You going to move?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him for a moment, then exits. He follows.</context>
      <utterance>If I win, it won't be good enough. If I lose, I lose it all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Kid. Good luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They don't kiss. He turns and goes out.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Christian.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four stacks? Right, Schooter?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Shooter takes advantage of the lull in the proceedings to move to the telephone.</context>
      <utterance>Four.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancey gives him a quick look, finding this a bit thick.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you for the entertainment, gentlemen. My particular gratitude to you, Lancey. It's been a rare pleasure to watch a great artist at work. Thank you for the privilege.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill puts his check down in front of The Shooter's place, and gets to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Well now, son, you're quite welcome. Can't say I recall another man, in all my days on the three rivers, who seemed to find it quite so pleasurable losing all that money.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA MOVES with Bill as he passes The Shooter, who is waiting on the phone while the hotel operator dials his number. Bill gives him a friendly pat on the back, and speaks in a low, harsh voice for The Shooter's ears alone.</context>
      <utterance>Good day, gentlemen. You're welcome to use the premises as long as you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill goes out. Shooter looks after him as his party comes on the phone.</context>
      <utterance>I want to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Kid. Shooter here. Listen, I told the woman I'd take her to the ball park, but I'm still working. How about you and Christian take her out?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid and Melba join them.</context>
      <utterance>You owe me two fish on the out, plus three on the inning, minus two on no strikeouts so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hiya, Kid. Getting yourself in shape for The Man?  Shooter still on the job?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN'S WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Christian?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lay off that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd she do, take off? So did mine. Don't lose no sweat, Kid, there's plenty more where they came from. All shapes and sizes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Melba sit down.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Hoban. Sokal. Pig.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boyer. One to two on the sacrifice.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five to three, I'll give you. Two- fifty against one-fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figure they'll walk him. Fill up first.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>While he is talking, Melba unbuttons his shirt.</context>
      <utterance>Not with who's coming up. I'll take the same odds.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get some of this sun.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes his shirt off. Melba finds some suntan lotion in her bag, and applies it to her face and arms, her eyes rarely straying from The Kid.</context>
      <utterance>Guess I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bunting, Sokal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So they pitched to him. I still win.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody been on the phone to everybody about coming to watch you and Lancey. Big Spriigi, Yeller to N'Orleans, Old Lady Fingers. They're all coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me give you some of this. Keep you from burning.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without waiting for his approval, she goes ahead and spreads the lotion on his skin, painstakingly, as if she were applying paint to canvas, working it in, one area at a time, with her fingertips.</context>
      <utterance>Can't hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chance to invest your profits. Bet you an even fin he make first.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men concentrate their attention on the diamond. CAMERA MOVES IN to Melba's fingers playing across The Kid's midriff. From the field comes the sharp CRACK of a bat against a ball, followed by a SHOUT from the crowd. CAMERA PANS UP to the faces of Melba and The Kid as he looks at her and she meets his gaze with inviting eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Who we got -- Warwick? You got yourself a bet, pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not your day, Hoban.  Hey, beer!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mais tu es charmant --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PULLS BACK. Wearing the same clothes as at the ball park, she is sitting in a chair with her legs tucked under her. The Kid is sitting on a straight chair at a table on which he has a cup of coffee. They are alone in the apartment.</context>
      <utterance>Charmant. Come here, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any special reason?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands up but doesn't move toward her.</context>
      <utterance>Me. I'm special.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you are. You're The Shooter's woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. And maybe I'll go on being The Shooter's Woman, even after you and I have had our little romp. What do you think about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First place, Old Shooter'll come barging through that door any minute. He said they were winding it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid stays where he is as she comes up against him.</context>
      <utterance>No barging. He doesn't have his key with him.  Have to buzz from downstairs.  So we can treat ourselves to a little sample of things to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Also it don't mean anything to you, you're Christian's friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He kisses her and lets himself enjoy it for a while, then pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, she lost her franchise the minute she got on that bus. You know that.  I have a shaky sense of security, Kid. Don't make me feel unwanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No good?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know damn well how good it was. Where's a pack of cards?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we need cards for?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gin or casino, you name it. All I know is we're switching to another indoor sport.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lady Fingers'll want to come, I bet, and she's right on the edge of her stake. She could spell me dealing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure. Haven't seen the dear old bitch in fifteen years.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's it, then. Monday night, Room Three-Eleven at the Dorset Hotel. And may the best man win.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, that's how it usually comes out in the long run. You think this boy is going to give me trouble, Shooter?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, he's going to give you trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want it to be one of those marathon games. Not any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like the session with The Portugee at Jolly's in Omaha. Remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure. Longest game I ever played though, I was a kid on my way to the Klondike gold rush. At Soapy Smith's in Skagway. Four nights and three days.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You win?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends how you look at it. When we wound up, the Yukon River had frozen over and you couldn't get through to Dawson City till the following June. Made myself a Hundred and fifty bucks and missed the gold rush.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been around a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is undeniably true. But it doesn't mean I'm ready to retire. How old is this boy of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-six, twenty-eight, something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, now, makes me feel a whole lot better, knowing that. I was thirty- six when I sliced up Eddie the Dude. This Kid of yours is just going to have to wait a few years.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ought to call my woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>FELIX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA MOVES with them as The Shooter leads the way to a row of telephone booths and enters one.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course. They always like to know it if you're going to be late for supper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still building eights.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He plays an eight and takes in the whole pile.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for putting it together for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The telephone RINGS. She stands up.</context>
      <utterance>It's not my game.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA FOLLOWS her to the phone. She picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Want to know what is?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to the hook-and-eye fastener at the top of the zipper that runs down the back of her dress. The Kid pantomimes the question "What for?" but she just wiggles her finger impatiently at the fastener while speaking into the phone.</context>
      <utterance>What's the switch?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid still doesn't know what she has in mind but it seems easier to humor her than not. He unfastens the hook. Melba smiles her thanks and, to his consternation, reaches back and pulls the zipper all the way down. She places her hand over the mouth-piece of the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Whose idea was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps out of the dress.</context>
      <utterance>He's not coming home now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever you say, Shooter man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Melba --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to tell you first. You're sitting down with Lancey next Monday night.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish it was sooner. I wish it was tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shooter'll give you all the details later.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like waiting that long.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She invites a kiss and he obliges her. But there is a contrary force at work inside him.</context>
      <utterance>Let's not kick a gift horse in the teeth, sugar. We've got this time together. Let's try to "fill each unforgiving minute with sixty seconds worth of distance run."</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, what I was going to say before, I don't want you to think I'm being some kind of jerk or I don't feel you'd be great to sack up with.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then let's cut the filibuster.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've made dolls that were friends of mine's wives. I figured if they were willing, they were doing it to their husbands, I wasn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again she presses close to him and again he savors her for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. Any other attitude, you're degrading the woman. You're not treating her as a person with a mind of her own, but as somebody's property.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only thing is, it's different with The Shooter than anybody else. He's so straight, I got the obligation to be straighter with him than other people. So do you. On account of we both owe him plenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we just agreed that what you and I did was strictly between us.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't be.  Shooter's the closest thing to family I got. It's almost like he was my old man. Don't you see how that's got a bearing on us? He starts out. Melba stares after him, scarcely able to believe what is being done to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, it means I'm your mother.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shooter -- very generous of you to come on such short notice. Rosanna you know, and I think you've met my daughter June.  No point introducing you to William the Fourth. He has a bad memory for names.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Schlaegel. How are you, June. What's it all about, Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little something I'd like to sound you out on. But the least I can do is offer you a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like me to fix it, love?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wonderful. Why don't you do a batch of your Bloody Marys? If that's okay with you, Shooter?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she goes off, Rosanna cautions June about her hair.</context>
      <utterance>Great. Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSANNA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As soon as his wife is gone, Bill goes right to the topic he doesn't want to discuss in her presence.</context>
      <utterance>Just don't let it get wet again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been quite busy on the telephone since I last saw you. There's a lot of interest all over the country in this game with Lancey and The Kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Betting interest?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack Doyle in New York is giving twelve to five on Lancey. Same odds in Reno. I've taken fifty thousand of it so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty thousand!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll probably go for more but I didn't want to rock the odds.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you liked The Kid's style but why you going in so deep?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two reasons. First, I want to see that smug old bastard gutted worse than he gutted me. Second, as long as that's going to happen, I don't see why I shouldn't make some money out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But how can you be so sure? The Kid could do it, we both know that, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Could" isn't good enough for a man who hates to lose money as much as I do. He's going to need help -- from the best man with a pack of cards between Omaha and New Orleans.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not a chance, Bill. You ought to know I never ever use what I got with the cards for nothing but tricks and dressing up a game.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, I know it. That's why you're the man they choose to give them a square deal. That's what makes it so perfect. Nobody'll be looking for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's out. Out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The great thing is they'll be so close, The Kid won't need much. Three or four key hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Understand this, Bill. I'd like for The Kid to win, and I sure as hell don't want to see you lose all that money --</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I did, I'd have to collect that twelve grand you owe me. Not myself. My collection agents. You knew poor Wildwood Jones, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK but I'm paying it off! It's comin' in ain't it? Six grand already.  Bill, you got to listen to me --!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't. It's quite the other way around. You have some delusion you're a free agent, but you're not. I own you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For God's sake --!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA MOVES to include Rosanna carrying a tray with glasses and a pitcher full of Bloody Marys.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up. I'll cross the twelve off the books and give you ten thousand dollars in cash. And you can tell The Kid if he needs more of a stake, I'll put it up.  Marvelous. Here's Rosanna with what you need.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- for that dry feeling on the roof of your mouth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shine them up for you sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fetch you a newspaper maybe?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about a singy-song then? I play good.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Boy takes out a tobacco can with the lid torn off and the top flattened down and shakes it, producing a sound like the rustle of dry leaves. Then he produces a similar can that makes a rattling noise when he shakes it.</context>
      <utterance>Play what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dry corn in this one. Blue shale stone from the river in this one. You ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Boy looks at the BARTENDER, who has moved closer to see what's going on.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Boy stands perfectly still for a few seconds, then begins to shake the can with corn in it. After a bit he brings in the shale stone can with the other hand to chord and accent the rustle of the first can. At the same time he begins to sing a simple song in a pure, delicate voice. It is catfish music created on the spot and sounds strangely like the idle tunes Christian likes to hum.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, I'm ready for anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you very much. That was nice. Where did you learn to do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I picked it up from Herman.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is Herman?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My friend I pick it up from.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he a good friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know 'bout that suh. He just a frien' who teach me some things.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't want a shine, but here's fifteen cents.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rings up a NO SALE and flips a dime to The Boy, who is astonished and then worried by this munificence. Suddenly he grabs his tobacco cans and his shoe-shine kit, and runs out into the street.</context>
      <utterance>And here's another dime for you, fella.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice little colored kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monday night, uh, Kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monday night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sprung for some of the action. A yard and a half of that five-to-two.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Jansen.  Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>JANSEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got to get you loosened up. I never felt you this tight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell The Shooter I'll be there on the dot Monday night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And until then?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't have to know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you with those?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns toward the side of the house and walks to the kitchen door. The Kid follows.</context>
      <utterance>Taking if off is harder than taking it on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's The Shooter?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't played yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Monday.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Eric, Mama. He's come to see me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christian crosses to the drain sink near the pump and turns her back. Mrs. Craigie lifts the cans off the yoke on to the drain board. She and Christian each take a can and pour the water from it to prime the pump.</context>
      <utterance>How do, Eric.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid looks at the stove with a couple of large steaming pots on it, and the table alongside with a half-dozen hampers of green beans.</context>
      <utterance>We lost suction on the pump right in the middle of canning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As soon as they are finished with the pump, Mrs. Craigie and Christian turn to the table, where they begin to snip stems and cut beans before putting them into the pots on the stove.</context>
      <utterance>There's coffee. And sour ham and bread in the warmer, if you're hungry Eric.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know anything about canning, you know we can't stop now. If we'd been looking for company, we never would have started.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spring beans, you have to cook them fast. But you find yourself some breakfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm all right. Bus stopped for doughnuts and coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can stay with us tonight and still make it back to St. Lou on the Sunday schedule by about midnight. I told Mama and Papa about The Man. And all.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is Mr. Craigie?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the barn. Why don't you go down and introduce yourself? Christian and me'll be at this another hour or two.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I will. I think I'd like that.  Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid looks quickly at her and then at Mrs. Craigie, who keeps her gaze fixed on the beans.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. And I'll see you a little later on.  Papa don't know everything. About you and me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="64">
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do, Mr. Craigie. I'm Eric Stoner.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christian's Eric.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seen her?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's helping her mother can.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid looks at him a long moment then --</context>
      <utterance>You minding to marry Christian?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craigie takes a couple of steps toward The Kid, his boots sucking in the muddy ground.</context>
      <utterance>You got any objections if I do, or if I don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son, that's what I call a sharp answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was what I call a sharp question.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't know much about you, Christian's mother and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm what's known as a three-river man. Which just means I go around playing stud poker wherever I can find the kind of action I'm looking for.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You met Christian when she was working to Hot Springs?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I was playing in this game in the hotel and she was a waitress in the coffee shop. We went out. I told her I thought she could get a better job in St. Louis.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now how did you happen to tell her that? Maybe you run some kind of employment service on the side?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said it because I wanted her in St. Louis. Anyway, she made it there and she called me and we been seeing each other ever since.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid takes his time before deciding how to answer this one.</context>
      <utterance>Living together?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, living together.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come she come home now? She going to have a baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that I know of.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two have a fight?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She must have had a reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think so? Well, you've known her longer than me.  Look, Mr. Craigie, let me and Christian find out a few things then maybe I won't have to answer your questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never run across anybody like you. I guess I don't understand gamblers.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all right. I don't understand farmers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You say things that sound smart alecky. But I'm not sure if they really are smart alecky.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I can't take into account what somebody's going to feel every time I say something.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a believer?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In some things.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean in God.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a tough one. I don't disbelieve in Him, but I couldn't say I believed in Him either. I guess I just never paid Him much mind. Didn't seem important.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God not important?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean what He does isn't important -- if He exists. I mean it's not important to me whether He exists or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christian was raised in a Christian home.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that so? I didn't know ---  I'm not aware of the difference.  I'm not asking permission to marry Christian, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I was, the only person I'd be asking it from is her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is this fella Christian says you're going to play that's so important?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the king of the stud poker players.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're going to play him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you any good?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm this good. The Man has got to play me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens if he don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I'm The Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That important to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been trying to figure that out ever since I set it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You playing because of money?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christian said you never was much worried about money -- I been worried about money most of my life -- up until I figured out it wasn't so important.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's necessary, but it isn't so important.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well how come you want to play this King fella?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ambition -- maybe security, like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it aspiration to be the King or just uncertainty about the future?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ain't looking for security if that's what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not trying to lock something up tight and nail it down?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would figure into it. But that isn't all of it. -- It's important to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now son which is more important to you, this king business or Christian?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craigie has finished piling the manure. He puts away his shovel.</context>
      <utterance>If you got the guts to ask that question, Mr. Craigie, I guess I got the guts to answer it. Christian, if you came right down to it, is not as important as doing what I have to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well son, I had to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There never was a man worth a damn, to my mind, who let his woman stand in the way of the thing he had to do.  I got to go now -- see what I can do for a sick heifer. Why don't you take Christian, when her Mama lets go of her, and tell her I said you should go to the old spring. It's a good place.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craigie walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. I'll tell her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Papa's mama used to bring her wash up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We liable to draw an audience?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to swim, CAMERA MOVING with her upper back as she reaches the side of the pool and pulls herself on to the bank, lying on her stomach. The Kid joins her, first drawing himself up on his stomach alongside her, then turning on his back to look through the slats at the sun.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. It's on our land -- Nobody uses it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must have said something to Papa gave him the picture on us in St. Lou. Else he never would have spoke to you about this place.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told him on account of he already knew. Never any sense feeding a man a lie he's not going to believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raises herself up so that she is directly above him.</context>
      <utterance>Even if he did know, I'm glad you told him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, you're all wet!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are you, foolish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid stands up and selects six playing cards from a deck in his pocket. During the next few lines he uses the paste on the shelf to stick together three pairs of them so as to form three double-thick cards. One of these has two faces, another two backs, and the third a back and a face.</context>
      <utterance>Let me get this straight in my head. Cards is all a matter of luck, who gets dealt the best ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So when one of you professional gamblers sits down with a bunch of your -- what do you call them -- customers, clients?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The technical term is "suckers." Or "marks."</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their chance of winning is just as good as yours, except if you got a way to control it, who gets what cards. Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not right. That's cheating and it's not any part of what we're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then how do you win?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He displays his three cards.</context>
      <utterance>I'll show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see one of these cards is white on both sides, one is red on both sides, and the other is white on one side, red on the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid lifts a straw hat off a peg on the porch wall.</context>
      <utterance>What about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Craigie does as instructed. The ensuing dialogue assumes the card he picks is red on top; if it's white the words "red" and "white" will be reversed in the dialogue.</context>
      <utterance>This. I put the three cards in a hat and shake them up, and then I ask you to draw one card out blind. Put it face down on the table so neither of us can see the bottom side.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, red on top. That eliminates the all-white card, right. So the card you've picked is one of two -- the all-red or the red-and-white. One out of two is an even chance, an even-money proposition. Right -- you follow me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So if I said I'll bet you a dollar to seventy-five cents the other side of that card is red, you'd take the bet wouldn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems like. Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that answer makes you a sucker. Because the odds are two to one, the other side of that card is red, and I ought to be offering you a dollar to fifty cents instead of seventy- five.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if there are just the two possibilities.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are three possibilities.  That can be the red side of the red- and-white card, or it can be either side of the all-red card. In two cases out of three the other side is red. And I'd win the bet from you two out of every three times we made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You would?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. It's obvious when I explain it, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reckon so. Except if there's only two things that the bottom side can be, red or white --</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take my word for it -- the odds are two to one. And knowing that is the difference between your gambling man and your sucker. Not who gets the better cards but who knows what the proper odds are. In a poker game there can be a million different situations, each with a different set of odds to figure. The man who ends up winners is the man who knows when to bet and how much...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sucker is still took advantage of, isn't he? The gambler knows something he don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure -- like if you grow better corn or raise a cow that gives more milk than the other guy's. Or two business men are in competition, or two lawyers are up against each other in a courtroom. Whatever your line is, the one who wins out is the one who knows his job better.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAIGIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems like there should be something else to it --</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is -- Making the man you're playing against think he's got the best hand -- and making him pay to find out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't stay long. Papa'll be getting up to milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the one can't stay. I got to head for that bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you come, Kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hell, I don't know. I had kind of a rough time after you left.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rough how?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tuesday there was a ball game, but then the Cardinals went on the road. I never known time to drag so; I was all torn apart --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because of the poker game coming up?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's how I read it, but I was reading it wrong. It wasn't Lancey or the game that was chewing at my insides --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else is there could give you such a bad time?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is genuinely surprised at this and at first a bit dismayed. But her more considered reaction is one of pleasure.</context>
      <utterance>I finally figured it. I located where the trouble was. It was you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, -- She kisses him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you talk about doing something besides poker if I get to be The Man, you don't mean pass up the chance to make some dough from it for a while?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sure don't. I told Papa, wherever money comes from, it feels the same when you spend it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were going to do some thinking down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then they both react as Craigie can be heard getting up.</context>
      <utterance>I done some.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be back after the game Christian -- You wait here for me and I'll let you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a quick kiss and stands up.</context>
      <utterance>All right Eric -- Good luck Monday.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got that made now. You said it right. My time's come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-five years I been building a reputation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Handle this thing right and your reputation will be better than ever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made up my mind to this. I ain't going to give him any help till he needs it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you're taking a stand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what if he starts off lucky and stays ahead of the game the whole way. It could happen, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll make it happen, Baby. I've got faith in you --</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Once more around the square.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA MOVES to take in the people around him, one after another. The Shooter is there, and Pig and Sokal and Hoban, and Melba and Hoban's woman and a couple of other women whose main attributes are physical, and Bill Schlaegel. Out of town representatives include LADY FINGERS, who is about fifty, down on her luck but still cheerful and remarkably energetic; and YELLER, a light-skinned Negro who has achieved stature in what is mainly a white man's world, through diplomacy and a quick wit. The room is the large living-room of a once splendid suite; there are enough chairs and couches around the walls to accommodate a good many spectators, while the middle of the room has been cleared for a round table with seven chairs.</context>
      <utterance>It's a friendly town, St. Louis. I've always said that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ain't seen much of you though, last seven, eight years.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Climate, Shooter. In my declining years, I spend more and more time in Florida and the Gulf Coast.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lot of folks been figuring another reason you was keeping clear of the three rivers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What reason is that, Lady Fingers?</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cincinnati Kid.  That the way it is, Lancey? You been scared of The Kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I be scared of him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn right you should! I'm telling you, that boy going to make your stomach ulcer bleed before the night is out. He's close to murder. I seen him give a fella the shakes so bad on a fourth card, it took a pint of corn liquor to settle him down.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancey notices that most of the people around him have turned to look at the doorway. He glances in the same direction in a casual sort of way.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the warning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mow the man down, sugar pie, make it quick and bloody. Been too many lean years for all of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I intend to take Shooter right along with Lancey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid would like these cryptic words explained, but Lady Fingers descends on him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not talking about the old Shooter. He's been factory rebuilt. A new spirit dwelleth in him, and his gaze is on distant hills.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you showed up after all. You're a braver boy than I thought, so much the worse for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'll be sorry I come?</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid sees Lancey approaching, and turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>Bound to. That Lancey ain't human, he's one of them barracuda fish. He's liable to bleed to death, right on a flush hand before he give up to you. I seen him gut a fella so bad, the fella quit and got up and spit red in the john and went square.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Kid. Pleasure to know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lancey. I been looking forward a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure. You seem to know about everybody. Yeller from New Orleans?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you say, Yeller? Still feeling salty with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgiven long since.  We had a little jurisdictional dispute.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hustled a couple of boys, right in his territory.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I tried to tell him our rules down there. Colored marks are for colored hustlers.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I tried to tell him how I got no prejudice. When I'm on the edge of my stake, I hustle anybody at all, regardless of race, creed or color. Anybody at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Including my girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, I figured I was doin' you a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly they both laugh over a private memory and shake hands, obviously old friends.</context>
      <utterance>You did.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know Old Cottonhead died?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I hadn't heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heart give out in a high-low game.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you feel, Kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. You?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The best. You think maybe we ought to see if we can stir up some action?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever you say, Lancey. You're the --  You're our guest in this town.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm kind of in the mood to play a little cards.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we ought to be able to get a game together in this crowd.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But first you take a look at things -- make sure everything's the way you want it. I already been around.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns toward the center of the room. The Shooter follows him.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. I'll do that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's an old table. Everything's pretty old in this hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancey comes into the SHOT behind them.</context>
      <utterance>It's solid, that's what counts. And you got the top fixed perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Light all right for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two hundred watt bulb.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, excellent. Okay with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure. Shooter's set us up just great.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure has.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, gents. Tried to do the best I could.  Cards?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good a time as any.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You both know Joe Hoban. He's a draw poker man, but clean and straight as they come. Hoban comes into the SHOT with a dispatch case, which he sets on the table. He unlocks it with a key and turns it upside down. Thirty sealed decks of cards spill on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Hoban! Okay!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They come from the St. Louis Bridge Club, but they're poker size cards. They been bonded by the club steward and I seen him take them out of the safe. Shooter, Lady Fingers and me pick them up and come straight here with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hoban's selling them to us at five dollars a pack, with the usual guarantee. If it's proved any deck is spooked, he pays off the losers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>St. Louis Bridge Club, eh? Steward still that old yard bird Okra?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old stud man, Okra.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite a character. Quite a character.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been ten years since I seen or spoke to Old Okra.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Kay, fine. Don't worry about it, Lancey. Who's sitting down with us, Shooter?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four of us. Me, Pig, Yeller and Doc Sokal. If that's all right with you both?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Kay, fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure.  Shall we have a look at the decks?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PULLS BACK to include the other four players, who have come up to the table, still not taking chairs until Lancey and The Kid have chosen theirs. Though Lancey's question is purely ritualistic, they look to The Kid for his reply.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Kid, what's your game?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mind stud poker if that's okay with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Consulting the others is a formality, but all four of them -- Yeller, Shooter, Pig and Sokal -- nod or grunt or otherwise indicate assent.</context>
      <utterance>I got no objections to stud.  Gentlemen?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell The Kid I have a suite on the fifth floor. He can drop up during the breaks. Bedroom all for him any time he wants a nap.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's thoughtful of you, Bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a thoughtful man. I hope you are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid, following protocol, moves to a seat directly across from Lancey's. The Shooter takes his place at the table halfway between The Kid and Lancey, and pulls the twenty- five eligible packs of cards to him.</context>
      <utterance>Privilege of age. Can't take the glare of the morning sun in my eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to have the usual brandy and coffee on hand, Kid? Anything special for you, Lancey?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, yes, Shooter. Creme de menthe frappe. Green.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got that, Hoban?  Gentlemen, if there are no objections, I'm the dealer. These rooms have been contracted for, and there will be an ante of ten dollars per chair, per day. During the breaks for me, Old Lady Fingers has agreed to deal, but she don't care to be a player --</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS to reveal Lady Fingers as she steps from among the spectators to a place behind Lancey.</context>
      <utterance>Do too care!</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't afford to play, that's the real truth. Had a bad year and I'm way over my edge.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lady Fingers will get three dollars an hour from the ante, plus her room and food, and a five-minute break every hour. Gents?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, Shooter man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Kay with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't see me when you need me, call room three-oh-eight.  You know who else ain't with us no more? Miriam, widow used to run the kitchen game to South Chi. Lost two month's Relief at blackjack, coal dealer cut her credit, and she froze in her bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid has completed his count.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, this is a game of five- card stud poker. There is no limit. A dead man has one half hour to raise his roll outside and get back in the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>REVERSE ANGLE - FEATURING LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He takes the money from his satchel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS to Yeller.</context>
      <utterance>Five grand? Nice, tidy sum. I'll put out the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS to Pig as he brings out a roll and drops it casually in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>I swear I don't know what I'm doing sitting down with you titans, but maybe it's worth putting up five thousand for the educational value.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS past The Kid to Sokal, who is counting out bills from an impressive roll.</context>
      <utterance>I'll play with what I have in my pocket till I have to send out for more. Twenty-seven, twenty-eight hundred, I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS to The Shooter, who is counting out a smaller stake than anyone.</context>
      <utterance>Five G's, I'm with it. Don't mean I'm goin' blow it all, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his money out without counting it, takes a deck of cards, rips the cellophane off it, takes the jokers and tosses them offhandedly to one side, not seeming to take aim.</context>
      <utterance>Last and certainly least --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven, nine, trey, nine, ace, and The Shooter guns up a ten. Ace bets.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dealer folds.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call the sawbuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE SHOT - FROM BEHIND KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks at his hole card: an ace.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POKER TABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Shooter deals again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>King to the seven, pair of nines, deuce to the trey, queen-nine, ace- eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Each other player folds in turn. The Shooter pulls in the cards, and The Kid pulls in the seventy dollars. The Shooter shuffles and deals again.</context>
      <utterance>Nines bet twenty bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Queen, ten, king, four, ace again, and a king for The Shooter.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ace bets ten dollars</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>King over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shooter won't stay on a king or an ace if there's another one showing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he have to have in the hole?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten or better. With no other ten showing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aces over eights.  Thank you, gents.  Be a laugh if the two champs ended up cleaned.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE SHOT - LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He barely notices Pig's remark.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any action?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you expect first five or six hours?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still feeling each other out?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pig's ahead about a grand, Shooter maybe three hundred.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SHOOTER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PULLS BACK to show the players. There is less oral accompaniment to the betting now.</context>
      <utterance>King bets.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancey calls, Shooter drops, Sokal calls, The Kid drops.</context>
      <utterance>King says twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In for twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the nine a ten, to the queen a seven, to the king a jack, and to the jack a jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pair of jacks will venture a hundred dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up two hundred dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave it to the rich folk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lancey could be laying for him with three jacks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pig don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call the two hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POKER TABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lancey puts in his money and so does Sokal.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sticking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Possible straight flush, pair of sevens. Pair of jacks are still high.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check to the sevens.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Likewise.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bet the size of the pot. Nine hundred and eighty dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In for nine eighty.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll play.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with Lancey? I thought he'd raise with three jacks or drop with two pair.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He probably thinks Pig's faking the queens. Anyhow, Doc's liable take them both with a straight or a flush.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Busted, no flush, no straight. Pair of sevens with a queen gets a nine. To the pair of jacks, a trey.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pair of sevens will bet whatever I got here. Twenty-four hundred bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call your twenty-four hundred --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes are on Pig, which doesn't make it any easier for him. He just sits there, his hands shaking.</context>
      <utterance>Comes to fourteen hundred fifty dollars, Pig. Don't imagine you'll have any problem promoting that much in half an hour -- plus whatever you care to raise me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is another long moment before Pig flips over his up cards.</context>
      <utterance>Fourteen fifty to the queens. You want to take your half hour, Pig?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Lancey with malevolence. Lancey turns over his up cards and tosses them in front of The Shooter. Pig suddenly lunges toward the cards, wanting a look at Lancey's hole card, but Lancey is too quick for him and pushes the cards into the pack The Shooter is assembling.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm out. Out of the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pig is suffering, weighing the advantages and disadvantages of making the dread admission. Finally he nods. The Shooter takes a ten dollar bill from his own stake, and the other four remaining players each add a ten. The Shooter pushes the money toward Pig.</context>
      <utterance>You Tap City?</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you and Hilda were quits.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other players look at The Shooter to see if he is going to accept this statement at face value. He nods, that he does, and each man contributes another ten. The Shooter passes the second fifty to Pig.</context>
      <utterance>We're back.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you around, Pig.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So long, Pig -- See you -- 'Night.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA FOLLOWS him to the door. The spectators make room for him, no one saying anything. At the door, Pig turns back for his valedictory gesture.</context>
      <utterance>So long.</utterance>
   <speaker>PIG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes out.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck -- Kid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He shouldn't have said that. Not after taking Tap City from the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His woman's been giving him a rough time. Wants him to quit and go square.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At his age? Crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wants to wish anybody luck, doesn't bother me. Personally, I don't figure The Kid needs it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that, the tension is gone. But just to make sure, The Shooter pushes his chair back.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Lancey.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it's early, men, but what about taking a little break?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="48">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It always distresses me, a man reaching his middle years and still having no assurance of next week's income.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Shooter's gaze wanders o.s. CAMERA MOVES to FEATURE the objects of his attention, who are Lady Fingers, Lancey and The Kid. The two men would like to talk to each other, but Lady Finger's is monopolizing Lancey, and he doesn't want to offend her.</context>
      <utterance>I know what you mean. I like a man to have plenty of assurance.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spider Man died kind of slow. First he give them a kidney, then his gall bladder, and then they taking his whole damn stomach. You remember Spider Man, run the dice table down at Turk's Club to Memphis.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who? Oh, Spider Man, sure, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Shooter comes to Lancey's rescue.</context>
      <utterance>He died kind of slow.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He whisks her away. Lancey and The Kid, finally facing each other alone, don't quite know how to begin.</context>
      <utterance>Need your help, Lady Fingers... to make arrangements for food and shelter.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good crowd.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Nice-looking broads.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a pretty thing to watch what you done to Pig with those jacks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Kid. From you, that's nice to hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When he bet out first, he was ready to think you had them back to back. Even when he bet the size of the pot, he figured there was still a chance you were laying for him. But when you called him, I could see it in his eyes he thought you had jacks and tens, and I knew you had him hooked.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew, did you? Before I raised?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancey is a bit taken aback by The Kid's confident assertion, but he manages a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, sure, I seen what you were pulling all along.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been to Miami, Kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beautiful town, lot of loose money around. You ought to come down some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure. Lot of room down there. Another spot you ought to work someday is Reno, Nevada.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got to have nerves though. So much going on. Action everywhere you turn. You lose the feel of the cards when you're in so much action day in, day out.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to make it out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's different levels of action there -- you'd find yours, any kind you could ask for.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I generally stick to stud.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, sure, for eating money. But you know how it is, I like to lay off once in a while and try craps. Nothing serious -- I don't even think of it as work.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I do that. I'll take a night off and shoot a little casino. Or even blackjack.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your age, you don't need a regular vacation every year. But me, I have to forget the grind for a couple of weeks. I go to this place near Delray Beach, and the whole time I don't play anything but bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's interesting. I could go for bridge if there was a way to do it without partners.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not keeping you from your woman, am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. We're -- she's gone away for a while. We're not sure we're looking for the same thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to hear that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was hoping Christian would run with me and wouldn't try to make a big deal out of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But she tried?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, and now I don't know. I don't figure a man can change his way because the way I see it a man's lucky he's got something going for him that he can hold on to. A man can't change his way for a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nooo, a man can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I been wondering if it isn't maybe a better idea not to look for a fixed thing. Just tie in to something nice when you're away from the action, and enjoy it, and let it wear itself out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's very interesting you should say that. You're pretty young to have figured things out already.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well she didn't understand how it was with me and ---</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Between us?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There ain't but a few people, I guess who would understand --</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid, you're the best stud man I've seen in 35 years of action. You know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well -- thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when it comes to broads, which is getting to be an academic problem -- I can look back now to the two or three I ever considered I might want to spend the rest of my life with, and you know what? I like it... looking back on them, that is --  I always got a lot of companionship out of a good book.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's very educational, hearing what it's like for a man your age.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad to be of help. And it's good we had this little talk so I know we can be friends regardless what happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds good to me. I didn't think you was coming in at me like a grudge match.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No room for any kind of emotion in a fair game of stud. I learned that a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS' VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They look at each other and then exit.</context>
      <utterance>Ready for some action, gentlemen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a whole New Deal. Good hands all around. Prosperity for everybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're still good, Fingers.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Getting crippled up, Lancey. Not many of the old gang left. You heard Whistling Sam was gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was the one got called to the morgue to identify him. I don't suppose you seen anybody been run over by a twelve- ton bulldozer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, can't say that I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go out of your way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bet the pot. Four hundred and twenty dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fold.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, gents. Makes me exactly even. This kind of a game, that's a smart place to quit.  Just do the dealing, if that's all right with everybody.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ace-king is the high man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot the works.  Nine hundred and thirty bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm over.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have you got?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't matter. If you can call me, you beat me. Ace-king high.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ace-king-queen high.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had them both with a pair of fives.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOKAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Winds it up for me, men. And I can't say it's been a pleasure.  That one I was sure I could steal.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yeller pulls in the money in front of him. There is now about $19,500 left on the table, $11,500 in front of Lancey, $8,000 in front of The Kid.</context>
      <utterance>Lancey has a built-in burglar alarm. I'm also withdrawing from the field of battle, gentlemen. Settle for the seventeen hundred I've already dropped.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, just the two of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, just the two of us. Deal them, Shooter Man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cost you a grand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid turns up a jack and pulls in the money.</context>
      <utterance>Compulsory call, Kid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two pair, jacks up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes in the money.</context>
      <utterance>Kings up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid lifts his hole card and we see it is a ten.</context>
      <utterance>Two thousand dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to watch The Shooter.</context>
      <utterance>Call two thousand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He exits. After a moment The Shooter follows. Lancey watches them go then rises, apparently still fresh and strong. Lady Fingers joins him.</context>
      <utterance>Take it. I can't beat three sevens.  I'd like a break to get some food and sleep -- I'm winners so it isn't up to me to say it but I'm saying it anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dear, that young man is a stud poker-playing son-of-a-bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancey looks at her a moment, then smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Gettin' to you, Lancey?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves through the crowd, then exits.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet he isn't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, just what the hell are you trying to pull?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid grabs him and slams him against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing -- what are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, Shooter Man -- you been feeding me cards for an hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell I was.  Christ, Kid, even if I was you couldn't spot it -- I'm too good a mechanic for anybody to spot it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I was looking for it, Shooter -- four times you give me the cards I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seen it before often enough. One player draws four good ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never in a game when I been told ahead the dealer has a stake in my coming out on top.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My woman told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She told me enough to make me start thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should you bitch if I give you a little help?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, you dumb bastard? -- You have to ask me why.  I could break you apart for what you've done.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kid, you got to understand. It wasn't my idea --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well who the hell's was it then -- Schlaegel? --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got the squeeze on me Kid and he's meaner than hell. He'll cut me up if I don't come through.  You think I wanted to deal a phony game? You think it don't mean something to me? I never done a crooked thing before in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My ass bleeds for you -- Now you get straight on this. No fix. You come along straight or I blow it wide open.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's liable to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ain't goin' to do nothin' to you except pay off because I'm goin' to win.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is a hell of a chance to take.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ain't goin' to like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ain't goin' to know.  Shooter, I'm goin' to win this one -- win it my way -- and you ride with me or you're out, finished.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ride with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shooter looks at him, then moves towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>You better not forget it -- now beat it. I need some sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Shooter goes out. The Kid crosses to the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Tell Mr. Schlaegel I accept his offer to use the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be called at 4 p.m. on the nose. For sure -- Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He awakens in considerable confusion. Melba is amused by his difficulty in adjusting to his circumstances.</context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon, sir. It's exactly four o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really only about twenty-five to four. You can stay right where you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you to think I'm getting too personal, but you mind telling me how the hell you come to be here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean you don't remember last night? We drank all that champagne and you said "Let's get married right away," and we chartered a plane to --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can it --  Where's Shooter?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I locked the door. It's incredible the way you invariably worry about The Shooter.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's incredible the way you invariably don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worrying takes time and we don't have a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're supposed to sit down again at half past four.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does it really matter so much to you now, that sense of obligation to The Shooter?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got no obligations to The Shooter.  Or to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obligations are not what I have in mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Melba, who is dressed again and applying her lipstick, comes into the SHOT, takes a towel from a rack and hands it to him after he opens the shower door. He gives himself a quick once-over with it, the secures it around his waist, steps out of the shower stall, and begins the process of shaving. Melba meanwhile finishes restoring her makeup.</context>
      <utterance>Reach me a towel?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You any idea how much The Shooter has involved in this game of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Schlaegel bet as much on me as I heard, I guess he'd pay a nice piece of change to be sure I won.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid stops shaving and looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>It's worse than that. Schlaegel staked him for three years. He has his hooks so deep in Shooter Man, he'll take out his liver when he pulls them out.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You asking me to go along with the fix?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm asking you to consider whether your ego is worth destroying another man's whole life.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're still working for him. On my time you're still working for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of switch is this? You criticize me for trying to chippie on him, then I get a little loyal and you're at me for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a KNOCK on the door.</context>
      <utterance>No -- I don't hold it against you. You wanting to make things right for him -- but this game I handle my way -- win, lose, or draw.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA PANS to take in the view of the bedroom as she crosses it to the door, talking as she goes.</context>
      <utterance>Rolls and coffee for the hard-headed hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has paused at the door to finish her sentence. Now she unlocks and opens it -- to Christian. Melba is so taken aback she can't do anything but stand there holding the door open. The Kid, in the bathroom in f.g., is similarly frozen in his tracks. After a moment Christian advances into the room.</context>
      <utterance>Believe me Kid there is too much at stake for us to rely on your doing it on your own.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Kid. Hello, Melba.  You said wait home 'til you let me know.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's what I said. We took a break in the game to catch some sleep. Shooter sent his woman up here to wake me up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I woke him up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It don't take much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I didn't find it any trouble.  Well, you children don't need me, that's for sure. See you downstairs.  You, too, honey, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be around if The Kid wants me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you, Melba. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks past CAMERA and a moment later comes the SOUND of the door closing behind her. The Kid, who has moved into the bedroom, crosses to his clothes on a chair, and picks up his undershorts and trousers. He returns to the bathroom, using the door for partial concealment as he removes his towel and puts on his shorts and trousers.</context>
      <utterance>Por nada, as they say. It was nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been to the place?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I've got my bag downstairs. Maybe I'll take it over later on tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's your Mama and Papa?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid fastens his trousers and returns to the basin to give his face a last few strokes with the razor and wash off the soap.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. How's the game going?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He comes back into the bedroom to finish dressing. As his movement brings him fairly close to Christian, he realizes he hasn't kissed her, and repairs the omission before putting his shirt on.</context>
      <utterance>It's come to be just me and Lancey.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was wondering.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got my mind on the cards.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To The Kid preoccupied by the game and the fix, feeling both affection and guilt. The idea that she can be any use to him against Lancey is one he can't grasp.</context>
      <utterance>I know. And I don't want to rattle you. We got plenty to talk about, but it can all wait. Except I want to say this. I came back because I figured if it was going to work with us, it's silly me sitting home with Mama while you're playing your big game. I mean if I'm any use to you at all, this is when it's most important.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you came, Christian. You got as much right here as anybody.  More right, I should have said.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, yes. The change I come out with when I win this one, you're going to be the one to spend it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eric --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him. After a moment he exits. She follows.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I said I'm glad you came -- and that's all until I wrap this up -- I'm a poker player, remember?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The eight'll try two bills.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lady Fingers scoops up the cards, shuffles them into the rest of the deck, submits it to Lancey for his cut, and deals them another two cards apiece -- all in the space of seconds. The Kid gets a queen, Lancey a nine.</context>
      <utterance>No stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No stay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA MOVES on PAST a window, showing it is night outside; past a group of other spectators; past Bill, Shooter and Melba who watch the game grimly; and finally to the table, where The Shooter is dealing again. The Kid is down to his undershirt, and even Lancey has made a few concessions to comfort. The players have just been dealt their third cards. Christian moves up to stand behind The Kid.</context>
      <utterance>Naaa, Kid paired kings. He wins a hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Queen bets another C-note.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at Christian.</context>
      <utterance>Take it away.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates. Then moves away. Lancey watches this.</context>
      <utterance>Go read a magazine, honey.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I break.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I don't either.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lady Fingers puts down the deck. Picks up a new one.</context>
      <utterance>Deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same deck is good enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want a new deck.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, alright -- A new deck then, Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lady Fingers looks at the two men for a long moment. Puts the cards down.</context>
      <utterance>Deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and stalks off. Lancey and The Kid look at each other for a moment, then both grin.</context>
      <utterance>You want to deal? Then deal them yourselves. I'm going to the john. I'm going to get something to eat, and I'm going to take a nap. You barracudas can snap all you want but at each other -- I'm taking a break and if you don't like it you can both go to hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess we been told.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See you in about 3/4 of an hour, Lancey, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make it an hour. Old bones need a little more time to loosen up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eric --</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your fan on the fifth floor wants you to have a bite with him. Alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing to talk about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christian scans both their faces as they talk... concerned.</context>
      <utterance>You better, Kid. You don't, you're only making worse trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you think so.  Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads for the door. Christian looks after him.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing, Nothing you have to worry about. I'll see you later.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get something to eat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to Felix, indicating a wine bottle on the table. Felix steps over and refills The Kid's glass.</context>
      <utterance>I thought it would be better if you and I sat down together to see if we couldn't work out our differences. Felix!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I told The Shooter goes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid just looks at him -- then returns to his meal.</context>
      <utterance>Are you saying no before we've even discussed it? Am I to feel all my arguments will be wasted?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes a peremptory gesture to Felix, who springs forward to offer the salad bowl to The Kid.</context>
      <utterance>I'll skip to the final argument.  More salad, perhaps?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Shooter will be back dealing when you start again. He will give you an occasional helpful card.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's an argument?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a fact. I'm coming to the argument.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll give you a fact. I won't let it happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Felix jumps into action again. He moves to The Kid's side, reaches into a breast pocket and takes out a switch blade, which he clocks open an inch or two from The Kid's neck. It is an extremely ugly-looking and menacing weapon.</context>
      <utterance>Is that knife sharp enough? Felix.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Felix hands the knife to The Kid, who tries it on his steak.</context>
      <utterance>See if it cuts better with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sharp?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jams the knife in the table and snaps off the blade.</context>
      <utterance>Very. But it don't cut any ice with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not this time. He exits.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not, for Chris sakes?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eric --</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should eat something.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops, looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>I've got to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's -- about us. What's going to happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going to happen? What's going to happen for Chris sake is I'm going to win the game.  You go back to the apartment, honey, this might take two more days.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I go, I'm not going back to the apartment. If I go -- I'm just going.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Shooter's not well. He didn't want to spoil the game, but he ought to be resting... He ought to be in the hospital.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we got Lady Fingers. Or we can deal ourselves.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay. What The Kid's talking about is nothing. It's just not important.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancey looks from The Kid to The Shooter, sensing that there may be something more behind this, but not knowing just what.</context>
      <utterance>It is to me... You want to kill yourself, do it on your own time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got to go along with that, Shooter. Lady Fingers! You ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE SHOT - LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rising from her chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like Eddie the Dude said on his deathbed, I'm as ready as I'll ever be.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid turns up the jack of clubs.</context>
      <utterance>I can't persuade myself you have the flush.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid pulls in the money.</context>
      <utterance>Now I can.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LANCEY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The kid turns up another nine and reaches for the money.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to pay the price to look at that third nine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Caveat emptor. New deck, please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten bucks and my notoriously fallible instinct tells me the boy is bluffing this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA MOVES to the other four remaining spectators: Christian, Melba, The Shooter and Bill. They are close enough to see the cards but too close to discuss them.</context>
      <utterance>Mark it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA MOVES to the other four spectators as they react to The Kid's successful streak.</context>
      <utterance>The Kid is pushing it and making it stick.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And it looks that way. Lancey appears old and unsure. The Kid sharp and cold. A young barracuda moving in for the kill. CAMERA MOVES in close to Christian as she tries to catch The Kid's eye. Thinking she has it, she smiles her encouragement.</context>
      <utterance>He's getting to him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And up five.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fold.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA MOVES in close enough for us to see the cards. Lancey has the jack of hearts, The Kid the ten of clubs.</context>
      <utterance>A jack and a ten. Jack bets.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid takes his first look at his hole card.</context>
      <utterance>Jack is willing to wager two hundred dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancey looks at him a long moment. His face pale and shaken. The Kid is beating him. Pushing -- buying -- always pressing and Lancey knows he is losing one hand at a time, not badly but consistently and inevitably. His age and fatigue are a strong handicap for the long pull. Then his face settles as if he had come to a decision. He smiles lightly summoning some last reserve of strength, almost as if he knows this will be the last hand, win or lose.</context>
      <utterance>And up five hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call your five hundred and five hundred more.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty to one hundred says Lancey paired his jacks.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pair of tens. Jack, ten of hearts.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The raise is a surprise. The Kid's eyes go up to study Lancey's face, even though he knows what a futile effort that is.</context>
      <utterance>Your five hundred -- and up one thousand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty to seventy-five he's got the jacks wired.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mark it -- Could be a high heart. Queen's the best, but that old man can be cocky with an ace or a deuce. 'Specially having one of The Kid's tens.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One thousand to the tens.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A third ten, and a nine of hearts to the ten, jack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll run. He's beat on the board anyway you look at it. Even if he has the jacks it is better than eight to one against improving.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He won't run and I don't think he's got the jacks. I think he's going for the flush.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lancey looks at him, then at the cards. The moment stretches.</context>
      <utterance>Two thousand, five hundred dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reasonable bet. Two thousand five hundred.  Deal them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going for it and The Kid's got him. He's going all the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid checks the amount of money in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>A queen of diamonds to the three tens.  And an eight of hearts to the possible flush. Possible straight flush. Three tens bet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOBAN AND YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They each take a quick turn with the binoculars.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOBAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If The Kid bets into the flush he's filled up with a queen in the hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>YELLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If The Man has a flush or a straight, he goes under.  But not with both.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He counts out all his money except a few smaller bills.</context>
      <utterance>Bet what's in front of me. Make it fifty-four hundred bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE WATCHERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reacting.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEATURING LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He takes his time before he responds.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly and deliberately, revealing nothing in his face, he reaches into his breast pocket and takes out a slim wallet and begins to let the bills flutter out on the table. The Kid looks at him frozen.</context>
      <utterance>Fifty-four hundred bucks is a nice piece of money.  I see the bet and raise sixty-seven hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE SHOOTER AND BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bill hisses softly into The Shooter's ear.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But The Shooter, like the Kid, is white-faced and frozen by the raise.</context>
      <utterance>Kid has him, doesn't he?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm taking my half hour to raise my stake.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I declare a thirty-minute break. Leave your cards and money on the table. The game will start again at five forty-five.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take your marker, Kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can raise it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long as you know.  -- Call.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Straight flush to the jack -- That's $6700 you owe me, Kid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New deck.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you playing, Kid? You got a half an hour to raise your stake.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- I'm through.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, this game is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're one hell of a poker player, Kid. That was a rough hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he settles up, the CAMERA FOLLOWS The Kid to his brandy bottle. As he pours himself a slug, Melba and Shooter join him.</context>
      <utterance>What's the tab for the whole show?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had to do it, didn't you -- you had to go for it your own way.  Well, sonny, I hope you learned something. I know we sure as hell did.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Christian?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's gone. She's got too much sense to stick with a two bit loser.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.  Sorry, Kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.  I should have known he had it, Shooter Man. I walked into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, Kid, it's like I said -- you just wasn't ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELBA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why me -- I'm not part of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHOOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes you are -- you and your big mouth -- you're part of it all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLAEGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Melba starts to protest, but Felix jerks her out the door. Shooter hesitates, then follows.</context>
      <utterance>He's right, my dear. Now run along with Felix. We're going to have a long talk about that big mouth of yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIFFERENT ANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Schlaegel turns to The Kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHLAEGEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid looks at him, looks at Lancey and Lady Fingers, wondering about what Schlaegel has said, angry about it.</context>
      <utterance>I was wrong. I figured you for brains. But you're a loser, Kid. You had a chance to play with grownups and you ran.  They weren't playing your game. They were playing mine. Think about that while you find a place to hide. But hide good, Kid -- because I got a message for you and I'm going to see it delivered.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schlaegel nods, moves to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Any time.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEW ANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lancey and Lady Fingers join The Kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY FINGERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never thought I'd see the day. You raising tens on a lousy three-flush.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gets down to what it's all about, doesn't it? Making the wrong play at the right time.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what it's all about?  You were crazy -- odds are three hundred to one against.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kid looks at him and doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>I don't play a percentage game. I play stud poker my way. And I got the money and you got the questions. Figure that out.  You're good. But as long as I'm around, you're second best, Kid... and you might as well learn to live with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LANCEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles his very pleasant smile and goes out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Look me up if you're in Miami after Christmas. Stillson Hotel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it ain't Eric Stone, from the foundry. It's the Cincinnati Kid King of the stud poker players.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- not the King -- not much of anything right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves toward The Kid.</context>
      <utterance>We'll start with giving you back what you gave me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eric -- The men hesitate.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEW ANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as Christian gets out of a taxi.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell her good-bye, sport. You ain't going any place.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses to Christian.</context>
      <utterance>I know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you all right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.  Weren't you going to say good-bye?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said good-bye.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I guess you did.  You don't know if I won or lost do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- it doesn't really matter.  I love you, Kid -- and it's not enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
