<movie id="175" title="Doors The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ENGINEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera moving tentatively along the shadows, discovering the sidelight on a Navy surplus pea jacket thrown on a chair; moving to a candle's orange flutter on pages written with verse... a hand breaking the seal of the bottle of Irish Bushmill's whiskey.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Jim, It's your birthday man, whaddaya say we try this another night...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes a TAMBOURINE at the mike and one of his sudden giant Indian YELLS rock through the studio.</context>
      <utterance>No music, No Doors. Let's roll... Is everybody in?... Is Everybody in?... Is everybody in? The ceremony is about to begin...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMEN, CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom's scared face...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grandma trying to hide Jim's face but he looks back...</context>
      <utterance>...but it was the first time I tasted fear. I musta been about four, like a child is just like a flower, his head is floating in the breeze.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just a dream, Jimmy, just a dream</utterance>
   <speaker>SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a killer on the road His brain is squirming like a toad Take a long holiday Let your children play If you give this man a ride Sweet family will die There's a killer on the road The boy's eyes going back to the Indian MAN looking at him... then to the dying opened body bleeding out its guts on the asphalt... the dying man's face, twisted, moaning, amazing eyes at the point of death -- they settle on Jim</utterance>
   <speaker>MOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A strange SOUND occurs -- the rattle of an ancient gourd, "shi-chi-chi, shi-chi-chi". Something flying through the air. A bull-roarer, a whirling leather thong, announcing the appearance of a shaman. INTO JIM -- his eyes staring out the back His receding point of view -- the Indians, the overturned truck...</context>
      <utterance>It's just a dream Jimmy, just a dream</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(wind, music)</context>
      <utterance>...The reaction I get now looking back is the soul of the ghosts of those dead Indians -- maybe one or two of them were just running around freaking out and just leaped into my soul -- and they're still there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car pulling away across the giant 1940's landscape</context>
      <utterance>Girl you gotta love your man  Take him by the hand Make him understand</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLOW MOTION: The Husband's face distorting, saying something on the track like: "What! God NO!" but it's subdued, low. Trying other stations. Jim turns to look out his window, as if he already knew.</context>
      <utterance>...from the Texas School Book Depository. We repeat. President John F. Kennedy was shot a few minutes ago in Dallas!</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WIFE'S and HUSBAND'S VOICES seem lost in the background.</context>
      <utterance>...taken to Parkland Memorial Hospital. There's no word on the President's condition. Mrs. Kennedy is...</utterance>
   <speaker>WIFE &amp; HUSBAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, Oh God. Not the President for Christ's sake. Oh God -- WHO'S</utterance>
   <speaker>NEXT?</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On Jim -- staring out the window. "Who's next!"</utterance>
   <speaker>SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Riders on the storm  On the DESERT.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The YOUNG MAN gestures, and goes back inside the house. She's alone now on the balcony, sitting on a kitchen table... It's now or never. Jim scales the tree alongside the house with the agility of a gymnast.</context>
      <utterance>She lives on Love Street Lingers long on Love Street She has a house and garden I would like to see what happens</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl's grinding up pot in an old shoebox with a spoon and kitchen strainer. She looks up and sees his crotch three feet from her face, balanced there effortlessly on the railing like a highwire act, opens her mouth in surprise. Jim drops softly to the balcony, a smile of disarming gentleness.</context>
      <utterance>She has robes and she has monkeys Lazy diamond studded flunkies She has wisdom and knows what to do She has me and she has you</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow! Hi...  You have a problem with doors?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His head cocked slightly onto his left shoulder, he drawls, southern gentleman, polite, slow, thoughtful as if he had all the time in the world, as if the guy would never come back.</context>
      <utterance>Waste of time...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I followed you... from the beach...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow! You followed me? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves. Kisses her swiftly, softly, right on the lips.</context>
      <utterance>...cause... you're the one...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow... neat...  ...maybe you should meet my old man?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks into her face. Classic American face, freckles, big round eyes soft as rain, long sunset red hair. She feels his intense, starving eyes. He kisses her a second time. The YOUNG MAN coming back with the rolling paper -- sees him. As he hops back on the railing -- swings out into the tree -- looks back once.</context>
      <utterance>Later. You got a name?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment. She must decide. The YOUNG MAN within earshot.</context>
      <utterance>Mine's Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ice broken in that instant. Jim smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Pam...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He vanishes. The Man abreast of Pamela, as if he's seen a vision.</context>
      <utterance>Jim and Pam, Pam and Jim...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Jim. My new friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>JIM'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STUDENTS in the audience groan at the pretention of it. Moving to JIM's eyes hidden in his parka hood, peeking through at the screen. A CLOSEUP now of JIM on screen looking straight into the lens as he takes a hit on a hash pipe, and winks.</context>
      <utterance>Nietzche said "all great things must first wear monstrous and terrifying masks in order to inscribe themselves on the hearts of humanity". Listen children -- to the sound of the Nuremberg night.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever seen God? -- a mandala. A symmetrical angel. Felt? Yes. Fucking the Sun. Heard? The music. Voices. Touched? An animal. Your hand Tasted? Rare meat, corn, water and wine</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights coming on as the last absurdist images flicker off. Hissing and a big Bronx cheer summarize the feelings of the 100 odd STUDENTS crammed into a bunker-like theater. A youngish INSTRUCTOR stirs to the front row from a row of upset FACULTY. Hands shooting up to criticize.</context>
      <utterance>Hey man it's great, don't listen to em, it's non-linear man, it's poetry man, everything Godard stands for.</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is pretty shocking stuff Mr. Morrison. And I might say indulgent. Naziism and masturbation, when used for shock value, are not art. But to be constructive, let's start with your intention. What was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRICK, BONES and JACK, three friends sitting next to Jim, shoot their hands up.</context>
      <utterance>It was a bore!! That's what!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey it was better'n a Warhol picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No it wasn't. It was worse!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A guy sleeping for seven hours...</utterance>
   <speaker>STUDENT 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...is less pretentious! There was no political consciousness. Naziism is...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey hold on man! You guys are the facists!</utterance>
   <speaker>BONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It takes genitalism to absurdity man, just cause the squares here can't dig it cause the film school's still so square...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cacophony of voices, critics, emotions blend out over Jim's quiet eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh c'mon man, give it a break. Boo! Beatniks go home! Take another mushroom...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>HOLD IT DOWN!!... Mr. Morrison -- what are your feelings?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(walks out)</context>
      <utterance>I quit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey man whatdya expect, an Oscar?</utterance>
   <speaker>BONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't quit, you gotta voice. People can't dig cause they don't understand yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're an individual, if you're too good, they wanna cut your dick off. Look what happened to Orson Wells.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You quit now, they'll yank your deferment in no time and they'll get you for Vietnam man. Three more months you graduate.</utterance>
   <speaker>BONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be cool, you never learned fuckin patience Morrison, you want everything at once.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They didn't get it. So make your films and fuck what they think.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slows, a dramatic young lion pose, surveying the girls.</context>
      <utterance>You know what I think?</utterance>
   <speaker>BONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah whadday you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cronies wait, anticipating something inescapably evil to escape his lips.</context>
      <utterance>You really want to know what I think?</utterance>
   <speaker>BONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah yeah, whatddaya think?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we gotta get really ripped!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera moving to reveal JOHN DENSMORE wiry, solid on the drums... moving on to ROBBIE KRIEGER, wispy, ethereal looking, the youngest, flamenco-type moves on his early electric guitar. Also a HARMONICA PLAYER and a BASE. They all seem slightly embarrassed by either the cheap sound system feedback or Ray's warbling, but the crowd couldn't care less -- a German beerhall, they want noise and sex. JIM and his GANG, beers in hand, mouth back the words, beers everywhere shoved to the smokey ceiling, everyone on their feet, nuts with spring fever. Jim eyeing the GIRL next to him.</context>
      <utterance>I tell you bout my baby 'bout five foot four from head to toe She came to my room Just 'bout midnight She makes me feel so good She makes me feel alright</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what I'd like to do to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really want to know what I'd like to do to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The FOOTBALL TEAM TYPES edge over nearby, one of them picking out Jim with a glare.</context>
      <utterance>What!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks puzzled by the suggestion.</context>
      <utterance>Wanna hear the scream of the butterfly...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOTBALL PLAYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Morrison!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They love it. The place going wild. The girl with the football player wanting him.</context>
      <utterance>She came to my room She came on my floor She came on my bed She came on my face Ooooooh I want to wrap your legs around my head baby baby and her name was Gloria</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode>SONG</mode>
      <context>Shake dreams from your hair, my pretty child my sweet one Choose the day and choose the sign of your day The day's divinity the first thing you see Jim slides her upstairs' door open, crawls in next to her bed. She's asleep with her boyfriend. He touches her toe. She awakes, startled.</context>
      <utterance>Awake!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, come out for a walk, it's a pretty night.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're crazy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I stay with you tonight? We could talk 'till dawn. I just don't want to be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... just talk though. No funny stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been real upset. I lost my car on the freeway yesterday. I left it somewhere and I can't remember where and when I went back it was gone. My sister...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She breaks into sobs, seeking his arms. He hugs her.</context>
      <utterance>I bet you never expected life could be this hard.  And you're still so young.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wonder where we'll be ten years from now?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really don't want to know</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode>SONG</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Choose now, they croon Beneath the moon Beside an ancient lake Enter again the sweet forest Enter the hot dream Come with us Everything is broken up and dances</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(mispronounces)</context>
      <utterance>These are like beautiful! I never read much poetry in school. I hated it. What's a "shaman"?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the medicine man who starts in a peyote trance. And he gets everyone in the tribe going and they share in his vision and it heals them. It's the same in all cultures -- Greeks, Jesus. Some Indians say the first shaman invented sex. He's the one who makes you crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a "shaman"?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh  no. I just write about it. What turns you on?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Experience. Freedom. Love... Now. Peyote's like love. When it's given it's blessed. When it's sold it's damned. I like peyote. I like acid, it's easier to get. I like the spiritual voyage. The first time I did acid I saw God. I did. I had a friend who was Christ. And he was Judas too. I suddenly knew the secret of everything -- that we're all one, the universe is one. And that everything is beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it? I don't know. I think you're alive by confronting death -- by experiencing pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're alive by recognizing beauty -- seeing truth because when you discover truth you discover what love is... we're all saying the same thing. It's "love me and I'll love you."</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only thru death that you know life. Jesus, medicine men heal people by sacrificing their own life.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you love Death?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pam shivers, a strange thought.</context>
      <utterance>I think life hurts a lot more than death. When you die the pain is over.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I look at you... and see my death?  No, that's ridiculous.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet your dad's a school teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was your father?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Military</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet you moved around a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, about 8 times.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many sisters and brothers?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs his fingers thru her hair, kissing her gently.</context>
      <utterance>One... she's the pretty one... I love your neck.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"...but one, the most beautiful one of all dances in a ring of fire and throws off the challenge with a shrug"</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's beautiful. Who did you write it for?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The panties coming off. Rousseau dangling from the Venice moon. He moves a little over excited, nervous, more awkward than we might expect.</context>
      <utterance>I wrote it for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...take your time, Jim... there's no hurry, I'm all you have to do tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Learn to forget, learn to forget, learn to forget</context>
      <utterance>Well the clock says it's time to close now I guess I'd better go now... As we depart the rooftop. Your fingers weak with minarets Speaking secret alphabets I light another cigarette</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim has approached closer, amused, looking down.</context>
      <utterance>Om om... No bliss! No bliss!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray opening his eyes -- his POV -- Jim, slouched, jacket over his shoulder, sun behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Ray, try acid man, it's guaranteed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morrison... Aw shit. Last trip I thought I was going through hell's digestive system. Something painted by Hieronymus Bosch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never had a bummer on acid.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like naturally high man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever works. Making movies at MGM yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I saw the head of production and I said Godard doesn't use scripts, he improvises with his camera and he said, "great who's Godard?"</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta take the planet back, reinvent the Gods, make new myths.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right on. I thought you went to New York?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never got there. Went out to the desert and uh... got lost y'know. Days. I been living on Trick's rooftop. Got stuck on this chick...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatcha been doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Writing. Poems. Songs.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Songs? Lemme hear one.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't sing.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So neither can Dylan. "Johnny's in the basement mixing up the medicine, I'm on the pavement thinking about the government". But he's got the words man. That's what they want.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim has crouched, digging his hand in the sand. As the grains spill out of his fist he has his eyes closed. Ray pantomimes chords in the keyboard sand. All of a sudden we're in RAY'S POV -- a mystical moment. Jim singing, no sound, then pure song, unadulterated by atmosphere.</context>
      <utterance>Let's swim to the moon un hunh Let's climb thru the tide Penetrate the evening That the city sleeps to hide</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim stops, shrugs. Ray looks at him a long beat. Intense eyes, the manner of a man who knows what he wants and cannot be stopped.</context>
      <utterance>Let's swim out tonight love It's our turn to try Parked beside the ocean On our moonlight drive</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow!... Y'know man those are hot lyrics -- really hot!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...could you write the music for that down, if we went over to your place, could you write that on your organ?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you kidding! I could fly. You wrote that? You got others?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bunch. It's like I'm taking notes at a rock concert going on inside my head. I actually hear the music -- the spirit of the wine y'know, intoxication.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man. You got a voice like Chet Baker -- haunted! What the hell happened to you in the desert? Let's get a rock and roll band together man and make a million bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...be great wouldn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the perfect time man! Two of the guys outta my band are really into this. I meditate with them. You know them... Robbie and John. We could have it in the can in three weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey why not, I could write the songs with you guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim laughs, loves Ray's ardor as they move along the ocean side.</context>
      <utterance>The Stones did it outta the London School of Economics for Chrissake. Things are about to explode man. You can feel it in the air.  Vietnam's right out there. Sides are being chosen. People wanna fight or fuck, love or kill, everything's gonna flame. The planet's screaming for change, Morrison. Make the myths man!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There oughta be great orgies man. Like when Dionysus arrived in Greece, he made all the women mad, leaving their homes and dancing off in the mountains. Great golden copulations in the streets of LA.  Hey, do you know her?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we call ourselves. "Dionysus"?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a name.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Doors?  That's the most ridiculous...  ...you mean the doors in your mind? Like the Huxley book.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The Doors of Perception"? Acid...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah sure mescaline experiments -- reducing the sugar flow to the brain. Great book.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's from William Blake actually, the line -- "when the doors of perception are cleansed -- things will appear as they truly are..."</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- infinite". It's great, Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So where do we start? How do we start? Where are the girls?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they walk off, the two of them along the edge of the Pacific. A dog jumping for a frisbee. The music of MOONLIGHT DRIVE now riffs over the real song now.</context>
      <utterance>Rehearsing. You're moving off the rooftop and in with me and Dorothy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's swim to the moon Let's climb thru the tide Penetrate the evening That the city sleeps to hide...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM straining to make it work, jumping around violent, still not in control. Yet searching. JOHN cutting out.</context>
      <utterance>The day destroys the night Night divides the day Tried to run Tried to hide Break on thru to the other side</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's really square. Let's hip it up. Jump on your cues.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tighten it up. Stay with the beat Jim. You're dragging.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's try it again, come on. I'm just getting into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think it's hot!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still think the lyrics are weird man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still think it sounds like the bottom of a fishbowl man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robbie's voice is tinny but something immediate's in the air, all the radar out.</context>
      <utterance>I been working on something goes like this... A minor.  "You know that it would be untrue You know that I would be a liar If I was to say to you Girl, we couldn't get much higher" F sharp... chorus "Come on baby, light my fire Try to set the night on fire..."</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay man there's some good changes in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got any more lyrics?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some. I call it "Light My Fire". I figger if I'm gonna compete with your stuff it's gotta be about earth, fire or snakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't underestimate Death.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah but it sounds like the Byrds man, we're not folk rock man. How 'bout trying it with a Latin beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought we could do the usual verse chorus verse chorus and</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't need a bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, we could maybe improvise a couple piano and guitar solos over it  "The time to hesitate is through"  Du du duh dud dada . . .</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"No time to wallow in the mire Try now we can only lose And our love become a funeral pyre Come on baby light my fire" John drumming it, different, more Latin.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty good! Pretty neat!!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice groove, John. Chaka chaka chaka, then bula burump bula  ...you're right, it could take a coupla long solos, that's wild man, like Butterfield did on "East-West" -- really hip.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'ever heard Coltrane's "Favorite Things"?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah -- maybe stretch it out and put it in 4/4 on bass, 3/4 on guitar and snare.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three excluded Doors head out to the beach like obedient schoolboys while Ray fools with his organ.</context>
      <utterance>Why not! A minor to B minor. Jazz! That then is jazz! But it needs a hook. Something. Give me some space. I need some space. Leave the room guys. Come on! Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guy's obnoxious, man always bossin' people around! I thought we were equals!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't we?  That was great Robbie. Whaddaya thinking about when you play?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't know. Mostly the fish in my fish tank.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey whadya say we take some of that Tijuana acid and see what kinda trouble we can get into tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The chicks always go for you man. I get the dogs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we'll start a religion or plan a murder or go to Tijuana.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatsamatter with you man, what about Pam, you got the morals of a coyote.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why you wanna sleep with her John, just to bug me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell NO!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...means "hell yes". She likes you man, she really does and y'all should. What's a rock and roll band for man, if you can't party all night and do bad things?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they head back.</context>
      <utterance>Sieg Heil!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay here it is. Bach and Rock. Count it off John</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know that it would be untrue etc.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The music was new black polished chrome and came over the summer like liquid night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GIRL GROUPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that horny motherfucker in the black pants here tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>IDs! IDs! Can't get in without an</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GIRL 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh please. I forgot my I.D.. I'm on the list.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I forgot my list.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn around Jim! Come on let 'em in.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found an island in your arms A country in your eyes Arms that chained us, eyes that lied</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Jerry... do we get paid for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What shit, "day destroys the night", "crawl back in your brain", "go insane". What do people wanna pay money to hear that shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The greater the suffering, the more terrible the events, the greater the pleasure Jerry. They want it, it's catharsis. Like the ancient Greeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're in Los Angeles punk, how would you know, they like your pants, they're not listenin' to you, what the hell they see in you I...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they understand Jerry. All our real desires are unconscious and unseen. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you're the weirdest fuckin' guy I ever...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You love us?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera gliding across the small crowded smokey room to RAY and JOHN in conversation with a slick Beverly Hills MANAGER type.</context>
      <utterance>I love ya. You got two more shows to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I got some real tight record company connections, just leave it to me man, I'll take you guys all the fuckin' way, you blew my mind out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah right, but what about the music?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey the music? I love it man, that's why we're talking right? Some of it's a little on the dark side though. Ya know ya oughta get some tunes like Herman's Hermits stuff -- "Mrs. Brown you got a lovely daughter". That shit goes right to the radio man.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh. Well, how 'bout gettin' us some real equipment?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I sign you guys to a five year management contract and you got it all. Equipment. Demo. A truck WITH roadies. Three, maybe four percent record deal. Wherever ya want to go babe, trust me, I'll get you there. Whatd'ya say?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll have a band meeting. The four of us do everything unanimously or we don't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives Ray a card, leaving, crossing to Jim and PAM talking.</context>
      <utterance>The musketeers. I'm touched. But lemme tell you something -- loyalty don't pay the bills. Think about it. Call me tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a sleaze! Man, Jim's gotta start facing the crowd if he's gonna be the front man.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just getting his confidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He never does what we rehearsed. What's the point of...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does it feel?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pam on payphone calling her friends to come.</context>
      <utterance>Great, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MANAGER on his way out leaning into Jim's face, slyly.</context>
      <utterance>...make sure you get Barb and Sue Anne to come. And tell them to ask for Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, how old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, twenty one...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, you're a gold mine, I'll make it quick and to the point and if you repeat it I'll deny it -- drop these guys, I'll put you with some real musicians, your voice, your looks, that's what'll sell records, we'll make a million bucks. A year. Goodbye. Call me. I'm right. He gives Jim a card and goes. Pam disgusted with the type, Jim laughs, likes the guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like a man wears his soul on his face.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Whiskey's" next, I can feel it in my bones.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still think the lyrics are weird.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Ray, every girl out there wanted to fuck me, I could feel it for the first time!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right on stud. But you better watch out for the guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys, I'm serious about the desert, we still gotta deepen man, we gotta take some peyote -- all of us together, we got one more stage to go...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know man, fucks up my playing. I been playing music for 10 years man and this is the first time in my whole damned life I ever played it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you satisfied?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you get off my case! I'm never doing acid again. Too many bad trips man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not acid John, it's peyote. It's a bonding ceremony. It's got to be more... more... more...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm into TM man. I promised my guru...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to! I want to! I'm ready. Let's go to the desert... do the peyote, the good peyote.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's on now?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Love".</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, Arthur Lee's cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're the best... better'n the Beatles.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GIRLS looking at each other like who is this jerk.</context>
      <utterance>You mean the Marx Brothers of music, we could blow 'em away.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter from the GIRLS.</context>
      <utterance>The Doors... We're up the street at the Fog.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Doors. I heard of you. That's the dumbest name. I wouldn't go to the Fog if you paid me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah what would you do for money?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile DENSMORE is hitting up on GIRL 2.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go Jim, come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you don't have a phone number? What do you mean you don't have a phone number?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a phone number. So give me your number then.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robbie is doing his imitation of a shrimp for ANOTHER GIRL who's laughing.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have a phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, would you leave my name at the door?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I don't know. What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Caprice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look between Jim and Caprice. Pamela pulling Jim away, gives the girl a look.</context>
      <utterance>Caprice? That's the dumbest name I ever heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd giggles. Jim climbs a pole, yells.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! I am the Lizard king. I can do Anything! Raise your hands if you understand! Alive, any of you alive -- let's take a poll -- how many of you know you're really alive!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We IRIS in on the Doors suddenly -- a strange sound -- REVERSE IRIS on Jim -- feeling it now. The peyote. JIM's POV -- Pam irising out. This strange sound in his ears -- a rattle of an Indian gourd, similar to what we heard in the car in Arizona when Jim was a boy. Now a distant Indian drum beating. The beginning strains of THE END dribble in.</context>
      <utterance>No one? Raise your hands c'mon man... let's go. On the crowd. A few raise their hands, smile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hug. She throws up again.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody having a good time?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim holds his head. Feels the ride.</context>
      <utterance>...awright, pretty good, it gets better.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JUMP CUTS: Jim and Pam are touching each other. Face. Shadows. Sand falls from Pam's hand. Jim turns to hawk at a bird. "Hawk! Hawk!" Then Pam is dancing alone on the dune. Abruptly Jim is back in the circle with the Doors in a sense torn between them and Pam. EXTREME CLOSEUPS of their faces, their eyes, the tensions of the trip tearing apart their teeth as they go from the laughing to the dangerous part.</context>
      <utterance>WOA!! It's fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John shutters -- as does Robbie and Ray. Jim seems possessed.</context>
      <utterance>When the serpent appears, his head is ten feet long and five feet wide. He has one red eye and one green eye. He's deadly and he's seven miles long. As he moves -- on his scales is written all the history of the world, all people, all actions, all of us our little pictures on the scales, God it's big! -- and it's eating as it moves all the time, devouring, digesting consciousness, power, a monster of energy!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. He has instilled a flux of fear in the group.</context>
      <utterance>We must kiss the snake on the tongue, if it senses our fear, it will eat us instantly. But if we kiss it without fear, the snake will take us through the garden and out the gate. To our freedom -we must ride this snake. To the end of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'm fucked up. I'm not thinking right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're fucked up John. Go with it, confusion is the sound of creation.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should see your eyes right now, you're death. Look at your eyes -- you're crazy man, you look crazy. You scare me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No no no John John. God is crazy too. God is part insane as well as sane. Not in control all the time. Dionysus was the God of the wine. He made ecstasy but he also made madness. Madness is all right. That's what you want, isn't it, isn't it? Where's that joint?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get scared thinking of all the choices inside. I could go. I could stay. I can live anywhere. I could die now if I wanted. It's limitless choice... and no one cares.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Die Robbie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim looking at her, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what I am. I'm on the cusp of Sagittarius and Capricorn. Sagittarius is wild and Capricorn domestic and safe, so I don't know which one to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray has his head buried in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, the light, it's so beautiful Ray. Can you see it... it's all one... honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in pain man. I want something from the peyote. I feel the universe functioning perfectly but I'm still perfectly locked inside myself. Instead of Oneness, I feel total Isolation. Aloneness. Fear... Pain... Jim, all I feel is pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pain makes me feel more alive Ray. Pain is meant to wake us up. People try to hide their pain but they're wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel Lust. I want to fuck everything I can, and I know it will never be enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pam wants you.  You're a good Catholic John, you want it so you can feel guilty about it... Fuck death away John.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel Fear... so bad I just numb out all my feelings. I'm afraid of my father, I'm afraid of Yahweh... I wish I could play my guitar.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you should kill your father Robbie. He tried to kill you. Kill him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so fucking scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes Ray and Robbie's hands, his voice calming them, reform the circle. John hesitant. Not all will enter the gates at evening.</context>
      <utterance>But you're Alive! It's beautiful! Fear, pain, lust, we've got to know all our feelings before we can come out the other side free men. Don't feel ashamed of yourselves, don't let society destroy your reality. Our freedom's the only thing worth dying for, it's the only thing worth living for!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna make it man. I'm scared Jim, I'm still scared. Blindness is coming on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pulling John into the circle, bonding, their four heads sunk to the desert floor, Jim making wild Indian sounds, deep- throated "shoooh... shoooh"... now humming a song from the desert.</context>
      <utterance>Then use us John, use our strength, it's us four now, a tribe of warriors, everything we have comes from the same source, the great Creator of Being. Trust him, trust us. Ride the snake. . . I promise you I will be with you till the end of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The OTHERS join in his chant, the four rising and falling like a collective breath.</context>
      <utterance>My wild love went riding... mmmmmm. She rode all the day. She ride to the devil. And ask for him to pay... shooo shoooo</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes, his boots in the sand.</context>
      <utterance>...I'm lying to you. I am scared.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, where are you going.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pamela calling from another dune, far away.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be back. I gotta go alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His POV -- of her, receding. She screams for him. He's in pain. Cannot help her. A BIRD of prey in the sky. Jim moving across a lunar landscape. SPECIAL EFFECT: The sun is black like night or else white in a black sky. Voices in the distance. "Jim, where are you going?" A mother's voice, a father's voice.</context>
      <utterance>Jim! Jim... come here, dance... don't go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desperately in need of some stranger's hand in a desperate land Lost in a Roman wilderness of pain and all the children are insane: waiting for the summer rain</context>
      <utterance>Can you picture what will be So limitless and free</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of a rattle -- "shichishichi" -- he realizes he's being watched. By what? He whips his eyes everywhere. A large LIZARD perches on a boulder assesses him calmly, tatters of a former skin clinging to its throat, spits a forked tongue and drills its black pearly eyes into his skull... Now the sound of the Bull-Roarer, whipping the air, announcing the appearance of the shaman. Jim's struck with an overwhelming sense of... awe... ancient mysteries. He turns. The lizard is looking at him. The GHOST of the DEAD INDIAN is also looking at him. We are looking at JIM from its point of view -- a blur of light, some headdress, a sense of skins... music drops back, no lyrics... the voice is old, familiar, possible Spanish descent dialect or huararchi.</context>
      <utterance>There's danger on the edge of town Ride the King's highway Weird scenes inside the gold mine Ride the King's highway west, baby</utterance>
   <speaker>INDIAN GHOST VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voice, the pretense, -- the glow too quickly fades -- leaving Jim so alone, not sure what he has heard, yet he knows he has heard, and he knows he has seen -- and once you have seen, it will never be the same again. His eyes.</context>
      <utterance>...you are a prince among white men, yet you are a warrior among us. You are ready now. Go out "walk with the pain of the world, travel to the end of the wind" -- and change it for all men as you were born to do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ride the snake, to the lake The ancient lake The snake is long, seven miles Ride the snake He's old, and his skin is cold Camera pulling out from his eyes. There's something different tonight. Something in the air. His eyes are open, he's facing outward, gripping the mike for his life, hair falling in his face, dripping sweat, we sense all his soul concentrated in what he has to say. Cliques of GROUPIES have staked claims at the foot of the stage, eyes fucking him as he writhes, spreading his legs. Every twitch, every moment he sucks out the tension on the musical interludes generates a whip of a reaction in his audience. Nobody is moving in the club. The DANCERS are still, the GO GO GIRLS in their white plastic boots and dresses hang motionless in their gilded cages. Even the WAITRESSES have stopped, frozen with their trays, denying something is going to happen. PAMELA, DOROTHY... JERRY from the Fog, also the manager of this place, watches from the balcony, shaking his head, doesn't understand. Panning to two RECORD TYPES with him -- JAC HOLZMAN, distinguished six footer, suit, and PAUL ROTHCHILD, funky, pigtailed, ex-con, early 30s.</context>
      <utterance>Ride the snake</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get here and we'll do the rest The blue bus is calling us (2) Driver where you taking us? The band has come together fully now. ROBBIE'S fingers sliding across the trembling strings, staring at the ceiling, wandering around the darkened portions of stage left, he feels Jim -- echoes him back with his flamenco-blues guitar. JOHN on drums, reading Jim's moods, throws in the spontaneous and violent riffs that keep it savage. He literally tortures Jim's ears with his drums. And RAY, concentrated with his nodding head like a big flamingo over his keyboard, mixing it up, throwing curves, yet also -- and more delicately -- torturing Jim with the messianic organ sounds that shriek in his ears. There is something of Merlin in Ray -- the alchemist knowing how to play Jim. And JIM -- "that sneaky silent lithe flowing flexing animal" -- ready at last to share both his body and his soul with the world, to live out the words of the Indian prophet... to lead.</context>
      <utterance>The west is best</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray looks over up from his board, catches Robby with a 'what's this?' look... They go with it, improvising... Jim clutching the mike tighter, seeking solace in its arms; it all hangs in the air as if he doesn't have any idea what he's going to say next.</context>
      <utterance>The killer awoke before dawn He put his boots on He took a face from the ancient gallery And he walked on down the hall</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pamela sensing something is coming... the AUDIENCE... Jerry... the go-go dancers...</context>
      <utterance>He went to the room where his sister lived And he paid a visit to his brother And then he went on down the hall...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLASH -- A FATHER'S FACE, any face, older, any man...</context>
      <utterance>And he came to a door, And he looked inside "Father?" "Yes, son?" "I want to kill you".</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLASH -- A MOTHER'S FACE, any face, older, a woman</context>
      <utterance>Mother... I want to...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on baby take a chance with us</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode>X3</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And meet me in the back of the blue bus Doona blue rog onna blue bus Doona blue yeah! Come on yeah!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NOBODY'S GONNA FUCK THEIR MOTHER ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>MY STAGE! YOU'RE OUTTA HERE. You don't ever come back to play, you don't ever come back to drink -- You're DEAD ON THE STRIP!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry pinning Jim to the wall,</context>
      <utterance>Kill the father, fuck the mother, kill the father, fuck the mother -- that's what I'm into! That's what I'm into!</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You -- MORRISON! You're fucking filthy twisted perverse punk, get back to your fucking sewer!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lost in the melee, RAY and JOHN springing Jim back from likely death</context>
      <utterance>You have the face of a pig man.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>JERRY JERRY... He was talking about Oedipus! GREEK TRAGEDY!! It's ART!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JAC HOLZMAN pushing past to Ray. Pamela separating Jim visually from Jerry.</context>
      <utterance>Come on Jerry, cool it, cool it... he's a kid, it's a song about dying, changing...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll never work again man. The Mafia controls all these clubs.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLZMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quite a night! Hi, I'm Jac Holzman. I own Elektra Records.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holzman pauses, a dramatic presence, six foot two, impeccably dressed, he knows the weight of his words.</context>
      <utterance>Oh sure, hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLZMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It hangs there. Impossible words.</context>
      <utterance>Listen... I think if you could just put what you did in there on record, we could really have something... and we could make a lot of money...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John and Robbie sharing looks.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLZMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... and Rothchild here was born to be your producer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, the guy that did Butterfield!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bertold Brecht, cabaret and rock. Give me a fucking break. You guys are amazing! Let's go make a record.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, is that asshole gonna pay us?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLZMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Strains of LIGHT MY FIRE cross the cut.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you go inside and ask him Jim?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera moving fast thru the control room, past the ENGINEER (BRUCE BOTNICK), taciturn, 20's, the PRODUCER (PAUL ROTHCHILD) in pig heaven, and the owner JAC HOLZMAN in his blue suit watching.</context>
      <utterance>You know that it would be untrue You know that I would be a liar If I was to say to you Girl, we couldn't get much higher</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Bruce, you feel it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRUCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm having big fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The song, now fully -- orchestrated, rolling on over the following MONTAGE:</context>
      <utterance>Come on baby, LIGHT MY FIIIRRRREEEE!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty good! Pretty neat!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mind dying in a plane crash, a smile on my face.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As compared to what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just don't want to go out slow -- brain tumor, botulism. I want to feel what it's like, cause death is only going to happen to you once.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to die ever, what a weird thing to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For if we don't find the next whisky bar I tell you we must die I tell you I tell you I tell you we must die</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GIRLS crying hysterically as Jim lazily, leopardly, moves across the CROWD, almost like Oswald waiting for the Ruby bullet but with that sweet, pleasant smile on his face, dark glasses concealing...</context>
      <utterance>Show me the way to the next little girl Oh don't ask why Oh don't ask why</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For if we don't find the next little girl I tell you we must die I tell you I tell you I tell you we must die</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PRODUCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right this way Mr. Sullivan. They're called "the Doors". They got the number one single in the country -- "Light Your Fire".</utterance>
   <speaker>SULLIVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Light Your Fire"? Is that sooo?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRODUCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They look pretty grungy but we're...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're gonna cut it!</utterance>
   <speaker>HAIRDRESSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm going to worship it. What kind of shampoo are you using?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The kind you get in hotels.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAIRDRESSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pamper yourself sweetheart, you don't want split ends, you're a celebrity now.  You have very serious-serious hair, it needs to rebel. I'll give it a tinge of something freaky.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd rather stay the same color.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAIRDRESSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scaredy cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>TV NEWSMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On JIM, as they pancake him, reflective.</context>
      <utterance>...here in Detroit, 42 people dead, more than 2000 injured... 1400 buildings burned, 5000 people have just lost their homes as Detroit joins more than 100 cities torn by riots this hot summer!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No wonder "Light My Fire's" number one.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAIRDRESSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you handsome?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The biggest mistakes in my life have been haircuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't wash it. Don't set it. He likes it the way it is...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAIRDRESSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Commotion from the doorway as the PRODUCER leads the lock- jawed MR. SULLIVAN in with everyone bowing and scraping to the Pope.</context>
      <utterance>All right, be mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRODUCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boys -- meet Mr. Sullivan Mr. Sullivan waves from the doorway.</utterance>
   <speaker>SULLIVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi boys, heard your song "Light That Fire"  ...think you're great... good luck out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh thanks Mr. Sullivan.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRODUCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look from the guys. Jim sullen. Tension in the air. Mr. Sullivan waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Well the guys at Network have told us they have a small problem with the lyrics "girl we couldn't get much higher". You can't say "higher" on network so they asked if... you could say, "girl we can't get much better"... can you dig that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. The producer puzzled a beat. It doesn't go down.</context>
      <utterance>How 'bout, "girl you couldn't bite my wire".</utterance>
   <speaker>PRODUCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sullivan exiting, waving at no one in particular like Nixon would.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think Standards and Practices would...</utterance>
   <speaker>SULLIVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, you boys don't forget to smile now. Don't be so sullen out there...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SIDDONS reassuring the Producer.</context>
      <utterance>Uh well, we're kind of a sullen group, Ed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll work it out Herb, promise. Give me five.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRODUCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Groovy! Uh you boys should know Mr. Sullivan is considering you boys for four more shows. You dig?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What -- are we the Beatles now John?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only a word man. The Stones changed...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Ray, why don't you change your name to Sid or Irving Manzarek or something... it's only a word y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray's seething tension. Younger brother starting to get out of hand.</context>
      <utterance>It's my words. I don't care, let's just jam.</utterance>
   <speaker>SULLIVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lights come up on the DOORS in their ultimate nightmare -- each Door appearing consecutively in a lightspot as Jim sings the ubiquitous "Light My Fire", trapped in this Elvis Presley -- Vegas act, he looks like he couldn't care less. DOORS hang suspended everywhere on the set -- their name spelled out in big block standup letters. Jim has a hard-on in his pants, barely concealed by his tight leathers.</context>
      <utterance>Now here on our stage direct from Los Angeles, California, ladies and gentlemen, The Doors!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know that it would be untrue You know that I would be a liar If I was to say to you Girl, we couldn't get much higher Come on baby light my fire</utterance>
   <speaker>PRODUCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said it! He said it! On National TV You can't do that! You can't do that!!! You blew it you little shit! You'll never play Ed Sullivan again. Jim on the monitors, singing through to his freedom, falls on the floor flat, the camera missing him completely.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on baby, light my fire Try to set the night on FIIIIRRRRRE!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I do, what do you want me to do?... Jim?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I guess I should see a doctor or something... maybe I should go to someone of the straight Jungian philosophy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim, quietly pissed, reaches for the whiskey bottle at the side of the bed.</context>
      <utterance>It happens to other guys too...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's so scary up there. To be adored. Isn't that irony? Teenage death girls want my dick -- a mere clown -- not my words. I'll never wake up in a good mood again... Lament for my cock, a tongue of knowledge deep in the feathered night, gives life, soar and crucify, I seek to know you...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not so complicated Jim, it's just sex, y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should marry an insurance salesman.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the hours man, the pressure, everything's like your last performance, you're setting yourself up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We weren't built to last.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you doing this for you, because you're a poet, not a rock star. Ed Sullivan's not a place for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really know what I am Pam? You know what poetry is? Where is the feast they promised us? Where is the wine -- the new wine -- dying on the vine?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'see -- I lied to you. I really love Fame.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing this to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to take the bottle away. He resists. They struggle. It becomes a fight.</context>
      <utterance>'Cause you're in the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is gonna help! It's probably the cause. 'Least put some soul in your success asshole!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you're the cause!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean I don't have this problem with anybody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it to me!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!!!!! Mommy!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs her. They lurch, smashing the lamp. WILD CHILD song kicking in.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you man I'm outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get mad! Yeahhh! Love my girl! Yeah, go fuck the other guys. How many white guys have you fucked Pam? 10, 20? Black guys what? You like Chinese dicks? Mongolian penis? 30?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...how many dogs have you fucked! You don't say No to anybody! Drugs, dogs, uglies, you'd fuck a doorknob with butter on it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could I do that</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Camera running at them from the end of the room. JIM laughs manically as they roll off the bed into a wall. Kicking, hitting hard.</context>
      <utterance>You're the first one who couldn't make it with me anyway! You're the only limp dick in the lot!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wild Child full of grace Savior of the human race Your cool face Natural child, terrible child Not your mother or your father's child Your own child, screaming wild</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They giggle, start to laugh. Then they cuddle on the floor, in the corner, in this semi-lit New York hotel room.</context>
      <utterance>You were saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...will you die for me, Pam, a clown, a despicable clown?... a mere despicable clown?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes yes yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I need a home. A place to hide.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...with me. Yes... yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...how could we make a home?... where there's sanctuary?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's hard now. She's guiding him inside her.</context>
      <utterance>...yes, yes, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...we're in Africa, we're just animals... I wanna stay inside you all night baby... let's fuck death away, now fuck death away...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...yes...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIME DISSOLVES over the questions and answers. A vaguely dreamy quality.</context>
      <utterance>What are your songs about Mr. Morrison?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh love death travel... revolt. We all write the songs, we're interested in anything about disorder, chaos, especially activity which seems to have no meaning... I think when you make peace with authority, you become authority.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you define that a little more?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah you can call us erotic politicians I guess.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...a scapegoat maybe -- I take on the audiences' fantasies, obeying their impulses. When the impulses are destructive, I'm destructive. It's kinda like sucking the puss out of a rattlesnake, something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...like a medicine man or witch doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim said to me once, the history of rock and roll's like Greek drama or caveman stories. The audience comes to see ancient rituals in ancient caves. Their souls in jeopardy. They're not watching any longer, they're participating -- and everything's in play, your life, your death...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Jim -- a beat. A sickly smile spreads.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Morrison, how do you feel about being called the "ultimate barbie doll".</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess when you say something like that, it's a shortcut to thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holding up a copy of "The Lords and New Creatures".</context>
      <utterance>Then do you "think" about the dreadful reviews your new poetry book has gotten?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess they didn't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim motions him over, whispers something at SIDDONS who goes to fetch a pair of scissors.</context>
      <utterance>And it's true you financed it's publication?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you bothered to read the poetry ma'm? You keep denying that anything good can come from L.A., I mean isn't that kind of a provincial attitude? That Bob Dylan's the only poet cause he's from the East Coast, but you won't even look past Jim's goddamn looks at the words man!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey c'mon Ray, hate should be allowed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...but what really are your songs about Mr. Morrison? You preach, "saving the planet", "making a new age" but how does drinking, taking drugs, this boozy sort of apocalyptic stance at the world influence young people in a positive way?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like that -- "boozy apocalyptic" -- you're a word man, but how does your newspaper influence young people to think about Vietnam? Who's sending the soldiers over there to die? The establishment -- right? Your newspaper -- right? That seems to me a lot more dangerous than the stuff we do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SIDDONS comes back in, hands Jim a pair of scissors.</context>
      <utterance>Do you believe in drugs Mr. Morrison?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know Nietzsche said, "all good consciousness, all evidence of truth comes only from the senses"? Hey you wanna arm wrestle? Come on, you look pretty tough today. C'mon, I'll take you all on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And alcohol? Is that considered part of the shaman's wisdom?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DOUBLE IMAGES on the DISSOLVES.</context>
      <utterance>Part of the clown's wisdom -- it's kinda the American way. You know we spend more on alcohol and tobacco than on education.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you by any chance in a trance now Mr. Morrison?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cuts his hair with the scissors. A commotion.</context>
      <utterance>What hurts you the most?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... got tired of the barbie doll look. It hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do your parents think about what you are doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they must've expressed some feeling?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flashbulbs hitting his face at that moment.</context>
      <utterance>Well, to be honest they're not living anymore so I don't like to talk about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim puts the scissors down, going to a low mysterious voice.</context>
      <utterance>Could you at least tell us how they died?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the room in a hush. He has mesmerized them and they're not sure whether to believe it or not.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it was a... horrible car crash... in the desert in the fifties, Arizona... ran right into a truckload of Indians... Navajos, they were lying out on the road, all bleeding, and I was with my Grandma and Grandad, we were banged up and all... and I was looking at my Dad and he was lying there... but his throat was severed and there was air coming out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOURNALIST 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim rises, staggers slightly as he makes his way to the bar on the way out of the room, smiles right at her, ignoring everybody else in the room.</context>
      <utterance>I have the feeling I'm being put on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes. The room in silence, embarrassed, nervous titters looking at Journalist 4 who flushes deeply as we cut to:</context>
      <utterance>Y'all believe what you want to believe, you will anyway... but it does kinda show you what excites people?  Fear, pity, horror -- all those good things that count. It's sorta I guess like being on the edge of an orgasm, y'know... that mystery just before you come. When? If? Should I? Will you die for me, eat me, this way, the end...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to do some more cocaine? It'll loosen you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she goes to a bowl of cocaine, laid alongside a bottle of champagne and a basketful of items all catered by Jim. He's at her bookcase, thumbing through an ancient manuscript.</context>
      <utterance>Great! A new thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSERT -- the DRAWINGS in the book pertain to Witchcraft.</context>
      <utterance>Wow how old is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>14th Century. I practice the Craft.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Craft?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a witch  A white one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM reappraising her. Her eye contact is very direct.</context>
      <utterance>The Kennealy's were Celtic cheiftains and pre-Christian shamans when your Druid ancestors the Morrisons were a minor Scottish clan founded by a bastard son of the king of Norway.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim waits. Something in the feeling of the room has shifted. The sound of her razor chopping coke. He snorts -- the first time.</context>
      <utterance>It's a religion, witchcraft. Witches are the protectors of the seasons, the harvests, goddesses of the grain. And when crossed, destroyers.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever try drinking blood?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim is down on his knees crawling around her. She is crawling back.</context>
      <utterance>It works you know. You drink blood the right time of the moon... they used to dance in the forests naked. I think that's what offended the Puritans and led to the Burnings. They were a sexual threat to their male order like the Bacchae -- five days a year for Dionysus, they used to wander the hills in ancient Greece, the first witches, clans of wild women fucking, looting, eating animals raw, the wine in their blood running hot -- looking for Dionysus... to tear him to pieces -- isn't that wild?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patricia laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Where do you get the blood?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blood is the rose of mysterious union, symbol of potency... now you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... I don't like... cutting myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before you slip into unconsciousness I'd like to have another kiss Another flashing chance at bliss Another kiss, another kiss</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna burn you down.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Incants him to climax with CELTIC WORDS. Jim is wild, reaching for the Moroccan dagger, holding it to her face as he continues to pump.</context>
      <utterance>Come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut me! Cut me go on!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody'd ever look at you again -- 'cept me. I'd scar you forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah YEAH!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take off your shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mooooooo!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the camera is like a roulette wheel Jim. It becomes whoever you want it to be -- a woman you want to seduce, a man you want to kill, a mother you want to upset, a wife you want to lie to or love, whatever you want it to be, it is...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He resists, he goes with it, push pull, prowling her loft on the acid, a bottle of cognac in one hand -- changing from shot to shot like a chameleon, free, wild, vicious, obscene.</context>
      <utterance>Where are the Doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget the Doors. It's you they want, Jim. You're the Doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We do everything together.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A weird dance ensuing between them -- teasing, enticing. He runs away, writhes along her wall, being photographed inch by moving inch. He crawls to her. She gets down with him on the floor, straddling him, photographing. Then he straddles her as she shoots him from her back. They kiss, flirting. He growls like an animal... dives into her closet... tearing open the doors, flinging away hanging clothes, he finds her white fur coat and puts it on... JUMP CUT -- him as he moves to her full-length MIRROR, contorting himself. She slides up behind him.</context>
      <utterance>You control the audience, like dogs, manipulate them Jim, one picture can control a million people, be anything you want -- growl at them, be ugly, be frightened, be selfish. Be man, woman, whild, animal. Live, die, return again. Anything you want. Everything is permitted.</utterance>
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause. She wants him. No longer so cool.</context>
      <utterance>Go on look at yourself, fall in love with yourself. You're your own audience now Jim. They want you. Worship and love and adore you...</utterance>
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Jim Morrison, the god of Rock and Cock...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the snake and you are the lute</utterance>
   <speaker>GLORIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our camera dwells on Jim in the mirror, closer, closer -- the image and the reality, which is which anymore -- where does it end? The Great Jim Morrison, The Shaman, then Pamela, Patricia, Gloria, a series of women who face after face fill the ancient gallery, interchangeable masks as PEOPLE ARE STRANGE climaxes and JIM's face SPINS OUT OPTICALLY TO:</context>
      <utterance>Exactly...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People are strange when you're a stranger Faces look ugly when you're alone Women seem wicked when you're unwanted Streets are uneven when you're down</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jim this is Tom... Baker, he's an actor, he was in Andy's movie and this is Count Ruspoli. He lives in Paris, but he's Italian. He's from a very famous family over there. They're seven hundred years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PR guy stays there, introduces himself to the count.</context>
      <utterance>Hi Jim, you are great... I see you at Ondine's with Bobby and Jimmy. It...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you like the way he talks. Isn't he cool?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... hey what's your trip?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saw your gig at 'The Scene'. Hot... very hot... You strung out? Here. Try this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom is obviously a major druggie. A popper -- joint trade- off going off. RAY's face leaning in distorted.</context>
      <utterance>Love your movies man. What a great penis...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, we're splitting man. Dorothy's waiting at the door. We'll get a bite at Max's and...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOHN DENSMORE appearing with a wasted looking ROBBIE who is giggling, high, and with a NEW GIRLFRIEND in tow.</context>
      <utterance>You can't leave. Where's your will to be weird man?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PR MAN is still next to Jim, jumping up and down excitedly waving across the room at nothing in particular. As the PHOTOGRAPHERS try to get Jim and the Doors in a photo opportunity.</context>
      <utterance>Get outta here man. This is fucking weird man.</utterance>
   <speaker>PR MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right this way Jim. Andy's in the bedroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go, y'see Norman Mailer, I hear he's here?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah can we meet him, he's great... just like he is.  You wanna meet him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... did he know who you were?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah sure, he's cool, come on, he's your hero!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wasted, emaciated Edie Sedgewick type floats into Jim's fractured POV -- introducing a MAN with a crew cut and silk suit.</context>
      <utterance>Nah... later...</utterance>
   <speaker>EDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Jim, this is Jake Johnson, you remember Jake Johnson -- the astronaut, he's just got back from outer space.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAKE JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like the Doors, I like the Doors, I like the Doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom Baker brings a tall, incredible looking BLONDE in black leather towards him.</context>
      <utterance>I like outer space.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at each other like two cats. Eye level stares that go on and on. She finally hisses in a German accent.</context>
      <utterance>Hey where's my joint?  There's this chick sings with the Velvet Underground, Andy's band. She says she can drink you under the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A voice to kill, looks to undress, fully as tall as Jim.</context>
      <utterance>I'm Nico. It's boring tonight. Some of us are going downtown to a new club. You want to come?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...elevate your taste in trolls man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vodka? Race you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your death...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanna go?... Come on let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She looks too freaky to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she floats away.</context>
      <utterance>Wait just a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on there's pussy Robbie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lynne is there, pretty, nods to Jim.</context>
      <utterance>Hey I met this chick Lynne, she wants to be alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on Jim, let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you guys wanna meet Andy Warhol?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you the truth, I can live without him. He's a freak. Let's get outta here. We got a show tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on man! I thought we were gonna be a band, the four of us -- and party all night, rock and roll!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go. Don't leave! You can't leave. I don't know what will happen. It might be Death.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment, strange. Slightly SLOW MOTION. Ray tapping Jim's shoulder goodbye... Robbie and John's faces passing on. As if they're parting -- in a symbolic way. Jim blinking in the same SLOW MOTION, looking. Nico is gone -- but Tom is there, across the room, waving. The INDIAN SHAMAN looks like he's standing there in a corner. Jim, ripped, heads for him, but the PR WOMAN cuts him off. Jim forgets he saw the Indian.</context>
      <utterance>Come on Jim, this isn't our scene, these people are vampires. We gotta stick together man, the four of us. Let's make the myths man.</utterance>
   <speaker>PR MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Past more faces. The Music has subtly shifted to STRANGE DAYS somewhere along the way.</context>
      <utterance>Right here Jim, right here. Andy's waiting. You know what you have in common is uniqueness.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Past a cache of QUEENS in white leather ogling Jim, one of them coming over boldly, chatting him up (AD LIB dimly heard), them grabbing his crotch and kissing him. Jim rearing back, laughing but wary. Past the RICH LADIES dripping with jewels and faces peeled from Brazilian sleep tanks and Swiss knives. Past a YOUNG MAN dressed in Jim Morrison leather pants with his hair and eye make-up, a warped image of Jim, smiling back at him.</context>
      <utterance>Strange days have found us Strange days have tracked us down They're going to destroy Our casual joys We shall go on playing or find a new town</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nico!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WARHOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it was such a big opening, we just had to go to Philadelphia, y'know, you were supposed to, mmm...</utterance>
   <speaker>PR GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANDY turning at the interruption. He looks like a chic voodoo doll. Holding an incongruous gold telephone in his arms like a teddy bear. Slightly SLOW MO as Warhol's black empty eyes confront Jim -- a pit of nothingness in them, amnesia, death. In Jim's SLOW MOTION reaction we read what he sees. Andy going on with his story, to the group that includes TOM BAKER.</context>
      <utterance>Andy! Andy!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(long pause)</context>
      <utterance>...but so many people showed up, the paintings were getting crushed, so they took them all down... um, it really looked great y'know... maybe uhhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>PR MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy is looking at Jim. Jim at Andy.</context>
      <utterance>...the walls. The blank walls. Andy was the art. Should do a show. Just walls. Today it's really about people, not what they do. It's the astronaut that matters, not the voyage, the actor, not the movie -- how do I say, it's the trip, not arriving.</utterance>
   <speaker>PR MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...you know what Andy says, some day everybody's gonna be famous for 15 seconds, but it won't mean anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They laugh. Andy's eyes hidden, face as white as styrofoam.</context>
      <utterance>That's too short. I need a coupla hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andy shows his eyes, gives Jim the gold telephone he's carrying.</context>
      <utterance>We'd just love to have you in our movies Jim, you're so beautiful, you'd be so good, you mmmm, here... this is for you Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vanishes, waving to somebody else. Jim holding the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Edie gave this to me and said mmmmm, I could talk to God with this. But I don't really have anything to say. So... mmmm now you can talk to God. Oh hi!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Strange days have found us And through their strange hours We linger alone Nico reappears waving at him to come quickly.</utterance>
   <speaker>NICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morrison!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TECHIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Testing one-two-three. Testing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROMOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, the Fire Marshall's not gonna let the show go on. Either you go back to your seats, you go to the aisle, you don't do that -- no show!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Lord Byron"? Really. You think? You like the poems?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like? I loved them! "Mad bad and dangerous to know." That's what they said about him. Your poems should be taken as seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are the kindest words I've ever heard in my life. No one has ever understood. Thank you.  Maybe I should always fuck my critics.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'know I don't even like rockers. They're sleazy. I made up my fuck list the other night -- out of 30 guys there were maybe three of them, y'know. I'm not a groupie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's do it, here, now... with the sound of the crowd. Like Nuremberg, wild German fucking.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like that hunh? Beg!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm begging! I'm begging you!</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna fuck me, Morrison, don't ever lie to me again. Ever!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About what!</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your father. Why do you tell me bullshit like your father's dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your problem with fathers! They're dead, both of them, I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim -- a look, struck.</context>
      <utterance>If he's so dead, then who answered the phone when I called the house?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't really think you'd get away with that, Morrison. An Admiral in the United States Navy. Who's at the Gulf of Tonkin when Vietnam starts. Your Dad's a Deputy Chief of Operations.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd he say? That was really stupid. Why didn't you just ask me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well naturally he wasn't too happy when I called. Your Mom wanted to talk but he shut her off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a fuckin' cunt. You could ruin his career if...</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fingering his pants, her hand slips inside. Teasing, dominating him. Her dark side radiant.</context>
      <utterance>What, I'm a "fuckin' cunt" because I called the house? Like it's hard to trace your school records. University of Florida, Albuquerque, New Mexico, Arlington, Virginia, Washington, D.C. Brother, sister, it's seven miles long baby -- it's all in the "The End", it's so easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim describes a small space between thumb and forefinger.</context>
      <utterance>Don't ever try to hide anything from me again. Okay? Go on... tell me. Did he make you cut your hair? Did he hit you, was he a bully? Did he love you? How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim makes a little larger space.</context>
      <utterance>And your mother?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim shakes his head, weary. Suddenly he's scared inside.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter anymore does it. Listen to them. It's you they want now. Not the Doors, not your mother or your father's child... They want you Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(the noise pounding)</context>
      <utterance>You're wrong. What they want I can't give... my death -- ripped to pieces -- do you feel their power?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have no choice, Jim. I see you up there like Icarus. I see you flying closer and closer to the sun. And your wings are melting...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim's ironic eyes, to the ceiling. Laden with a power to which he has married himself yet brave, resisting as she pulls his zipper down and goes to her knees in front of him. Shaking his head.</context>
      <utterance>I want to live, Patricia. I don't wanna die.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beefy COP stands there looking at them,</context>
      <utterance>Patricia... Patricia...</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatcha doing there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... nuthin'</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, outta there both of you. No one's allowed backstage. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You idiot, don't you know who...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE COP has no patience, grabs JIM by the arm and pulls. JIM shoves him off. THE COP pushes back. A shoving match.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm with the band man. It's cool. Take it easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go. NOW! You're both under arrest.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cop whips out a black can from his belt, sprays Jim.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, eat it man!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Patricia screaming at the COP grabs JIM, propelling him violently out the stall of the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Mace! Shit!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help! They got Jim!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SIDDONS and RAY running up with ROADIES and OTHERS.</context>
      <utterance>Why'd you blind me man? You blinded me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell happened!  Don't touch Jim. Get some water. Don't touch your eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey all he said was...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>COP 2 comes up.</context>
      <utterance>He was WHAT! He's Jim Morrison for chrissake. Jim, Jim -- you okay -- let's get you under the water here. Don't touch, you'll be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to have to issue a warrant for his arrest.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM guided back into the shower stall by his entourage, eyes blind as Oedipus, starts to laugh. A black Irish laugh. Ray looking on PATRICIA in the hallway. A beat, senses what happened.</context>
      <utterance>Are you NUTS!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you leave him alone lady, he doesn't need more shit in his life.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A precise military Drum Beat hits as we launch into "The Unknown Soldier".</context>
      <utterance>What do you know what Jim needs?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Hup two -- three -- four...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The famous drum roll, tension building. Sudden sound of guitar. Jim crumples to the ground. Blood shooting from his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Present arms!...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience is enrapt. Jim suddenly jumps up, looses the blood curdling scream of an aroused demon and the band bangs into Willie Dixon's BACK DOOR MAN.</context>
      <utterance>Make a grave for the unknown soldier Nestled in your hollow shoulder The unknown soldier Practice as the news is read Television children dead Bullet strikes the helmet's head It's all over The war is over!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the little girls unnerstan'... Joints sail onto the stage at his feet, ready to be smoked. A TEENAGE BOY &amp; GIRL make a break thru the cordon of COPS at the front of the stage, heading for Jim. The Cops chase them down mid-stage, and wrestle them back to the edge -- throwing them back into the audience.</context>
      <utterance>Well the men don't know</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danger fills the air, electric. Jim strutting, Indian like, up to one of the Cops, whipping off his hat and flipping it to the Crowd, which roars with approval. A couple Cops looking at Jim, sensing they're being challenged but not sure how. They shuffle and look offstage for direction. Their apparent impotence brings redoubled jeering from the Kids. RAY, next to his stick of incense on the organ, shares a look with JOHN as they head into the instrumental break in the song. There's something different about Jim -- more demonic, more driven -- a spirit has taken him over. RAY'S POV -- JIM catching his look, but no recognition in those eyes. They're dark pools, like Warhol's eyes. He turns away, taking the mike and off the cuff rapping improvisationally with the backbeat, keeping poetic meter.</context>
      <utterance>When all the good people are trying to sleep I'm out there making my midnight creep Yeah, cause I'm a backdoor man The men don't know But the little girls unnerstan'...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CROWD yells in acknowledgement, one stoned TEENAGER naked from the waist up and ripped on beer, yelling out.</context>
      <utterance>I wanna tell you 'bout something that happened just a few minutes ago right here in New Haven. This is New Haven isn't it? New Haven, Connecticut, United States of America?</utterance>
   <speaker>HECKLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>HEY MORRISON, is the West really the best or are you just stoned on weeeeeedddddd??????</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More COPS turning to face Jim from front stage, getting the point now. RAY sees it coming...</context>
      <utterance>...and then this little man came in there, this little man in a little blue suit and a little blue cap...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LIGHTS coming on suddenly, the AUDIENCE seething. Shouts of "Fuck em! Right on!"</context>
      <utterance>And he started pushing me and I pushed back and he didn't like that so he reached back there and got out his little can of mace. And sprayed it right in my eyes. And blinded me. Why? Cause I was alone in a room with a lady doing what he would like to be doing if he could ever get it up without a gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the United States of America. Land of the free. Home of the Brave man -- in God We Trust right? TURN</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More cops come out, snatch the microphone, as Jim flashes the audience a "touchy aren't they?" shrug.</context>
      <utterance>Say your thing man!</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO more COPS moving on Jim, pinning both his arms and dragging him off stage.</context>
      <utterance>Young man you've gone too far. The show's over. You're under arrest.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAY moving to intercede with SIDDONS and ROADIES.</context>
      <utterance>They're gonna beat the shit out of him man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey whatcha got here? A boy or a girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you care. You're gonna fuck him anyway... Okay rock star, let's see the backdoor you keep bawling about.  Where's the roach powder?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't he the prettiest long-haired boy y'ever saw?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Jim defiantly does so, Cop 2 looses a big cloud of roach powder into his long hair.</context>
      <utterance>Turn around rock star.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he's smacked by COP 2, sending him sprawling into the wall...</context>
      <utterance>You finished? You sure you're finished? Haven't you forgotten something -- the consolation prize they gave ya for taking your cock and balls? The guns. Why don't you use em you withered dicks! You shit- eating red-neck chickenshit bastards, I hope this makes your worthless lives...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better kill me cause I'm gonna come back and fuck everyone of your daughters...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>his friend, is there in the Engineer's booth, with the Door's SECRETARY, Leticia, and an elegant MYSTERY WOMAN. They're smoking dope, partying.</context>
      <utterance>I drink so I can talk to assholes. This includes me. Let's just say I was testing the bounds of reality -- that's-all -- I was curious... I kinda always preferred to be hated. Like Erich Von Stroheim in the movies... the man you loved to hate... it's meant to be ironic, courage wants to laugh. Y'know it's essentially a stupid situation. I go out on a stage and I howl for people. In me they see what they want to see -- some say the Lizard King, whatever that means, or some black-clad leather demon whatever that means... but really I think of myself as a sensitive, intelligent human being but with the soul of a clown which always forces me to blow it at the most crucial moment...  a fake hero... a joke the gods played on me... it's okay, I accept the joke... and smile. Death old friend, death and my cock, I can forgive my injuries in the name of wisdom, luxury, romance. Words got me the wound and will get me well. All join now in lament of my cock, a tongue of knowledge in the feathered night. Boys get crazy in the head and suffer. I sacrifice my cock on the alter of silence. The ENGINEER looking at him puzzled. Has Jim lost it? MIKE,</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey Jim, how 'bout hitting a strip- joint? It's getting late and we can...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The violent backbeat of THE WASP now picking up.</context>
      <utterance>Nah, later...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now listen to this I'll tell you about Texas Radio and the big beat soft driven slow and mad like some new language reaching your head with the cold sudden fury of a divine messenger let me tell you about heartache and the loss of God wandering, wandering in hopeless night out here on the perimeter there are no stars out here we is stoned, immaculate... but I tell you this: No eternal reward will forgive us now for wasting the dawn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's blood in the streets &amp; it's up to my knees She came Blood in the streets of Chicago She came Blood on the rise and it's following me Just about the break of day (etc) The river runs red down the legs of the city She came The women are crying red rivers of weeping The MONTAGE collides into an ECU on JIM -- drinking as if to silence the images, the sounds we hear and see on his face. Spirits crying for release. In alcoholic solace. He passes out, head hitting the bar. Jim's English friend, MIKE, walks in, throwing a harsh shaft of LA morning light across the dark bar and JIM's face, bleary eyed, passed out on the counter. He has a drinking paunch. With him are TOM BAKER, "TOM", the actor from the Warhol scene in New York and a huge biker type drinker named DOG, one of Jim's roadmen, a beard fanning his chest, tattoos everywhere. In the front of these three monoliths are about twenty beer bottles, numerous Jack Daniels bottles emptied and a lesbian BARTENDRESS pouring up a breakfast shot of bloody Marys... Mike hands Dog a breakfast in a brown paper bag.</context>
      <utterance>Blood is the rose of mysterious union!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delores pouring the bloody mary. As Mike scoffs at Jim passed out.</context>
      <utterance>Morning. Pour me breakfast Delores...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatsa matter with Jimbo? Can't handle it huh</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DOG reaching in, dragging Jim's face up by the hair. Sticks Mike's greasy eggs and bacon in front of Jim.</context>
      <utterance>Pussy whipped, man...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim is suddenly alert -- an instant and surprising transformation, without hangover, eager eyed.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Jim, come on babe, eat this. . . one last place to go. Ray's getting it on.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alive she cried! Right Dog, another cubic centimeter of chance  Ugh, I can't eat this stuff, it'll really make me sick. Gimme a Dos Equis will ya Delores? And a Ramos gin fizz with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck man did you fade or what, we were on a "death run" up to the 9000 building after the gig, you bet me a grand you'd walk the ledge.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go... Right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then mumbling about "gotta go home, sanctuary," pussy whipped. We were gonna film it! A thousand bucks!  Give him a double.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A triple, Tom, shem and shaun...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...imagine me and Morrison in a fuckin movie together, can you imagine two powerful two-fisted Irish fucking drinking guys in a movie, in a documentary movie!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll direct the shit out of it, man. Dennis Hopper can do it, I can do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he pisses on the floor next to the bar stool.</context>
      <utterance>...all of us direct it! In black and white. Call it "Zero." A real road movie! Two of these  you feel a lot better.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatcha doing! Oh fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you Morrison. You're outta here you fuckhead, get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on Jimbo, one more place to go. Ray's getting married man, this morning, remember! You're the best man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck Ray -- fuckin Pollock all he cares about's money. Fuckin sell out. You sold out too man. The last album's shit, and lemme tell ya something, people know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on Baker, lighten up.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all right. I like it</utterance>
   <speaker>DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on man, toe the line. Boots to the pavement. Let's walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>OMIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sequence omitted from original script.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TOM catching up to him.</context>
      <utterance>I LOVE L.A. -- the best neon. City of Night! City of Light... why are you going to work? You're not slaves, you're free, cars, you're free...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awright shaddup Morrison, just cause you don't gotta work.  Give me some of your money, asshole, and I'll yell anything you fucking want.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that speckled motherfucker you just took? Give me some!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moving through traffic. Horns honking, incessant insanity.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta fail to succeed Tom, gotta surrender to the waiting tides.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HIPPIE PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Awright, the vibrations are right now, I feel peace and love here today, I feel a grooviness coming on, do you Ray Manzarek take your lady love...  fill the white wings of death, scatter your ashes forever... JIM slinks up through the trees, alone, quiet, changing faces to face them as SUMMER'S ALMOST GONE plays sinuously.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Summer's almost gone Where will we be When the summer's gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the fuck you been man?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles innocently. Ray, a beat, turns away. Pam coming over, squeezes his hand, sweetly, no fights today, she's his lady.</context>
      <utterance>Man, I been here all the time... over there watching. I'm really happy for you Ray you found life...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, I need some safflower oil. Do you think you can find me a bottle?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Safflower oil, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And get some Gravy Train for Sage.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim looking, zombie-like for the food. PEOPLE of course stare at him, knowing who he is.</context>
      <utterance>I'll meet you up front.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeking in his pocket -- nothing but a credit card and a rumpled old dollar bill... The faces of the Hippies looking at him. With one of the magic markers on the counter, he draws in his beard on his cover shot.</context>
      <utterance>Jim you got any cash?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning found us clearly unaware Noon burned gold into our hair At night we swam the laughing sea When summer's gone where will we be</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only another $95,000 but I could get the best clothes. From India, Morocco Jim, clothes you can't find anywhere, we could get the richest people to come, Miles Davis, Cher, the Stones, it's gonna be the best boutique on La Cienega Jim... why are we walking, how come we don't have a car?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...cause you lost it. It's fun to walk, isn't it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that was months ago. We got another car.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which car?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The red one with the black interior. Remember it was a shift and I didn't like it. What happened to it?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah... I wrecked it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Jim! Damn! Where's the Gravy Train? Whatsamatter? What are you on? You promised you wouldn't drink today.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No Ma I ain't drinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not gonna drink any more are you Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No Ma I ain't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're gonna change those stinky leathers you been wearing for three weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know 'bout that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh -- just some low grade acid. It's not heavy.  Pam, read my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Jim! Goddamit! You PROMISED. I made the duck! People are coming! Ray and Dorothy think we're flaky enough and I... you said you'd wait till after, you're going to peak before me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey it's okay, it's okay... come on, we'll trip and then eat our feast.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Putting down the bags at their porch, pausing. He moves to her, kisses her, conciliatory and gentle.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(spawning like minnows)</context>
      <utterance>Come on baby, y'know it's a good thing for Ray and Dorothy I think women are such noble creatures -- they carry on your name with dignity after you die.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you saying? You wanna marry me Jim?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think women basically have a comic approach to life -- I mean how can they not when they look up in the dark and see a dangling penis, seeking entry. It looks like a face y'know -- little beard "Hi mom"  I wanna get inside you. Look around.  "Do the funky chicken, do dah, dah, funky chicken do da da "love my girl" -- She's cracking up now. As he takes the acid out, holds it in front of her like a sacrament.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she takes the tablet on her tongue, swallows.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go wild child, let's get out there Romeo and Juliet, Marilyn Monroe and Vincent Van Gogh, Jim and Pam, rock and roll  ...all the poetry has wolves in it, but one Pam -- the most beautiful one of all -- dances in a ring of fire and throws off the challenge with a shrug</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it when you sing to me</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Strains of YOU'RE LOST, LITTLE GIRL drift in, setting a more ominous tone.</context>
      <utterance>'cause I'm the poet and you're my muse</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim is somewhere else -- pulling out the DUCK which is totally charred black. He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>What am I going to do about these papers! Jim, Jim -- you really need someone to organize this stuff. Your handwriting's just like a little kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAY and DOROTHY walking in. ROBBIE and JOHN general commotion. Dorothy immediately seeing the duck, runs to it...</context>
      <utterance>My God look at this. I wonder if William Blake was ever this disorganized.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh the duck!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get some drinks, man. Over there  Pam!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna be your editor now, seriously I'm going to organize all your stuff. I'm gonna take out all the fuck words.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PEOPLE are introducing themselves, coming in from all over, like in a shoebox. Hippies. Doors people... now TOM BAKER with MIKE and DOG... Now an aggressive Chuck Berry type BLACK SINGER with John's GIRLFRIEND. Then a TIMOTHY LEARY look- alike appears. CHATTER blending everywhere as we build to a vast confusion at Jim and Pam's party.</context>
      <utterance>You're lost little girl You're lost little girl You're lost, tell me Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she takes the tablet on her tongue, swallows.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go wild child, let's get out there Romeo and Juliet, Marilyn Monroe and Vincent Van Gogh, Jim and Pam, rock and roll  "Clothed in sunlight Restless in wanting Dying of fever Changed shapes of an empire Vast promissory notes of joy How it has changed you How slowly estranged you Solely arranged you Beg you for mercy"</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pam... Honey, you're trying too hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not -- I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's some great poetry here Jim, some wonderful ideas.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah but nobody wants to read poetry anymore, nobody cares, it's not like important y'know. Just put it away. Not right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darling Pamela, I brought you a little something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're my girl, that's who...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Jim...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right so I do. I live my life the way I want. I don't want anyone expecting anything from me -- including you! You don't like it then get the fuck out!  Oh hi Anne. You know Pam? She's a little pissed off right now but...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay Jim let's eat that duck.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on Pam, let's put out the plates...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anne O'Riordan. Are you Anne O'Riordan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must be Pamela</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You actually put your dick in this woman Jim?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I... sometimes yeah</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand... I really do but don't ever think that Jim's gonna love you or take care of you. You're one of a hundred you know Anne uncomfortable, Jim getting pissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey -- don't you know when to stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look who's talking</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to think Jim can make up his own mind who he loves and who he doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAMELA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't kid yourself sweetheart, Jim's crazy but he's not that crazy. He loves me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, it's not gonna be one of these dinners is it Jim? How 'bout some turkey?</utterance>
   <speaker>BAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love it!! Far out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John's GIRLFRIEND is trying to introduce the BLACK SINGER to Jim.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, let's go into the kitchen. The duck's ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLFRIEND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, you should meet Chuck Vincent. He came specially to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you the white boy makin' all that money.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still can't hold a candle to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey everybody Chuck Vincent's here. Yo sho can't boy, I ain't heard much of yor stuff. What I done heard don't show me much.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So fuck you man...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chuck Vincent man! No. He's right... Chuck Vincent's here, everybody, Chuck Vincent.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The charred TURKEY is being carved up. A moment of peace, then: Pamela walks up to Jim with a bowl of sweet potatoes in her arms, an announcement.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't no honkey ever gonna sing the blues, you ain't been there. Where dat turkey at?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just have one thing to say to you --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOM &amp; MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray about to lose his temper with Tom, checks it.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah FUCK OFF MAN!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUCK VINCENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Exiting with the other Doors... Dog picking the duck up from the floor.</context>
      <utterance>This party's gettin' low rent. Let's go babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pamela is sobbing, in a quiet bewildered voice, repeating to herself.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, fuck him, let's eat this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Jim... saddened.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell's happened to us Jim? What the hell is happening to us. There's some great poetry...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOORS SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're lost little girl  You're lost, tell me Who are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ladies and Gentlemen, from Los Angeles California -- The DOORS!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim! Your Mom's here with your brother. What do you want me to do with 'em?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SIDDONS yelling at MIKE, the roadie.</context>
      <utterance>There's been a slaughter here Don't stop to speak or look around Your gloves and fan are on the ground We're getting out of town we're going on the run And you're the one I want to come Not to touch the earth Not to see the sun Nothing left to do But run, run, run Let's run, let's run...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vice Squad says one more "fuck or shit" they're gonna close us down man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim ignoring all this, one hand cupped to his ear listening for the sound of the earth, gone into a shaman-like state, weird spiralling chords carrying over the following MONTAGE of hallucinatory insanity.</context>
      <utterance>Stick my dick in their ear!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>House upon the hill Moon is lying still...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM'S POV entering the bedroom -- PAMELA naked in bed with the COUNT, is snorting heroin. Shadows of the trees and leaves blowing against the walls. Their voices, dim, distant.</context>
      <utterance>Shadows of the trees witnessing the wild breeze Come on baby run with me Run with me, let's run...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh hi... I didn't realize you were entertaining.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits up on the bed, wobbly. The COUNT, more sophisticated in these things, lights a cigarette from the bedside table, revealing heroin paraphernalia.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>COUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scusi Jimmy, I hope you're cool about this...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't forget your smack on the way out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you about that shit. Or are we talking about death choices here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just doing my thing, just like you said, it's my thing, why can't I have a thing. Ow! You're hurting me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah sanctuary!... a soft place to hide.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he picks up a can of lighter fluid and douses the closet door and the floor.</context>
      <utterance>...from you, you pig!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We INTERCUT with PAM inside the closet yelling for mercy inside.</context>
      <utterance>I'll give you a place to hide forever!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HIGH PRIESTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...it is a blending of souls on a karmi and cosmic plane that affects your future incarnations on this planet. Death does not part -- only lack of love -- and the vow is forever in the Goddess' sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run with me, run with me Run with me, let's run Some outlaws live by the side of a lake The minister's daughter's in love with a snake Jim faints.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAY, gone into his own trance, happening to look up from his keyboard. His eyes widen. His POV -- an INDIAN SHAMAN hovers over the microphone. Cloaked in hides, his face obscured by a horned headdress with colored tails and feathers streaming down his shoulders, rattles in each fist, the BONFIRE glowing...</context>
      <utterance>Who lives in a well by the side of the road Wake up girl! We're almost home We shall see the gates by morning We shall be inside by evening Sun, sun, sun Burn, burn, burn Moon, moon, moon!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Soon -- soooooooon... SOOOOOOONNNN... The COPS can't hold. TEENAGE SHOCK TROOPS hitting the stage, clambering up. The stage becoming a riot. Cops wading in with sticks. ROADIES and BODYGUARDS yanking the MUSICIANS from their places...</context>
      <utterance>I will GET YOU</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As DOG hauls the shaman king off in a bearhug, smiling stoned, immaculate.</context>
      <utterance>I am the Lizard King I can do anything</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man wow -- watsa matter Jim? It was beautiful... wasn't it? Kim? Wasn't it great?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was all right Jim continues to cry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey it's no big deal. I like to cry when I come. It's close to death... maybe you'd better go home now before your mama gets home.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is home Jim</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know you've always been good to me in bed Judy. And it was nice of you to bring your friend. I want to keep seeing both of you but it can't be all the time y'know. It would be a night every few weeks or so. That's just the way I am, I'm not dependable. I can't be a boyfriend. Would you do that? I mean could you handle it? That way? I don't want you to get hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already been hurt enuf' by you Jim, I don't have much to lose do I?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...do you love me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...yes</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's so concerned, so solicitous that both girls crack up laughing.</context>
      <utterance>...Well, just think about it awhile. Call me when you get your new number...  Hey that's a really nice outfit you're wearing, you really have good taste in clothes. How long have you two been friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A knock at the door.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come back later!  Who is it!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whyn't you come back later. I don't have any clothes on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, I gotta talk! Let me in please. I gotta talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pamela listening at the door. She's on the second story of a cheap motel overlooking a boring parking lot on the edge of La Cienega.</context>
      <utterance>Now Pam sweetheart, I'm busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, I know there's someone in there, I can't believe you're doing this again. You're disgusting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well you see Pam there's this crazy girl in here, she's just lying on the bed with her legs open and I don't know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>FUCK YOU!!! I want to see her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your cousin Lizzie, you don't want to see her. Go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're all sisters, let me see her. Jim,... I got this wonderful leg of lamb in the oven for supper... and the house is immaculate. Sage is waiting. He wants you to play with him... are you coming...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(no answer, she yells)</context>
      <utterance>Jim goddamit answer me!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>VARIOUS PEOPLE are hanging around the studio listening -- a couple of HIPPIE CHICKS, A BURN VICTIM w/ bandages, a CHARLES MANSON TYPE, a Siberian HUSKY, the TIM LEARY type. Paper bags, burgers, bottles, California rose, apple juice, hard- boiled eggs. In the ENGINEERING BOOTH. ROTHCHILD, the producer, is displeased.</context>
      <utterance>What was that promise you made Why don't you tell me what she said What was that promise that she made I'm gonna love you Till the heaven stops the rain I'm gonna love you Till the stars fall from the sky For you and I...</utterance>
   <speaker>DENSMORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his fucking problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right here baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he stalks out of the booth. Raging, near-incomprehensible. A small portable TV set is playing the "Dean Martin Show" low on one end of the recording console. Around the room the detritus of the time -- Mailer's "Armies of the Night", The Stone's "Beggar's Banquet", Janis' "Cheap Thrills", Traffic, The Band.</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you suck a fart out of my asshole you slave driving facist motherfucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear the booze, I hear the smokes Jim, I don't hear the voice and babe I didn't hear the song!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are we going to tonight Paul! 67 takes! It's stale!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, let's try something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna sing blues. This stuffs getting too self-conscious.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause it's my song man?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's sing "Rock is Dead"! You're all a buncha slaves... "Oh come all ye faithful."</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up Jim! I don't understand! I don't. What are ya doing! I love you like a brother, I do, but why are you fucking this up. It's a perfect radio song for chrissake! No one wants to hear the blues anymore! Think like a singer, you're the only baritone crooner we got left... Sinatra, Elvis, Crosby, you're as good as they are, but WHY ARE YOU</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray, Siddons, Robbie, John, shuffling for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Catchy, you sold it to a commercial?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For that? How much did you get for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, Jim...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was $50,000. You weren't talking to us that week and we figgered you...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You figured? What the fuck is this Ray?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not like a big deal Jim, the song's already been commercialized, the money was great. Robbie wrote the lyrics and he didn't mind, neither did I, neither did John... we gotta get to TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?... are you saying? Are we the Doors? One for all and all for one? Do you know what you're saying to those millions of kids! "Just kidding, not real". That's what you're saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh come on man, you think just cause you're the lead man in the band you can run the whole show.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PAMELA, looking drawn and pathetic finds this moment to walk into the studio.</context>
      <utterance>You think I was kidding Ray?  Hey John, those are interesting shoes, you like those shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Then do you want 50 of those shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. Turning to Ray.</context>
      <utterance>Then what do you need more money for?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm dying Ray. I wasn't kidding. Maybe you were. But I'll tell you something, it's not about these desires you have man, or money, or these records, it's about breaking through wasn't it? You just lost something man.  We all lost something boys. We lost something.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so Jim. There's a bigger picture here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A small smile flickers Jim's face as he picks up the small TV and like a quarterback, hurls it, spinning end over end from his corner of the Control Room towards Ray and Rothchild and the Doors. They dive for the floor as it smashes to bits into the wall behind the tape machines.</context>
      <utterance>There sure is. In your fucking face!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He seems pleased to distract his anger into her. She doesn't seem to notice anything unusual going on. The Doors silent, feeling Jim's rage.</context>
      <utterance>Just kidding...  Hi Pam. Just watchin' some TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted you to find us Jim. It meant nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others all look away embarrassed. This is certainly a moment the ordinary partner might turn away from Pamela, her tears running, but her pathacy, her inability to deal with pain is precisely what moves Jim the most -- a side of himself in her -- an ultimate weakness she has, he shares. As he goes to her, puts his arms gently around her.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have to torture me Jim. Let me make it up to you, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's alright honey, it's gonna be alright. You're my girl and that's the way it's always gonna stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rothchild looking to Botnick and to Ray. But the real look, the unforgiving one, is from Jim to Ray who feels it. Rothchild douses the lights in the studio.</context>
      <utterance>So, let's keep that money machine rolling. Come on guys...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right on Jimbo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the control booth RAY and ROBBIE share a look. The lights have been dimmed in Jim's booth, and he's weaving back and forth a bottle of Ripple in his hand as they kick in with the music. Camera closing now on Jim in the tender section, on the money.</context>
      <utterance>Where the hell did she go?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the darkened booth, PAM is on her knees his pants worked down around his ankles, caressing him, sucking him off.</context>
      <utterance>Can you give me sanctuary I must find a place to hide A place for me to hide...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...sing to me, Jim, sing to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The DOORS sense it. ROTHCHILD knows it, hushed. Magic's suddenly in the air once more as we jump stanzas to:</context>
      <utterance>Can you find me soft asylum I can't make it any more The man is at the door</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Jim's voice has now gone off key, floating carefree, drifting -- drifting away. ROTHCHILD chuckles, philosophically. The Doors in control booth start leaving. Robbie goes back out to get his personal items. But the OVERDUB still plays over the booth as Jim doesn't realize. We take liberties cutting around on the song.</context>
      <utterance>Catacombs, nursury bones Winter women Streets and shoes, avenues Leather riders selling shoes  Successful hills are here to stay Everything must be this way Gentle street where people play Welcome to the soft parade</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Doors and ROTHCHILD all exiting, leaving BOTNICK the engineer to clean up some technical things... and of course the two occupants of the darkened booth.</context>
      <utterance>All our lives we sweat and save Building for a shallow grave  The soft parade has now begun Listen to the engines hum People out to have some fun A cobra on my left Leopard on my right</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside the booth, two shadows breathe deep, huddled on the floor in each other's arms. A whisper out of the dark.</context>
      <utterance>Calling on the dogs  When all else fails You can whip the horses' eyes And make them sleep And cry. The music stops. Silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGINEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's send out for some pizza Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(pause)</context>
      <utterance>Nah, how 'bout some tacos when we're through?  The world on fire Taxi from Africa The grand hotel he was drunk a big party last night back, going back in all directions sleeping these insane hours I'll never wake up in a good mood again I'm sick of these stinky boots Do you know we are being led to slaughters by placid admirals? And that fat slow generals are getting obscene on young blood? Do you know we are ruled by TV?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RADIO DJ/CRITIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A hot night in Miami January '69 -- every space in the auditorium is consumed... unfortunately the Doors have long since sold out. They've become an act. Morrison "falls" off the stage at least every other performance. "The Soft Parade" album only confirms the plasticity of their approach. Songs like "Touch Me" and "Follow Me Down" are not the Doors we once knew. So the question is: Why am I here? Are funerals entertainment? DENSMORE looks on from the stage wings, withdraws -- to RAY nearby.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENSMORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He ain't gonna show! I know it man. We should fuckin' go on without him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bill's with him. They're an hour away, he'll get him here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim slams has shot glass on the bar. He's got a beard for the first time, looking like a tribal elder.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamit Jim! We missed one already, we gotta get this one man!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the WAITRESS takes the order</context>
      <utterance>Four more all around and up and down!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be so melodramatic Bill, it's not fun anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't fly sober.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim, you don't show for this one, we're dead, the whole group -- no more bookings.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I care.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on Jim, we'll get fuckin' laid in Miami.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need the work Jim! They're making us post a $10,000 bond just to show up -- we're the only group in rock-n- roll with a fuck clause!  Get him on the fuckin' plane. That's what I pay you for.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're an awful little guy to be talking like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chump change, we're working for chump change.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at you, you're a pathetic fuckin' slob and so are all your friends!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got an idea Bill, you're fired.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to 'em! They're not coming for the music anymore. They're coming to see a fuckin' freak show!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think it's easy for him. He moves left he's got vice squad, on the right narcs -- and the audience just waiting for him to get busted.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wanted it! Not us. I just don't fuckin' get the point anymore. I never did I guess. Y'ask me he's just become a drunken fuckin' asshole that's what. And he's gonna take us down with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Compassion was never your forte man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robbie strums his guitar, breaks the tension in the room. A lick of "Five to One".</context>
      <utterance>Don't lecture me Mr. Philosopher, you never felt a fuckin thing in your life. I loved that man. I loved what he was.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It ain't the old Jim that's for sure. I think he's living for everybody else man and somewhere along the way he's lost his own self.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The wine man, the ancient wine. The ancient wine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something he once told us. About Dionysos. When the madness took over...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Rita Hager and if...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(guffaws)</context>
      <utterance>If your name is Rita, then yor ol man must be ol man Rita!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM, MIKE &amp; DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That ol man Riva, he just keep rolling along!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BABY, with her MOTHER, stares at Jim fascinated. He lifts his dark glasses, winks back at her.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me sir, my father is not my old man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the event of a decrease of pressure, pull the oxygen mask to your...</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ma ol lady had one of those but she calls it a diaphragm when I'm eating her out!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, it's a douche bag on a dixie cup.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry sir, but you're embarrassing me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great tits.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Other PASSENGERS looking over.</context>
      <utterance>Come on guys, cool it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon Paul, you can get us some heroin man.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No I can't and I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause I don't want to participate in anything that would accomplish your goal?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh and what is my goal Paul? Death?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Death old friend".</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong. I just want the pure beauty of absolute zero and sing the blues man -- do nuthin, go nowhere, just be.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With that waistline Jimbo you got no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with being a large mammal, a big beast like a tank. I feel great!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. What's wrong with being fat.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean "Crawling King Flab"? Rock is cock babe and your rock is dyin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rock is death! There is no longer belief. Hey, I'll write poetry and direct movies.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what are you offering? Sex? You can't get it up. Salvation? You can't even save yourself. Come on Jim, you're not gonna be remembered.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss?...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some love.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll still be talking about Jim when you're a walk on Baker. I'll make you a deal. When you do something, I'll criticize it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you both should take your heads out of the toilet bowl. After "Soft Parade" You need an album sweetheart.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should take it outta your ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first two novels come along they love you, next few they slam but if you stay around long enough, one day they say, "hey he's part of the national psyche".</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you drinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(lifts her skirt)</context>
      <utterance>Screwdrives-her.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to have to call the captain if you can't control these people. I guarantee that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...if you live long enough, don't kid yourself Jimbo -- you're all alone out there, Jimbo, cept for me, cause you're too wacked out man, they're scared, you're too fuckin crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't mad, Tom. I was only interested in freedom.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit! You're bored, you're not free. You tested all the limits, fame, fucking, money, -- whatcha gonna do now Jimbo! When the music's over, when you're too fat and ugly to get on a stage, whatcha gonna do for act three -- puke on Heaven's door?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen you two bit fuckin actor, you underestimate the audience. You think they all want a better job, a house, two cars, money, that's what you think but you know what they really want, Tom, in their lives, what they really want --</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you ignorant devil's asshole slave!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you. Something sacred. My cock is sacred. Suck on that!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A full fledged food fight in progress. Dog, Tom, Jim, Mike pushing and shoving. A drink spills over an innocent</context>
      <utterance>I don't eat shrimp.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The STEWARDESS coming up with the CAPTAIN.</context>
      <utterance>Incoming!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ALL RIGHT!! If you young men don't change your attitude right now, when we get to Miami you're going to be arrested.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(reflexively)</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>YESSIR -- you asshole.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As captain of this ship I'm placing all four of you under arrest. The FBI will...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what! What'd we do!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JIM stunned in his drunkenness. SIDDONS and ROTHCHILD protesting AD LIBS.</context>
      <utterance>Read me my rights, motherfuckers... motherfuckin bulls!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PROMOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took 'em out! What's wrong with that! We stuffed an extra five thou in there.  Where the fuck you been!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That wasn't THE FUCKING IDEA MAN!! We're gonna sue you!... We're pulling the plug.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROMOTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So sue me! You're playing or you ain't leaving here with your equipment sonny!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, JOHN arguing with RAY and JIM who sways, drunk. The FBI agents get lost in the background.</context>
      <utterance>We're not playing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going out there man!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at him! I'm not going out there 'till I get some sorta guarantee he's gonna stay in line. I've had it with this shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatsa matter, scared Johnny boy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're pushing death Morrison. Everybody thinks we're drug addicts cause of you Morrison.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We the Beatles yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We took drugs to EXPAND MINDS ASSHOLE, not ESCAPE. I'M NOT GOING OUT THERE</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey John y'ever eaten human flesh? When we get to New York, I know this chick...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going out there!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As JIM brings up a tiny vial with a lubricating head on it, holds it to Robbie's lips playfully. They're in the shadows.</context>
      <utterance>We'll talk tomorrow, we'll settle it. Just do it tonight man and...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...just a touch Robbie, it's the funkiest stuff, you'll play like an orgasm tonight...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No man come on, I don't want any.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something so sincere in Jim's eyes. Robbie takes the fatal lick. Jim smiles manically as the NUREMBERG SOUNDS of the CROWD drown them out.</context>
      <utterance>...just a little lick, come on trust me... for old times, the four of us, let's get together one more time,... the Doors man... Please. For me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you love pain man, but you run from it every chance you get.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TEENAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then splits at a full run thru the crowd chased by the perplexed Cops. Everybody surging back towards the stage as JIM looses one of his primal SCREAMS.</context>
      <utterance>Wow!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slobbers, drunk, slouches, stumbles, regains his balance. The Crowd loves it, but Ray senses something wrong. Robbie starts to feel the effects of the acid Jim gave him -- his eyes registering fear.</context>
      <utterance>YAAAAAOOOOOOOOOOWWWWWW... Love my girl!  Five to one One in five No one here gets out alive You gets your baby I'll get mine Gonna make it, baby If we try</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During the instrumental break, Jim picks up one of the roses from the floor, pokes it at John on the drums, who whacks it to death on his skins. Jim starts to whirl the mike cord like a slingshot or bolo, in an ever-widening arc... ...it flies off and smashes into the head of the PROMOTER at the edge of the stage arguing with SIDDONS. The man is staggered, weaving, Siddons helping him to a FIRST AID TEAM.</context>
      <utterance>The old get old The young get stronger May take a week And it may take longer They got the guns But we got the numbers Gonna win yeah -- WE'RE TAKING OVER!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PHOTOGRAPHERS flashing cameras. BAKER urging him on from the wings as he passes out. A GIRL runs onto the stage, dumps a bottle of champagne on Jim's head. Jim takes his shirt off, soaking wet. The CROWD is also stripping in the heat, shirts, blouses, screaming so much now they are obviously way past listening to any song. It has become a view of the future -- the NAKED GIRL and BOY dancing stark naked drugged out in the middle of it all, the FAT GIRL prowling naked on the edge of the stage before she's arrested, the FIGHTS in the Crowd, fists, blood, a black man chased and beaten, the sense of Altamont here, the hippie flower trip gone to shit -- it's all come down here tonight, the end of an era.</context>
      <utterance>Your ballroom days are over baby Night is drawing near Shadows of the evening Crawl across the years You walk across the floor With a flower in your hand Tryin to tell me no one understands</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops singing suddenly, squinting out into the madness. The arena echoes with the uncomprehending chant of the Mob...</context>
      <utterance>Trade in your hours for a handful of dimes Gonna make it baby -- in our prime Get together one more time Get together</utterance>
   <speaker>MOB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get together one more time Get together one more time SPECIAL EFFECT -- the INDIAN GHOST is leaving Jim's body -- spectrally moving off him, hovering there in the air, its eyes -- the face of a dying Indian on an Arizona highway -- then gone. A moment, only three, four beats. An optical illusion? Maybe. Or is it saying, 'now you are just a white man'... maybe not. As it drifts off in a cloud, into the vast audience's EYEBALL.</context>
      <utterance>...one more time</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waits. INTERCUTS of the FACES in the crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Lettin people tell you what you're gonna do! Lettin people push you around! How long you think it's gonna last! How long you gonna let them push you around!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Light My Fire"! Play "Light My Fire"!! Come on Jim...  Take your clothes off man! Get wild! Fuck me baby. Fuck me girl, suck my cock honey around the world! Mexican whore suck my prick! Keeper of the royal sperm man! CELEBRATE THE LIZARD</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, come on, come on and FUCK me babe! Can't you see that I am not afraid</utterance>
   <speaker>HEY WAIT A MINUTE...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miami Beach Florida hunh? I was BORN and RAISED not far from here... went to Florida State...  Then I GOT SMART. I went to California where you can let your hair grow long and walk down the street without people calling you a FREAK... They're trying to CHANGE THE WORLD out there in California.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, STOP THE WAR MAN, PEACEEE...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim pulling his shirt off -- barechested -- waving it like a toreador in front of his leather crotch.</context>
      <utterance>NO I'm not talkin' 'bout NO REVOLUTION. I'm not talkin 'bout no DEMONSTRATION. I'm talking 'bout HAVING SOME FUN. I'm talkin' 'bout DANCIN. I'm talkin 'bout LOVE. I'm talkin' 'bout some LOVE. LOVE LOVE LOVE LOVE... LOVE!!!! Grab your friend -- and LOVE him. Come oooooaaaannnnn. Yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He saunters to the edge of the stage. Hisses at them. He clasps his crotch, leering at a cute LITTLE GIRL in the front row, shaking it at her. Her BOYFRIEND, pissed at Jim, runs for the stage. Jim unzips his leathers.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't nobody gonna love my ass? Come on... I need ya. There's so many of ya out there and nobody's gonna love me! C'mon -- what'cha come here for anyway? You didn't come here for music. You didn't come here to see a good band. You came here for THIS didn't ya...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm lonely out here -- Ya wanna SEE IT... COME ON SWEETHEART... I need it, I NEED IT, need ya, need ya,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it off! Take it all off!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He feigns opening his belt and exposing himself, flipping his shirt back and forth over the crotch in a mock striptease.</context>
      <utterance>What if I pull it out fer ya!! And SHAKE IT AROUND!!! Will that do it for you! Would ya, would ya, would ya!! Now watch -- I'm gonna show it to ya!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A flock of TEENAGE GIRLS are sure they've seen it, hysterical.</context>
      <utterance>There it was! Ya see it? Ya see it?... Ya wanna see it again?</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw it!... Yes, yes! Jim! Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>TEENAGE GIRL 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where? I didn't see it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Who is out there leading his naked drunken FLOCK, hundreds of them in a phallic Pied Piper dance thru the darkened seaplane hanger. From BREAK ON THROUGH PART TWO:</context>
      <utterance>Where's the guy with the penis!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM ET AL &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know the day destroys the night Night divides the day Try to run, try to hide</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JUDGE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A blues riff goes by -- brief, ghostly from RUNNING BLUE.</context>
      <utterance>...you are charged under four counts with lewd behavior, simulated masturbation, public drunkenness, profanity, and public exposure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM SONG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Poor Otis dead and gone Left me here to sing his song Pretty little girl with the red dress on Poor Otis dead and gone</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The PRESS SECTION is full as Jim's older LAWYER argues in front of the JURY, a distant voice.</context>
      <utterance>I can't believe this is happening I can't believe all these people are sniffing each other &amp; backing away, teeth grinning, hair raised, growling, here in the slaughtered wind This is it No more fun the death of all joy has come</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Honor, I would like to bring to the Court's attention the contemporary Broadway musical "Hair" in which cast members disrobe and appear naked on the stage.</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inadmissable evidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM VOICE OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had a vision of America Seen from the air 28,000 ft. &amp; going fast A one-armed man in a Texas parking labyrinth A burnt tree like a giant primeval bird in an empty lot in Fresno</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your Honor... any difference from the Miami nightclubs where comedians frequently incorporate profanity into their acts</utterance>
   <speaker>JUDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Inadmissable evidence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM VOICE OVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The backbeat of WHEN THE MUSIC'S OVER starts, into its spiralling descent.</context>
      <utterance>Miles &amp; miles of hotel corridors &amp; elevators, filled with citizens Motel Money Murder, Madness Change the mood from glad to sadness Play the ghost song baby</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PRESS section is now down to about THREE bored FACES, one of them PATRICIA KENNEALY who looks pregnant. JIM smiles at her.</context>
      <utterance>...this is a major First Amendment violation by the Police and Politicians of Miami. Every witness they've brought has admitted under oath to not actually seeing the client's genitals -- except one who...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cancel my subscription to the Resurrection Send my credentials to the house of detention I got some friends inside</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause. PATRICIA -- four and a half months pregnant, stares. A glary window onto a balcony overlooking the sea with Florida palms and a strip of beach. A room in a highrise hotel. Jim's mess is everywhere.</context>
      <utterance>...Well, you gonna get rid of it? Fucked up people y'know, crazies, unwanted Indians just throw it in the river.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't fucking believe you just said that!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Patricia, wouldn't it be better to have a kid with someone who wanted to be its father?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'd be a fucking genius, that's what it'd be! You and me. The child would be a god, goddess!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look. She's stunned, ugly wrath gathering. He tries to soothe her.</context>
      <utterance>It'd be a monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got this trial dragging on me, Patricia. I couldn't support the kid -- I can't afford it and I don't want the responsibility right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a COWARD!! A LITTLE BOY!! The only way you can't afford it is emotionally. You forgot your vows man. They were forever in the goddess' sight. Death doesn't part, only love Jim!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls a dagger with a skull's head on it, goes for him.</context>
      <utterance>Come on Patricia, I was stoned... it seemed like the fun thing at the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna cut your balls off Morrison!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>FUCK YOU. I'm gonna have the kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it'll be your kid. If you want the abortion I'll pay for it and I'll come up to New York to be with you when you have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bullshit Morrison  You know who you are...  NO. What difference does it make. You know, you never pretended. I did. I don't even like kids particularly,  but I don't want the other thing either. I guess what I really want is to throw myself off this fucking balcony  Well now that you've fucked the future, Morrison, have you fucked everything?...  Have you looked at yourself in the mirror. Your stomach...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She suddenly grasps him, clutching, hunger, lust.</context>
      <utterance>Please don't say those things to me, Patricia.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck me one last time, you worthless piece of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the scream of the butterfly Come back baby Back into my arms On Jim's face.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...endorsed by President Richard Nixon!  The immoral conduct of degenerates such as Jim Morrison is an unacceptable insult to this country and the principles for which it stands...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're getting tired of hanging around Waiting around with our heads to the ground I hear the gentle sound Very near yet very far Very soft, yeah, very clear Come today, come today</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well uh, it's designed to wear you down y'know... when that rap sheet says the "United States of America versus You" it takes you down day by day, specially when no one really gives a shit about, y'know, the First Amendment that's on trial here... Nobody says anything about that, it's just uh did you take your pants off y'know, I mean that's not what it's about, it's about freedom, that's what it's about... but who cares, right? Freedom exists in a schoolbook.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...but the promoters are cancelling your shows, will this affect the way you play?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I can only open doors, M'am. I can't drag people thru 'em. I'm no savior.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you've called yourself a shaman?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I? Well, I'll tell ya, my words stand a far better chance of being around a hundred years from now than my waistline. As he goes into the courtroom, a dolled up REPORTER 1, the local anchor-lady turns to her camera.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHORLADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The question that will be answered today: Did Jim Morrison or did he not take off his pants last March? This is...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I booked you round trip to New York for Thursday, Pamela's called six times, Patricia, Kathy, Judy, Gayle is pregnant, she says but... you gotta get straight, honey, go to sleep, get a massage, go to the dentist, get a haircut honey, you gotta cool out...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably a bath too...</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus Jim, this guy really despises you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...didn't invite us to Woodstock. Twenty other groups but not...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's heavy is the radio stations pulling us from their playlists. The big cities -- Philly, Cinci, Chicago, Detroit -- it's insane! Record sales suck!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"The band you love to hate".</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can drag this appeal out for years, we can keep you out of jail.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're drinking with number three.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIDDONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Max firmly believes the FBI's behind it. We're subpoenaing their records -- they had memos on you in Phoenix and they got you extradicted to Miami illegally without a felony...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A new image -- Jim Morrison as "Renaissance Man" -- We bring you back slow, quiet, the beard, elder of the tribe.</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...like Lennon said "you either grow with the music or it grows without you."</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the voices merging into one:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, it was fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim, during this, picking up the TV remote, flicking on the images. The VOICES blending with TV VOICES as he swithes the channels. The camera moving in on Jim, the VOICES fading. All we see is Jim. All we hear and see is the TV:</context>
      <utterance>First Hendrix now Janis Robbie flew to Hawaii legalities pending dispositions book in Toronto interview with PBS renew your diverse license psychic predictions nine paternity suits fifty thousand dollar bond recoup our losses Pamela's shopping spree with your credit card Morrison Hotel some-body from film school mountain of coke in the broom closet Jac Holzman eight thirty in the morning remix perform schedule Paul Rothchild taxes Texas teenyboppers tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>TELEVISION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SONG climaxes into an inner scream of madness.</context>
      <utterance>Chicago Seven in it's tenth day... Bobby Seale gagged and chained...  L.A. shootout with Black Panthers...  Charles Manson indicted for murder of actress Sharon Tate...  U. S. ground troops in Laos and Cambodia...  Indians still occupying Alcatraz Island...  For the My Lai massacre testified 120 villagers shot by American soldiers in a trench...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode>CONCLUDE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the music is your special friend Dance on fire as it intends Music is your only friend Until the end</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of wind, the backbeat of LA WOMAN flooding in.</context>
      <utterance>I think I'm having a nervous breakdown.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>Siddons and Ray terrified. Is this the night it's finally going to end in a suicide plunge? Ray trying to stop Pam, too late.</context>
      <utterance>LA Woman  LA Woman Sunday afternoon  Drive thru your suburbs Into your blues  Into your blue-blue Blues Into your blues</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pam's moving shakily along the ledge, cracked on downers. Jim watching her come, amazed at her risk.</context>
      <utterance>Pam!! Oh shit... get the ambulances man...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>JIM! HELP HER. She's gonna fall.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches, does nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Jump!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on baby, come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim we gotta finish "LA Woman".</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reaches his hand out. She is closer. But shaky.</context>
      <utterance>Don't have an ending Ray.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're both gonna die... ARE YOU</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on baby, come on</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"...but one, the most beautiful one of all -- dances in a ring of fire --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"I see your hair is burning. If they say I never loved you, you know they are a liar!"</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"...and throws off the challenge with a shrug"</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has never been so concentrated, inching closer to him. Her heels overhanging oblivion.</context>
      <utterance>All the poetry has wolves in it Pam!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wanna die with you Jim Morrison, I don't wanna die!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never saw a woman So alone  So alone -- lone lone</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ray, Tom, Siddons, Mike, Dog, they all watch in horror, sensing it will happen. They have even stopped filming. Inches... inches. He dodges her touch, confused... to the last possible second. Then SHE'S THERE -- in his arms. Her arms latch around him and she hugs him with all her wiry soul.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon Pam, this is it! We'll do it right here! Right now! You and me!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jim -- let's go, let's leave this town! You and me! Never come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can. Right now. Just one more step...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two lovers huddled together on the ledge. He slips his head down on her lap, looking up into her eyes with the strangest tears in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No Jim. I want to LIVE with you. I want to LIVE with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was preserved in her the fresh miracle of surprise... clothed in sunlight restless in wanting dying of fever married to doubt how it has changed you how slowly estranged you solely arranged you beg for your mercy -- OR -- ...but all will pass lie down in green grass and smile and muse and gaze upon her smooth resemblance to the mating-Queen who it seems is in love with the horseman Tomorrow we enter the tomb of my birth I want to be ready. On her face -- moved. Pause. LA WOMAN floods in on his smile, an upbeat surge. Upstairs, the ONLOOKERS relax. HOTEL MANAGEMENT and COPS are now rushing up in background.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Mojo Rising Mr. Mojo Risin'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eek Dorothy! You cut your hair!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're trying to have another baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What -- was your hair getting in the way?  Where are the kids?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey -- am I late or is this the cool remnant of a dream?</utterance>
   <speaker>KIDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eee! Jim! It's Uncle Jim... Come on... what did you bring me Jim...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As RAY and ROBBIE and JOHN and the others circle him.</context>
      <utterance>For you... Pancho gets this one... Melanie -- yours... Hey Dorothy don't grab now... open that one, that's yours... keep your paws off that now...</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As ROBIN, the cutest of them all, a bow in her hair, takes the package, opens it.</context>
      <utterance>...and to you, princess, from your Royal servant, James Douglas Morrison</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna hear the new mixes on "LA</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I gotta plane to catch.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't take long man, it's the best one since "Days".</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim cocks his head, listening to it playing from an inner room, his eyes on ROBIN opening the gift -- a beautiful, ANTIQUE DOLL of an 19th century poet -- rock star, stuffed, velour jacket, white fluffy lace collar, it could be Byron or it could be Jim Morrison -- in fact the hair is perfectly weaved to resemble Jim in his young lion phase -- an ironic gift, meant from the heart. It stops everybody -- they all look. A haunted quality to the doll.</context>
      <utterance>We added rain to "Riders", come on.</utterance>
   <speaker>KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ugh! What's that!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>Forever young...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh it's beautiful... Thank you Uncle Jim.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>JIM &amp; DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where we and Jim came in, I guess. Jim drinks from a cognac bottle straight, foot tapping, enjoying it, knows it's good -- but other things are calling. This is history.</context>
      <utterance>Riders on the Storm  Into this house we're born Into this world we're thrown Like a dog without a bone An actor out on loan Riders on the storm</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slapping shoulders, shaking hands.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta admit -- that ain't bad for four guys who weren't even talking that day.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really gonna live in Paris man?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah John, be anonymous, write a book: "Observations of an American While on Trial in Miami".</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still think we got a couple of great blues albums in us man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm pinned man. Everything I do they got a category for it, y'know. Freedom's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm gonna miss you Jim. I'm gonna miss the feeling of playing music with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can always whip the horses' eyes. You, John, miss me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More than you think asshole.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well far as I'm concerned, Jim, I made music with Dionysus man. We had some moments on stage like no one will ever fucking know.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah -- and you lay off those drugs Rob. We're gonna play again some day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids running up to grab JIM, pulls him back to the party.</context>
      <utterance>Jim -- "do not go gently into that good night. Rage rage against the dying of the light".</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come 'ere Uncle Jim, we're playing blind man's bluff...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what are you gonna be when you grow up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs, looks at Dorothy who's shooting him with the Super</context>
      <utterance>I wanna be your wife</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, can I afford you? Pam kinda wiped me out with her dress store y'know...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make my own dresses and you'll see, I'll be the best wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOROTHY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll never be alone Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim coming awake in that instant alert way of his, but obviously hung over.</context>
      <utterance>Gotta plane to catch man?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Puzzling remark, He gets up, shaky, exits, kids tearing at him. Goodbyes.</context>
      <utterance>O?... splittling headache from which the future is made.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Pam really there in Paris waiting?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. The Count's there so where else would she be? Gotta try to start over, without all the hassles, y'know. I think we can.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never knew what you saw in that nightmare chick man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well she is kinda flakey -- like me. I mean she's just so vulnerable about everything. It makes me sad man.  But she's always kinda believed in something about me y'know -- her little picture of me as the unsung poet -- and it's a fantasy I kinda dig y'know, 'stead of the one I live.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know man, I don't wanna sound like your old man but you're only 27, you're living like you gotta get it all in, you gotta slow down man, you did it, you broke thru to the other side.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't break thru Ray, we just pushed things a little. When you really break thru, there's nothing left. No music, no Doors, no God, nothing -- only a will to power.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jim, not the sentimental type, climbs in his car, amused.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe that. You were an American prince, man -- with overbred genes --  No! What could've been Jim? You could've been President.  No man! What could've been Jim? We stood here on this beach on the edge of the Pacific that crazy summer day in '65 -- and we knew, you and I, we knew we were at the edge of the mind. we were there, man. One planet, one globe, one mind. Consciousness, we raised it, we were there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now?  You've made me into Ishmael. I am the last survivor of the Pequod. And I exist only to tell the story of Ahab who fought the black whale.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ignites engine. Ray leans in, lightening up.</context>
      <utterance>It was white Ray. You gotta stop harpin' on that day. I was so ripped I can hardly remember it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what was that poem you once wrote about two chicks on the pier?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on man, I gotta fly.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Just once.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he departs, waving.</context>
      <utterance>In that year we had a great Visitation of energy Back in those days Everything was simpler and more confused One summer night, going to the pier I ran into two young girls The blonde was called Freedom The dark one Enterprise We talked And they told me this story.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAY</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context>His point of view -- Jim receding into the sun in his mustang -- making a shakey, screeching curve at the bend of the beach. And he's gone. An ominous ROAR of an AIRPLANE above RAY. -- flying away.</context>
      <utterance>What was the story?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MORRISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, didja get all that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GHOSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ENGINEER, exhausted, doesn't feel anything funny.</context>
      <utterance>You done good, Jim, go now -- rest</utterance>
   <speaker>ENGINEER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The poets face brightens. A small but ever-so-sweet smile of triumph hikes up the corners of his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I got it Jim.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands, sways, than moves out of view. The empty bottle of whiskey, its sands run out, is left behind. As we FADE OUT, a hardy, mischievous Morrison laugh and a ripple of sensuous MUSIC carry us into the lilting, lamenting strains of AN AMERICAN PRAYER -- THE END without lyrics for now as we cut to:</context>
      <utterance>Aw right. Let's get some tacos!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face. At peace, as she sobs, the MUSIC cresting to Jim's lyrics.</context>
      <utterance>Jim! It was you. I always know when it's you.  Come on baby get out of the tub... mama'll dry you off...  Jim Morrison, now you stop joking you hear me, cut it out!</utterance>
   <speaker>PAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...was it all right Jim, did you enjoy it when it came my baby? Just like you said it'd be?</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode>OVER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are waiting to take us into the severed garden do you know how pale and wanton thrillful comes death at a strange hour? Unannounced unplanned for like a scaring overfriendly guest you've brought to bed? Death makes angels of us all? And gives us wings where we had shoulders smooth as raven's claws...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GHOST ANNOUNCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(ghostly applause)</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and Gentlemen, from Los Angeles California -- The Doors!</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM &amp; THE DOORS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...have you seen the warm progress under the stars? Have you forgotten the keys to the kingdom? Have you been born yet and are you alive? Where is the feast we were promised? Let's reinvent the gods, the myths of the ages! We need great golden copulations Camera closing past the DOORS to JIM alone, circling the mike with his dance -- the INDIAN GHOSTMAN jigging, shaman- like, off to the side -- now levitating above the stage, all crazy, gawky dancing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll tell you a story of whiskey, mystics and men And about the believers and how the whole thing began First there were women and children obeying the moon Then daylight brought wisdom and sickness too soon... the moon is a dry blood beast We have assembled inside this ancient and insane theatre to propagate our lust for life and flee the swarming wisdom of the streets we live we die and death not ends it</utterance>
   <speaker>JIM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bird of prey, bird of prey Flying high, flying high in the summer sky Bird of prey, bird of prey flying high, flying high gently pass by Bird of prey, bird of prey flying high, flying high Take me on your flight  I will come again down from the wild mountains</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
