<movie id="224" title="Game The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That Business Week reporter called again--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him to fuck himself. Nicely.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER FREEZES at this, stares at her.</context>
      <utterance>--and, um, somebody who identified himself as, um, P.P. Willy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I figured it was a crank, but he swore you'd know who he was. He wanted to meet you for lunch, I told him you had appointments all--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cancel. Cancel the whole afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do it. Did he leave a number?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maria hands him a slip of paper, lingers, awaiting explanation...</context>
      <utterance>No. He just said he'd be at Leo's in the Haight. At noon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She heads out quickly. Schuyler stares at the slip, then turns to look out the window, lost in thought.</context>
      <utterance>That's all, Maria.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="51">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I take your order?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't seen the menu.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him a menu and starts off. Schuyler calls after her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, right. Here, see ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waves a hand, "yeah, right," without looking back. Schuyler sighs and opens the menu. Suddenly, someone BACKHANDS the side of his skull, he assumes a defensive posture. Schuyler sees his LAUGHING brother: DAVID VAN ORTON.</context>
      <utterance>An iced tea, please--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yo, Sky. Happy birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DAVID slides into the seat opposite him. He's in his early 30's, good-looking but unkempt, wears bright, funky clothes, an earring and a perpetual grin. There's an intense, edgy quality to him which Schuyler has some trouble readjusting to.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, "Pee-pee." I never get tired of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, since Mom died-- what, five years? So how you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Business as usual...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's Elizabeth? Any kids?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congrat--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not mine, she married a pediatrician in Sausalito.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're divorced...  Too bad, she was actually interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She stopped drinking, I guess getting rid of me was the 13th step.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're all alone in the House of Pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I redecorated. Where have</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I called them off two years ago, David. You'd kicked the heroin, you'd left the ashram, you were windsurfing somewhere in Central America...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's gorgeous down there... you should go sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, are you in trouble, is there anything you need? You can't have gone through the trust fund...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not why I'm here, Sky, I just wanted to see you... I even brought a gift, for a change.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't bake me a cake, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler's unamused by the memory. David grins and pulls a small envelope out of his pocket, tosses it on the table in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>You can't still be mad about the hash brownies...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy birthday, bro.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler shrugs, opens the envelope and shakes out-- A BUSINESS CARD in BLUE and ORANGE: "CONSUMER RECREATION SERVICES." The C, R and S are HIGHLIGHTED, a PHONE NUMBER at the bottom. SCHUYLER picks up the card, fingers it.</context>
      <utterance>It's a bomb. Open it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Consumer Recreation Services. OK...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't tell you very much about it, that'd ruin the surprise. Just promise me you'll give 'em a call.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just call 'em. OK look, it's simple, really. They entertain you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this an escort service?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler gives him a bored, blank look. David throws up his hands.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's nothing like that. They're a business, they're for real... They guarantee just one thing-- you won't be bored.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They make your life fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine the waitress has shown up with Schuyler's iced tea. She puts it down hastily, spilling some across the table. Schuyler shies away, grabbing a napkin and blotting it up before it can drip into his lap. Cracking gum:</context>
      <utterance>You've heard of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves off as Schuyler tries to order, raising a finger--</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a cheesebur... how'd you find this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old connection used to meet me here. So you gonna call 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, David, this is sweet, but it's an awfully busy time, I'm in the midst of a delicate liquidation--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"A delicate liquidation," God, you would do this...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't get together once without you making me feel like shit. That's important to you, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David slumps in his seat, won't meet Schuyler's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Forget about it, don't bother.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David glares at him. With the impeccable timing of all waitresses, CHRISTINE appears, chipper.</context>
      <utterance>Are you still on medication...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys know what you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She curls her lip and departs before Schuyler can open his mouth. He sighs, resigned to the idea of not eating. Calmly:</context>
      <utterance>Go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just thought you'd like it. I did, it was a blast, best thing that ever happened to me. And for your information, I'm not on anything anymore, I'm not even seeing a shrink, I'm in a better place than I've ever been, I'm even</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, take a pill. Just be normal for thirty seconds and tell me what this is. I hate surprises.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David WINKS, puts a finger to his lips-- not another word. CLOSE as Schuyler slips the brightly-colored CARD into his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ELIZABETH is Schuyler's ex-wife-- an earnest woman, a stranger to subtlety. STAY WITH SCHUYLER, who half-smiles, looks at his watch.</context>
      <utterance>Van Orton. ELIZABETH  Hello, Schuyler.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How was it?</context>
      <utterance>Eleven forty, you almost didn't make it. ELIZABETH  I always call on your birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, the usual, big party, circus clowns, naked lady in a cake... ELIZABETH   How are</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hm? Just another birthday, another year closer to death. ELIZABETH  I meant-- because of your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh that's right, I guess he</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great, that's great. Well, give my regards to Dr. Mel and the baby-- ELIZABETH  She has a little brother on the way... we just did the ultrasound.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really. Congratulations-- two kids, an official nuclear family, you must be very happy. ELIZABETH  We are, Sky. Very happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you deserved someone who wanted the same things you did--</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He asked about you. He's on a new kick, some personal improvement cult. I'm gonna check it out, I'm sure he's getting fleeced again. ELIZABETH  Who knows, maybe it'll be good for you. Send David my love.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Well, thanks again for calling, Elizabeth, take care. ELIZABETH  You too, Schuyler-- I mean that--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He PUNCHES off the phone in the middle of her "Good-bye." Schuyler returns to his work, as if the call hadn't taken place-- but a few seconds later, we see his concentration is completely shattered, he leans back in his SQUEAKING deskchair.</context>
      <utterance>Mm, good luck, bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BERNARD SHAW</speaker>
      <mode>TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--for the residents of the Crescent Heights project, a truly tragic day is over at last--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER raises his champagne glass to the TV, his birthday done. Then he toasts in the direction of a FRAMED PICTURE on the coffee table-- a WEDDING PHOTO OF SCHUYLER and ELIZABETH.</context>
      <utterance>I'll drink to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BERNARD SHAW</speaker>
      <mode>TV</mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER reaches for the REMOTE CONTROL. He settles back on the sofa, CHANNEL HOPPING. He despairs of this quickly, points the remote at his own head-- CLICK, CLICK. He closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>--up next, the latest in sports. For all of us here at CNN, thank you for watching--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman flips through an appointment book with a logo, CRS. IN BG, JIM FEINGOLD pays a CHINESE DELIVERY GUY for a BAG OF FOOD.</context>
      <utterance>Is this Consumer Recreation Services? I have an appointment, the name's Van Orton.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hm... I don't seem to--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman shakes her head. FEINGOLD slows as he crosses past Schuyler, carrying the bag. He's 30-40, a no-nonsense engineer, looks a bit dull, but he exudes competence and trustworthiness.</context>
      <utterance>Schuyler Van Orton, I called last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Feingold glances at Schuyler, shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>This gentlemen says he has an appointment, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man leads Schuyler to a row of open boxes on the floor, looks in a couple, then finds what he's after. He snatches up a couple of pages, hands them to Schuyler. Then he finds a clipboard on the floor, tosses it to him like a frisbee.</context>
      <utterance>Van Orton, huh? I'll take him.  Jim Feingold, v. p. in charge of engineering and data analysis.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into a box of PENS, passes one to Schuyler. CLOSE ON PEN-- the CRS LOGO.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry about the chaos, we're still in the process of moving... follow me, I've got an office around here someplace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER sits on a couch, looking at the forms.</context>
      <utterance>I can't remember the last time I ate in a restaurant, all I do is work...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fast-talking Feingold moves energetically through the office, occasionally picking at his food or poking at the air with chopsticks-- he's a bit hyper and fidgety in general.</context>
      <utterance>I know what you mean. Look-- what is all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Application, MMPI and TAT tests, financial statement...  Want some? Tung Hoy, best in Chinatown...  The tests serve a threefold purpose. First off, are you right for us? Are we right for you? Unfortunately, there's a limited number of slots--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's back up here--</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>B, we need an idea of your abilities and limitations, what turns you on, and off. Numero tres, our insurance company requires it.  You're familiar with our service, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. What</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A game.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Recharges the batteries, gets you off the treadmill, it's an experience. Sort of a-- vacation for the guy who's been everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Feingold sits on the edge of his desk, arms crossed, nodding and smiling condescendingly-- he raises a hand to stop Schuyler.</context>
      <utterance>This really doesn't sound like my sort of--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so amusing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I know who you are. You're David Van Orton's brother, he got you in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David was-- impressive, one of the better I've seen. But frankly, I can see you're not the type.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The type.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, a player.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a player.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean anything personal by it-- I know you're an important guy, powerful guy, you're used to being on top. It's just, this isn't for everyone. Not everyone can handle it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of fu-- game is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ultimate fucking game. I wish I could tell you more, but it's different every time.  Thanks for coming in--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not an idiot. I see what you're doing. First the vague yet intriguing pitch, then I'm supposed to feel like my manhood's in question because I'm not up for, what, some motivational role-playing fantasy nonsense--</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting, you don't know the first thing about it but you've already decided what it is... Listen, I don't wanna waste any more--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Feingold cocks his head, reappraising him. Then, with a smile, he calls to an attractive young WOMAN passing in the hall; Schuyler, meanwhile, flips through the pages of the tests.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Jim, cut the hard-to-get shit. I've got the afternoon free, I'll take your silly tests.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ms. Nelson, are you busy? We need someone to run Mr. Van Orton.</utterance>
   <speaker>MS. NELSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she leads Schuyler out the door, Feingold WINKS at him.</context>
      <utterance>This way, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler reacts-- a physical? He throws up a hand and follows the woman into the hall. Alone now, Feingold cracks a fortune cookie and glances at the slip of paper inside. He furrows his brow with concern at the fortune-- then tosses it aside.</context>
      <utterance>I'll catch up with you after the physical.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FEINGOLD BURSTS IN, a slew of COMPUTER PRINT-OUTS under his arm.</context>
      <utterance>David, you suck.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws open a closet door. Schuyler reaches inside for his clothes, which are neatly folded and on hangers. Feingold turns his back on him as he DRESSES, perching on the examination table and studying the unburst print-outs.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry to keep you waiting, a client's head exploded...  You can get dressed, we're done.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks promising at this point. You test well, you're in decent shape for someone in your tax bracket... Hm, some resistance to the psych questions, but we got the general idea... He heads out, beckons for Schuyler to follow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We design the game around your schedule, you're free to give it as much or as little time as you wish. And of course, you can call it quits at any point.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This was actually a gift. Did my brother pay in advance?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd have to ask our billing department... the price varies. But our service comes with a guarantee. If you're not satisfied, there's no charge. And we've never had an unsatisfied customer...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean dissatisfied.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm, that's right-- you're a left- brain word fetishist.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Feingold smiles tightly and leads Schuyler back into his office.</context>
      <utterance>I get that all the time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'm supposed to sign up for a game when I don't know the rules, I don't know the object, I don't know how much it costs...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler CLICKS the ballpoint pen, they both lean over the papers.</context>
      <utterance>It's a leap of faith. But at this stage, there's no commitment-- we just need to process your application. And if you qualify, you're in for the ride of your life. What have you got to lose?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler's about to sign when Feingold grabs his wrist.</context>
      <utterance>Initials-- initials-- sign here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE, as Schuyler SIGNS on the dotted line. FEINGOLD snatches up the forms, suddenly seems in a hurry for Schuyler to go.</context>
      <utterance>In blood.  ---Just kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler shrugs, sticks it in his breast pocket, starts out.</context>
      <utterance>Very good, Mr. Van Orton. Please, keep the pen.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When can I expect to hear--</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Feingold gently shuts the door on schuyler's face.</context>
      <utterance>We'll be in touch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode>V. O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David, where the hell are you, we were supposed to meet at the club--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode>V. O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit, sorry Sky, I spaced-- next Tuesday?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode>V. O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be in Seattle.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode>V. O.</mode>
      <context>Fed up with playing alone, Schuyler lets the ball bounce, exits the court and heads for a LOCKER ROOM down the hall...</context>
      <utterance>Buy you lunch soon as you get back, I swear...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode>V. O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I checked out CRS by the way--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode>V. O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, great, you gonna go for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode>V. O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Haven't decided yet...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--like fuckin' wildfire, just opened an office in Frisco here--</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I played my game in New York... What do you think John, will CRS ever go public?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler slows down, eavesdropping, then moves toward the bar, addresses the BARTENDER with a nod toward John and Pete.</context>
      <utterance>Not likely, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>New members?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler moves casually toward the men--</context>
      <utterance>This round's on me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others CHUCKLE knowingly. Schuyler sips his drink, blinking and coughing discretely at the smoke; there's a slight pause.</context>
      <utterance>...last time I played Pebble, I swore I'd never pick up a club again...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great thing about golf, the way it takes you out of your life... Speaking of games-- I take it you two are familiar with CRS...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slides off his stool. Pete studies Schuyler, sizing him up.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh. Time to piss...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you ask, Schuyler?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't help overhearing--</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't usually talk about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only bring it up because, well, I recently tested for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you? Kudos.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just wasn't sure if they're for real, whether it's worth it--</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worth it... Gee, I dunno... they did save my fucking life...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler raises his glass, numbed by this outpouring. Pete drains his drink, chuckling to himself. His friend comes back, looking concerned, takes the man's arm.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't know you, you don't know me, but... I hit a certain point, nothing meant anything. My work, the wife and kids-- hell with 'em, I was sick of it all, y'know? But CRS... they changed everything. "Are they for real?" Who cares, maybe nothing is.  To reality.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon Pete.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler stares after the two men dubiously as they move off.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck, pal. You'll need it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PLYMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler has been going through paperwork in the back of the room, he steps forward during the above.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. Excuse me! Postponing the Baer-Grace meeting is out of the question. Schuyler gets on a plane for Washington tomorrow morning at seven with every contract, every side agreement, the complete closing package!</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THWAP! Schuyler DROPS the stack of papers on the table, SILENCE.</context>
      <utterance>But there's simply no--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHIRP. Schuyler's CELL-PHONE has started RINGING during the above. He finally removes it from his pocket and moves to a quiet corner.</context>
      <utterance>No is not an option. If you fail to recognize that, I'll find ten other law firms in the yellow pages that can get the job done--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>QUIET COMMOTION resumes IN BG during the following. On the other end of the line, there's the bland, bureaucratic VOICE of CYNTHIA: CYNTHIA (filter) Mr. Van Orton?</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, who</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in a meeting-- CYNTHIA  --and I'm afraid you didn't qualify.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--so I don't have time for--  Excuse me, what was that? CYNTHIA  Well... your application was rejected.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Why? CYNTHIA  Oh, I'm afraid I don't have that information, but-- many applicants don't meet the criteria. We apologize, we hope it hasn't caused you any inconvenience--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLICK and a DIAL TONE. Schuyler shuts the phone and replaces it in his pocket, his mind suddenly far away from the meeting at hand. PLYMPTON, a wel1-meaning man with a fatherly attitude toward Schuyler, steps close to him and speaks quietly, concerned:</context>
      <utterance>This is absurd-- CYNTHIA  Thank you for thinking of CRS.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLYMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bad news, Sky?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, nothing. Sorry, Bob.  So were there any more questions, or may I assume it's under control...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE BODY doesn't stir. He approaches gingerly.</context>
      <utterance>Hello! What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crouches by the wino, winces at a strong smell, covers his nose. He reaches out to touch the body, but hesitates, pulls back. Alive or dead, he doesn't want to have anything to do with this person.</context>
      <utterance>Wonderful. You OK? You dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The "wino" suddenly SPRINGS UP like a jack-in-the-box, bending backwards impossibly at the hips. Schuyler lets out a CRY and scrambles back toward his car. THE HEAD swivels to face him-- it's a grotesque HARLEQUIN, its head made of COLORED GLASS, LIT from within. The MOUTH DROPS OPEN and a tongue in the shape of a corkscrew SPRINGS OUT. A SMALL KEY ON A HOOK dangles from the tip of the tongue. One of the harlequin's glass eyes WINKS. SCHUYLER stares in amazement for a few moments. CLOSE on the dangling KEY as Schuyler fingers it. The key catches the light and we see the letters "CRS" embossed on it.</context>
      <utterance>Shit, shit, shit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CYBERSHAW (on TV) This might be a good time to lay out a few ground rules, help you enjoy your adventure. You've received the first key. There will be others. Pay attention-- you never know where you'll find 'em, you never know when you'll need 'em, so keep 'em with you at all times... As he speaks, Schuyler reaches for the gold key on his bedside table. He starts putting it onto his keychain. ON TV SCREEN-- below CyberShaw, a PHONE NUMBER SCROLLS PAST. CYBERSHAW (on TV) You might want to write this number down, it's the CRS hotline, operators are standing by to assist... but please don't call to ask what the object of the game is-- figuring that out is the object of the game... SCHUYLER has snatched up the CRS pen to write down the number-- it doesn't work. SWEARING, he tosses it aside, grabs another. ON TV, CyberShaw MORPHS back into the original Bernard Shaw. There's a quick VISUAL GLITCH on the tube as the original TV feed resumes-- Bernard Shaw is delivering a normal news story. BERNARD SHAW (on TV) --reaction on wall Street was muted following the Fed's announcement of... SCHUYLER is taken with the display of electronic pyrotechnics, in spite of himself. He hits the speaker button on his phone, dials. OPERATOR VOICE (filter) You've reached CRS...</context>
      <utterance>Fuckers!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, this is pretty impressive but listen-- OPERATOR VOICE  Our office is closed. Please call back during business hours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man shakes his head, Schuyler, exasperated, whips out his cell- phone and dials. As he and the driver move through the CROWD, they pass a red-eyed, dredlocked, homeless-looking RASTA MAN in a BRIGHTLY COLORED outfit with knit cap, hassling other TRAVELERS. He turns his attention to Schuyler and begins walking alongside.</context>
      <utterance>I'm expecting a package with some documents. Did it arrive?</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ay mon, got sometin' fo you mon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get lost, pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The driver and Schuyler climb into a little white people mover cart, the driver starts forward, BEEPING at folks in the way. The rasta man continues to badger Schuyler.</context>
      <utterance>No can do. SCHUYLER  Bob, it's Sky, what the hell is going on? No, the papers aren't here, you'll have to fax signature copies straight to the BG offices now. Yeah I'll hold.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want what I got, mon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dere are many paths to enlightenment, but you must choose one and stay on it-- or you will surely die in the darkness--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rasta man jogs alongside, holds up a stained, newsprint religious TRACT, Schuyler glances at it without taking it-- CLOSE-- we see the words "CRISIS, REVELATION, SOLUTION." The letters C, Rand S are printed in a different color from the rest. WIDER-- Schuyler ignores the tract, he's talking to Bob again on the phone. The driver SPEEDS UP as they pass a guard, entering a restricted access area. SCHUYLER (on phone) What?! Fire their asses, that's it. The Rasta Man runs out of breath as the cart SPEEDS UP. He calls after Schuyler:</context>
      <utterance>I'll take my chances.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jah Love mon, dat's the key, dat's the key...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alan! What's wrong with a car--</utterance>
   <speaker>BAER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER looks uncomfortable with this prospect. The driver is already loading his bag into the chopper. Baer claps a hand on Schuyler's shoulder, leading him under the wash, into the chopper. THE RASTA MAN is walking slowly across the tarmac nearby. He watches the HELICOPTER ASCEND with a half-smile.</context>
      <utterance>I'm giving you an overview of our little operation! You gotta see the new breed of high yield saplings...</utterance>
   <speaker>BAER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How was your flight?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler looks out the window. SCHUYLER'S POV - On the PASTA MAN in his colorful clothes, now holding up a dangling KEY on a chain. Moments later, he's invisible in the MIST. ON SCHUYLER, looking disappointed, and annoyed with himself-- he realizes he's missed something. He reaches into his pocket as Baer DRONES ON beside him. Schuyler pulls out his KEYS, fingers the gold one with the CRS logo, thinking.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BAER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've been planning this for months, haven't you? Sandbagging me like this, selling us for scrap...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he speaks, Schuyler moves to the fax machine. A TRANSMISSION has come through, he picks up the sheaf of papers.</context>
      <utterance>BG lumber is not profitable and hasn't been for years, my duty is to salvage what I can. These are the closing papers, in ten minutes I'm going to present the sale terms to the shareholders and elect my new management team.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler squints at the papers in his hand, flipping through them. CLOSE, the entire transmission has been GARBLED. The words all BLEED TOGETHER incomprehensibly, it looks like a child's scribbles.</context>
      <utterance>I was friends with your father, you bastard, I watched you grow up, and now you kick me in the balls--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>BAER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could've fucking</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In BG, one exec picks up a page, WHISPERS to an ASSISTANT, who moves out of the room. Schuyler moves to his briefcase. It's LOCKED. He starts patting his pockets.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind... we'll just have to go with the earlier draft.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baer has a malevolent expression. Schuyler looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Can't find your keys?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are they.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A couple of execs stifle chuckles. Schuyler's suspicions mount.</context>
      <utterance>Up your ass?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes drift to a piece of CORPORATE STATIONARY on the table in front of him. He picks it up: INSERT - UNDER BAER-GRACE LETTERHEAD we see a handscrawled note: "CRS CALLED." We don't see what's written below. SCHUYLER is reeling, paranoia confirmed.</context>
      <utterance>Up my ass, very funny...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Baer stares at him blankly. Schuyler puts a hand over his eyes, seems disoriented, trying to piece it all together.</context>
      <utterance>I don't-- OK. OK, you're with CRS...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the game, it's just a screen, to blow this deal...</utterance>
   <speaker>BAER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not following you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The assembled execs are looking at Schuyler in utter confusion. As he speaks, the ASSISTANT returns with some PAPERWORK. Schuyler stares at him menacingly. Hesitantly:</context>
      <utterance>Like hell you aren't. How did you get my brother involved, that's unforgivable.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The assistant comes over, cheerfully places the crucial documents in front of Schuyler. The assistant fishes in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Um... sorry to interrupt. We've been having some trouble with this fax, so they re-sent the material. It's all OK now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler gingerly takes the KEYS which the assistant holds out, looks from them to the paperwork. Then he glances back at the handwritten note on the table: INSERT NOTE: It actually reads "CBS CALLED." (Schuyler's thumb or a Post-It note covered the base of the B before, making it look like an R.) It continues "Re: Interview with Alan B. on Sun..." SCHUYLER takes a breath, reassembles his composure and consults his watch. He rises, anxious to put the last few minutes behind him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh and Mr. Van Orton-- are these yours? The pilot found 'em on the floor of the chopper...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads for the door. As he leaves, the execs exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>Everything seems to be in order. Please disregard my last comments. The shareholders meeting is about to get underway... Shall we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RASTA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler gets up, dusts himself off. As calmly as possible:</context>
      <utterance>Shit mon sorry oughta pay more attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snatches up the briefcase, dances back a few paces. Schuyler speaks as if to a child.</context>
      <utterance>Free at last... you won't be needin' this, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rasta man keeps backing away, puts a hand to his ear.</context>
      <utterance>No, cretin. I'm quitting the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler is pursuing the man, walking faster and faster.</context>
      <utterance>Wha's that, mon? I didna hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rasta turns and RUNS, Schuyler bolts after him, unable to believe this is happening. They draw a lot of looks during the brief chase through the terminal, the suited businessman, garment bag flapping behind him, in pursuit of the crazy rasta.</context>
      <utterance>I said I-- shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs into a MEN'S ROOM, Schuyler follows a moment later.</context>
      <utterance>Help, help! The mon is crazy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rasta men holds out a SHINY KEY on a chain. Schuyler narrows his eyes, he's trying not to lose control of his temper.</context>
      <utterance>Got something better.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE RASTA makes a sad face, SNIFFLES, still dangling the key.</context>
      <utterance>I realize you're just some bit player, but I'd like you to get a message to your employers. This bullshit is interfering with my work, it's breaking my concentration and I can't allow that to happen--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rasta nods with a big grin. Schuyler steps forward, hand extended. The rasta flings open the door of a STALL beside him and hurls the key into the TOILET. Instinctively, Schuyler moves to grab it, reaches into the toilet, pulls out the chain, his hand and sleeve DRIPPING. The key is missing from the end of the chain.</context>
      <utterance>If I take that stupid key, will you give me back my briefcase and go away?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck am I</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off his sunglasses, folds them and tucks them in the pocket of Schuyler's suit. Then he reaches above him and pulls down the briefcase, which was perched on top of the stall. Schuyler grabs it from him, raises his voice:</context>
      <utterance>So try looking at it through rose- colored glasses... here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, this is over! I quit!</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives Schuyler a hearty SLAP on the back and strolls off, HUMMING. Schuyler leans against the wall, shaking his head. He puts down his luggage, pulls the sunglasses from his pocket. CLOSE ON SUNGLASSES-- there's the image of a tiny GOLD KEY embossed on each of the arms. SCHUYLER puts them on, looks around for a moment, catches a GLIMPSE of himself in the mirror-- he looks silly. He quickly takes them off. As Schuyler heads out the door we see him from behind... the Rasta has slapped a colorful SIGN that reads "KICK ME" on his back.</context>
      <utterance>They all say that at first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was supposed to meet someone here, a David Van Orton-- I was wondering if he'd left a message.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drums his fingers, then whips out a CELLPHONE, spins around quickly as he starts to dial-- --and SMACKS into Christine the waitress as she emerges from the kitchen carrying a tray-- --SCHUYLER gets hit in the chest with a TRAY OF DESSERTS, colorful JELLO, CREAM PIE, etc. He stands there, stunned and DRIPPING.</context>
      <utterance>'Fraid not, sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts picking up plates and silverware, oblivious to Schuyler's own plight; Ronnie charges out from behind the bar. After the first shock, Schuyler CHUCKLES with annoyance. He wipes the phone clean, pocketing it.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh this is cute. Very cute.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened here, you OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was an accident--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie gives Christine a look as she starts wiping at Schuyler with a rag. He picks at his chest, examines the WHIPPED CREAM, tastes it. Schuyler addresses the kneeling Christine:</context>
      <utterance>No it wasn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHRISTINE squints up at him, puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>What's next, a giant banana peel?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh? Oh I get it-- you're nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chrissy, just apologize...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dickhead here was on the</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut the fuck up.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go home, you're fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She THROWS a plate on the ground, it shatters, then storms off into the kitchen. Schuyler CHUCKLES angrily, pushing through the slop on the floor with his shoe, looking for something.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ronnie stares, uncomprehending... Schuyler goes after Christine.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get this over with... Where's the next key? Does she have it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHRISTINE notices him for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>I wish you people could be a little more subtle.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waves a hand at him, "go away" and ducks out of view, finishing dressing into punk-grungy street clothes. She SLAMS the locker, starts to push past him, pulling on her backpack bag.</context>
      <utterance>Asshole, just send me the goddamn dry-cleaning bill. Could you--?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you have something for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her hand into her side pocket, pulls it out with her middle finger extended, moving away from him in a hurry. Schuyler's face falls-- he made another mistake.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh sure, here you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, you really work here--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's out the SWINGING kitchen door. Schuyler absorbs his blunder for a moment, then hurries after her.</context>
      <utterance>Not anymore, thanks to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slow down-- you don't understand, I thought it was a gag.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reaches into her purse/backpack, Schuyler backs off.</context>
      <utterance>No, you don't understand. I carry mace and I know how to use it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was only trying to apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, it's in here somewhere--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to move away, then they both hear GASPING O. S.-- ON THE STEPS, a HEAVY MAN, 60, in a coat and tie has collapsed, struggling for breath, very pale. Christine and Schuyler are the only pedestrians around now.</context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rushes to help the guy, loosening his tie-- he JOLTS. SCHUYLER looks up at them dubiously, brushing a scrap of food still clinging to his suit. CHRISTINE reaches in to clear the guy's throat, starting CPR. She shoots a look at Schuyler.</context>
      <utterance>Shit--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler approaches slowly, pulling out his phone, studying the guy as Christine gives him mouth-to-mouth.</context>
      <utterance>You got a fucking phone, call an ambulance!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is just too weird-- it can't be real--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER leans close to look at the man. ON THE MAN'S FACE-- sweating, contorted, unnaturally pale, his eyes rolling back as he GAGS his last... CHRISTINE grabs the phone away from Schuyler, dials.</context>
      <utterance>You really are insane!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need an ambulance, guy's having a heart attack near the MUNI station at 5th and Market--  What's the number on this thing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't give it out--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stuffs the phone in a pocket and pumps the man's chest, returns to the mouth-to-mouth. Schuyler looks around uncomfortably, starting to believe this is a real heart attack.</context>
      <utterance>731-5723-- yeah, thanks--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHRISTINE ignores him, all attention on saving this guy's life... 56A. WIDE as an AMBULANCE pulls up, SIREN BLARING. A couple of MALE PARAMEDICS hurry out with a stretcher. ON THE STEPS, the two PARAMEDICS lift the unconscious HEAVY MAN onto the stretcher while Christine and Schuyler stand aside. Both have small EARPIECES that look like hearing aids, with wires into their clothes. Throughout the following, there's a lot of MEDICAL BUSINESS-- feeding the victim OXYGEN, giving him INJECTIONS, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Is there anything I can do?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARAMEDIC #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you come with us, help us fill out a few forms--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I have work to do--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She climbs into the back, they start to shut the doors.</context>
      <utterance>I'll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He climbs in to get it back, they SLAM THE DOORS and start moving. THE AMBULANCE peels out. We now see the LOGO on the back: "CITYWIDE RESCUE SYSTEMS," with the C, R and S in RED.</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, you've got my phone--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chill, will you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BUMP almost sends him flying atop the stretcher. Schuyler sits near Christine on a ledge near the back doors. Petulant:</context>
      <utterance>Neither do I, now siddown, get outta their way!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like my phone back please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="56">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, this day keeps getting better.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she says this, she walks right into the ELECTRIC DOORS, which fail to open for them. THEIR POV-- THROUGH THE DOORS the gathered STAFF and PATIENTS all turn at once to regard Christine and Schuyler. They GRIN and WINK. ON SCHUYLER AND CHRISTINE, who barely get the chance to register this before-- THE LIGHTS GO OUT... PITCH BLACKNESS and SUDDEN SILENCE. We hear only SCHUYLER'S BITTER LAUGHTER. Dialogue OVER DARKNESS:</context>
      <utterance>What is your problem, you think the whole fucking world revolves around you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a matter of fact...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear RUSTLING in a purse, but still see next to nothing.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck is going on?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a little hard to explain...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the STRIKING OF A MATCH, there's some ORANGE LIGHT-- CHRISTINE holds the match. The whole area is DESERTED, except for the two of them. SCHUYLER kicks at the glass doors-- they're not going to give, nothing is visible beyond them.</context>
      <utterance>Try!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I seem to be playing a game. This is supposed to be funny--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--a challenge, a puzzle.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, I'm puzzled. Where</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here's a lightswitch--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She flips it on, A BLINDING STROBE FLASHES for a few seconds-- both CRY OUT-- then the BULB EXPLODES in a shower of sparks.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know the rules, if there are any, but it seems the obvious move usually backfires...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've taken a few steps forward, exploring the DARK. She LIGHTS a cigarette with the next match, nearly running into ANOTHER DOOR. She RATTLES it-- locked.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. I have no idea what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler pulls out his keyring and tries the gold CRS key-- nope.</context>
      <utterance>I think I have a key.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it...  Wrong key...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the matchlight, we see Schuyler fumbling in his pockets, pulling out the ROSY SUNGLASSES from the Rasta. He puts them on.</context>
      <utterance>Last match.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER'S POV as the last MATCH GOES OUT-- CHRISTINE GLOWS RED in the matchlight for a moment, then as soon as it goes out, we see a GLOW of FLUORESCENT PAINT on the ground... a series of STRIPES and ARROWS in DIFFERENT COLORS, GLOWING. These start PARALLEL near where he stands, then RADIATE in different directions. CHRISTINE is but a SILHOUETTE against the COLORED LINES.</context>
      <utterance>Too bright for you, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see now. Grab my arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHRISTINE moves away from him.</context>
      <utterance>No way! You're crazy!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BURST OF FLAME erupts from the GROUND close enough to scare the shit out of CHRISTINE, who SCREAMS. SCHUYLER hurries toward her. The FLAMES VANISH, she lurches in a differrent direction--</context>
      <utterance>Stay on the path!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christine, don't move!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She LOSES HER FOOTING on a slippery surface, falls, sliding down a gentle SLOPE.</context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER follows. FALLING himself. They try to reach toward each other for purchase, but it's no good, the slope is getting steeper. 58A. In a moment SCHUYLER tumbles on top of Christine in a four- foot deep round CHILDREN'S POOL, but it isn't full of water. There's a bit of BLACK LIGHT here, enough to make out-- --COCKROACHES, thousands of them, a TEEMING ROIL OF INSECTS in a CHURNING LIQUID. There's a BUZZING NOISE, both SCREAM.</context>
      <utterance>Help!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER quickly helps lift Christine out. She starts to pull him upward, but--</context>
      <utterance>Aaggh! BUGS!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the glasses?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck the glasses!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steels himself and rummages amidst the bugs, about to get sick, finally coming up with the glasses. He shakes them free of INSECTS and clambers out to join Christine, who's GASPING and brushing the bugs off of her. SCHUYLER puts on the glasses and holds up a BUG.</context>
      <utterance>We can't get out of here without them!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're rubber. Hold onto me, I'll get us out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, stay.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She grabs his arm; both are now covered in MUCK from the bug soup.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your favorite color?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off the glasses, puts them on her. She looks around. HER POV-- the RAINBOW of COLORED LINES on the FLOOR...</context>
      <utterance>...Blue?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER slips the glasses off her, puts them back on.</context>
      <utterance>Wow... OK, this is kinda cool. Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HIS POV-- a BLUE LINE moves in a snaking path ahead of them, going in circles now and then, INTERSECTING or moving PARALLEL to other colors, up a series of ramps. This space sometimes resembles a PARKING GARAGE, scmetimes a SEWER or a STEAM TUNNEL. CHRISTINE keeps a hand on Schuyler as he follows the path.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, it's my game. But we'll take blue.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk about the blind leading the blind... what's your name anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sky Van Orton.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sky? Were your folks hippies or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Far from it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Christine Kaminsky.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>58B. LATER, CHRISTINE almost hugs Schuyler now, as they move in a seemingly random pattern in the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a company called Consumer Recreation Services, CRS. I never know what's gonna happen next.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, who does.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BLUE LINE has led them into a NARROW TUNNEL, soon they're crawling on hands and knees.</context>
      <utterance>Until recently, I had a pretty good idea... Duck.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So are you like a serious masochist, or just really, really bored?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, you shouldn't have been dragged into this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I have to tell you something. Some guy came into Leo's yesterday, showed me your picture, offered me 250 bucks to spill that food on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Said it was a practical joke. I figured what the hell, I can use the money-- I got him up to 500. I hated that fucking job anyway--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, so the heart attack, you knew that was a joke too--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! It scared the shit out of me--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that CPR routine--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to be a lifeguard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER steps on the circle of WHITE-- it's a BUTTON. A ROPE LADDER drops down.</context>
      <utterance>How do we get up there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that was pointless... but different... kind of fun...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's your middle name?</context>
      <utterance>Mm, a different kind of fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER points to some GRAFFITI-- a HEART with "SVO + CLK."</context>
      <utterance>Louise... why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're supposed to be here... they picked you for a reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start to move shakily down the CONSTRUCTION WALKWAY, both bedraggled, covered in goo. HANDBILLS cover one wall.</context>
      <utterance>But-- why?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE WALL, a series of HANDBILLS say, "AREN'T YOU FORGETTING SOMETHING?" SCHUYLER puzzles over these as they move, gets to one last one-- "BEHIND YOU, STUPID." SCHUYLER looks back toward the end of the alley-- A YELLOW DUMPSTER with the logo, "CONSOLIDATED REFUSE SUPPLY" and the smaller image of a KEY. SCHUYLER moves quickly to it, throws open the lid. ANGLE IN DUMPSTER-- a MOUNTAIN of SHREDDED PAPER. SCHUYLER rolls his eyes, sorting through it. Christine approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Probably knew you'd play Good Samaritan for that guy, drag me along-- but they could have hired an actor for that, less of a risk...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is really sick. I think they're trying to fix us up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you can't play alone--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who says I want to play?  OK, what the fuck are you doing in the dumpster.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He climbs inside, dives in... and pops up again in a moment with-- CLOSE-- A Z-SHAPED WINDOW CRANK. Sure enough, there's a KEY embossed on the side. SCHUYLER climbs out again, brandishing the small crank.</context>
      <utterance>There's something in here I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that for?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I imagine I'll find out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find everything you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're outta conditioner.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to a MINI-FRIDGE, shuts the door, a moment later we hear WATER RUNNING. She looks around the office, letting down her facade. She seems quite impressed, and intimidated, by the place. She looks back toward the bathroom door-- maybe this guy isn't so bad after all. From this point, she takes a more seductive tack.</context>
      <utterance>My apologies, I'll have it taken care of. Help yourself to the fridge.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode>O. S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So um... how rich are you anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rich enough. Bit forward, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode>O. S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what exactly do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manage investments, some venture capital, I'm on the board of a number of publicly traded companies...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode>O. S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you just like, move money around?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine sits on his desk, with her bag slung over her shoulder, eating an APPLE. She slides off the desk, flirting rather bluntly.</context>
      <utterance>Basically. Beats working, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't look so bad, without the tie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I hope you haven't been too put out... I could probably get you another job, I have a stake in a couple of restaurants--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Y'know, today's been kind of--</context>
      <utterance>I'm not much of a waitress, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you type?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like fucking in a graveyard.</context>
      <utterance>Kind of a turn-on, you know?  I didn't mean-- just, the danger...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine realizes her come-on is falling flat, she pulls back, tossing her unfinished apple in the trash.</context>
      <utterance>Mm. So where do you live?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out in Concord, with my folks, unfortunately. They're never gonna believe that I've been hanging out with a guy like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing, just-- most of the guys I see have tats, y'know?  Tattoos...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine nods disappointedly as Schuyler moves to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Of course. We'd better head downstairs, the limo's waiting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind if I smoke in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the limo pulls over, he and Christine turn to each other. It's a somewhat awkward moment.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.  Up here on the left.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's our next move? I mean, in the game. Obviously we need to figure out what that crank thing is for--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not playing anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a life. Jack'll take you home, or wherever you want to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The limo has stopped now. Schuyler has started to open the door.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, maybe I'll get in a little ballroom dancing before bed--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, what about your clothes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So saying, she pulls it off. She's wearing a black bra... a ROSE is tattooed on her shoulder. Schuyler can't help but react. She thrusts the shirt at him, he's half out of the car.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon it's a brand new sweatshirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's not-- just-- back from the cleaners.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler nods again, torn. She's looking at him expectantly. He's clearly aroused, but this is such an inappropriate female. Sadly, he waves a hand.</context>
      <utterance>See ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drive. Anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, David, you scared the shit out of me--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Sky, just drive, please-- SCHUYLER pulls forward.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you today?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I almost didn't make it at all. I been in the bar for hours, waiting for you to come back to your car-- Jesus, I can't believe I did this to you, I'm so sorry--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slow down, take a breath-- what are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The game! It just doesn't stop! I thought I'd finished playing a long time ago, I paid the bill, then it started all over again, they won't leave me alone--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calm down. What are they doing to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything. It just doesn't stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. That's crazy. Yes, it's a pain in the ass, but why would they keep playing once you paid them?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sees the crumpled note on the floor, picks it up--</context>
      <utterance>I don't know! I paid them MORE to make it stop, God help me I even gave you to them... but they won't leave me alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was on my windshield--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cranks his neck around, looking for pursuers. Schuyler looks at him for a beat-- BANG! He almost loses control of the wheel.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit, oh SHIT they must be following us--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're shooting at us!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up the phone, punches buttons, gets nothing.</context>
      <utterance>David, get a grip, it's just a flat tire!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it, the phone's not working--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, I'll change the fucking thing myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David reaches for the glovebox.</context>
      <utterance>Just hurry-- I'll pop the trunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON GLOVEBOX-- it POPS OPEN and KEYS SPILL OUT. There are at least fifty of them jammed in there, all kinds, silver and gold... and all have CRS stamped on them. SCHUYLER leans closer, intrigued. David's eyes go wide as he fingers a few of these keys.</context>
      <utterance>No, you can't do it from--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are those--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like you don't know. Sonofabitch, they got to you first, didn't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um, David-- hello?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's more than that isn't it? You're part of it, you're one of them! Of course, it makes perfect sense!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler tries hard to be rational, but David is over the edge.</context>
      <utterance>They planted those keys! I don't know what the hell they're for--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're behind the whole thing aren't you? You and your sick fucking friends set it up--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! What friends? Get a grip, David-- why would I do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, out of boredom, to get back at me--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For being a weirdo, for trying to be happy? Well, congratulations, you win. Now make it stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't! Listen to me--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David SLUGS HIM in the face, Schuyler staggers back, clutches his BLEEDING nose. David runs, full tilt, into the woods near the Japanese Tea Garden. SCHUYLER pursues amidst the trees and vegetation, running out of breath, calling after David, who's vanished. He leans against a tree, PANTING, dabbing at his bleeding nose with a SCRAP OF TISSUE from his pocket. He hears a PHONE RINGING, moves toward it, emerging through bushes near the ACADEMY OF SCIENCE... He pauses at the RINGING PAYPHONE. He decides not to pick it up, looking around at the deserted MUSEUM BUILDINGS and hurrying toward civilization. He passes other PAYPHONES en route to the park exit... each one STARTS RINGING as he approaches it. He moves faster, freaked. At the edge of the park, he snatches one up-- SCHUYLER (on phone) What have you done to my brother, you bastards?! This is over, I'm not playing anymore-- (beat) Hello, is anyone there--</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>PHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER slams the phone down. He dabs his nose one more time, tosses the paper scrap into the trash. CLOSE ON SCRAP-- "CRS" with the emergency NUMBER, the blue ink has BLED with the rain and Schuyler's BLOOD...</context>
      <utterance>If you'd like to make a call, please hang up and dial again-- if you need help--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cabbie turns IN PROFILE for a moment. He appears to be wearing a HEARING AID, a round piece of plastic, a tiny WIRE disappearing into his shirt. And there's something familiar about his face. Schuyler glances at the driver ID on the back of the seat-- CLOSE ON PHOTO, the man is the RASTA from the airport, with a new hairdo. The COMPANY NAME-- "CONSOLIDATED REGENCY SEDANS." CRS. SCHUYLER rubs his head, very angry.</context>
      <utterance>You're heading the wrong way. CABBIE  Relax, pal, you'll get where you're going.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cab STOPS at a RED LIGHT. SCHUYLER tries the doorhandle-- it doesn't work.</context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing this-- CABBIE/RASTA  We do it all for you! We're the best friends you got, no one ever worked so hard to make you feel alive... but you gotta let it happen...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck is this--</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE/RASTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cabbie opens his own door and leaps out of the MOVING CAB--</context>
      <utterance>Have a nice day...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you... I'm very grateful.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler nods, looking around, recovering from the shock.</context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't swim in the Bay, you could get hepatitis.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to get in touch with the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're freezing, I got some dry clothes below.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His back is turned as the girl climbs down, opens her raincoat-- only a STRING BIKINI beneath. She could be a Playboy centerfold.</context>
      <utterance>Do you need any help?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns slowly, just as the girl reaches behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, no. I'm fine. These fit...  ...perfectly.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She WINKS as she lets her top drop. Schuyler smiles strangely. She takes this for lust, approaches him with open arms. He GRABS her by the hair. Menacingly:</context>
      <utterance>Sure I can't do something for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am finished playing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pounds at him, tries to kick. He wrestles her to the floor, kneels on top of her. He seems about to hit her.</context>
      <utterance>OW! Let go!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This has got to fucking STOP!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're hurting me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you!?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler gets his rage under control, horrified at himself. He climbs off her, she scrambles away, afraid, covering herself.</context>
      <utterance>I just got hired to show you a good time! C'mon please get off me...</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not into this kinda shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who hired you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, the service set it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The service?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler realizes he's not going to get anything more out of her, pulls on a shirt, grabs his wet clothes and leaves the cabin.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know, Fantasy Girls. They said you had this wild fantasy, I should just wait in the boat...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler pauses, turns slowly, approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Doncha want your thing? I'm supposed to give you this, this key thingie...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE GIRL nods quickly, reaches over the railing to hand him a SMALL WOODEN COFFIN with a BLACK BOW and a RED KEY BURNED into the lid.</context>
      <utterance>A key.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER takes it from her gingerly, undoes the bow, opens the lid: ANGLE IN COFFIN-- an ornate HATCHET with a KEY DESIGN on the blade. SCHUYLER REMOVES it from its QUILTED resting place. THE GIRL backs away, nervous to see SCHUYLER with a weapon.</context>
      <utterance>They said you'd figure out what to do with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drops the AXE and the COFFIN into the water with a SPLASH-- 95PT. THEY GO UNDER and DISAPPEAR...</context>
      <utterance>I'm supposed to carry a fucking hatchet around...? Relax. I don't want it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PLYMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you for your promptness, officers. I'm Robert Plympton, Mr. Van Orton's attorney--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go. Seventh floor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Management company for the building said this floor hasn't been rented. We checked with the Secretary of State and the county recorder, there's no listing of a "consumer research service."</utterance>
   <speaker>PLYMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Recreation service.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gallo, who'd been talking on a phone IN BG, approaches.</context>
      <utterance>Right. No sign of the boat or the girl. Divers got the cab's vehicle ID, the company junked it a month ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>GALLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The numbers you gave us are disconnected, sir, this was the only address the phone company had. And we found your car-- it's in impound.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a little confused as to motive here. You said your brother sent you to these people...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not his fault, he's unstable, he didn't know what he was doing--</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And they were supposed to show you a, a good time?</utterance>
   <speaker>GALLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler spots an empty CHINESE FOOD CARTON crumpled in the corner. CLOSER as SCHUYLER picks up and fingers the container-- Chinese characters on it, the name TUNG HOY.</context>
      <utterance>My guess is this Feingold guy's using an alias... is there anything else you can tell us about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He likes Chinese food...</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER nods, unconvinced.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Mr. Van Orton, we'll get these jokers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PLYMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's clearly a civil case once we locate the defendant...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLYMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER sighs and nods, closes the car door and waves good-bye. He climbs the steps to his front door and Plympton pulls away.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know, Sky, things are quiet since the closing-- you could take some time off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler realizes this is a two-way conversation as the CRS-MAN WINKS at him, making a stiff WAVE.</context>
      <utterance>No no no-- CRS-MAN  Oh you're always so negative...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You people are insane... CRS-MAN  Hey, look who's talking to their TV set.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you do this, how did you get in here? CRS-MAN  Simple, we duped your keys the day you came in for your physical, wired the whole house while you were at work. You rich people all have alarms, but you never set 'em, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, at least leave my brother alone, he's fragile enough as it is-- CRS-MAN  Don't worry about him, he's just playing his own game-- at a more advanced level, you might say...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CRS-MAN (on TV)</context>
      <utterance>You can't just fuck with people like this, you don't know who you're dealing with!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode>LAUGHS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son of a bitch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BELLHOP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler stares after the bellhop, whom he's clearly never seen before. He proceeds to the check-in desk. Before he can even introduce himself, the DESK CLERK turns to him with a tight smile--</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Van Orton.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From under the desk he removes a small ATTACHE CASE, places it gingerly in front of Schuyler.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Van Orton. Here's your credit card... and the maid found this under the bed...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That isn't mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER examines the case closely for the first time, sees the gold monogram, "S. V. O."</context>
      <utterance>It has your initials on it, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man trails off and moves away.</context>
      <utterance>We'd just as soon you took it with you, in any event... and in the future, you might consider choosing another hotel for your...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man ignores him now. Schuyler pockets his credit card, thinks a beat, then grabs the briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>I've never been here before in my life!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack... the woman you took home the other night, where did you go?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out to Concord...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACK is a bit nervous, he doesn't want to piss off the boss.</context>
      <utterance>I know, what was the address?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm... it was... Beulah Drive, I think, yeah, offa Oakdale... but didn't you-- never mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just-- I thought you followed us there. There was a black 500SE behind us the whole way, I just assumed...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. Shit! It wasn't me, Jack.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, sir. It was a white house, I remember... big tree in the front... with one of those, you know, tire swings...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack, I'm serious. It wasn't me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler looks at the man, who stares straight ahead, not believing him for a second. Schuyler shakes his head, looks down at the open briefcase in his lap. ANGLE IN BRIEFCASE-- a set of HANDCUFFS, assorted BONDAGE GEAR... and a few BLURRY POLAROID PHOTOS, showing a NAKED WOMAN with a LEATHER MASK chained to a bed. ONE SHOT shows her shoulder clearly-- we see a ROSE TATTOO.</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't you, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>IMPOUND WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler shakes his head. They've reached his MBZ.</context>
      <utterance>Triple A changed your tire... bad blow-out was it? Anyone hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>IMPOUND WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HIS POV-- THE BACKSEAT has been SLASHED. A few SPLASHES OF BLOOD, not too much. Schuyler's HARVARD SWEATSHIRT is torn and STAINED with blood, crumpled in a corner of the seat. SCHUYLER swallows, recovers quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Just... we were a little curious about the mess in the back... SCHUYLER bends down to look in the window.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A friend's dog-- he'd been hit by a car, I drove him to the vet...  Golden retriever, beautiful animal.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMPOUND WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He quickly gets behind the wheel.</context>
      <utterance>Too early to say.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR. KAMINSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Kaminsky? Schuyler Van Orton--</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. KAMINSKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(starts to close the door)</context>
      <utterance>Is that a name? Look, I'm kinda busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MR. KAMINSKY narrows his eyes at him as we hear--</context>
      <utterance>You have a daughter named Christine? I'm afraid she might be in danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode>O. S.</mode>
      <context>Schuyler, very surprised, peers around Mr. Kaminsky--</context>
      <utterance>Daddy? Who is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MR. KAMINSKY allows the relieved Schuyler to enter now.</context>
      <utterance>Sky? Hi, Sky.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine's dad WINKS at his daughter as he moves back to the basement. She rolls her eyes, but mouths, "thanks," and then moves to sit beside Schuyler in the modest, over-knick-knacked living room: religious pictures and statues, family photos, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm gonna get back to that carburetor... nice meeting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER is smiling at himself now, shaking his head. Christine reaches across him to FLIP ON a lamp.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't think I'd-- what are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last night, when Jack dropped you off-- did anything happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... unfortunately.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought-- eh, you don't wanna know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought they kidnapped you, tortured you--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>CRS... I saw pictures, girl with a tattoo on her shoulder like yours--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ssh, my folks don't know about that yet. So, what-- they wanted ransom from you or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I thought they were trying to frame me, they planted evidence...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would they do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no idea, nothing they do makes any sense. Forget it, it's just a game.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So that's the only reason you came out here to East Hell, your stupid goddamn game.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was worried about you. I wanted to see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you pretend to mean that, I'll pretend to believe it. Well, looks like your pals are trying to keep us together. Buy me dinner at least?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, why not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler nods casually toward the photo as she sits beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Can you get us into Chez Panisse? I always wanted to eat there--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm-hmm, First Communion.  What's the matter, you look a little green around the gills-- He grabs her hand away. Icily:</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His tone alarms her-- he stares at her with hatred. A silent BEAT between them, each tries to assess the new situation. She realizes he's onto her. She swallows, makes a quick decision. Suddenly she leans close to him, reaching around him to SHUT OFF the table lamp. She leaves her arms around him and HISSES in his ear-- she drops her lower-class accent, speaks in a clipped, educated voice:</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be stupid. Don't say anything, not here, they're watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She kisses him, he doesn't open his mouth, neither shuts their eyes. Then she gets up quickly, moves to a corner of the room.</context>
      <utterance>God damn it...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances up quickly to indicate something on the ceiling-- ON CEILING, a large SMOKE DETECTOR with a RED LIGHT, a cable from it-- there's a small LENS in the center... A HIDDEN CAMERA. SCHUYLER looks at this, starting to rise. She moves to a window, out of range of the camera, beckons him over.</context>
      <utterance>OK, I know a good place we could go and like, be alone...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler comes up beside her, she nods for him to look outside-- POV-- THROUGH WINDOW-- the CRS VAN. Christine WHISPERS urgently:</context>
      <utterance>It's a beautiful night, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's four of them in the van, they're armed. Just play along, I'll get us out of here-- SCHUYLER turns to her, his voice is tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.  OK, that's it, game over--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode>FILTER</mode>
      <context>He moves toward the front door, a panicked Christine behind him--</context>
      <utterance>--you can come out now, assholes--</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA MAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear MEN GETTING TO THEIR FEET, see BODIES MOVE in FG.</context>
      <utterance>We're blown, let's do it--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to pull him away from the door, he throws off her arm.</context>
      <utterance>You idiot! Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes to the window and opens the curtain. THROUGH WINDOW-- the Hack/Cabbie, the Rasta/Pilot and a pair of CRS AGENTS (JOHN and PETER from the men's club) hurry toward the house, the older men reach inside their jackets--</context>
      <utterance>No, enough already. I've had it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get away from there!!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's THROWN FORWARD as Schuyler SLAMS ON THE BRAKES, reaches across her and THROWS OPEN the passenger door, which CREAKS from the collision. He gives her a shove, she clings to the doorframe--</context>
      <utterance>OK, we lost 'em--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing!?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of my car.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I coulda handed you to them! They find me now I'm dead-- Schuyler pushes harder.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler pulls the door shut, the car starts BACKING AWAY. Christine gets to her feet, looks after him. He reaches the end of the alley and stops-- then SCREECHES FORWARD. She jumps to the edge of the alley, fearing he's trying to run her down. Schuyler HITS THE BRAKES a few feet away. He leans across, calls to her.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me you bastard-- I know what's going on! No one else is gonna tell you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine puts a hand on the wheel before he can back up again.</context>
      <utterance>You can talk while I drive to the police station.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just drive.</context>
      <utterance>No cops, I got an outstanding warrant.  Mail fraud. I'll get nailed, but you'll never be able to prove a thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heard about this big swindle and-- I needed the money. You wouldn't know what that's like.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spare me the snide comments. And please don't do that in here--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Second-hand smoke is the least of your problems.  Shit, they really screwed up, I can't believe they didn't take the time to get the house right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait, how did-- before the game, you</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, David's in on it...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not his fault, he thought it was the only way out... just another victim.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How the hell did they think they were gonna get my money?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a pitying look. Schuyler throws her a sidelong glance; this is absurd. She gestures at his car phone.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, they already got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CAMERA MOVES IN ON SCHUYLER'S FACE during the following and--</context>
      <utterance>You don't believe me, check your bank accounts. Listen, that night in your office, remember? I downloaded files off your computer while you were in the shower...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode>V. O.</mode>
      <context>127. --RAPID INSERTS from the CRS OFFICES-- Schuyler's SIGNATURE, financial FORMS, a TAPE RECORDER, TEST FORMS, etc.</context>
      <utterance>I stuck in a code-breaking program to glve CRS remote access to Van Orton Group files...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode>V. O.</mode>
      <context>--ON A CRT SCREEN as various combinations of letters and numbers SCROLL BY, too quickly for the eye to read.</context>
      <utterance>--you'd already given them everything else they needed. Your handwriting, voice samples, personal information, all the tests you took... they used the data to generate your passwords.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode>V. O.</mode>
      <context>--PAN OVER BANKS Of COMPUTER TERMINALS in DARK OffICES as financial READOUTS FLIP and CHANGE, VANISH. HIGH NUMBERS go to 0.00.</context>
      <utterance>From there they just had to break into the financial networks, transfer your holdings into some dummy accounts--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode>V. O.</mode>
      <context>--MOVE FROM deft fingers at a computer keyboard UPWARD toward the screen. POLARIZE to show, in reflection... FEINGOLD'S FACE, LIT BY the BLUE-GREEN CRT LIGHT, a mask of evil.</context>
      <utterance>Remember Jim Feingold, guy who signed you up? He's one of the original hackers, did a five-year stretch for zapping Citibank.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode>V. O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not some dweeb flunkie, he runs the whole show.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. They already did your brother, I guess they figured you for a family of suckers... SCHUYLER  Overseas operator? Please dial the number for Allgemeine Bank in Zurich...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bet you haven't really been taking care of business the past few days, huh? This "game," the psych shit about your dad going sui... SCHUYLER  Guten tag-- Vilen dank, Englisch...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler sets his jaw, drops the phone-- and turns the wheel hard.</context>
      <utterance>All of it was just to buy time, keep you from paying attention... SCHUYLER  Blue Two-Five... 6-9-0-D... Yes, I consent to voice-print... My name is Schuyler Van Orton. I'd like to know my balance, please... that account is closed?! CHRISTINE  I think maybe you should pull over...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler sighs, "of course," Christine fishes in her pocket.</context>
      <utterance>They say I gotta confiscate your card...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I have some cash.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler is seething, clutching the trunk lid for a beat, then SLAMS it hard when she steps back, making her jump.</context>
      <utterance>Money isn't everything, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It might be best if you didn't speak. I very nearly crushed your skull just now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon chill, what'd they take you for, a couple hundred G's? Chump change for a guy like you, chalk it up to experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just under a billion dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bil--?  You're kidding, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I look like I'm kidding? This is about more than my personal lifestyle-- your pals raided pension plans, charitable foundations, company payrolls...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her, she looks sick and truly scared. He climbs in the car. For once without a comeback, she gets in the car quietly.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what kind of jerk-off con games you've played in the past, but now you're in the big leagues, hon. You just helped sabotage a small portion of the national economy-- and destroy a whole lotta lives.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not having any?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler gives her a sidelong glance, looks back at a photo. ON PHOTO-- he rubs away the dust from a shot showing Schuyler's father, with young Schuyler, on a boat with fishing equipment. CHRISTINE takes a step and CRIES out, clutching her foot and sitting beside Schuyler. A small FISHHOOK protrudes from her foot,</context>
      <utterance>Never drink it. Makes my tits hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He talks while he carefully removes the hook from her foot.</context>
      <utterance>Hold still.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out the hook, puts it aside; she rubs her foot.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, this place hasn't been cleaned in a while. My dad built it himself, spent a lot of time here alone.  Rotten carpenter...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER suddenly starts LAUGHING, wipes tears from his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just-- private joke...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine looks at the photo of MR. VAN ORTON, then at Schuyler.</context>
      <utterance>Well... I always told myself I wasn't gonna end up like him. And now here I am, running his corporation, living in his house, hiding in the cabin where he went to hide right before he... I even look like the bastard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that much.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE CELL-PHONE CHIRPS, Schuyler shakes off his self-pity, snatches up the handset.</context>
      <utterance>Mm, plus I'm a helluva lot more gullible than he ever was...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. CHRISTINE mouths, "Who is it?" PLYMPTON   It's me, Schuyler... I got your message... I'll admlt, I was very disturbed...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>During the following, Christine's eyes go wide, she shakes her head frantically, draws a finger across her throat-- PLYMPTON (filter) I've been on the phone all morning... your funds are intact, nothing's changed, there's been no activity whatsoever... SCHUYLER struggles to absorb the import of this as well as Christine's behavior. She shakes her head with a sigh, rises to refill his coffee cup.</context>
      <utterance>My, lawyer.  So. What's our next move?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER looks at Christine with horror. She nods and WHISPERS:</context>
      <utterance>Wait-- that's not true-- PLYMPTON   It is true, no one is after your money, no one is trying to hurt you--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's in on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, God... PLYMPTON  Listen to me, Sky!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler HANGS UP, breathing hard, pacing, clutching the phone.</context>
      <utterance>What are they paying you, Robert? Piece of the action? PLYMPTON  Schuyler! Look, you've done the right thing going up there, maybe it's best if you just sit tight for a while, forget about everything, it's all under control--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine approaches him with a fresh cup of coffee, which he sips. The PHONE CHIRPS again, Schuyler THROWS it violently against the wall, it's silenced. He gulps more coffee, rising again, looking at the smashed phone, sickened by his own loss of control.</context>
      <utterance>We have to get out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine watches him closely. He keeps balling his hands into fists as he paces, trying to think out his next play.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that was stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is there anyone I can trust?</context>
      <utterance>OK, they've gotten to him. OK.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mm... I wouldn't worry about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a step, stumbles, shakes his head to clear it. She rises, picks up his half-empty cup and heads for the kitchen area. His gaze follows this, he realizes he's been drugged.</context>
      <utterance>It's out of your hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christine!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a CRY OF RAGE he lunges after her, but CRASHES into the wall, clutching at a hanging ROD, which falls when he does-- he KNOCKS OVER the table of photos as he goes down, PANTING for air like a fish out of water, clutching his stomach, nauseated. HIS POV-- SIDEWAYS, LOW ANGLE. SFX, BLOOD POUNDING in his head. Schuyler's eyes FOLLOW the GROOVES of the wet, warped hardwood floor, they lead to-- and almost seem to point to-- Christine. ANOTHER ANGLE, CLOSE-- from the counter she picks up a small vial with a bit of powder at the bottom, slips it into her pocket. SCHUYLER's eyes roll into his head as he struggles against the effects, tries to get to his hands and knees. He gasps:</context>
      <utterance>That's not my name.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHRISTINE approaches, stands a few feet away, lights a cigarette,</context>
      <utterance>Why...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crouches by him, flicking ashes a few inches from his nose.</context>
      <utterance>We needed you to call your banks. Cellular calls can be intercepted, rerouted, y'know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He CLAWS at her helplessly with a GROAN, but misses. His glasses fall off, he collapses again. SCHUYLER'S POV-- everything a BLUR NOW, except in EXTREME FG-- the photo of himself and his father, which now lies on the floor. 137. FLASH-CUT TO: FLASHBACK POV-- THE MOMENT OF IMPACT, as MR. VAN ORTON'S FACE SMASHES into the ground, his GLASSES SHATTERING, BLOOD SPRAYING from his head. 138. CUT BACK TO: SCHUYLER writhes, fighting the drug. 139. FLASH-CUT TO: The moment of his father's jump-- only in this HALLUCINATION, SCHUYLER himself wears the robe, leaps into space. 140. SCHUYLER'S POV-- FROM FLOOR-- Christine moves INTO FOCUS, crouches near him, studying her victim almost clinically.</context>
      <utterance>All those calls to Switzerland and Chase Manhattan-- you were talking to our people. See, we were still missing a lotta pieces-- access codes, passwords, stuff even Plyrnpton didn't have-- but now we have I everything. I guess you are pretty fucking stupid-- but thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SFX POUNDING STOPS, and--</context>
      <utterance>It's over. Just let go...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man replies with an EXCLAMATION in SPANISH, pushes Schuyler away, CAMERA TUMBLES-- OBJECTIVE SHOT-- Schuyler's on his knees in the middle of this third-world thoroughfare, utterly disoriented. STREET VENDORS sell weird-looking foods, squads of SQLDIERS march with rifles, MUSICIANS PLAY odd instruments... Schuyler clutches his head, as if trying to wish it all away. A COP IN BEIGE UNIFORM suddenly prods at him with a nightstick, YELLING AT HIM in SPANISH to move on. SCHUYLER'S POV-- the COP looming over him, a BLURRY menace, the end of the nightstick SHARP in FG as it POKES at him. ANOTHER ANGLE-- Schuyler pleads with the man:</context>
      <utterance>Where am I?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This doesn't seem to help. He tries to get away from the stick, but the cop pursues. He bangs into people as he tries to move quickly, the stick right behind him. Schuyler FALLS over a BEGGAR on the ground, in far worse shape than he is. The cop YELLS at him. Schuyler covers his head, holding out the NOTE WITH THE KEY, which the cop finally snatches away. He studies it for a moment, then BARKS with LAUGHTER. SCHUYLER'S POV-- the cop reaches down to him-- OBJECTIVE ANGLE-- Schuyler cringes, expecting a blow, but the cop just pulls him to his feet. He drags him away with him, speaking more gently IN SPANISH, amused. Schuyler nods thankfully. HIGH ANGLE-- the THRONGS on this crowded street.</context>
      <utterance>Please, help me, I'm an American! I'm lost! Please!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello. Where am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tegucigalpa.  Tegucigalpa. Tegucigalpa?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's gibberish!</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER buries his face in his hands, nods. He's relieved to have found an English speaker at least.</context>
      <utterance>It is the capital of Honduras.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So-- you have become, lost from, from your father...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sergeant cocks his head, confused. Indicating the note:</context>
      <utterance>My father's dead, God damn it. I have to get to the United States embassy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what this says?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANOTHER ANGLE-- Schuyler, utterly humiliated, sits in a chair on the other side of the desk.</context>
      <utterance>"I am an American. I am an idiot. My father is very rich. If I become lost, please take me to the police. There is a reward."</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Van Orton... is this a joke of some sort? What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, without any identification it will take at least a week to get you a temporary visa--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A week?! Christ knows what they can do in a week-- and what the hell am I supposed to, to live on?! What day is it anyway?  Where's the nearest pawn shop?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PAWN SHOP OWNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the other side of the counter, SCHUYLER Sorts through A BOX OF EYEGLASSES, trying on different pairs.</context>
      <utterance>This will buy you a plane ticket.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pawn shop owner nods knowingly. There's one other CUSTOMER, a shabbily-dressed but honest-looking HONDURAN MAN, looking through a BIN full of sports equipment. He seems to have been eavesdropping, the pawn shop owner now exchanges a few words with him IN SPANISH, clearly they're coming to some kind of deal. Meanwhile, Schuyler puts on a rhinestone-studded pair of woman's glasses, looks around.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well I, I seem to have lost my passport...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh, close enough...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAWN SHOP OWNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler narrows his eyes at the Honduran man, who flashes a crooked-toothed smile.</context>
      <utterance>I throw them in.  This man says he can help you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David turns to him, half-smiles; food particles on his lips.</context>
      <utterance>David...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler sits close to David, upset.</context>
      <utterance>Hello Sky...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David does seem in control now, if a little hazy.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, I was just eating... I'm much better. Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He clutches his brother's hand. David narrows his eyes, confused.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God... Listen, I know you put them onto me-- but I understand, we're both victims of this thing... They've stolen everything we ever had, they're trying to drive us both crazy-- but we won't let them. We'll find a way. There's gotta be a way to beat these bastards! We're in it together...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In what together?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The game.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Schuyler, there is no game. It was just a fantasy of mine, a self- aggrandizing delusion... I can't believe you took that shit seriously.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, David-- please...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler stares at him for a beat-- no getting through. David leans forward, turns UP THE TV VOLUME, aiming the set at Schuyler.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, man, stop fucking with me! You know the game doesn't exist... it never did! It never did...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON SCREEN-- a golf ball rolls on a green and PLOPS into the cup.</context>
      <utterance>Can you see?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the waitress was in on it--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She isn't really a waitress.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER narrows his eyes at the question. GALLO, beyond a METAL DETECTOR in the rear area of the station, gestures to Barnett, who holds up a finger.</context>
      <utterance>--and now you're brother's been institutionalized... is there a history of mental illness in your family?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moving away, Barnett glances at the leatherbound book, which Schuyler clutches very possessively.</context>
      <utterance>'Scuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatcha reading?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barnett purses his lips, nods, steps around the metal detector to chat with Gallo.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GALLO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WITH SCHUYLER as GALLO AND BARNETT glance in his direction, gesture for him to approach. Gallo WINKS casually at Schuyler. SCHUYLER, wary now, moves toward them through the METAL DETECTOR-- which GOES OFF with a WHINE. The ALARM MONITOR woman approaches with a wand-- but Schuyler steps back, wide-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>I just spoke with his lawyer Plympton, he thinks Van Orton's having a nervous breakdown, we should probably hold onto him till his people can get down here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ALARM MONITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER turns and moves quickly for the exit.</context>
      <utterance>Probably just your keys, sir--</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's through the door. The WHINE OF THE DETECTOR continues as we--</context>
      <utterance>Yo, Schuyler, wait up--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER starts; the PUNK keeps the knife on him. He's a young, glassy-eyed junkie. He wears a RADIO EARPLUG in one ear, a wire heading down to his waist. Schuyler nods, starts studying the man's arms, heavily TATTOOED with crude cabalistic SYMBOLS.</context>
      <utterance>End of the line, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are the tattoos supposed to mean something?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, they mean you're dead, you don't gimme what you got.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, there's the C...</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me the fucking bag!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Schuyler speaks he sits up, the PUNK grabs the bag-- Schuyler grabs the guy's knife hand, they wrestle on the floor of the car, clawing at each other. The punk drops the knife, it gets knocked beneath the seat, both men reach for it...</context>
      <utterance>Come on, you're not going to put me through all this shit and then kill me on a fucking train, it won't look like a suicide...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSIT COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler and the punk look up to see a TRANSIT COP pointing his WEAPON. The punk throws his hands up, scrambles to his feet--</context>
      <utterance>Freeze assholes!</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cop has grabbed the still prone Schuyler, flipping him over and slapping a handcuff on him--</context>
      <utterance>Psycho pulled a knife on me!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cop has dropped his guard; the punk spins and bolts into the next car, squeezing through the door. The TRANSIT COP hastily cuffs Schuyler to an armrest--</context>
      <utterance>What do you think you're doing, this guy attacked me!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRANSIT COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dashes into the next car after the punk. Schuyler looks at the floor of the car, sees-- THE SMALL RADIO and its EARPLUG attached by a WIRE. The radio has a tiny LOOP/RABBIT EAR antenna on it. He snatches it up, then YANKS at the cuff. He spots the knife under the seat, grabs it, starts using the blade to unscrew the armrest from its post. FROM THE NEXT CAR he hears SHOUTS, SCREAMS, a serious commotion going on, he doesn't know who's winning. Schuyler's almost gotten free as the TRAIN SLOWS, when-- --the DOOR at the far end of the car opens, it's the PUNK, bruised and bloody, ready to kill. He lunges at Schuyler just as he PRIES THE ARMREST off the seat and CLOBBERS him with it. The punk reels back. The train has stopped, the doors have opened-- Schuyler grabs his bag and squeezes out onto the platform just before they shut again.</context>
      <utterance>Wait here--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER listens intently, leaning against a wall in the shadows, breathing hard. He stares nervously at a couple of nearby STREET PEOPLE huddled by a shopping cart, they stare back. Another VOICE on the radio talks OVER the first:</context>
      <utterance>--can't let him get away with this, he's outta control! The next thing you know, he'll push the wrong button and we'll all be dead--</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hear the HYSTERICAL GIGGLING of ROBIN QUIVERS. SCHUYLER blinks, recognizing the voice of RADIO DJ HOWARD STERN.</context>
      <utterance>--Whoah whoah whoah-- OK the guy's a moron, sure, but he doesn't have the balls to end the world! Anyway I'm sicka talking politics, let's get back to the business of nipple piercing-- you got a ring, don't ya Robin?</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE #2</speaker>
      <mode>HOWARD STERN</mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER fiddles frantically with the dial and antennas, calling up RANDOM RADIO MUSIC, COMMERCIALS, etc. CLOSE ON A TRASH CAN-- Schuyler tosses his hollowed leather book into it. It falls open, we see the gun is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Ugh, we gotta do commercials, this is the Howard Stern show...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I shouldn't be bothering you-- you're a genuinely good person, your work is important, it's real, nothing that happens to me is real anymore--</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What has happened to you, Sky?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need your help, you're the only one left, the only one I can trust-- not that I deserve your help, God how could you have even married me, I was a shit to you--</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you weren't--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I was. Sometimes I think I'm being punished for my sins, I mean, there has to be a reason...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler waves dismissively, "you don't understand," takes the radio back from her and pockets it.</context>
      <utterance>It's... a radio...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't find the right channel... Listen, I may not make it through this-- if anything happens, get that notebook to, to, the press, or the FBI or something. Someone you can trust, I don't know, assuming you can trust</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches her as she retreats, leans toward Elizabeth, puts his hand on top of her cup.</context>
      <utterance>No sir. Just like you said.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler opens the bottle and drinks straight from it thirstily. Elizabeth registers the CLINKING HANDCUFFS on his left wrist.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think coffee is safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Schuyler, try and listen to me. I love you, I always have, I always will. And maybe this is... good. Maybe this a point you had to reach, before--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before-- I'm just glad you came to me for help. I don't know if I'm strong enough to, to handle this on my own but I know a lot of excellent crisis people--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A CELL-PHONE RINGS in her purse, she makes an exasperated noise and pulls it out, with a "one sec" gesture at Schuyler. He rises during her conversation, a new look on his face-- he can't trust her either.</context>
      <utterance>Crisis people. Crisis people?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler's distracted by something on the TV... he lets out a STRANGLED CRY. Elizabeth turns her head to see. ON TV SCREEN-- It's JIM FEINGOLD, clutching his head, rubbing his temples with a look of pain. CHEESY MUSIC, THROBBING SPFX. SCHUYLER approaches the set, shouting at it.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Hi, hon, I'm OK... um, could I call you back...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elizabeth gets up, tries to pull him back to the booth, he pushes her away, not taking his eyes from the set. PATRONS react nervously to the deranged man. FEINGOLD (ON TV, filter) Ooof-- my head is killing me!</context>
      <utterance>You bastard! You fucking bastard! How did you find me here!?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE TV IMAGE WIDENS, a COMMERCIAL ACTRESS rubs Feingold's neck.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course he's an actor, it's a commercial.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head, waves his hand dismissively. He's thinking about something else. Elizabeth starts dialing.</context>
      <utterance>Are you on drugs?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler tries to sound normal, claps her on the arm. WHILE HE TALKS, CAMERA FINDS Schuyler's other hand, which slips stealthily into her PURSE, lying on the seat of the booth.</context>
      <utterance>Schuyler, I'm calling a friend right now, I want you to wait here with me until--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves quickly down a corridor marked RESTROOMS and EMERGENCY EXIT. She looks after him, quite puzzled, phone still to her ear.</context>
      <utterance>Elizabeth, please... I'm sorry, I'II be alright, it's just been a hard day... Listen, I gotta use the restroom, be right back--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's an actor, does TV commercials, I know he's ordered from you, he had food delivered to an office building on Mission--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINESE WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Many customers, very busy, I don't know, I don't know--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler stalks away from her, finds himself facing the wall of signed photographs-- ON WALL, old and stained pictures, the most famous being the likes of ED McMAHON and CHARO. Among them is a newer HEAD SHOT of FEINGOLD with a shit-eating grin... below, the name WILLIAM FISHER. SCHUYLER leaps on the counter and tears the photo off the wall--</context>
      <utterance>Damn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHINESE WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler's already leapt off the counter, bolts out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Stop that, what you doing?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bill Fisher, hi! I really admire your work...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler releases him, Feingold sheepishly avoids his eyes. Schuyler casually shows him the gun, the man's eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>Oh please... I got my kids here...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get rid of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dangles the bill over their heads, the KIDS CHEER, leap like dolphins after fish. The girl's tallest, grabs the cash, they run for a nearby concession. Schuyler and Feingold stroll together.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, everyone-- here's a twenty! Snack time!</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, buddy, it was just a job-- nothing personal, y'know? I play my part, improvise a little, that's what I'm good at, I still do a little stand-up--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen your resume. I'm sick of foot soldiers, I've gotta get to whoever's in charge.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FEINGOLD'S BOYS ARE THROWING ROCKS at the monkeys. They give their father a look and saunter along. SCHUYLER's not interested in the zoo drama.</context>
      <utterance>Of CRS? Christ, nobody knows, nobody gets the big picture--  Jason, Tommy, cut it out!</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddammit, why do they do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I find them!? Their offices were abandoned--</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler takes this in for a moment, thinking.</context>
      <utterance>They own the whole building, they just move from floor to floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK... They know you, you've worked for them. You're going to get me inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-uh, I'm sorry and all, but--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell them anything, tell them the cops are after you, you've gotta talk to someone or you'll blow the whistle.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler cocks his head, steps in front of him. Right in his face:</context>
      <utterance>No way, it's too dangerous.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't seem to understand. Right here, right now--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEHIND THE SEAT-- Schuyler crouches under a blanket.</context>
      <utterance>We're here, Sky. They said they're on the twelfth floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drive in, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look-- what are you gonna do? Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really-- I don't know. Improvise. Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GATE GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE INTO GARAGE-- the gate guard jogs TOWARD the elevators, pulling his gun. SCHUYLER starts to panic, pulls his own gun and POINTS IT AT THE GUARD, who freezes and raises his hands. Behind him, the Security Man approaches Schuyler from a different angle, his gun out. Schuyler can't get a bead on both of them.</context>
      <utterance>Yo!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler looks one more time at the elevator panel-- AT BASE OF PANEL, a gold keyhole. CLOSER-- the letters CRS are printed beneath it, very small. SCHUYLER shakes his head-- it couldn't be; but what else can he do? ANGLE INTO GARAGE-- the guards are fanning out and getting closer. SCHUYLER reaches with one hand for his keys, fumbling for the small gold key he received at the start of the game. ON PANEL-- his hand shakes as he tries to insert the gold key... it fits into the hole; he turns it and PUSHES THE BUTTON for 12. WIDER-- as the DOORS CLOSE, both guards train their guns-- but too late. Schuyler's on his way up. 184A. THE GLASS ELEVATOR RISES through completely blackened spaces. SCHUYLER stares at a BULLET HOLE in the back of the glass elevator, a remnant of Feingold's murder. He holds the gun in front of himself in both hands... then he closes his eyes, steeling himself, almost in an attitude of prayer.</context>
      <utterance>You're a dead man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, everything's OK, nobody touched your money, nobody stole a thing, that's impossible--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't give a fuck about the money, I wanna know who's behind this, who did this to me, how, why--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even though she's keeping a surface cool, he notices the GLASS and SILVERWARE on her tray RATTLING. She starts to move toward a table, he blocks her path.</context>
      <utterance>It's just a game!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not going anywhere. Feingold, or or Fisher, was that just a game too?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler shows her his BLOOD-STAINED HAND. Christine looks utterly perplexed, then shrugs, finding a place to put down her tray.</context>
      <utterance>I watched him die...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seemed like a nice guy, actually, father of three--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, look, I'm sure it's just another stunt-- that can't be real, taste it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes his palm in her face, she flinches, swipes him away, then puts a finger to her ear as-- THE ELEVATOR DOORS OPEN and the guard and security man from downstairs burst into the commissary. Suddenly the ROOM QUIETS, many others are touching their ears. They all TURN in the direction of Schuyler and Christine. The gate guard gestures at Schuyler, attempting a smile.</context>
      <utterance>You taste it, you fucking vampire.</utterance>
   <speaker>GATE GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler grabs Christine, wraps an arm around her throat, puts his GUN to her neck.</context>
      <utterance>Could you come with us, please? You're not authorized to be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He uses his knee in the small of her back to push her brutally toward the nearest door, she CHOKES and GASPS.</context>
      <utterance>Back off. Everybody back off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler addresses her as if speaking to a child:</context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute. What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my gun...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't give it to you? Where did it come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A gun store.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We searched your house!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine touches her ear, listening to something, then puts her hand to her mouth, speaks urgently.</context>
      <utterance>Guess you fucked up again.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler steps forward and violently wrenches the EAR PIECE and HAND MIKE away from Christine, the wire tears her blouse open.</context>
      <utterance>He's armed, he's got a real gun. Real Situation, real--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's real all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Schuyler this is all</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The key!! They, we gave you a key to the elevator! Why would we do that?! We wanted you to come up--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you did. So you could kill me or, or frame me for murder--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler hesitates a moment, looking in the direction of the door.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, it's THE GAME!! Blanks, squibs, high-tech special effects, none of it's real! Just open that door and I'll show you!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON THE DOOR-- POUNDING DESPERATE, but the ALARM DROWNS out the sounds of VOICES on the other side. SCHUYLER turns quickly as she takes a step towards him. He points the gun at her again. He looks ready to use it. The following DIALOG overlaps and collides, growing AURAL CHAOS--</context>
      <utterance>I open the door and I die.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You move again I swear I'll kill you, you bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>THINK ABOUT IT!! They followed you every step of the way, the cab, in the trunk, we had a diver--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They? We?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--the guy in Honduras, the cop on the train, there was always a safety net, always--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AXES DENT the metal door, which BULGES. He looks at the monitor in his hand, the one he tore from her body, putting it in his own ear, letting the rest of the device dangle. RADIO VOICE (filter) --just hang in there, keep talking him down, we're on our way--</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, shut the fuck up!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been trying to end it since you got back, our people came to your house, they tried to bring you in from the subway, you kept running, you weren't supposed to keep getting lost--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just said you wanted me to come here-- you're making this up as you go along!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please Sky, please. Take a breath and think about it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler runs a hand over his sweating forehead, the gun TREMBLING in his hand. Christine's regaining control. Schuyler's mind whirls, he GROANS, almost crying as he considers for the first time that she might be telling the truth. She steps closer.</context>
      <utterance>Stop. Fucking. With my head!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're all right, it's OK, just relax... RADIO VOICE  Are you there? How's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please... when you open the door, the game ends... just open the door... Bill Fisher's out there, he's fine, nobody got hurt. Why would we do the crazy things we did, if it wasn't part of a game? We thought you</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DAVID steps through. He wears a brightly colored, silly looking PARTY HAT, carries a magnum of CHAMPAGNE bearing a huge BOW that reads, "SURPRISE." BLOOD PUMPS from HIS CHEST. He DROPS THE BOTTLE, which SHATTERS... David collapses amidst the broken glass. A BLOW OF THE AXE SEVERS the deadbolt and Door 1 flies open behind Schuyler. FEINGOLD is the first of a group to come charging through, he wears a TUXEDO with a ROSE in the lapel, holds the axe. SCHUYLER spins, points the gun at this axe-wielding man, then, utterly stunned, lowers it in disbelief. FEINGOLD looks from Schuyler to the wounded Christine-- her agony is painful to watch. He drops the axe with a CLATTER and runs to her side, kneels. His voice CRACKS.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God. I blew it... we blew it... DOOR 2 OPENS and--</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David, David, no, no--</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, Oh God, Sky, save me, I don't wanna die, I don't wanna--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WITH FEINGOLD and CHRISTINE. He holds his colorful cummerbund over her stomach to staunch the bleeding. She CHOKES in pain.</context>
      <utterance>You're not gonna die. I'm here, you're not gonna die... David's already DEAD, eyes wide, body limp.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang on, just hang on, you're gonna make it--</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare over at Schuyler, registering David's death. Schuyler is now drenched in his brother's blood, rocking him in his arms. Most of the assorted CRS people move to get out of the building before the cops show, MURMURING amongst themselves in fear.</context>
      <utterance>That stupid...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHRISTINE yells at Schuyler, unable to stand--</context>
      <utterance>Oh God. I thought you could handle it. All the tests... they said you could handle it...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER gently lowers his brother and rises, like a zombie now. The big security man picks up his gun and backs away with it, keeping it out of his reach. Schuyler backs away from the body, starts to SHAKE, looks as if he really has lost his mind. Feingold SOBS aloud.</context>
      <utterance>You fucking psycho, you piece of shit, how could you--</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler looks back and forth from the wounded Christine-- who GASPS silent curses, beyond speech-- to David's body... He slowly turns to the Atrium pit directly in front of him. He's strangely calm...</context>
      <utterance>God, why-- there was no point. It was supposed to be fun...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fun...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Getting no response, David hops closer, squats by Schuyler's side.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, bro, how you doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER remains motionless, David's worried now, grabs his arm and starts shaking him.</context>
      <utterance>Admit it, you weren't bored...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SCHUYLER begins to LAUGH, a tremendous catharsis. DAVID laughs too, greatly relieved as he helps Schuyler to his feet. THE TWO BROTHERS clutch each other for support on the BOUNCING surface, LAUGHING. CRS EMPLOYEES have gathered around the cushion, CHEERING and APPLAUDING. SCHUYLER wipes his eyes, shaking his head with amazement. Then he hauls back and SLUGS DAVID in the jaw, sending him flying onto his back on the cushion. MORE CHEERS from the crowd, as if they were watching a boxing match.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus. Sky, c'mon Sky--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler half-smiles. The SECURITY MAN unlocks Schuyler's handcuffs, giving him back his gun, which Schuyler stares at.</context>
      <utterance>You've been wanting to do that for a long, long time, haven't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn a corner into the main lobby, Schuyler absently pockets the gun, looks up in wonder... SCHUYLER'S POV-- a SURPRISE PARTY: A STEREO, STREAMERS and BALLOONS, a CHAMPAGNE FOUNTAIN, CAKE and FOOD. CRS EMPLOYEES (mostly ordinary-looking office workers) CLAP and CHEER for Schuyler. They wear PARTY HATS, blow PLASTIC HORNS. SMILING PEOPLE eager to offer CONGRATULATIONS surround him. He's pretty shaky, like a newborn calf. JOHN and PETE shake his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Like they'd really leave a loaded gun lying around. They went over the whole place with a metal detector, then packed that thing with blanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good one, buddy, really had you going, didn't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The RASTA SLAPS his back, Schuyler instinctively looks over his shoulder for a gag message.</context>
      <utterance>Wait'll you try level two...  Joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>RASTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The RECEPTIONIST POPS a bottle of Dom Perignon, hands it to Sky.</context>
      <utterance>That look on your face up there? Shit, man, I almost lost it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not knowing what else to do, Schuyler takes a slug. The GIRL from the boat KISSES his cheek. TECHNICIANS, men with STUNTS UNLIMITED T-SHIRTS, the NURSE from the asylum, the SECURITY PEOPLE, CRS GUARDS, AGENTS, all want a piece of him at once. The "MESSIAH" FADES and an R &amp; B BAND breaks into ROUSING MUSIC as Feingold approaches and sticks a CIGAR in his mouth, LIGHTS it.</context>
      <utterance>Awesome game-- best I've seen.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEINGOLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christine approaches, wobbly and dazed herself; she touches his arm. Her voice is soft for the first time, accents gone.</context>
      <utterance>Sure glad you jumped, compadre. Otherwise I was supposed to throw you off.  It's not strictly legal, so don't tell anyone...  The cigar. It's a Monte Cristo, straight from Havana.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so. You?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little shook. I'm pretty much a method actress, y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Susan. Susan Waters.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you, Susan...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a DRAG on his cigar.</context>
      <utterance>Can I have a puff?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs, blows a SMOKE RING and sticks her finger through it.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I have to know. Who's really in charge?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She winks and strolls off. Schuyler smiles, looking after her. DANCING is starting up IN BG. A clutch of non-CRS people approach tentatively-- including PLYMPTON, ELIZABETH, MARIA and JACK. They all look very confused.</context>
      <utterance>God?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLYMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this, Sky? We got a call from your brother, said there was a surprise party...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Schuyler LAUGHS, gives her a hug, surprising her. He still has a giddy smile plastered on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Kind of late for your birthday, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELIZABETH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you wanted to borrow my car, you could've just asked--</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, Liz, I've been an idiot, and I'm sorry...</utterance>
   <speaker>PLYMPTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves away quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah-- I'm good, really. Happy to be alive... Listen, it's great to see all of you, thanks for coming-- but there's something I have to do. Excuse me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's the object of the game?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What game?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it always like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David pulls out A COLORED ENVELOPE, slips it into Schuyler's shirt. Schuyler looks at him curiously as he dries his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Mine was a little weirder. Tell you about it sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bill. It's itemized. Don't bother opening it now...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it was a gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, no, the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCHUYLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move into a stairwell and start climbing O. S., their hands all over each other. We hear the MUSIC and FESTIVITIES continuing in BG. CAMERA HOLDS for a beat on a SIGN painted on the wall with an arrow upward: "LEVEL 2..."</context>
      <utterance>Does it matter?</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
