<movie id="447" title="Prophecy The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GARGOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon's climbed to his feet, the two men in sunglasses now walking slow circles around each other.</context>
      <utterance>Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARGOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've found it, haven't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gargoyle drops his head and DRIVES himself into Simon, who HAMMERS the gargoyle with his fists. Blood SMEARS. The gargoyle's gotten free a knife that he JAMS into Simon's leg. Pressing home his advantage, the gargoyle SLAMS Simon up against the wall. He TEARS open Simon's shirt, digging his fingers into the chest, RIPPING the skin aside, the first plunging deep, CRACKING the sternum bone, pushing even further, toward the blood gouged pumping beneath -- -- Simon PLOWS his knee up between the gargoyle's legs. Over and over. Till the grip loosens and Simon SHOVES him to one side, using the momentum and drives to SWING the body around and at the shattered window. The gargoyle SMACKS the frame and COLLAPSES, his head CRACKING on the sill and FORCING a shard of glass through his neck. Simon moves to the window and brushes aside the gargoyle's sunglasses, revealing two totally empty eye sockets. Pushing his thumbs into them, Simon uses the leverage to lift the gargoyle off the sill and push his body out the window. The gargoyle bounces once on the fire escape, then spread- eagles thirty feet to the asphalt. Somebody turns up their Mexican radio station. The gargoyle's a wreck. But he manages, slowly -- his shattered remains arguing every inch -- to climb first to his knees, then miserably to his feet. A bent, splattered, hopeless thing that manages to stumble three or four feet before being HIT by a freeway- speed firebird BOMBING down the alley. The impact PINS the gargoyle to the grill and RAMS him into a brick wall, CRUSHING a chest that BELCHES out a sickly, bruised heart like a wet rag against the firebird's windshield.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>THOMAS DAGGET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I warned you about that cheerful shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He eyes finally make their way to the gargoyle.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry. I'm working on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the word?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friend here did a half-gainer with a firebird tuck from the third floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jumper?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not unless he decided not to bother opening the window first.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drugs? Alcohol?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he wasn't exactly in a condition to walk a chalk line when we got here. You're welcome to try and smell his breath if you like, that is if you can find the mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ghouls been by?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On their way. Willie promises a white paper tomorrow. Or Wednesday, depending on his golf game.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burrows nods in the direction of a very shook up young man sitting on the curb.</context>
      <utterance>Firebird driver?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Jiminez. Was taking a short cut to his job at a packing plant on San Pedro. First thing he remembers about the deceased is several vital organs bouncing off his windshield.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you had him walk a chalk line?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's straight. Shook up some.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything on him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No wallet, license, nothing. He is missing one or two things, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Along with everything else.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've found everything else -- and what fun that was, let me tell you -- but the eyes are still AWOL. Might just be stuck in the radiator grill. Little weird though.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Both popping out together like that. Worth a page in my scrapbook.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the room registered under?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John Smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything interesting inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They enter the room, which is, of course, totally trashed. Thomas steps over the splintered furniture.</context>
      <utterance>There are, what an intelligent, experienced detective like yourself could possibly construe as signs of a struggle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naturally nobody saw or heard anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas looks at the splashes of blood, overturned dressers, a newspaper, the "Chimney Rock Republican"; one name in its obit section circled. Burrows sighs and checks his watch.</context>
      <utterance>In such a fine establishment as this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ku San's on fourteenth is still open for another hour. Whatd'ya say we pull out the 'ol "SUICIDE" rubber stamp and get some lunch. Rancid chow mein and watered beer for under three bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's glass in the carpet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That usually happens when you break a window.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Amongst the glass fragments at Thomas' feet is a pair of dark sunglasses. He picks them up, taps them in his palm, and looks out the window down to the man with no eyes, pinched between brick and chrome.</context>
      <utterance>It's on the inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Chimney Rock?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arizona desert, I think. Which is exactly where I'm going to be in two years, three months.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And give up all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROWS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're breaking my heart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl's eyes seem too serious for a child's. Too perceptive.</context>
      <utterance>Hey bright eyes, what's the deal being out here all alone without a coat?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine looks out into the night.</context>
      <utterance>Someone's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary stares a moment longer, then becomes a child again, smiling and popping Katherine one on the arm.</context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pig out on all the cake?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary suddenly points past Katherine's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, there might be one, tiny, skinny piece left, but you're gonna have to race me for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Katherine turns Mary dashes back into the building.</context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine chases after her.</context>
      <utterance>You little sneak!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it going?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just looking for my "SUICIDE" rubber stamp.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about leaving you without a partner. Everything's up in the air till the commission settles their manpower budget.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm okay.  Dagget... It's done already?  Must have rained over the golf course this morning. I'll be right over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="35">
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The coroner just stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Willie, sorry to hear about the weather.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I bother sitting?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas obeys as the coroner spreads out a stack of white sheets.</context>
      <utterance>Sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where would you like me to start?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we can skip the cause of death.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. To begin with, your man has no eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weren't stuck in the radiator grill?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he never had any eyes. We checked the sockets. There's no optic nerve, muscle pores, loose viscus, nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We also did a toxicology on his blood: High sodium, elevated selenium, no floating cholesterol platelets, trace ammonia.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something wrong with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's actually pretty common -- for an aborted fetus.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should have listened to Burrows...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We also did a bone section. Wasn't that much trouble since most of them were sticking out of his chest anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When babies grow up their bones get larger by adding calcium layers over the interior haversham canals. Child growth isn't uniform though, comes in spurts that always leave growth rings in the bone. Everybody has them -- except your man. That would, to a hasty observer, seem to indicate he had never been a child.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I assume you, a cautious and learned observer, of course have an explanation.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not even remotely. Want to hear the last one?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not even remotely.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a hermaphrodite.  -- Has both male and female sex organs.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think of the possibilities.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas sighs and climbs to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you can be impotent and frigid all at the same time -- they don't normally work.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'd love to say thank you, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The coroner opens his desk and pulls out a small, ancient looking leather bound book.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I also have a bonus prize for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas turns it over in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Found this sealed in his coat lining.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a bible.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas runs his finger across the gold-leaf cover.</context>
      <utterance>A pretty old one, I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We checked it out inside. Thought there might be a name or fingerprint somewhere. All we found was a curled page marking the fourteenth chapter of St. John's Revelations.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no fourteenth chapter to Revelations.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas opens the bible and there it is, in Latin, the fourteenth chapter.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe this is the teacher's edition.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I keep this awhile?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you sit on all this a few days, Willie? Not circulate the file? I need some time before all the questions start.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooh, are we breaking the rules again?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what else is new?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out an empty cup Katherine fills. Sipping painfully, he lays down beside her and pulls the brim of his baseball cap over his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You could save my life with some coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tough night?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't want to hear about it.  Or maybe you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bus is full of young school kids.</context>
      <utterance>Just checking.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't they be getting to school?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine's horse snorts.</context>
      <utterance>Impromptu field trip. I'm broadening their minds. And sparing them the sight of their beloved chauffeur barfing his guts out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate horses. How was the canyon? Honey-suckle out yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't see any.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate that canyon. I hate this this whole plateau. Too many goddamn ghosts. Leave it to them I say. San Diego, that's where I'm going. Or Oxnard. I like the sound of that. Ox- nard.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm happy here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh lord protect us, another romantic pale face in love with the desert.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just got to give it a chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try growing up here.  Ox-nard.  Uno mas, see-boo-play.  Speaking of romantic pale faces, the rumor mill is in high gear again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That funny looking guy from Window Rock. The BIA lawyer.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Say it isn't so!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't so.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finishes the coffee and climbs painfully to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the joe.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No prob.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shuffles back to the bus.</context>
      <utterance>You're a credit to the community.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bus coughs alive and crawls forward. Katherine waves to the faces behind glass, then settles back for a last moment of peace as silence lays again over the land.</context>
      <utterance>All right children, looks sharp! This is a school day! And no talking loud!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little girls smile. They like Camposaurus. Katherine holds up another bone fragment.</context>
      <utterance>This is "Camposaurus". Camposaurus was a herbavore, which meant he only ate plants. Camposaur stayed mostly to himself and never bothered anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little boys grin. They like Alosaurus.</context>
      <utterance>This is a leg fragment that belongs to the killer of the plateau, Alosaurus. Alosaurus was a vicious carnivore, which meant he'd eat anything that moved, especially nice, juicy Camposaurs.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Both these guys lived together right here on the White Rock plateau eighty million years ago, when this area used to be on the banks of a huge, shallow sea. Remember how we talked about how sedimentation fossilizes bones? That's also what made the hills out behind our town and put the copper in the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIGH SCHOOL KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine lifts off the desk an ancient 1950s gieger counter and switches it on. It ticks softly when she points it at the dino bone.</context>
      <utterance>Lot of good that did us.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's radioactive! Like Godzilla!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a tiny bit, Alex. Do you know why? Uranium, that's the rock they use in nuclear power plants --</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And bombs!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The class CHEERS.</context>
      <utterance>And bombs Alex, yes, is all through these hills naturally. Millions of years ago the dinosaurs here ate plants and drank water which had uranium in it that became concentrated in their bones, which is exactly how, with Mr. Geiger counter here, we're going to find some.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl folds her arms defiantly. The boy is pissed, embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>-- Hey. Come on. What's the deal, Brian?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...She, she called me a "Dick Head".</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sandra?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brian concentrates.</context>
      <utterance>All right, Brian. You get one free insult. Make it good.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You... You're a... Cow Demon!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... Okay. Everybody satisfied?  Cow Demon?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The high school kids come up and help dig.</context>
      <utterance>I got one! I got one!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Almost immediately, an eye socket appears in the dust. As the students carefully brush away the dust, Katherine looks back across the crumbly path. A coyote has crept up onto a near ledge. It just stands there. Watching her.</context>
      <utterance>Easy... Easy... Don't break it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm all done with the cleaning, Miss Henley.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Jason. I appreciate it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Find out what it is, yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy, still standing beside her, begins to look nervous. Slowly, he lets his weight rest against Katherine's shoulder. She smiles good naturedly up at him.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's either a 44 million year old Strychtosaurus or that cow Mr. Sorenson lost last winter.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy immediately stiffens and begins backing up, almost relieved.</context>
      <utterance>Go eat your lunch, Jason.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine watches him leave, smiles again, and goes back to the book.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, Miss Henley. Thanks. See ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't look so good, Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does Miss Henley know you're here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary thinks.</context>
      <utterance>No one does, Mary. Can we keep it just our secret. For a little while?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You can hear her friends coming closer.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary goes to leave, stops, turns back.</context>
      <utterance>It was nice meeting you, Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you hungry? I could bring something.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles and runs down the hall. Simon grits his teeth, turns to the wall, and prepares himself for a long, long day.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Bye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The eyes lift to Gabriel, revealing a pale, bloodless face eaten with dried sores.</context>
      <utterance>Gee Jerry, you look like shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone, Gabriel.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel drops into the chair across from Jerry and pushes aside with distaste the maggot-ridden plates of food piled on the table. He reaches his hand out to Jerry.</context>
      <utterance>Soon, pal. Soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel puts his hand under Jerry's chin and turns the face side to side, examining the cracked, decaying skin and filmy eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Come here...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm. Still a little life left in you. Barely.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel releases Jerry's chin and slouches down in the chair.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something I want you to do for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just want to... Why won't you let me...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dark, intestinal looking amber fluid begins to pool out of Jerry's pant leg.</context>
      <utterance>I will, I will. Promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tear wells in Jerry's decomposing face.</context>
      <utterance>You need some new clothes, son.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw come on, don't start. You know how I hate that...</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so tired. I'm so goddamn tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch the profanity. -- Just one more favor. Honest.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to get something for me. A few personal effects the cops ripped off from the lovely Allenwood Arms on Seventh Street. It'll be sitting in their property room down on San Julian.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm supposed to just go in there? Like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give you a bath, put on some decent clothes,  Maybe a very large brim hat, you'll be fine. Just go in between five and five-ten, it's a shift change and nobody'll notice you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon.  This should be more or less up to date.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a name this stuff is under?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John Doe.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel gets up, pats Jerry on the head, and walks to the door.</context>
      <utterance>Why doesn't that surprise me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see you tonight.  Here's some bus fare.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PLAYER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas dives into position to make the save, recovers, and yells to the player as he dashes to the next corner.</context>
      <utterance>Cover me! Cover me!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The player SLAMS it brutally at Thomas, who misses miserably.</context>
      <utterance>Pop it up!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another player picks up the dead ball and puts his arm around Thomas.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Player 2 tosses the ball to Thomas, who serves, and the scuffling is back on. Shouts to one another. Promises of support.</context>
      <utterance>You're missing the point of the game, Thomas. You must absolutely trust no one. Form alliances, but break them. Lure another to trust you, then betray him! You play with too much honor. Sink to the gutter. Use people. Lie and double-cross them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas and Player 2 team up on a third player, pressing him hard. Suddenly Thomas breaks back, intercepts the ball, and drives against Player 2. The about-face is too abrupt for him and Player 2 is eliminated in a double-cross. He smiles proudly at Thomas.</context>
      <utterance>Come on Thomas, let's take out Sam together!</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Magnificent decadence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PLAYER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The important thing, Tom, is seeing the game for what it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLAYER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughs.</context>
      <utterance>A sickening, hopeless, giant sucking hole of depravity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>PRIEST #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas is left alone with Player (priest) 2, Bill.</context>
      <utterance>See ya guys next Tuesday, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how's work?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Y'now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life on the dark side.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you about something?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has to stay between us. I need your word on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As a racquetball player or a priest?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take the priest for the moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's on your mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the bible out of a cloth sack and hands it to Bill.</context>
      <utterance>It's a case. We found this guy. He was... different. But he had on him an old bible.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a Vichini.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worth a little?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More than a little. They're the best. Sixth century. Hand illuminated. Vichini only did twenty, each pocket size for a king to carry into battle beside his heart. Some consider them the finest bibles ever made. I thought they'd all be in museums. What are you doing with it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This one's a bit special.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's has a bonus chapter to St, John's Revelations.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? What does it say?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"And as in the first war, the angels so fought over the nature of their God, and there was much vanity and destruction in heaven. For some angels called their Lord the son of God, and others called Him the begotten father of Jesus Christ." What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never heard that quote before. Theologically, The "first war" obviously refers to the war in heaven where Michael the archangel threw out Satan and his gang. Old time bible stuff. But this implies there was a second war. That's news to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the rest of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's a fairly common theological debate. Or was. The idea that if Christ is God's son, does that make him less than God or are they the same being in different forms. That very argument almost tore the early Christian church apart in the 4th Century. That was the good old days when people actually worried about theology. Anyway, it was settled when the bishops of the world got to together at the Council of Nicene in 325 and hashed out the various interpretations of scripture into a uniform dogma of belief. The result was the Nicene Creed, which basically said that Christ was in fact the same as God and was owed the same power and respect as the Father. That they were the same.  But it's not exactly the sort of thing angels would fight over.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, they could just ask God, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think it's possible that John might have written that extra chapter?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who knows? Vichini was the greatest biblical scholar of the age, some claimed he made his own translations from the original writings. Maybe he did find some unknown writings by John. It's possible I suppose. John always was a little negative about angels. All this actually has something to do with an LAPD murder?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know yet. Maybe. Probably not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate to break it you, but that particular family spat has been settled for 1,600 years. Nobody loses sleep over it anymore. Honest.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did John have against angels?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he didn't trust them much. All that running around smiting and killing in the name of the Lord. God's wild bunch. He thought it made them fickle and vain. One click above ghosts. Satan didn't help the image much either.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Satan?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he did start as an angel.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So when are you going to get a real job?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean with the Church?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You almost did it once. I never saw a seminary student more called to the collar than you. Why didn't you ever become ordained?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a long story.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll have to tell it to me sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Need a pass, friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll just be a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel walks back to the guard, smiles, and KNOCKS him clean out of his chair with the back of his arm. The guard SMACKS against the wall and crumples out of view.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brian, have you seen Mary?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think she's out back somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Allison?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALLISON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We haven't seen her since lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girls, Mary's friends, shrug innocently. Katherine sighs.</context>
      <utterance>We're you guys up in the...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine closes the door behind her. The class immediately erupts into goofing off. The door opens again.</context>
      <utterance>Okay everybody, get started on today's reading. Quietly. I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean quiet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="33">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's spooky up here. A part of the building Katherine clearly dislikes.</context>
      <utterance>Mary...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine calls out Mary's name a few more times, turns a few more corners, and suddenly comes on her.</context>
      <utterance>Mary...  Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary's sitting beside Simon, the bleeding, ashen-faced man with sunglasses. She's giving Simon a piece of sandwich and a coke. Katherine is instantly wary.</context>
      <utterance>Mary?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary, come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But Simon and I were --</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary reluctantly walks over to Katherine.</context>
      <utterance>Come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go back to class.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But --</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary frowns, waves once to Simon, and leaves. There's a heaviness to the air around Simon. A kind of buzzing. Katherine blinks her eyes a few times. Focuses.</context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She wasn't doing any harm.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not her I'm worried about.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Small job. Mostly done now. Just passing through.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is school property, you can't sleep here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't part of the plan. Honest.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That buzz. Katherine rubs the side of her temple.</context>
      <utterance>No. Not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll have to call the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish you wouldn't, but I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine turns and leaves, her footsteps fading. Mary appears again.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I rather doubt that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello. I thought you'd left.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hid. I'm very clever.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you are.  You were nice to give me the food.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't much time, Mary. And since you've been so nice to me, there's something I'd very much like to give to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just for a little while. Something very special. Can you keep it a secret? The biggest secret ever?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a couple of shy steps toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Come here, Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she does --</context>
      <utterance>Closer...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't feel good...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary coughs up the last of her lunch.</context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, pumpkin? Did you eat something?  Did he give you something?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine wipes off Mary's mouth with a hanky.</context>
      <utterance>Can I go home now?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, hon. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...He's was just laying up there. I thought, with the kids and everything...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most of my boys are up the highway on a tanker spill at the moment. They may be a while. These people are rarely any problem. I'll have a deputy come by tonight or tomorrow and shoo him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looked hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They all do, ma'am. Inside or out, they're all damaged goods.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your friendly coroner.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why is my friendly coroner, after a long day at work, calling me at home?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have something you'll want to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I doubt it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you'll definitely want to see this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They also took the autopsy file.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"They"?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He, she, it. They took it. They also lifted all the physical evidence from the San Julian impound.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where was everyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cop at the desk is in the hospital as we speak with a broken collarbone. Everyone else was down the hall watching the basketball playoffs.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who won?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Temple.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas jams his hands in his pockets and leans against an autopsy table. Watches the smoke curl slowly up from the impossibly melted goo in front of him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Foul on the buzzer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like the snow angels we used to make as kids. Lie down in a clean bank. Move your arms up and down...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what this means. Our friend's cleaned out all the evidence on this guy. Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did the cop get a look at who nailed him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tall. Smiled a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas pulls out out his notebook.</context>
      <utterance>He wore sunglasses.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna figure this one out, Tom?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to try.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORONER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you do, give me a call. Tell me I'm not crazy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry is looking worse by the day. A rotting, oozing fissure has opened on his forehead. His right eye doesn't move anymore. He sits on a kitchen chair glumly.</context>
      <utterance>You like the desert, Jerry?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You promised. You promised that --</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Soon. Honest. Don't be a pest about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never trust a fucking angel.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent advice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LT. PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you ever have one of those afternoons where you feel no one's giving you a straight answer about anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, maybe five or six times a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says here somebody got into the property warehouse and cleaned everything out of your evidence box. No, he did leave one thing. A footprint. 11-D.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mud on his shoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas slowly closes his notebook.</context>
      <utterance>Spinal fluid.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to get a straight answer out of you either, am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lt. rubs his eyes tiredly.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need to go to Arizona.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For your health?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I can give you a straight answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, why not? Take the kids. See the Grand Canyon. Send me a fucking postcard.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. PAUL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got a headache, Tom, and I hate my life. If you have to go, go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you need me? I can hardly walk now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some things are human work, son. Live or dead, human work. Besides, I like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel suddenly stands on the brakes, SCREECHING the rambler to a dusty stop. He kills the engine and everything is instantly whispering night and coyote howls. Gabriel climbs out and walks to the edge of a cliff. Far below, nestled among the finger-like spires of volcanic cones, lies The Town. Twinkling lights in a cold, dark embrace. Gabriel pushes his sunglasses up his nose and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Lucky moi.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two coyotes begin fighting and snarling with each other in the dust nearby.</context>
      <utterance>I can always smell a graveyard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you're enjoying this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always enjoy watching you work, Jerry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did I ever get you in my life?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, you didn't really want to kill yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I did it, didn't I? I did kill myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, yes. Technically.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're just keeping me alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Letting you die slower.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so in your debt.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry's shovel CLANKS onto something hard. He scrapes away the dirt, revealing a coffin lid. With a socket wrench Jerry removes the fastening bolts, then with the edge of his shovel, pries open the lid. It's the ancient, wasted general we saw at the beginning. His medals flash in the moonlight.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Jerry. I'm touched. Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much to look at.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel leaps off his perch down into the grave.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, but it's not what's on the outside that matters --</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel reaches down, places one hand on the General's forehead, one on his chin, and BREAKS the mouth open. He gazes down into it. Then suddenly stiffens and straightens up.</context>
      <utterance>-- It's what's on the inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel frantically look in the ears. Up the nose.</context>
      <utterance>It's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not here!</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oooh, bad news for the war effort.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel BANGS the coffin lid in frustration. Tries to think.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, if you were a soul, where would you hide?</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell away from you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>FEMALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey little brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey. How's the world?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The world's the usual. Except for a guppy. the world's minus one guppy this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Jamie and Mac?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They keep asking for Uncle Tommy. The only man that can make stuffed bears talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My one true calling. What's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's five-thirty in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just thought I should call.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You always were telepathic.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas looks up at his overnight bag, sitting half-packed on the dresser.</context>
      <utterance>Don't go.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my job, Jan. I go places sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just had this terrible feeling about it. What's happening, Tom?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss you. Even when you're here. I miss you. I miss my brother. It's been four years, Tom, since...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're the only blood family we have left, you and me. I worry about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about the dawn-attack call. I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cradles the phone, stares at it, then picks up his overnight bag.</context>
      <utterance>I love you too, Jan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry, limping on a foot that's caving in on itself, wiping the spinal fluid out of his dead eye, shuffles along behind. Gabriel pops off the elevated sidewalk, grabs a parking meter and swings himself playfully around.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, what a dump, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why can't this shit ever go down in Miami? Or Bora Bora? I feel like I've spent my whole damn stay in gin swills like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel suddenly freezes. He sticks his nose up, sniffs like a coyote, then abruptly drops to the ground in a push-up and smells the dirt. Tastes it with his tongue. Smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Life's a bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well well...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon rolls on his back and sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon looks up at puss-faced Jerry, leaning quietly in a dark corner.</context>
      <utterance>Gabriel.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel sits down against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Don't mind me. Just along for the ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, what shall we talk about? Theology?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a little talked out on theology.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel turns his boot to the moon, watches the pale light glint back off the lizard scales.</context>
      <utterance>Fair enough...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know why I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't happen to have it on you by chance?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon suddenly JUMPS to his feet. Tries to escape. Jerry trips him, SPRAWLING Simon back to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>That would have been too easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel walks over to him. Puts his face close.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Simon. Get serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simon doesn't answer. Gabriel shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Now. Where's the soul?  You know. So high. Used to reside in the recently departed General Hawthorne.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have it your way, big guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do have one question.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel pauses, almost thoughtfully. Then he smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Do you even remember what this war's about?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's hardly the point, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I never did get the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you do it, Gabriel? How do you go on and on in this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like it here, Simon. I always have.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel grasps Simon's hand.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so tired...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then join us, Simon. Reject the Nicene Council. We were here first.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do it, Gabriel. I don't even know why anymore, but I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know the routine.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel's hand is suddenly on Simon's face, fingers spread, claw-like. They press into the flesh. Hard. And harder. Until Simon starts to bleed. Then to burn.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the fires go out. Gabriel drops the crackling, acrid body onto the floor. Impossibly, through the sizzling mucus and molten hair, it breathes. It gasps in pain. It won't die.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can do this for five months, Simon...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is getting boring, Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The seared skin around Simon's mouth comes off in Gabriel's hand. But Simon is still, even now, silent.</context>
      <utterance>Where is it? Where did you put it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flings Simon with a horrible crunch against the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Where is it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks over and places a hand with something like friendship on Simon's charred shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just about out of tricks here. You're a tough one, friend. Old school.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with the other hand Gabriel JAMS his fist into Simon's chest, PULLING OUT a lumpy, burned heart. Simon's mouth springs open and hisses emptily. Gabriel slips the heart into his pocket and lets go of Simon's shoulder. The body instantly disintegrates and crashes to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>God loves you, Simon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine looks past him to where a second deputy crouches down beside... beside something. It's human shaped, but like a shadow. A shadow twisted in agony and slicked with a tarry, smoldering ooze. The smell is overpowering. The crouched deputy has a handkerchief over his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>You may want to skip this, ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROUCHED DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God damn...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were any of your students up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did the doctor come by?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man mumbles a soft chant as he moves the pouch back and forth across Mary's body.</context>
      <utterance>He found nothing. But something is in her. I know. Something the Belagaana doctor can't see. The night people have been around two days now. It is a warning.  So we have called the hand trembler. To find if she must have an Enemy Ghost Way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the coffee to Thomas, sitting in a chair beside his solid oak desk.</context>
      <utterance>And to what do I owe the thrill of a visit from a So Cal homicide cop?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run of of the mill psycho killer body dismemberment on our end. The usual.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lovely place, Los Angeles.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a lead I wanted to run down Chimney Rock way. Thought I'd do the courtesy of telling you first.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sheriff smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome to put a babysitter on me if you like.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son, this is the third biggest county in the country, not even counting the 25,000 square mile Indian reservation right next door, and I've got fewer men than just one of your little palm tree precincts to cover all of it. 'Fraid the only help you're gonna get from me, short of another shoot out at the OK Corral, is that cup of coffee in your hand. A middle-aged secretary enters with a stack of paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands them to the Sheriff, who passes them on to Thomas. He flips through the stack, comes up with nothing. The secretary hands another, single sheet to the Sheriff.</context>
      <utterance>Here's the last week's watch reports.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas perks at The Town's name.</context>
      <utterance>Bobby just called this in from Chimney Rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sent a car up there this morning. Teacher complained some vagrant was sleeping in her schoolhouse. The Sheriff's brow crinkles in consternation as he reads further.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it, get Bobby on the phone, Clarice. What the hell is this suppose to be?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sheriff hands it to him. Glancing at it we pick up words like BURNED, BLACK SLICK, BODY OUTLINE. Thomas copies the name of the school down, gulps his coffee, and shakes the Sheriff's hand.</context>
      <utterance>May I?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Small piece of advice, Lt. Dagget, that I give free of charge to all visiting big city policemen: It's wild country up there. Always has been, always will be. You come across anything that snarls, you call me first, hear?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never turn down advice, Sheriff. Especially when it's free.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long ago was he buried?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAVE KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which time?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAVE KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody dug him up last night. I just finished putting him back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they take anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAVE KEEPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothin' on the outside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you with something?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom Dagget. I'm with the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About the guy upstairs?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to ask you a few questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've kinda got my hands full right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine unlocks a hall cabinet and pulls out a stack of volleyballs. She tosses two to Thomas.</context>
      <utterance>I'll just tag along.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arms full, she pushes the building door open with her shoulder and backs out into the sunshine. She tosses the balls out to the kids.</context>
      <utterance>Here, make yourself useful.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits down beside Thomas on the building's stone steps.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, everbody stays on the courts today.  -- I mean it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What grade is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Town doesn't look that small.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nearly all ghosts now. When the copper mine closed it took most of the town with it. We just teach out of this one corner of the schoolhouse now. Rest of it's been abandoned for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the only teacher.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup. Just me.  -- Randy...</utterance>
   <speaker>RANDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he --</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do it again and I'll put your head in the door and slam it.  Love and understanding are important tools in education.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children skitter back and forth playing.</context>
      <utterance>Clearly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The man upstairs, did you talk to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to know what the hell he was doing there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That it wasn't part of the plan. He looked hurt. Bloody. Like someone had cut him. That happens here.  Was that... stuff... on the floor really him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did any of the children talk to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's home sick from school today.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I speak with her parents?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're dead. She lives with her grandmother. I'll have to ask her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas starts away. Pauses.</context>
      <utterance>All right.  This is my number at the hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you know Arnold Hawthorne?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The General? Saw him here and there. It's a small town.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Military man?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About a million years ago. His interests lately were more like gardening and herbal tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you go to the funeral?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone did. He lived here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No dark hidden secrets?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are no secrets in small towns, Mr. Dagget, dark or otherwise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GABRIEL'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas turns in surprise. Gabriel is kneeling in the row behind, inches from his ear.</context>
      <utterance>It's unusual to see someone of your age in church on a weekday.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's something cold and creepy about Gabriel. Out of place in here. There's another sound. Teeth chattering far in the back. Thomas turns and sees Jerry, deep in the shadows of the choir box. Jerry waves.</context>
      <utterance>Don't get me wrong. I think it's an excellent sign of character.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Those sunglasses. Impenetrably dark. Like at the skid row flophouse.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind him. He shouldn't even be in here. Least not standing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not from here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Either are you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for something.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you found it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will. Have you found what you're looking for?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't doubt it.  You'll let me know? When you find it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you staying?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he walks out, leaving Thomas alone in a place gone suddenly cold.</context>
      <utterance>I'm around.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got your note.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a seat. You need a card. Here, play one of mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's okay. Really --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must learn to shed your high- strung ways, pale face. You must learn the spirit joy in patience, peace, and making fifty or sixty bucks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John, this is Mr. Dagget. Says he's with the police, though judging by his coat and basic command of the english language, I don't think it's from anywhere around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom. From Los Angeles.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That near Oxnard?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort of.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long way from home, Tom-from-Los- Angeles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Hey, wait. I won. I won!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- What? No way --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Recount! Recount!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leads him out onto the floor.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, don't be a drip.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not very good at this...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles. Gets a smile out of him.</context>
      <utterance>No, you're not, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me lead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how's our star pupil feeling today?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary? The school doctor came by. Declared it "Non-specific gastrointestinal disorder".</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Latin for "I don't have the slightest fucking idea".</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will she be able to talk with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's up to her.  Mary's grandmother called a hand trembler.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh oh. Hocus pocus time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that serious?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends what the hand trembler says. People call them in when they think a witch or a Yei is trying to sprinkle corpse sickness in their hogan, or if the Night People have been hanging around too much. Night people screw around a lot, but they're good at warning of evil ghosts.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are the Night People?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They come as coyotes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John drinks again from his bottle, rests his head on the open window and looks out.</context>
      <utterance>Beautiful stars out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too much fucking sky in the desert. It pushes on you.  Sometimes I wonder if anyone in heaven even knows this place is here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you keep the coffee in this joint?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She messes with the grounds and filter. Thomas paces the room, looks over the pictures and a few weavings.</context>
      <utterance>Above the stove.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens if the hand trembler says a ghost has been...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Messing with Mary? If you're smart you say thank you very much and forget about it. But if you're heavy traditional, and Mary's people are serious traditional, you have an Enemy Ghost Way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn expensive. It's a Sing to purify and drive off the corpse sickness. Two days of dancing and ceremony and feeding the whole damn village. Not even to mention hiring the yataallii, if you can even find one these days. And you can bet they don't come cheap. But every clan does it a bit different. Especially Mary's.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know them?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Bitter Sky Clan. Hard core reservation. No lights, no running water, no HBO. Their village is out on the edge of Old Woman Butte. Million miles from anything. Witch country. Settled right there in the Dead People Land where no one else would, right on top of the old Anasazi village. They're a dying clan. Just the old ones now. All alone out there in the middle of nothing.  They can keep it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do people really still believe in it all? Ghosts, Sings, corpse sickness?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John closes his eyes and drifts off. Thomas wanders into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Depends, I guess. Sometimes you go along because it's a village thing, or you don't want to disappoint grandma. But sometimes, when you're alone out there, far from town, and the wind kicks up and sneaks into your hogan... I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think John's out for the evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands him a mug of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Saturday night in Chimney Rock.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how does a person like you end up teaching here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was younger I used to believe that no matter how much you mucked around in your life, one day, if you listened hard enough, a voice would tell you what you were really cut out to do. And when it didn't show up on schedule I decided to go look for it. And I looked in a lot of places, believe me. I drove that road out there so far that the end became the beginning again. And it was when I got here that I realized there never was going to be a voice. So I stopped looking and took the first job they offered me. That make any sense to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I know all about voices. Problem is not all of them are very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you end up a cop?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was the evil of two lessers.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you always this cryptic?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. When you get to know me I can be down right evasive.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the lift. Tomorrow at noon? At the little girl's house?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas climbs out.</context>
      <utterance>First trailer on the highway past town.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must say, Mr. Dagget, that you don't seem very like a police officer to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what my bosses keep saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I meant it as a compliment.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So taken. Goodnight, Miss Henley.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Tom-from-Los-Angeles.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy puffs lightly. The trumpet emits a piercing, clear note that SHATTERS a window high up in the abandoned part of the building. The youngsters whoop and applaud.</context>
      <utterance>...There, and there. Now pucker your lips... aim it that way, and just blow a little bit, this is a special trumpet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Timmy opens his mouth we clearly see Gabriel looking down into it. Looking for something...</context>
      <utterance>Very good, Timmy. Very good. Here, have a Junior Mint on me. Open up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine approaches the scene warily. The children all beg for their turn. Gabriel selects Sandra, one of Mary's second grade friends, and puts her on his knee.</context>
      <utterance>Who's next?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can barely get her fingers around the trumpet.</context>
      <utterance>Sandra.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And did you see the man upstairs, Sandra?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you talk to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And who did, Sandra. Who talked to the man?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where is Mary, Sandra?</utterance>
   <speaker>SANDRA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She isn't here. She's sick.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gently pushes down her chin with his thumb, opens her mouth, and gazes in. Katherine enters the circle.</context>
      <utterance>You've got very pretty teeth, Sandra. Here, let me see...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel looks up, unperturbed, and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell do you think you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just talking to the kids, Ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids reluctantly shuffle off.</context>
      <utterance>Get off his knee, Sandra. Everyone else, go inside. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Bye, Gabriel.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has the same sunglasses as Simon. The same cold, creepy air about him.</context>
      <utterance>See ya, kids. Be sure to study your math.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry suddenly snorts loudly, trying to retrieve a sticky red glop that starts running out of his nose.</context>
      <utterance>It's a long story.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ignore him.</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone else does.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what the hell is going on, but you both better get out of here. Right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He climbs to his feet and stands close to her.</context>
      <utterance>You're right...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands there a beat. That terrible coldness that swirls about him. The shriek of ghosts under his breath. Then he climbs into the rambler with Jerry and pulls away. Katherine watches the car drive off, then yells over to the school janitor.</context>
      <utterance>...You have no idea what's going on.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Al! Keep an eye on the children for me. I'll be right back. And call the sheriff.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANITOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheriff? What the hell do I tell him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine gets into her pickup and starts the engine.</context>
      <utterance>Just call.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't suppose to be here till noon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a little early yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to check on her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That makes two of us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you feeling, pumpkin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Mr. Dagget, Mary. He'd like to ask you some questions. You don't have to answer if you don't want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a dreamy, far-away look in Mary's eyes. It worries Katherine.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary, when you talked to man up in the building --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Simon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Simon. What did Simon say?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's funny. "Simon says".</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Like the game.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm good at it. I'm very clever.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll have to play together sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Simon even said so. He also asked if I could keep a secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something he gave me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, pumpkin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it wouldn't be a secret.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a good friend not to tell, Mary. But I'm a friend of Simon's too. So if you ever want to tell, you can to me. Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary lowers her head and shuts her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>It's a secret...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas and Katherine exchange looks. Mary's pretty eyes rise again as she calmly asks, in that cute little eight year old voice:</context>
      <utterance>...But sometimes it hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever killed a chinaman?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No Mary, I haven't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas looks to Katherine for an explanation, but she's as confused as him.</context>
      <utterance>They don't bleed. Not the way you and I do. Or maybe it was just the cold...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary's been explaining this in a girlish, show-'n-tell kind of way. Suddenly her face cracks as her voice chokes with a sob.</context>
      <utterance>I've killed them, you know. Lots. You could always tell when they were coming. There'd be the trumpets first. Every note flat. Then those songs... After that they'd charge. Right down through the snow. The guns would freeze and it would be just knives... It was so cold and there were so many of them. But I was smarter than they were. Even at Chosin, I was smarter...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She buries herself into Katherine's arms, sobbing.</context>
      <utterance>It scares me, Miss Henley. I hate it. Please, make it stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make it stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary suddenly pushes away and runs back toward the trailer, into the arms of her grandmother.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay... It's okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I didn't mean to --</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right, Miss Henley. We know you love Mary...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The grandmother turns and walks back to the trailer.</context>
      <utterance>She's going to have the Enemy Ghost Way. We leave this afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where will they do the ceremony?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the home village. The Hand Trembler must have found corpse sickness...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're taking her away? Shouldn't she see a doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's already seen a doctor.  That son of a bitch...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gabriel the children called him. The little shit was hanging around my kids this morning asking about Mary. He and his buddy make a real pair.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine turns from trailer and looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's time I checked out Mr. Gabriel.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know where he parks his car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chinamen? Chosin? I've never heard her talk like that before.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chosin Reservoir was a Korean war battle the Marines had against the Chinese, supposedly the bloodiest hand-to-hand fighting of the century. Someone been teaching that to your class?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, right next to Jack 'N Jill.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where would she have heard it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody I can think of.  Maybe one.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General Hawthorne.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't like children.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls over to the side near the copper mine entrance. No sign of the rambler.</context>
      <utterance>You couldn't and tell a story like that to one.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas drives up the dirt path to the mine's tunnel entrance. They climb out and stand near its mouth. In the dust is the rambler's tracks and several footprints leading into the mine. Thomas steps up to the edge of the tunnel. It's a black, yawning thing that swallows the sunlight whole for breakfast.</context>
      <utterance>It was there earlier.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I was smart I'd call the Sheriff or somebody in town who knows this place. Then again, there is one thing worse than getting killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking like an idiot if it's nothing. He pops his trunk and takes out a flashlight.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll come along.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas switches on the light and takes a tentative step inside.</context>
      <utterance>No, if someone has to fall a hundred feet down a black pit, he should at least be on official duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then again, it is kind of spooky in there. Here, you can hold the flashlight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk further down into the mine. The atmosphere becomes close and creepy. Thomas has been following tracks left in the dusty floor that abruptly disappear. He stops and sighs.</context>
      <utterance>It's cold...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- A BAT suddenly SHRIEKS out of the darkness, glancing off Thomas's shoulder and TANGLING in Katherine's hair. She screams and spins around, loosing her footing and half falling into a yawning ore chute she hadn't seen beside her. Thomas rushes over and pulls her out. She climbs shakily to her feet.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas takes a last pass at the mine shaft with his flashlight.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he turns to leave the flashlight burns out.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I've seen enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bangs it once against his thigh before he notices for the first time a dim, amber light coming from a space between the rocks.</context>
      <utterance>Wonderful.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But his gun's out at his side. Just in case. They follow the light to the gap in the rock, gingerly stepping into</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Maybe a bum or something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you feel it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Thomas can't hear Katherine anymore, her voice has disappeared beneath the whine. As it becomes too much he leans his weight against the rock wall and shuts his eyes. It's then they come. Flashes of images: Of screams and fire. Of impossible vistas of emptiness and death. And shrieking overhead, shrieking everywhere; grotesque, winged creatures with no eyes. Some with faces we know; Gabriel, Simon, and the gargoyle. All these images are being jammed into both their minds by the cave. Thomas forces his eyes open but the scenes playing all around him won't go away. Tears are running down Katherine's face as she stands there locked in the same images. Thomas stumbles about the room as if drunk, the visions, incomprehendibly black visions of war and destruction on an alien plateau, eat his brain. He sinks to his knees and begins to cry.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine's curled up on the floor like a child, weeping. The images are driving them mad. Thomas, fighting the insanity pounding at him, crawls pathetically across the floor to the oil lamp. His fingers grasp it spasmotically as he rises to his knees and leans back.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no... Oh God no...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He HEAVES the lamp against the cave wall, where it EXPLODES, the oil erupting into a swirling blaze that CONSUMES the corner. The images break a second in the heat and light and sucking wind. Just long enough for Thomas to grab Katherine's arm and pull her out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What... What was that? Hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He squeezes a handful of dirt in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>...No. The voices. They were screaming and fighting over... theology. They don't sweat much about that in hell. But they do in... heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The son of a bitch. He carries it around with him like a photo album. A big, greasy cloud wherever he goes. They all do.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tears start rolling down her face. She looks up and shouts at the endless sky above them.</context>
      <utterance>How can that be heaven? Jesus Christ. How? I don't even believe in heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You dumb fucking assholes! How could you have done that!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs hopelessly at the insanity of it all.</context>
      <utterance>That extra chapter by St. John was right. It's a war... Just like the first one. Just like when the angel Michael beat Lucifer and cast him out. Only now they've turned on each other... Turned on each other in a civil war over theology.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh sweet God, theology.  "God's wild bunch".  God's morons!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know know so much about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just know.  Yes folks, the good news is that there's life after death in heaven. The bad news is that it's as screwed up as here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were like us.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are us. Aborted children. And they need us. They need our corrupt, dark souls for their fight. They need...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine climbs abruptly to her feet and walks for the car.</context>
      <utterance>...Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what this is. I don't know what I believe. I don't know if my sanity is lying back in that cave flopping around waiting for me. But I know one thing. Those... Those things aren't taking her!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In those... visions... did you ever see... God?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me either.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas looks out the window and notices for the first time, parked behind the trailer, Gabriel's rambler. He immediately pulls out his pistol, runs for the closed door at the end of the hall and KICKS it in. The door FLIES open, revealing Gabriel sitting on the bed beside Mary.</context>
      <utterance>Mary?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His gun's leveled at Gabriel's head. The angel sits there impassively, then smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Get away from her.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know. Son of a bitch, the priest wanna-be actually figured it out. That's a rare club, son. At least down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back away from the kid, man. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She won't feel anything, honest. I'll have to tear her apart of course -- just the way it goes -- but it'll be all right in the end. A good catholic boy like you, Mr. Daggett, you should be on my side.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it --</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jerry suddenly LEAPS out from behind the door and TACKLES Thomas to the carpet. The gun skitters to one side as Jerry SINKS his rotting teeth into Thomas's shoulder. Thomas cries out and SLAMS his fist against Jerry's head, knocking off an ear. Gabriel turns back to Mary's frightened face and smiles as he runs a hand through her hair.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna have to watch that profanity.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine suddenly HAMMERS Gabriel across the side of the head with a chair, KNOCKING him to the floor. As he gets up she HITS him again. Thomas manages to bring his leg up and KICKS Jerry hard against the chest, forcing him off. Gabriel GRABS both of Katherine's legs and PULLS, CRASHING her flat on her back. Thomas scrambles for his gun, grabs it, and as Jerry comes at him again spins and FIRES twice. The slugs RIP into Jerry's chest and knock him to his knees. As the putrid, curdled juices pump lumpily out of him, Jerry looks up at Thomas and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>It'll only be a moment...</utterance>
   <speaker>JERRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas FIRES a slug into his forehead. Jerry's brain winks out as he collapses to the floor, dead. Thomas's gun is abruptly WRENCHED from his hand onto the bed as Gabriel NAILS him with a thrown lamp, vaults the bed between them, and grabs him by the collar, SLAMMING Thomas up against the wall. He looks down at Jerry's finally lifeless corpse, incensed at Thomas's handiwork.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks man, I appreciate it. You're a sport.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He THROWS Thomas down onto a table, SPLINTERING it. Katherine climbs shakily to her knees.</context>
      <utterance>You little pest, do you have any idea how hard it is to get one of those?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You son of a bitch, why? Why do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel walks over to the bed. The moment he gets close, Mary lifts Thomas's pistol up from the sheets and SHOOTS him twice, the impact KNOCKING him on his ass. Katherine rushes to Mary, scoops her up and runs for the door. She pauses beside Thomas, still lying in the wreckage of the table.</context>
      <utterance>Because I'm an angel, you miserable wretch! I kill first borns while their mothers watch! I turn whole cities into salt! I even, when I feel like it, rip the souls from little girls! And from now until eternity, the only thing you'll be able to count on in your pathetic little existence is never knowing why!  I'm wasting my time here.  C'mon petunia, let's get on with it...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine disappears through the bedroom doorway. Gabriel spins around and stands. Thomas leaps from a ragged crouch, HITTING Gabriel low with a body-block. It's like butting concrete. Gabriel picks up Thomas by the scruff of the neck and HEAVES him THROUGH the flimsy room paneling. Thomas CRASHES with a mass of splinters into the kitchen. He stumbles backward hopelessly as Gabriel peruses him through the trailer. He desperately throws pots, glasses, anything at Gabriel. Finally trapped, he scrambles up onto the dinner table, SCATTERING salt and sugar bowls, and DIVES through the levored window.</context>
      <utterance>Go. Go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He eases his gait, measuring the distance to her.</context>
      <utterance>...You...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's just those sunglasses coming. Those endless pits of black.</context>
      <utterance>...Can't...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine lifts Thomas's pistol and FIRES. Again. Again. The slugs BANG off the corregated metal, SMASH a window, KICK up some dust, And PUNCTURE the propane tank beneath the trailer.</context>
      <utterance>...Have Her!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was coming up the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary's knelt down beside Thomas.</context>
      <utterance>Is Gabriel dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sheriff car ROARS up, the two deputies exiting warily.</context>
      <utterance>They're not like you and me. You've got to cut their hearts out. The only thing God gave them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine's wiping the blood out of Thomas's eye. Gasping from the shearing pain, he tosses an ID at the foot of the deputy.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell happened here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From somewhere back in town there's the growl of a volunteer fire engine.</context>
      <utterance>That's a start. How about the rest of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pain's unbareable. Katherine dabs his cut with disinfectant.</context>
      <utterance>That man over there. He's wanted. Murder. I'm taking him in.  -- Shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're going to the hospital first.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- No, I have to -- Again, the pain. The second deputy has walked over to Gabriel.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cuff him. We'll take him to the hospital in our car.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The volunteer fire engine growls up through the weeds, drowning out Thomas's words. Two firemen kneel down beside him with medical kits. The deputy has walked over to his partner and the two are dragging back between them a cuffed, comatose Gabriel.</context>
      <utterance>-- No, you don't understand. You have to let me have him --</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas tries to get up, but the pain and a hand from the firemen keep him down. As the deputies pass, he manages to desperately grab the one's pant cuff.</context>
      <utterance>You'll never hold him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel's head lies low between the shoulders. The deputy looks with concern at the firemen.</context>
      <utterance>Take off his sunglasses... Jesus Christ, just take off his sunglasses...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The patrol car pulls away. As the firemen walk back to their engine, Thomas looks frantically at Katherine.</context>
      <utterance>Let's get a splint.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But your head...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They lock eyes. Then Katherine without a word helps Thomas up into the passenger side of the pickup. Mary gathers her grandmother into the pickup's bed and climbs up beside her as Katherine starts the engine. The firemen turn in confusion as the truck peels out of the lot and up onto the road.</context>
      <utterance>If you want Mary to stay alive past sundown we have to leave, and we have to do it now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine looks over her shoulder to Mary's grandmother sitting in the truck bed. She nods in understanding.</context>
      <utterance>Mary's village.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TELEPHONE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>County Coroner's office, Assistant Coroner Raphael speaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Willie?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And Thomas hangs up. He backs away from the phone and for the first time notices the church it's attached to.</context>
      <utterance>You weren't crazy, man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pew creaks and groans as he shifts his weight.</context>
      <utterance>So what's the deal, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jesus' pressed-metal eyes gaze only upward.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, do you have any kind of plan here? Cause I'm just about of ideas, friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas holds his face in his hands a silent moment. When it raises we see the raw hurt in the eyes as he shouts,</context>
      <utterance>Do you even listen? Do you still come to places like this? Old Man, you have been calling me most of my goddamn life, but every time I get close, you just keep moving that far away. What's it to be? You want me to kill your henchmen? Can't you even control your own killers anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The only reply is dust dancing in the light and the rumble of semis on the highway. Standing in the back, watching Thomas with tears welling in her eyes, is Katherine.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want from me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old man, Bartholomew Grey Horse, walks up to Mary and her grandmother sitting in the bed.</context>
      <utterance>I am Bartholomew Grey Horse, born to the Deer Spring Clan, born for the Slow Talking People. Today I am the yataalii for Mary Tsosie of the Bitter Sky Clan.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya-tah.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANDMOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several villagers approach and greet Mary and her grandmother, some nodding politely to Thomas and Katherine as they climb out of the cab. Nearly all of them are elderly. Thomas, one eye still half-shut by a bandage, walks over to the village's edge where a short stone wall, and little else, separates the adobe homes from the long, 2000 foot drop to the desert floor. He leans against it and gazes out on a view that must encompass half the world. In all directions, for tens upon tens of miles, there are only volcanic spires and crumbling buttes, all reduced from up here to short, ominous playthings. A village truly alone in the world.</context>
      <utterance>Ya-tah-hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's appeared beside him. Thomas crouches down to her level and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>This is a good place.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary's sight is on the view, eyeing it critically.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas's voice sighs sadly as he runs a hand softly through her hair.</context>
      <utterance>Separate water source. Stocked grain. Only one possible approach. A man could, with the proper defenses, hold off an entire battalion for weeks. Months.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary's eyes fill with tears as her grandmother appears and leads her back to the adobe hogans. Grey Horse, the yataalii, is there now.</context>
      <utterance>Which one of you is that talking, Mary? Or do you even know anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will start the Sing soon to remove the Yei spirit and stop the ghost sickness.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This might not be the work of a Navaho ghost.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all the same.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Like the wind, it is low and thin and hoarse. Like the wind it seems to come from everywhere. And, like the wind, it is utterly without pity or remorse. Katherine turns. Perched on the wall behind her in a low crouch is a figure clad entirely in layers of black. Its head and hands are hairless and waxy white. There are eyes in this winged head, but blood chilling ones of putrid yellow. There are endless scars and shapes and wrinkles, but mostly, only, there are the eyes. Katherine gulps down, with only partial success, the hysteria rising in her throat.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Katherine.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Lord, I can't do this. I can't do this anymore...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must talk, Katherine. It's takes all her strength to look upon him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're... You're...  ...God?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The eyes narrow. Rippling pools of unfathomable evil.</context>
      <utterance>God is love, Katherine.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a crouched silhouette beside the figure. Dimmer. Skinny. A wheezing sycophant. An afterthought. Katherine backs away from both of them.</context>
      <utterance>-- I don't love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. I can't do this tonight. Go away.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine stops. Faces him.</context>
      <utterance>I can kill you, Katherine. I can lay you out and fill your mouth with your mother's feces. Or I can talk with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am here, before you, in a form to put you at ease.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sycophant shivers and ruffles something feathery under its cloak.</context>
      <utterance>Good job.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I rarely do this in person. I am, perhaps, somewhat out of touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you one of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not an angel?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure cranes his neck around to the horizon beyond them. The movement makes a liquid, snapping sound.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I am an angel. A very special one. The first. The oldest. The naive eagle scout, he once loved me above all others, and I him. It was the only true love for either of us, but like all true love, it couldn't possibly last.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The winged party boys will come, Katherine. They'll come to feed on the guts of your little Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you care?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns back to her.</context>
      <utterance>I have my interests...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure shifts his perch on the wall.</context>
      <utterance>The naive eagle scout, he has his interests too. He even has a place for them, as I do for mine. Big, shiny place. You'd like it. Only it's been empty for a long time. Can't open till after the resurrection. The problem's with the hired help. Always had problems with the hired help. They're arrogant, boastful little pricks. Not like me. What I did I did for love. But they, the winged party boys, even before the park could open for its first customer, they started fighting over the popcorn stand.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure's face darkens.</context>
      <utterance>You see, Katherine, heaven can't start accepting guests till this fight is settled. And without people, there is no heaven. All those good and true souls left mouldering in the ground clutching their H-tickets and waiting and waiting and waiting... Some, lying down there with the worms century after century, they start to get doubts about the whole program. That's when, out of sheer boredom, some of them come to me. Because I'm always open for business. 24 hours a day, seven days a week. Even on Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of the angels cheat. They sneak a few souls in to help with the fight. The really dark ones. And now one of them has found a special soul so wonderfully sick that it might just win it for them. And if one side wins, even the wrong one, then there's no fight. And if there's no fight, there can be a heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if there's a heaven?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The figure straightens up, stretching its spine.</context>
      <utterance>I'd be very unhappy.  I am here to help you and the little bitch not because I love you, not because I care about you, but because I want this war to go on and on and on.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bring you the chance to save your Mary, Katherine. And along the way, stop the resurrection.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen when I speak. Now go to bed, Katherine. Tomorrow, I promise you, is a big day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="40">
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it over?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For now. They start again tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And at the end of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Enemy Way chant removes the invading yei ghost.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will it work on a general's soul?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll see.  How's the head?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits down on the floor beside him.</context>
      <utterance>Still attached. Barely.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, I'll change the bandage. She carefully unwraps the blood-soaked gauze.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does that hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She peels back the compress and dabs the wound.</context>
      <utterance>Then I must be doing it wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw the devil tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How nice. Which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The main one. Satan. Lucifer. The dark angel. You know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he have to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That he did it all for love. That and I have a choice. Mary's life or a billion souls waiting in the pipeline for heavenland to open.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not kidding, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Satan? You're sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas suddenly slams his fist against the wall in anger.</context>
      <utterance>You had to be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wasn't I!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can double date next time if it's that important to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ache in his head's flared up. He leans it back against the wall to ease the pain.</context>
      <utterance>You don't understand, I've spent my whole life...  I don't suppose it would occur to anyone in authority to fill me in on what's going on every once in awhile, huh? Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he say anything about the Nicene Council? About the rank of Jesus Christ in the holy Trinity?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine finishes taping the new bandage.</context>
      <utterance>It didn't seem important to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a priest?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A near miss.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a long story.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wind outside rustles through the hogans.</context>
      <utterance>This may be your last chance to tell it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses, the old emotions creeping back up on him.</context>
      <utterance>The other night, you were talking about waiting for a voice to call you to something. Well, let me tell you, the worst thing that can happen to you is to be called to something. Since I can remember a voice from somewhere deep in the Church called me. So loud and so often that by thirteen I knew I was going to be a priest. You know what that's like? My parents, friends, all of them thought I was crazy. But see, I had this voice. The voice that kept coaxing me along, telling me there was a reason. So I entered the seminary and was half way to my starched white collar when my mother, father, and my little brother were wiped out in a car crash.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He blinks back the tears welling in his eye.</context>
      <utterance>I had never asked anything of the voice. Not when the neighborhood kids made fun of me, not when my father looked down at me like some knock-kneed faggot. I never questioned a damn thing. But on the morning I spent looking down at three parallel graves, I asked it one question. Why. Why were these people taken from me? And the voice, that same voice that would wrench me out of my sleep some nights with its jabbering, it was suddenly stone silent. It was the only question I ever asked of it and it just left me hanging in the fucking wind...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So after that I traded in priest school for homicide school. Because if God wouldn't talk to me the devil sure as hell would, and his ways were a lot easier to understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've never seen God, have we? Not in any of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, He's certainly a shy son of a bitch, I'll give Him that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we're not supposed to. Maybe that's faith.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you still have faith in anything, Katherine?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have faith in Mary. And that I'm going to save that little girl from those creeping things out there. From all of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you were called to something after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The oil lamp wanes and fades. Katherine lays her head on Thomas's shoulder, and as darkness swallows them he holds her. They hold each other.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we both were.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>John's eyes open wide in shock. Gabriel's skin is blackened and blistered in parts. Whole shards of his shirt are missing. John tries to sit up but Gabriel forces his head back down with his palm. With the ease of a spider he slides down and beside John.</context>
      <utterance>Heavy sleeper, John.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't -- Don't hurt me, man. My wallet's in the dresser.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be such a materialist, John.  No end to your bad habits.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A moment of your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel leans said nose in very close and whispers,</context>
      <utterance>You ought to have that nose looked at, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are they, John? Katherine and Mary? Where would they go?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Mary? I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you do. Think hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, really. I don't know. The school maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you're not even trying, John. You're Katherine's best friend. She tells you everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel extends a blistered, open palm over John's face.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just the driver, y'know?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can help you remember, John...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone's going to die here soon. I'll just be a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>NURSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no visitors allowed in ICU.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nurse reaches for the telephone. Gabriel takes it away from her with one hand and with the other grasps her face open-palmed and whispers,</context>
      <utterance>The timing's important. I can smell these things, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nurse slides out of her chair and collapses to the floor. Gabriel pulls out the metal clipboards holding each patient's chart and flips through them, tossing one after another aside as unsuitable.</context>
      <utterance>Go to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Satisfied, he steps over to one of the beds, pulls back the curtain and sits down beside an unconscious, middle-aged woman. He watches patiently, listening the beeping scrawl of the EKG above her. It was weak to begin with but now it's faltering badly, becoming the unsynched etchings of a child. A beeping alarm has begun to ring and her breathing is slowing to nothing. At the last possible moment Gabriel places his fingers across her face, whispering to her, coaxing her.</context>
      <utterance>Recovering... Recovering... Stable...  Deteriorating critical.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The EKG's still flat but the woman is breathing. She begins to choke, to cough, then suddenly sits up and opens her eyes. She looks in disbelief around her, finally settling on Gabriel's grin.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa, not just yet. Come on back. That's it...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look of utter desolation and sadness sweeps over her as she begins to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, c'mon, don't start...  -- Rachael. Here...  It's only for a short time.  Promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Miss Henley.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grey Horse is kneeling near the bed preparing a bowl drink. Into it he crushes charcoal, dodge weed, juniper and ghost plant. This he stirs, heats over flame, and feeds to Mary. She grimaces and leans back in the bed as Grey Horse says a brief prayer.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, pumpkin. Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>OUTSIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Katherine runs into Thomas outside the hogan.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's the head?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She accepts a mug, blowing a cloud of steam off the top.</context>
      <utterance>Shitty. Coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we going to do if he comes?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean when, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When he comes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no phone here? Radio?  Stupid question.  If we were smart we'd leave. Get to a town. A sheriff station.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mary's ceremony isn't over yet. The Enemy Ghost Way. The alien spirit hasn't been driven out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you really believe in the ceremony?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you have believed in any of this three days ago?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So we stay and dump the General's soul.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have the gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With one shot left. The spares --  -- And a change of clothing, are all still at the hotel.  We're going to have to come up with something.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas looks up. She's referring to Lucifer, who's appeared perched on the edge of the low, eye-level hogan roof. The sycophant is also nearby, chattering its teeth and staring at Katherine with jealous, rabid eyes. Lucifer shivers, a claw turning up the collar of his cloak.</context>
      <utterance>We could always ask him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I always forget how cold it gets in the desert. The swimming, bottomless eyes fall on Thomas.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas can't bring himself to say anything. To form the words.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Daggett, I presume. How's the faith?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come come, must you be so wishy-washy about everything? With the absent- minded eagle scout, I can see that. But you're looking at the devil man, say something.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas gingerly hands him the cup. The angel Lucifer lifts it, and with something unimaginably awful darting out of his mouth, drinks. He offers the mug back to Thomas for a sip.</context>
      <utterance>Much better. Can I have some coffee?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finishes it. Cranes his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Keep it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have come to remind you that the winged party boys are just that: spoiled boys. You are armed, however pathetically, with the one thing they never really understood: theology. It's not much, but that's life.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this supposed to be our "win one for The Ripper" speech?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And you know instantly, in the bottom of your stomach, that those eyes mean it.</context>
      <utterance>Don't press your luck, Mr. Daggett.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas hesitates, holds the gaze, then turns and leaves. In an instant Lucifer sweeps down from the hogan roof to Katherine's side. Face and eyes and maggot breath uncomfortably close, he smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Go and get ready, Thomas.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucifer places a cloaked arm around her shoulder and leads her to the walled edge to look out across the endless plateau. His mouth presses against her ear and whispers,</context>
      <utterance>Have you ever considered Katherine, that the great absentee landlord, the soft-eyed eagle scout your childhood prayers are for, is just using you? That you're only the exterminator to get rid of his pests?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God's junkies are coming, Katherine. And when they do, all hell is going to break loose...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say, Ma'am, any idea where I can find Old Woman Butte?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's on the reservation.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waitress' eyes move from the guy with sunglasses and burn marks on his shirt to the woman sitting alone outside in the rambler.</context>
      <utterance>I don't suppose you could be just a tad more specific. Madge.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't your friend hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Madge has a lot of things she misses in her life, but one of them she decides isn't Gabriel.</context>
      <utterance>Not for a while, I'm afraid. Funniest thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel downs the coffee, stands, and tosses a bill on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>Take 522 to the Sonsela Wash cut- off. First dirt road go left. Twenty, twenty-five miles you'll see it. Big, black and all alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I doubt we'll meet again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suits me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas sticks his head into the kiva, speaks softly to one of the elderly villagers attending the ceremony.</context>
      <utterance>He's coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there any way to speed this up?</utterance>
   <speaker>VILLAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A fire has been built on the kiva's floor. Through the choking smoke can be seen Mary lying on a mat as Grey Horse chants to the yei spirits and adds fine colored earth to the growing sand painting beside her. His voice rises and falls in guttural syntax. He's coaxing. Coaxing the alien spirit out of the child.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls his head out and hands Katherine the pistol.</context>
      <utterance>Lock the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a pause and for a moment their eyes lock. She touches his arm, almost says something, then disappears into the kiva. Thomas closes the door behind her. He turns and looks out at the distant plume of dust. Growing closer.</context>
      <utterance>Stay inside. It's only one round, so make it count.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a sudden glint of metal in the headlights as Thomas at the last moment PULLS UP the heavy chain and HOOKS it over the far post. Gabriel does something pointless with the brakes and SLAMS forward into it. The whole rear of the car STANDS UP on impact, PITCHING Gabriel through the windshield into the dust. Thomas steps out from behind the post armed with an iron bar. The rambler hisses and belches a death rattle as he cautiously walks toward the spot of gloom where Gabriel lies.</context>
      <utterance>You'll like this, Rachael. Maybe not.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas's feet crunch softly closer.</context>
      <utterance>Nice move.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas doesn't answer. Gabriel's body looks ravaged as he carefully steps closer and closer.</context>
      <utterance>You ought to come work for us. Upstairs. We sneak the odd civilian in now and then, you know. You'd like it. Nobody tells you when to go to bed, can eat all the ice cream you want. And you get to kill. All day and all night. Just like an angel.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Save yourself, friend. Why go to the wall with the bitch and her rug rat? It'll all turn out the same anyway. Here or in heaven, we're still gonna tear the kid apart.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not an angel, heaven or hell. I'm a man you eyeless puke, which means I have one thing you never will. A soul. And though I may, somewhere inside, believe in a God, I will never, never, believe in you.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel's legs suddenly SWING AROUND and SMACK Thomas, sprawling him back into the dirt. The iron bar goes flying as Gabriel in a flash is on top of him. Thomas thrashes but Gabriel easily pins his shoulders and sits on his chest. Without hurry he uncurls the fingers of his right hand.</context>
      <utterance>A little speechy today, aren't we?  Okay pal, have it your way.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas's eyes are wild with fear.</context>
      <utterance>This is going to really, really hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel's spread fingers lower themselves toward his face.</context>
      <utterance>...You -- your war...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, son, out with it. Make this one count.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your war's a lie!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Running around acting like this is really about whether Christ is just the son of God or if he is God. Bullshit! That's not what this is about at all, is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Then prove it to me, Gabriel. I studied three fucking years of theology before I picked up a gun. C'mon, you're chief goddamn angel, I'm just a little man. Prove to me Christ is just a son and less than God. Prove it!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you can't! Because this war isn't about some obscure medieval hangup. You're just jealous.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're wrong!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try me, Gabriel. Go on. Prove to me the temporal nature of the Trinity. Show me through logic how the Son of the Word can be separated from the Father. Fight me with philosophy, Gabriel!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you and your army are wrong! And you know it. You knew it sixteen centuries ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have to listen to him! He's just a son!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it. You're jealous. Jealous He could love something more than you...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel's becoming unglued.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shudder passes through Gabriel. He straightens up and looks down at Thomas as emotion racks his body.</context>
      <utterance>If you wanted to know so badly, Gabriel, why didn't you just ask Him? Why didn't you just ask God?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two stare at one another. Then Gabriel, lost in himself, suddenly turns away from Thomas and walks into the darkness. For the village. Thomas climbs quickly to his feet, spins around -- -- And is HIT full-force by a rabid, SHRIEKING Rachael. Her legs lock around his body vise-like as her teeth and nails DIG into his skin. He cries out and stumbles to the ground. The two grapple furiously in the dust, Rachel's crazed face taking BITE after BITE out of his shoulder and neck. Thomas manages a fistfull of her hair and YANKS the fangs off his shoulder. With his other arm he CUFFS her hard, BREAKING the grip and ROLLING her aside. He staggers to his knees and begins to run. Shrieking, a mad porcelain banshee out of the dusk, Rachael catches up and TACKLES him. On the way down his head strikes a small stone wall and the pain is white thunder. Gagging and weeping in blank shock, he crawls on his hands and knees as Rachael OPENS UP his arm from shoulder to elbow with her nails. As the blood tumbles like ribbons, Rachael JUMPS onto his back, DIGGING her claws into his scalp. It's about all one human can take. Mad with pain and anger and desperation, Thomas manages to climb to a shaky crouch, Rachael still shrieking on his back. Throwing all his weight backward, he JAMS her into the short stone wall. The impact SNAPS her hold and PROPELS her over the wall -- And two thousand feet down the side of the butte. Thomas Daggett can only curl up into a ball, gulping shallow, shuddering breaths.</context>
      <utterance>Because He doesn't talk to us anymore!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="54">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From out of the smoke steps Katherine. She FIRES, one round, into Gabriel's side. The archangel is pitched against the kiva's wall, where he stays a moment before turning to Katherine.</context>
      <utterance>Relax folks, it's just a soul.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands her ground between him and the child.</context>
      <utterance>I'm getting real tired of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heaven, darling. Heaven. At least get the zip code right.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all the same, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. In heaven we believe in love.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Once again, the shade of doubt holds him up. But it's quickly pushed aside for a corrupted grin. He's given up all pretense.</context>
      <utterance>And what do you love, Gabriel?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He advances on her.</context>
      <utterance>-- Cracking your skull.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all it is for you anymore, Gabriel, isn't it? Just the killing and the burning. You don't work for God anymore. You don't fight for love.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he's on her. With his left arm he brutally forces her to her knees as his right hand, palm out and fingers splayed, clamp themselves over her face. Katherine's mouth opens in a silent scream as the pain, immediate and beyond endurance, flows through her body. From somewhere outside, there's a sound. Katherine gulps chokes of agony as her very clothes begin to smolder around her. We hear the sound once more, closer, before -- The entire kiva wall EXPLODES INWARD as Katherine's pickup CRASHES through it. The mangled grill and hood SLAM into Gabriel from the side and SMASH him to the ground like a broken puppet. Katherine falls backward to the floor, gets up, and runs to the truck's cab. Inside sits a near catatonic Thomas. Katherine takes only a second to share a look with him before reaching back and pulling out the pickup's tire iron. Gabriel, a shattered, broken thing, pulls himself up to his knees. The sunglasses are gone and two eyeless pits stare out at Mary, huddled in the corner. Bleeding from every pore, one arm bent back the wrong way, he crawls across the floor toward her, his voice the milky slur of a stroke victim.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine brings the tire iron down on his skull with all her might, DRIVING him to the floor. She turns to Grey Horse, her eyes wild.</context>
      <utterance>God loves you, Mary!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He, everyone, just stare. Stunned to stone.</context>
      <utterance>Finish it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grey Horse timidly picks up his prayer stick and with a voice faltering and cracked, in the insane glare of the wrecked pickup's headlights, resumes the Enemy Ghost Way chant. Katherine turns back to Gabriel.</context>
      <utterance>Finish it!</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She HITS him again with the tire iron. Then lifts it high once more above her head. She's going to crush him, to implode his skull. When a hand stops her. Sort of a hand. A claw. Lucifer's. He's standing behind her, holding the raised bar still.</context>
      <utterance>Go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine releases the bar and lets it clang to the floor. Lucifer turns to the villagers, gazing fearfully at him as they awkwardly try to finish the chant.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucifer's gaze falls on a deeply fucked-up Gabriel who groans at the sight of him.</context>
      <utterance>Please. Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucifer kneels down beside him. Katherine instinctively starts to reach for the tire iron but the sycophant hisses a liquid, chattering warning at her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh man, this just isn't my day.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The world's young, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And full of ambition.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't your war.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I remember the last one. Michael's war.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But lots of angels were with me. every one followed their leader out of heaven.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah yeah, I was there, remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Except one. Oh, he was with me all right. He hated the Eagle Scout. Envied the power He gave to His Son. But this angel never came out front during the war. And when it ended he thought maybe, maybe the Eagle Scout didn't notice. So he laid low and towed the company line till he could start his own war. It was all just jealousy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're dreaming.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But maybe He did notice. Maybe that's why I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Stay away from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've always been a part of me, Gabriel. And now it's time to come home.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lucifer slams Gabriel's head against the floor and pins it. As the angel thrashes furiously, Lucifer FORCES his arm into Gabriel's chest. Gabriel cries out as Lucifer PULLS his arm half out and FORCES it deeper. Again. And again. Soon Gabriel's screams become giggles, then a crazed, hysterical laughter. The room goes insane. An impossible nightmare of chanting Navahos, glaring headlights, and Gabriel's echoing laughter as Lucifer pumps his chest. Laughter that rises to a kind of orgasmic cry then instantly stops as Lucifer pulls out the angel's heart, And eats it. At that instant Grey Horse places his hand on Mary's forehead, speaks a last line, and the chant is completed. Sticky, smoky, awful silence. Gabriel is a non-thing. A battered, hollow shell. Bartholomew Grey Horse, his voice cracked and finished, turns to Katherine.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>GREY HORSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The enemy spirit is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From outside the kiva suddenly comes the sound of a wounded, savage GROWL. Katherine walks to the doorway. Just outside a lone coyote is twisting in the dirt with furious agony. Abruptly its thrashings cease. The animal stands and flashes for an instant at Katherine cold yellow eyes more than animal. Then it's gone into the blackness. Forever. She turns and goes back to Thomas in the cab. Bleeding to death is a real possibility for him. She pulls an old shirt out of the back and tries to makeshift a wrap for his sliced arm.</context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More will come... To look for the soul...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few of the village elders appear at the cab.</context>
      <utterance>And they won't find it. Not in Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you help him?</utterance>
   <speaker>VILLAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine walks over to where Mary, sweaty and shaken, sits huddled in a corner attended by Grey Horse.</context>
      <utterance>We have some bandages.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mary's voice shakes as tears roll out her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Are you all right, pumpkin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Katherine gathers her up into her arms and holds her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chattering, hissing sycophant grabs Gabriel's body by the hair and shoulders and drags it out the door. Lucifer has remained behind, crouched on his haunches, his liquid, yellow eyes on Katherine.</context>
      <utterance>It's going to be okay... We're all going to be okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't quite bring myself to say thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then this is done.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises to his feet and steps slowly toward her.</context>
      <utterance>Not necessarily. Maybe I like you. Maybe I want you to come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You owe me, Katherine. And you're going to ask me to take you home.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will. You will because any other way is going to be more awful than you can imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just a grinning, twisted stare.</context>
      <utterance>Are you threatening me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The smallest hint of a pause.</context>
      <utterance>Then you've picked the wrong person this time. I've just about had it up to here with ghosts. So you can put away the horror movie sneer and the K-Mart halloween eyes, because we know you now. We know you all. And if you want to force the issue then go ahead because you're just another angel to me. Take a look at your buddy Gabriel. Then ask yourself, do you really, really want to fuck with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps another time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm holding my breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUCIFER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he's gone. Through the door and into the night.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Katherine. For now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he coming back?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so, honey... I don't think so...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="45">
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he going to live?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With any luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I told you to give me a call if anything snarled.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There wasn't a phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He chews some more on his stalk. Looks off at the village.</context>
      <utterance>Hmmm.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This fella, Gabriel...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gabriel what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just Gabriel.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty violent guy, Gabriel. Even for out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Caught up with him at the village?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He caught up with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What were you doing way up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Enemy Ghost Way for Mary Tsosie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Indian stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sheriff looks over at Katherine's pickup still jammed into the side of the kiva.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Indian stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you kill this Gabriel?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't have any idea where the body is I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if he's alive he won't get far out there. Us or the coyotes, it'll be the same.  I rang your office in LA. They don't have a warrant out for a Gabriel. Or anybody else in Arizona.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hadn't gotten around to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort of an out of pocket thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sheriff takes his hat off. Runs his finger along the inside band.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That woman lying at the bottom of the arroyo, the one still in her hospital gown, know anything about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Gabriel was sure one busy dude.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, he was.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be going back to Los Angeles now?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sheriff pushes off from the patrol car and tosses aside the oak stalk.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The deputy finishes his bandaging.</context>
      <utterance>Don't hurry back.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do much but breathe the next few days. And get to a hospital. You're going to need some serious stitches.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He follows his boss. Katherine and Mary walk up.</context>
      <utterance>Say hi to Hollywood for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. I feel worse.  They lean on you much?</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really. I think they might have even understood. One of them's related to this clan. He'll give us a ride back if we want.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moment drifts into silence.</context>
      <utterance>Good. I think I've about run out of hospitality with the sheriff's department.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think it's really over?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes settle on his.</context>
      <utterance>Till we die.</utterance>
   <speaker>KATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I die, I want you with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAGGETT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She touches his cheek, Mary cradled between them.</context>
      <utterance>I want that too.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
