<movie id="484" title="Seventh Seal The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Death.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you come for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have been walking by your side for a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you prepared?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My body is frightened, but I am not.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT has risen to his feet. He shivers. DEATH opens his cloak to place it around the KNIGHT'S shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there is no shame in that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what they all say. I grant no reprieves.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A gleam of interest kindles in DEATH'S eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You play chess, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have seen it in paintings and heard it sung in ballads.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, in fact I'm quite a good chess player.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT rummages in the big black bag which he keeps beside him and takes out a small chessboard. He places it carefully on the ground and begins setting up the pieces.</context>
      <utterance>But you can't be better than I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you want to play chess with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have my reasons.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is your privilege.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT holds out his two fists to DEATH, who smiles at him suddenly. DEATH points to one of the KNIGHT'S hands; it contains a black pawn.</context>
      <utterance>The condition is that I may live as long as I hold out against you. If I win, you will release me. Is it agreed?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You drew black!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT and DEATH bend over the chessboard. After a moment of hesitation, Antonius Block opens with his king's pawn. DEATH moves, also using his king's pawn.</context>
      <utterance>Very appropriate. Don't you think so?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JONS finally gets the KNIGHT'S attention. He stops singing. The KNIGHT, his horse, JONS'S own horse and JONS himself know all the songs by heart. The long, dusty journey from the Holy Land hasn't made them any cleaner. They ride across a mossy heath which stretches towards the horizon. Beyond it, the sea lies shimmering in the white glitter of the sun.</context>
      <utterance>Up above is God Almighty So very far away, But your brother the Devil You will meet on every level.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In F‰rjestad everyone was talking about evil omens and other horrible things. Two horses had eaten each other in the night, and, in the churchyard, graves had been opened and the remains of corpses scattered all over the place. Yesterday afternoon there were as many as four suns in the heavens.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, did he show you the way?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was he a mute?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir, I wouldn't say that. As a matter of fact, he was quite eloquent.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was eloquent, all right. The trouble is that what he had to say was most depressing.  One moment you're bright and lively, The next you're crawling with worms. Fate is a terrible villain And you, my friend, its poor victim.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must you sing?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT hands his squire a piece of bread, which keeps him quiet for a while. The sun burns down on them cruelly, and beads of perspiration trickle down their faces. There is a cloud of dust around the horses' hooves. They ride past an inlet and along verdant groves. In the shade of some large trees stands a bulging wagon covered with a mottled canvas. A horse whinnies nearby and is answered by the KNIGHT'S horse. The two travelers do not stop to rest under the shade of the trees but continue riding until they disappear at the bend of the road.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He has picked up the juggling balls and slowly begins to toss them. Then he stands on his head and cackles like a hen. Suddenly he stops and sits down with a look of utter astonishment on his face. The wind causes the trees to sway slightly. The leaves stir and there is a soft murmur. The flowers and the grass bend gracefully, and somewhere a bird raises its voice in a long warble. JOF'S face breaks into a smile and his eyes fill with tears. With a dazed expression he sits flat on his behind while the grass rustles softly, and bees and butterflies hum around his head. The unseen bird continues to sing. Suddenly the breeze stops blowing, the bird stops singing, JOF'S smile fades, the flowers and grass wilt in the heat. The old horse is still walking around grazing and swishing its tail to ward off the flies. JOF comes to life. He rushes into the wagon and shakes MIA awake.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning. Have you had breakfast? I can't eat grass, worse luck. Can't you teach me how? We're a little hard up. People aren't very interested in juggling in this part of the country.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mia, wake up. Wake up! Mia, I've just seen something. I've got to tell you about it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it? What's happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, I've had a vision. No, it wasn't a vision. It was real, absolutely real.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MIA's voice is filled with gentle irony. JOF shakes his head and grabs her by the shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, so you've had a vision again!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I did see her!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whom did you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MIA can't help being impressed by her husband's fervor. She lowers her voice.</context>
      <utterance>The Virgin Mary.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you really see her?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>touched her. She had a golden crown on her head and wore a blue gown with flowers of gold. She was barefoot and had small brown hands with which she was holding the Child and teaching Him to walk. And then she saw me watching her and she smiled at me. My eyes filled with tears and when I wiped them away, she had disappeared. And everything became so still in the sky and on the earth. Can you understand ...</context>
      <utterance>She was so close to me that I could have</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What an imagination you have.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't believe me! But it was real, I tell you, not the kind of reality you see every day, but a different kind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps it was the kind of reality you told us about when you saw the Devil painting our wagon wheels red, using his tail as a brush.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why must you keep bringing that up?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then you discovered that you had red paint under your nails.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I did it just so that you would believe in my other visions. The real ones. The ones that I didn't make up.</context>
      <utterance>Well, perhaps that time I made it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we would only get some rain. Everything is burned to cinders. We won't have anything to eat this winter.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He says this smilingly, with a casual air. He stretches and laughs contentedly.</context>
      <utterance>We'll get by.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want Mikael to have a better life than ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mikael will grow up to be a great acrobat -- or a juggler who can do the one impossible trick.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To make one of the balls stand absolutely still in the air.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Impossible for us -- but not for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She yawns. The sun, has made her a bit drowsy and she lies down on the grass. JOF does likewise and puts one arm around his wife's shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>You're dreaming again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've composed a song. I made it up during the night when I couldn't sleep. Do you want to hear it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sing it. I'm very curious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits with his legs crossed, makes a dramatic gesture with his arms and sings in a loud voice.</context>
      <utterance>I have to sit up first.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He interrupts his singing in order to be complimented by his wife.</context>
      <utterance>On a lily branch a dove is perched Against the summer sky, She sings a wondrous song of Christ And there's great joy on high.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mia! Are you asleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a lovely song.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't finished yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard it, but I think I'll sleep a little longer. You can sing the rest to me afterwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOF is a bit offended and glances over at his son, MIKAEL, but he is also sleeping soundly in the high grass. JONAS SKAT comes out from the wagon. He yawns; he is very tired and in a bad humor. In his hands he holds a crudely made death mask.</context>
      <utterance>All you do is sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this supposed to be a mask for an actor? If the priests didn't pay us so well, I'd say no thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to play Death?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just think, scaring decent folk out of their wits with this kind of nonsense.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When are we supposed to do this play?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the saints' feast in Elsinore. We're going to perform right on the church steps, believe it or not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't it be better to play something bawdy? People like it better, and, besides, it's more fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MIA is awake now and lies contentedly on her back, sucking on a blade of grass and looking smilingly at her husband.</context>
      <utterance>Idiot. There's a rumor going around that there's a terrible pestilence in the land, and now the priests are prophesying sudden death and all sorts of spiritual agonies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what part am I to play?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're such a damn fool, so you're going to be the Soul of Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a bad part, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SKAT, grinning, holds the mask in front of his face and recites dramatically.</context>
      <utterance>Who makes the decisions around here? Who is the director of this company anyhow?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stumbles into the wagon muttering furiously. JOF sits, leaning forward. MIA lies beside him on the grass.</context>
      <utterance>Bear this in mind, you fool. Your life hangs by a thread. Your time is short.  Are the women going to like me in this getup? Will I make a hit? No! I feel as if I were dead already.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jof!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit still. Don't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't say anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm as silent as a grave.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shh! I love you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this supposed to represent?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Dance of Death.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that one is Death?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you paint such nonsense?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it would serve to remind people that they must die.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's not going to make them feel any happier.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why should one always make people happy? It might not be a bad idea to scare them a little once in a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then they'll close their eyes and refuse to look at your painting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you do scare them ...</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll think.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if they think ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then they'll run right into the arms of the priests.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not my business.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're only painting your Dance of Death.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm only painting things as they are. Everyone else can do as he likes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just think how some people will curse you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe. But then I'll paint something amusing for them to look at. I have to make a living -- at least until the plague takes me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The plague. That sounds horrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PAINTER points with his brush. JONS sees a small human form writhing in the grass, its eyes turned upwards in a frenzied look of horror and pain.</context>
      <utterance>You should see the boils on a diseased man's throat. You should see how his body shrivels up so that his legs look like knotted strings -- like the man I've painted over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That looks terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It certainly does. He tries to rip out the boil, he bites his hands, tears his veins open with his fingernails and his screams can be heard everywhere. Does that scare you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scare? Me? You don't know me. What are the horrors you've painted over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The remarkable thing is that the poor creatures think the pestilence is the Lord's punishment. Mobs of people who call themselves Slaves of Sin are swarming over the country, flagellating themselves and others, all for the glory of God.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do they really whip themselves?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it's a terrible sight. I crawl into a ditch and hide when they pass by.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any brandy? I've been drinking water all day and it's made me as thirsty as a camel in the desert.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JONS sits down with the PAINTER, who produces a jug of brandy. The KNIGHT is kneeling before a small altar. It is dark and quiet around him. The air is cool and musty. Pictures of saints look down on him with stony eyes. Christ's face is turned upwards, His mouth open as if in a cry of anguish. On the ceiling beam there is a representation of a hideous devil spying on a miserable human being. The KNIGHT hears a sound from the confession booth and approaches it. The face of DEATH appears behind the grille for an instant, but the KNIGHT doesn't see him.</context>
      <utterance>I think I frightened you after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to talk to you as openly as I can, but my heart is empty. DEATH doesn't answer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Through my indifference to my fellow men, I have isolated myself from their company. Now I live in a world of phantoms. I am imprisoned in my dreams and fantasies.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And yet you don't want to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you waiting for?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want knowledge.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want guarantees?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call it whatever you like. Is it so cruelly inconceivable to grasp God with the senses? Why should He hide himself in a mist of half-spoken promises and unseen miracles? DEATH doesn't answer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT stops and waits for a reply, but no one speaks or answers him. There is complete silence.</context>
      <utterance>How can we have faith in those who believe when we can't have faith in ourselves? What is going to happen to those of us who want to believe but aren't able to? And what is to become of those who neither want to nor are capable of believing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why can't I kill God within me? Why does He live on in this painful and humiliating way even though I curse Him and want to tear Him out of my heart? Why, in spite of everything, is He a baffling reality that I can't shake off? Do you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I hear you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want knowledge, not faith, not suppositions, but knowledge. I want God to stretch out His hand towards me, reveal Himself and speak to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But He remains silent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then life is an outrageous horror. No one can live in the face of death, knowing that all is nothingness.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most people never reflect about either death or the futility of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But one day they will have to stand at that last moment of life and look towards the darkness.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When that day comes ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are worrying ...</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Death visited me this morning. We are playing chess together. This reprieve gives me the chance to arrange an urgent matter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What matter is that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My life has been a futile pursuit, a wandering, a great deal of talk without meaning. I feel no bitterness or self-reproach because the lives of most people are very much like this. But I will use my reprieve for one meaningful deed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that why you are playing chess with Death?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is a clever opponent, but up to now I haven't lost a single man.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How will you outwit Death in your game?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I use a combination of the bishop and the knight which he hasn't yet discovered. In the next move I'll shatter one of his flanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH shows his face at the grill of the confession booth for a moment but disappears instantly.</context>
      <utterance>I'll remember that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've tricked and cheated me! But we'll meet again, and I'll find a way.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meanwhile, JONS and the PAINTER have got drunk and are talking animatedly together.</context>
      <utterance>This is my hand. I can move it, feel the blood pulsing through it. The sun is still high in the sky and I, Antonius Block, am playing chess with Death. He makes a fist of his hand and lifts it to his temple.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me and my master have been abroad and have just come home. Do you understand, you little pictor?</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Crusade.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's worse than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, me. No matter which way you turn, you have your rump behind you. That's the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>PAINTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JONS paints a small figure which is supposed to represent himself.</context>
      <utterance>The rump behind you, the rump behind you there's a profound truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT walks by, calls to his squire and goes out into the bright sunshine. JONS manages to set himself down from the scaffolding. Outside the church, four soldiers and a monk are in the process of putting a woman in the stocks. Her face is pale and child-like, her head has been shaved, and her knuckles are bloody and broken. Her eyes are wide open, yet she doesn't appear to be fully conscious. JONS and the KNIGHT stop and watch in silence. The soldiers are working quickly and skillfully, but they seem frightened and dejected. The monk mumbles from a small book. One of the soldiers picks up a wooden bucket and with his hand begins to smear a bloody paste on the wall of the church and around the woman. JONS holds his nose.</context>
      <utterance>This is squire Jˆns. He grins at Death, mocks the Lord, laughs at himself and leers at the girls. His world is a Jˆnsworld, believable only to himself, ridiculous to all including himself, meaningless to Heaven and of no interest to Hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That soup of yours has a hell of a stink. What is it good for?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He whispers this with a horrified face and continues to splash the sticky mess on the wall.</context>
      <utterance>She has had carnal intercourse with the Evil One.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now she's in the stocks.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She will be burned tomorrow morning at the parish boundary. But we have to keep the Devil away from the rest of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you do that with this stinking mess?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the best remedy: blood mixed with the bile of a big black dog. The Devil can't stand the smell.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither can I.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MONK stops reading and raises his head.</context>
      <utterance>Have you seen the Devil?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must not talk to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can that be so dangerous?</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but she is believed to have caused the pestilence with which we are affected.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods resignedly and walks away. The young woman starts to moan as though she were having a horrible nightmare. The sound of her cries follows the two riders for a considerable distance down the road.</context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RAVEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you look so surprised? I steal from the dead. These days it's quite a lucrative enterprise. The GIRL makes a movement as if to run away.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're thinking of running to the village and telling. That wouldn't serve any purpose. Each of us has to save his own skin. It's as simple as that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slowly he closes the door behind the GIRL. The stuffy room is now in almost total darkness. But JONS becomes clearly visible.</context>
      <utterance>Don't try to scream. There's no one around to hear you, neither God nor man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I recognize you, although it's a long time since we met. Your name is Raval, from the theological college at Roskilde. You are Dr. Mirabilis, Coelestis et Diabilis. RAVAL smiles uneasily and looks around.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GIRL stands immobile.</context>
      <utterance>Am I not right?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were the one who, ten years ago, convinced my master of the necessity to join a better- class crusade to the Holy Land. RAVAL looks around.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look uncomfortable. Do you have a stomach- ache? RAVAL smiles anxiously.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>meaning of these ten years, which previously seemed to me such a waste. Our life was too good and we were too satisfied with ourselves. The Lord wanted to punish us for our complacency. That is why He sent you to spew out your holy venom and poison the knight.</context>
      <utterance>When I see you, I suddenly understand the</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I acted in good faith.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a quick movement he knocks the knife out of RAVAL'S hand, gives him a kick so that he falls on the floor and is about to finish him off. Suddenly the GIRL screams. JONS stops and makes a gesture of generosity with his hand.</context>
      <utterance>But now you know better, don't you? Because now you have turned into a thief. A more fitting and rewarding occupation for scoundrels. Isn't that so?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bends over RAVAL.</context>
      <utterance>By all means. I'm not bloodthirsty.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't beat me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have the heart to touch you, Doctor. But remember this: the next time we meet, I'll brand your face the way one does with thieves.  What I really came for is to get my waterskin filled.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk out of the house. RAVAL lies still for a few moments, then he rises slowly and looks around. When no one is in sight, he takes his bag and steals away. JONS quenches his thirst and fills his bag with water. The GIRL helps him.</context>
      <utterance>We have a deep well with cool, fresh water. Come, I'll show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He embraces her and tries to kiss her, but she holds herself back. Almost immediately he loses interest, hoists the waterbag on his shoulder and pats the GIRL on the cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Jˆns is my name. I am a pleasant and talkative young man who has never had anything but kind thoughts and has only done beautiful and noble deeds. I'm kindest of all to young women. With them, there is no limit to my kindness.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs kindly and walks away from her. When he has walked a short distance he turns; the GIRL is still there.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, my girl. I could very well have raped you, but between you and me, I'm tired of that kind of love. It runs a little dry in the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins walking towards him, her head bent. He doesn't wait for her but walks towards the KNIGHT, who patiently awaits his squire.</context>
      <utterance>Now that I think of it, I will need a housekeeper. Can you prepare good food?  As far as I know, I'm still a married man, but I have high hopes that my wife is dead by now. That's why I need a housekeeper.  The devil with it! Come along and don't stand there staring. I've saved your life, so you owe me a great deal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MIA and JOF have quickly changed costumes and again step out on the stage. They bow, to the public.</context>
      <utterance>Noble ladies and gentlemen, I thank you for your interest. Please remain standing for a little longer, or sit on the ground, because we are now going to perform a tragedia about an unfaithful wife, her jealous husband, and the handsome lover -- that's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He places his leg in front of JOF as if to trip him, raises MIA's skirt, makes a face as if he could see all the wonders of the world underneath it, and disappears behind the gaudily patched curtains. SKAT is very handsome, now that he can see himself in the reflection of a tin washbowl. His hair is tightly curled, his eyebrows are beautifully bushy, glittering earrings vie for equal attention with his teeth, and his cheeks are flushed rose red.</context>
      <utterance>Here is the husband. Here is the wife. If you'll shut up over there, you'll see something splendid. As I said, I play the lover and I haven't entered yet. That's why I'm going to hide behind the curtain for the time being.  It's damned hot. I think we'll have a thunderstorm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Night and moonlight now prevail Here sleeps my wife so frail ...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE FROM THE PUBLIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does she snore?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I point out that this is a tragedy, and in tragedies one doesn't snore.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE FROM THE PUBLIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This opinion causes mirth in the audience. JOF becomes slightly confused and goes out of character, but MIA keeps her head and begins snoring.</context>
      <utterance>I think she should snore anyhow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MONK falls silent, looking around with a bitter face and a cold, scornful glance. Now, he clenches his hands, straddles the ground and turns his face upwards.</context>
      <utterance>God has sentenced us to punishment. We shall all perish in the black death. You, standing there like gaping cattle, you who sit there in your glutted complacency, do you know that this may be your last hour? Death stands right behind you. I can see how his crown gleams in the sun. His scythe flashes as he raises it above your heads. Which one of you shall he strike first? You there, who stand staring like a goat, will your mouth be twisted into the last unfinished gasp before nightfall? And you, woman, who bloom with life and self- satisfaction, will you pale and become extinguished before the morning dawns? You back there, with your swollen nose and stupid grin, do you have another year left to dirty the earth with your refuse? Do you know, you insensible fools, that you shall die today or tomorrow, or the next day, because all of you have been sentenced? Do you hear what I say? Do you hear the word? You have been sentenced, sentenced!</utterance>
   <speaker>MONK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes the sign of the cross over the crowd and then begins a new song in a strong voice. The monks rise and join in the song. As if driven by some superhuman force, the penitents begin to whip themselves again, still wailing and moaning. The procession continues. New members have joined the rear of the column; others who were unable to go on lie weeping in the dust of the road. JONS the squire drinks his beer.</context>
      <utterance>Lord have mercy on us in our humiliation! Don't turn your face from us in loathing and contempt, but be merciful to us for the sake of your son, Jesus Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This damned ranting about doom. Is that food for the minds of modern people? Do they really expect us to take them seriously? The KNIGHT grins tiredly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, now you grin at me, my lord. But allow me to point out that I've either read, heard or experienced most of the tales which we people tell each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans down over the GIRL as she crouches at his feet and pats her on the head. The KNIGHT drinks his beer silently.</context>
      <utterance>Even the ghost stories about God the Father, the angels, Jesus Christ and the Holy Ghost -- all these I've accepted without too much emotion.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you screaming about?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Plog, the smith, and you are the squire Jˆns.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen my wife?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I haven't. But if I had seen her and she looked like you, I'd quickly forget that I'd seen her.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, in that case you haven't seen her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe she's run off.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know anything?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MERCHANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it's true! The plague is spreading along the west coast. People are dying like flies. Usually business would be good at this time of year, but, damn it, I've still got my whole stock unsold.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They speak of the judgment day. And all these omens are terrible. Worms, chopped-off hands and other monstrosities began pouring out of an old woman, and down in the village another woman gave birth to a calf's head.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The day of judgment. Imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It hasn't rained here for a month. We'll surely lose our crops.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCHANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And people are acting crazy, I'd say. They flee the country and carry the plague with them wherever they go.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The day of judgment. Just think, just think!</utterance>
   <speaker>FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's as they say, I suppose a person should look after his house and try to enjoy life as long as he can.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Things that mustn't be named -- but the priests say that the woman carries it between her legs and that's why she must cleanse herself.</context>
      <utterance>But there have been other things too, such things that can't even be spoken of.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Judgment day. And the Riders of the Apocalypse stand at the bend in the village road. I imagine they'll come on judgment night, at sundown.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are many who have purged themselves with fire and died from it, but the priests say that it's better to die pure than to live for hell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>MERCHANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the end, yes, it is. No one says it out loud, but all of us know that it's the end. And people are going mad from fear.</utterance>
   <speaker>FARMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're afraid too.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCHANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I'm afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLOG, the smith, shoves his way into a place next to JOF, who is still dressed in his costume. Opposite him sits RAVAL, leaning slightly forward, his face perspiring heavily. RAVAL rolls an armlet out on the table.</context>
      <utterance>The judgment day becomes night, and the angels descend and the graves open. It will be terrible to see. They whisper in low tones and sit close to each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want this armlet? You can have it cheap.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't afford it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's real silver.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nice. But it's surely too expensive for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, but has anyone here seen my wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has she disappeared?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say she's run away.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has she deserted you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With an actor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An actor! If she's got such bad taste, then I think you should let her go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right. My first thought, of course, was to kill her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. But to murder her, that's a terrible thing to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm also going to kill the actor.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The actor?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, the one she eloped with.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What has he done to deserve that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you stupid?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The actor! Now I understand. There are too many of them, so even if he hasn't done anything in particular you ought to kill him merely because he's an actor.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, my wife has always been interested in the tricks of the theatre.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that turned out to be her misfortune.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now RAVAL enters the discussion. He is slightly drunk and his voice is shrill and evil.</context>
      <utterance>Her misfortune, but not mine, because a person who's born unfortunate can hardly suffer from any further misfortune. Isn't that true?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, you! You sit there and lie to the smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I! A liar!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're an actor too and it's probably your partner who's run off with Plog's old lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you an actor too?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An actor! Me! I wouldn't quite call myself that!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ought to kill you; it's only logical.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How strange -- you've turned pale. Have you anything on your conscience?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're funny. Don't you think he's funny?  Oh, you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLOG bangs his hands down on the table so that the dishes jump. He gets up.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe we should mark you up a little with a knife, like they do petty scoundrels of your kind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOF gets up on the table and stands on his head. A hand pushes him forward so that he collapses on the floor. PLOG rises, pulls him to his feet with one hand.</context>
      <utterance>Stand on your head so that we can see how good an actor you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLOG beats him so furiously that JOF flies across the table. RAVAL leans over him.</context>
      <utterance>What have you done with my wife?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't lie there moaning. Get up and dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to. I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show us how you imitate a bear.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't play a bear.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAVAL prods JOF lightly with the knife point. JOF gets up with cold sweat on his cheeks and forehead, frightened half to death. He begins to jump and hop on top of the tables, swinging his arms and legs and making grotesque faces. Some laugh, but most of the people sit silently. JOF gasps as if his lungs were about to burst. He sinks to his knees, and someone pours beer over him.</context>
      <utterance>Let's see if you can't after all.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up again! Be a good bear.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment the door opens and JONS enters. JOF sees his chance and steals out. RAVAL intends to follow him, but suddenly stops. JONS and RAVAL look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>I haven't done any harm. I haven't got the strength to play a bear any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you remember what I was going to do to you if we met again? RAVAL steps back without speaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JONS raises his knife and cuts RAVAL from forehead to cheek. RAVAL staggers towards the wall.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a man who keeps his word.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mikael.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he'll soon be two.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's big for his age.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts the child down on the ground and half rises to shake out her red skirt. When she sits down again, the KNIGHT steps closer.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think so? Yes, I guess he's rather big.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You played some kind of show this afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you think it was bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are more beautiful now without your face painted, and this gown is more becoming.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, Jonas Skat has run off and left us, so we're in real trouble now.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that your husband?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now there's only him and me. We'll have to start doing tricks again and that's more trouble than it's worth.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you do tricks also?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We certainly do. And Jof is a very skillful juggler.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Mikael going to be an acrobat?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jof wants him to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.  Perhaps he'll become a knight.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me assure you, that's no pleasure either.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you don't look so happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you tired?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have dull company.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mean your squire?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you mean, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you, really?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch, it hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MIA's anxiety has been replaced by a mild anger. She pats him a little harder than necessary.</context>
      <utterance>Why did you have to go there? And of course you drank.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch! I didn't drink anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I suppose you were boasting about the angels and devils you consort with. People don't like someone who has too many ideas and fantasies.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I swear to you that I didn't say a word about angels.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOF doesn't answer but searches for the armlet. He holds it up in front of MIA with an injured expression.</context>
      <utterance>You were, of course, busy singing and dancing. You can never stop being an actor. People also become angry at that, and you know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look what I bought for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You couldn't afford it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The armlet glitters faintly in the twilight. MIA now pulls it across her wrist. They look at it in silence, and their faces soften. They look at each other, touch each other's hands. JOF puts his head against MIA'S shoulder and sighs.</context>
      <utterance>But I got it anyhow.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, how they beat me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you beat them back?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only become frightened and angry. I never get a chance to hit back. I can get angry, you know that. I roared like a lion.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were they frightened?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their son MIKAEL crawls over to them. JOF lies down on the ground and pulls his son on top of him. MIA gets down on her hands and knees and playfully sniffs at MIKAEL.</context>
      <utterance>No, they just laughed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you notice how good he smells?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts MIKAEL up and holds him by the legs. MIA looks up suddenly, remembering the knight's presence.</context>
      <utterance>And he is so compact to hold. You're a sturdy one. A real acrobat's body.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, this is my husband, Jof.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have just told your wife that you have a splendid son. He'll bring great joy to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, he's fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They become silent again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have we nothing to offer the knight, Mia?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, I don't want anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I picked a basket of wild strawberries this afternoon. And we have a drop of milk fresh from a cow ...</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... that we were allowed to milk. So, if you would like to partake of this humble fare, it would be a great honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please be seated and I'll bring the food. They sit down. MIA disappears with MIKAEL.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going next?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up to the saints' feast at Elsinore.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't advise you to go there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not, if I may ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>following the coast line south. It's said that people are dying by the tens of thousands.</context>
      <utterance>The plague has spread in that direction,</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really! Well, sometimes life is a little hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MIA has returned with a bowl of wild strawberries and the milk, places it between them and gives each of them a spoon.</context>
      <utterance>May I suggest ...  ... that you follow me through the forest tonight and stay at my home if you like. Or go along the east coast. You'll probably be safer there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish you good appetite.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I humbly thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points with a spoon and smiles. The KNIGHT nods, as if he were pondering some profound thought. JOF eats heartily.</context>
      <utterance>These are wild strawberries from the forest. I have never seen such large ones. They grow up there on the hillside. Notice how they smell!</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your suggestion is good, but I must think it over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It might be wise to have company going through the forest. It's said to be full of trolls and ghosts and bandits. That's what I've heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want some strawberries?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This man saved my life. Sit down, my friend, and let us be together.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, how nice this is.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For a short while.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nearly always. One day is like another. There is nothing strange about that. The summer, of course, is better than the winter, because in summer you don't have to be cold. But spring is best of all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have written a poem about the spring. Perhaps you'd like to hear it. I'll run and get my lyre. He sprints towards the wagon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now, Jof. Our guests may not be amused by your songs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOF has come out with his lyre, sits on a small, gaudy box and plucks at the instrument, humming quietly, searching for his melody. JONS yawns and lies down.</context>
      <utterance>You'll not get to hear it either. There are persons here who don't appreciate my art and I don't want to upset anyone. I'm a sensitive soul.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People are troubled by so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's always better when one is two. Have you no one of your own?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I think I had someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what is she doing now?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look so solemn. Was she your beloved?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were newly married and we played together. We laughed a great deal. I wrote songs to her eyes, to her nose, to her beautiful little ears. We went hunting together and at night we danced. The house was full of life ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want some more strawberries?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the bowl of milk in his hand and drinks deeply from it several times. Then he carefully puts it down and looks up, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Everything I've said seems meaningless and unreal while I sit here with you and your husband. How unimportant it all becomes suddenly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you don't look so solemn.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns his face away and looks out towards the sea and the colorless gray sky.</context>
      <utterance>I shall remember this moment. The silence, the twilight, the bowls of strawberries and milk, your faces in the evening light. Mikael sleeping, Jof with his lyre. I'll try to remember what we have talked about. I'll carry this memory between my hands as carefully as if it were a bowl filled to the brim with fresh milk.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rises, nods to the others and walks down towards the forest. JOF continues to play on his lyre. MIA stretches out on the grass. The KNIGHT picks up his chess game and carries it towards the beach. It is quiet and deserted; the sea is still.</context>
      <utterance>And it will be an adequate sign -- it will be enough for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have been waiting for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me. I was detained for a few moments. Because I revealed my tactics to you, I'm in retreat. It's your move.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you look so satisfied?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my secret.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Now I take your knight.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did the right thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you tricked me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. You fell right in the trap. Check!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you laughing at?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about my laughter; save your king instead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're rather arrogant.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our game amuses me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your move. Hurry up. I'm a little pressed for time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH is about to answer him but stops and leans over the board. The KNIGHT smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I understand that you've a lot to do, but you can't get out of our game. It takes time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to escort the juggler and his wife through the forest? Those whose names are Jof and Mia and who have a small son?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, no reason at all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God in heaven, isn't this Plog, the smith?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sitting here sniveling in loneliness?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes, look at the smith. He moans like a rabbit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JONS pats the smith on the back, quenches his thirst with beer, and sits down by his side.</context>
      <utterance>If I were in your boots, I'd be happy to get rid of a wife in such an easy way.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you married?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I! A hundred times and more. I can't keep count of all my wives any longer. But it's often that way when you're a traveling man.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can assure you that one wife is worse than a hundred, or else I've had worse luck than any poor wretch in this miserable world, which isn't impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it's hell with women and hell without them. So, however you look at it, it's still best to kill them off while it's most amusing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JONS nods delightedly. He has drunk deeply and talks with an old woman's voice.</context>
      <utterance>Women's nagging, the shrieking of children and wet diapers, sharp nails and sharp words, blows and pokes, and the devil's aunt for a mother-in-law. And then, when one wants to sleep after a long day, there's a new song -- tears, whining and moans loud enough to wake the dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you kiss me good night?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you sing a song for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you love me the way you did when we first met?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you look at my new slip?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You only turn your back and snore.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh hell!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look how he howls again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I love her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>misguided ham shank, I'll tell you that love is another word for lust, plus lust, plus lust and a damn lot of cheating, falseness, lies and all kinds of other fooling around.</context>
      <utterance>So, maybe you love her! Then, you poor</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but it hurts anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. Love is the blackest of all plagues, and if one could die of it, there would be some pleasure in love. But you almost always get over it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, not me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you too. There are only a couple of poor wretches who die of love once in a while. Love is as contagious as a cold in the nose. It eats away at your strength, your independence, your morale, if you have any. If everything is imperfect in this imperfect world, love is most perfect in its perfect imperfection.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're happy, you with your oily words, and, besides, you believe your own drivel.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JONS gets up from the table and strokes his face with his hands. PLOG becomes very unhappy and grabs his belt.</context>
      <utterance>Believe! Who said that I believed it? But I love to give good advice. If you ask me for advice you'll get two pieces for the price of one, because after all I really am an educated man.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, Jˆns. May I go with you through the forest? I'm so lonely and don't want to go home because everyone will laugh at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLOG gets up and embraces JONS. Slightly drunk, the two new friends walk towards the door.</context>
      <utterance>Only if you don't whimper all the time, because in that case we'll all have to avoid you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jˆns! Watch out. That one wants to fight all the time. He's not quite sane.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLOG steps up to JOF, who blanches with fear. PLOG offers his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, but now he's just sniveling.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOF gingerly proffers a frightened hand and gets it thoroughly shaken and squeezed. While JOF tries to straighten out his fingers, PLOG is seized by great good will and opens his arms.</context>
      <utterance>I'm really sorry if I hurt you. But I have such a hell of a temper, you know. Shake hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come in my arms, little brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOF climbs up on the wagon seat quickly and clucks at the horse.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, thank you, perhaps later. But now we're really in a hurry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now the moon has come out of the clouds.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good. Now we can see the road better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like the moon tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The trees stand so still.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's because there's no wind.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess he means that they stand very still.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's completely quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If one could hear a fox at least.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or an owl.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or a human voice besides one's own.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, out of the silence and the dim light falling across the forest road, a ghostlike cart emerges. It is the WITCH being taken to the place where she will be burned. Next to her eight soldiers shuffle along tiredly, carrying their lances on their backs. The girl sits in the cart, bound with iron chains around her throat and arms. She stares fixedly into the moonlight.</context>
      <utterance>They say it's dangerous to remain standing in moonlight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the place of execution.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SOLDIER nods sourly. Hesitantly, the travelers follow. The KNIGHT guides his horse over to the side of the cart. The WITCH seems to be half-conscious, but her eyes are wide open.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, now I can see. It's the girl who has done it with the Black One. The witch?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WITCH'S pale, childish face turns towards the KNIGHT and she shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>I see that they have hurt your hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a potion that will stop your pain. She shakes her head again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saints preserve us, be quiet! It's said that she brings the Devil with her wherever she goes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are eight brave men, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SOLDIER speaks in whispers while glancing anxiously at the WITCH.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we've been paid. And this is a volunteer job.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Tyan, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fourteen, my lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TYAN nods quietly and looks away. Now they arrive at the parish border. At the foot of the nearby hills lies a crossroads. The pyre has already been stacked in the center of the forest clearing. The travelers remain there, hesitant and curious.</context>
      <utterance>And is it true that you have been in league with the Devil?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say that you have been in league with the Devil.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not out of curiosity, but for very personal reasons. I too want to meet him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to ask him about God. He, if anyone, must know.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can see him anytime.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT grips the wooden rail of the cart so tightly that his knuckles whiten. TYAN leans forward and joins her gaze with his.</context>
      <utterance>You must do as I tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT meets her gaze. They stare at each other for a long time.</context>
      <utterance>Look into my eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you see? Do you see him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He falls silent. The soldiers work at the stakes; their hammering echoes in the forest.</context>
      <utterance>I see fear in your eyes, an empty, numb fear. But nothing else.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one, nothing, no one?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you see him behind your back?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, there is no one there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he is with me everywhere. I only have to stretch out my hand and I can feel his hand. He is with me now too. The fire won't hurt me. He will protect me from everything evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has he told you this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has he said it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TYAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sounds of the hammers stops. The soldiers stand like black shadows rooted in the moss. They fumble with the chains and pull at the neck iron. TYAN moans weakly, as if she were far away.</context>
      <utterance>I know it, I know it. You must see him somewhere, you must. The priests had no difficulty seeing him, nor did the soldiers. They are so afraid of him that they don't even dare touch me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why have you crushed her hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who did?</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers pull the iron and the chains. TYAN'S shaven head sways, gleaming in the moonlight. Her blackened mouth opens as if to scream, but no sound emerges. They take her down from the cart and lead her towards the ladder and the stake. The KNIGHT turns to the MONK, who remains seated in the cart.</context>
      <utterance>Ask the monk.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH turns around and looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>What have you done with the child?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you ever stop asking questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The soldiers chain TYAN to the rungs of the ladder. She submits resignedly, moans weakly like an animal and tries to ease her body into position.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'll never stop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the soldiers approaches. Thick smoke wells down from the pyre and sweeps over the quiet shadows near the crossroads and the hill.</context>
      <utterance>For a moment I thought of killing the soldiers, but it would do no good. She's nearly dead already.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT doesn't heed this warning. He cups his hand, fills it with water from the skin and gives it to TYAN. Then he gives her a potion.</context>
      <utterance>I've told you to be careful. Don't go too close to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smoke billows down over them and they begin to cough. The soldiers step forward and raise the ladder against a nearby fir tree. TYAN hangs there motionlessly, her eyes wide open. The KNIGHT straightens up and stands immobile. JONS is behind him, his voice nearly choked with rage.</context>
      <utterance>Take this and it will stop the pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does she see? Can you tell me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She feels no more pain.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't answer my question. Who watches over that child? Is it the angels, or God, or the Devil, or only the emptiness? Emptiness, my lord!</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This cannot be.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at her eyes, my lord. Her poor brain has just made a discovery. Emptiness under the moon.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice sticks in his throat and he suddenly walks away. The KNIGHT mounts his horse. The travelers depart from the crossroads. TYAN finally closes her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>We stand powerless, our arms hanging at our sides, because we see what she sees, and our terror and hers are the same.  That poor little child. I can't stand it, I can't stand it ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, now it came over me again!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't scream. What came over you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My wife, damn it. She is so beautiful. She is so beautiful that she can't be described without the accompaniment of a lyre.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now it starts again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PLOG searches for beautiful words. He gestures gropingly with his large hands.</context>
      <utterance>Her smile is like brandy. Her eyes like blackberries ...</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course, of course. Her nose is like a little pink potato; her behind is like a juicy pear -- yes, the whole woman is like a strawberry patch. I can see her in front of me, with arms like wonderful cucumbers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk across an open meadow. Here it is a little brighter and the moon shimmers behind a thin sky. Suddenly PLOG points a large finger towards the edge of the forest.</context>
      <utterance>Saints almighty, stop! You're a very bad poet, despite the fact that you're drunk. And your vegetable garden bores me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you see something?</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There, over there!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't see anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two lovers discover PLOG and it's too late. They cannot retreat. SKAT immediately takes to his heels. PLOG chases him, swinging his sledge and bellowing like a wild boar. For a few confusing moments the two rivals stumble among the stones and bushes in the gray gloom of the forest. The duel begins to look senseless, because both of them are equally frightened. The travelers silently observe this confused performance. LISA screams once in a while, more out of duty than out of impulse.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on to something, my friends. The hour is near! Who is that at the edge of the forest if not my own dearly beloved, with actor attached?</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forgive me, dear little husband, I'll never do it again. I am so sorry and you can't imagine how terribly that man over there betrayed me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll kill him anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, do that, just kill him. He isn't even a human being.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell, he's an actor.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LISA sobs with excitement and sorrow. PLOG looks around, a little confused. SKAT uses this opportunity. He pulls out a dagger and places the point against his breast.</context>
      <utterance>He is only a false beard, false teeth, false smiles, rehearsed lines, and he's as empty as a jug. Just kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's right. Just kill me. If you thought that I was going to apologize for being what I am, you are mistaken.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look how sickening he is. How he makes a fool of himself, how he puts on an act. Dear Plog, kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>unreality will soon be transformed into a new, solid reality. An absolutely tangible corpse.</context>
      <utterance>My friends, you have only to push, and my</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do something then. Kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your life's thread now hangs by a very ragged shred. Idiot, your day is short.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SKAT looks at the travelers with a pained expression and then lifts his eyes towards the night sky.</context>
      <utterance>You'll have to irritate me a little more to get me as angry as before.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SKAT sinks the dagger into his breast and slowly falls to the ground. The travelers stand confused. PLOG rushes forward and begins to pull at SKAT'S hands.</context>
      <utterance>I forgive all of you. Pray for me sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh dear, dear, I didn't mean it that way! Look, there's no life left in him. I was beginning to like him, and in my opinion Lisa was much too spiteful. JOF leans over his colleague.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's dead, totally, enormously dead. In fact, I've never seen such a dead actor.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, let's go. This is nothing to mourn over. He has only himself to blame.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I have to be married to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SKAT lies in the grass and keeps the dagger pressed tightly to his breast. The travelers depart and soon they have disappeared into the dark forest on the other side of the meadow. When SKAT is sure that no one can see him, he sits up and lifts the dagger from his breast. It is a stage dagger with a blade that pushes into the handle. SKAT laughs to himself.</context>
      <utterance>We must go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He soon finds a likely tree and climbs up into its thick foliage. He sits down as comfortably as possible and reaches for his food pouch.</context>
      <utterance>Now that was a good scene. I'm really a good actor. After all, why shouldn't I be a little pleased with myself? But where shall I go? I'll wait until it becomes light and then I'll find the easiest way out of the forest. I'll climb up a tree for the time being so that no bears, wolves or ghosts can get at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He peers through the foliage. Below him stands a dark figure diligently sawing away at the base of the tree. SKAT becomes frightened and angry.</context>
      <utterance>Workmen in the forest. Oh, well!  The terrible night doesn't frighten me ...  Hey, what the devil ... it's my tree they're cutting down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sawing continues without a pause. SKAT becomes more frightened.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you! Do you hear me, you tricky bastard? What are you doing with my tree?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH straightens his back and squints up at him. SKAT cries out in terror.</context>
      <utterance>Can't you at least answer me? Politeness costs so little. Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sawing down your tree because your time is up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't do. I haven't got time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you haven't got time.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I have my performance.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it's canceled because of death.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My contract.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your contract is terminated.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My children, my family.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shame on you, Skat!</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH begins to saw again. The tree creaks.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm ashamed.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't there any way to get off? Aren't there any special rules for actors?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not in this case.</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH saws.</context>
      <utterance>No loopholes, no exceptions?</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH saws.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you'll take a bribe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH saws.</context>
      <utterance>Help!</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tree falls. The forest becomes silent again.</context>
      <utterance>Help! Help!</utterance>
   <speaker>SKAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The travelers have come to a sort of clearing and have collapsed on the moss. They lie quietly and listen to their own breathing, their heartbeats, and the wind in the tree tops. Here the forest is wild and impenetrable. Huge boulders stick up out of the ground like the heads of black giants. A fallen tree lies like a mighty barrier between light and shadow. MIA, JOF and their child have sat down apart from the others. They look at the light of the moon, which is no longer full and dead but mysterious and unstable. The KNIGHT sits bent over his chess game. LISA cries quietly behind PLOG'S back. JONS lies on the ground and looks up at the heavens.</context>
      <utterance>Night and then dawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Soon dawn will come, but the heat continues to hang over us like a smothering blanket.</utterance>
   <speaker>LISA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so frightened.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We feel that something is going to happen to us, but we don't know what.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's the day of judgment.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now, something moves behind the fallen tree. There is a rustling sound and a moaning cry that seems to come from a wounded animal. Everyone listens intently, all faces turned towards the sound. A voice comes out of the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>The day of judgment ...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>RAVAL'S perspiring face soon becomes visible. He disappears in the darkness, but his voice is heard again.</context>
      <utterance>Do you have some water?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you give me a little water?  I have the plague.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't come here. If you do I'll slit your throat. Keep to the other side of the tree.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one answers. There is complete silence. RAVAL gasps heavily for air. The dry leaves rustle with his movements.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid of death.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to die! I don't want to!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one answers. The trees sigh. RAVAL begins to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Can't you have pity on me? Help me! At least talk to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His words are choked off by a gurgling sound. He disappears in the darkness behind the fallen tree. It becomes quiet for a few moments.</context>
      <utterance>I am going to die. I. I. I! What will happen to me! Can no one console me? Haven't you any compassion? Can't you see that I ...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's no use. It's no use. I know that it's no use. It's meaningless. It's totally meaningless. I tell you that it's meaningless. Can't you hear that I'm consoling you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAVEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one answers, no one moves. RAVAL'S sobs are dry and convulsive, like a frightened child's. His sudden scream is cut off in the middle. Then it becomes quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Help me, help me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall we play our game to the end?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DEATH raises his hand and strikes the KNIGHT'S queen. Antonius Block looks at</context>
      <utterance>Your move!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I take your queen.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT leans over the game. The moonlight moves over the chess pieces, which seem to have a life of their own. JOF has dozed off for a few moments, but suddenly he wakens. Then he sees the KNIGHT and DEATH together. He becomes very frightened and awakens MIA.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't notice that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mia!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see something terrible. Something I almost can't talk about.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The knight is sitting over there playing chess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I can see that too and I don't think it's so terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But do you see who he's playing with?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is alone. You mustn't frighten me this way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, he isn't alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it, then?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Death. He is sitting there playing chess with Death himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mustn't say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We must try to escape.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JOF gets up carefully and disappears into the darkness behind the trees. MIA remains standing, as if paralyzed by fear. She stares fixedly at the KNIGHT and the chess game. She holds her son in her arms. Now JOF returns.</context>
      <utterance>We must try. They are so occupied with their game that if we move very quietly, they won't notice us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MIA does what JOF has told her. At the same moment, the KNIGHT looks up from his game.</context>
      <utterance>I have harnessed the horse. The wagon is standing near the big tree. You go first and I'll follow you with the packs. See that Mikael doesn't wake up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT remains silent. He sees MIA go through the moonlight towards the wagon. JOF bends down to pick up the pack and follows at a distance.</context>
      <utterance>It is your move, Antonius Block.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you lost interest in our game?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lost interest? On the contrary.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem anxious. Are you hiding anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing escapes you -- or does it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing escapes me. No one escapes from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pretends to be clumsy and knocks the chess pieces over with the hem of his coat. He looks up at DEATH.</context>
      <utterance>It's true that I'm worried.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've forgotten how the pieces stood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I see something interesting.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are mated on the next move, Antonius Block.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's true.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you enjoy your reprieve?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm happy to hear that. Now I'll be leaving you. When we meet again, you and your companions' time will be up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you will divulge your secrets.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no secrets.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you know nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEATH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT wants to answer, but DEATH is already gone. A murmur is heard in the tree tops. Dawn comes, a flickering light without life, making the forest seem threatening and evil. JOF drives over the twisting road. MIA sits beside him.</context>
      <utterance>I have nothing to tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What a strange light.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess it's the thunderstorm which comes with dawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's something else. Something terrible. Do you hear the roar in the forest?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's probably rain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it isn't rain. He has seen us and he's following us. He has overtaken us; he's coming towards us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet, Mia. In any case, not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wagon rattles over roots and stones; it sways and creaks. Now the horse stops with his ears flat against his head. The forest sighs and stirs ponderously.</context>
      <utterance>I'm so afraid. I'm so afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They crawl into the wagon and crouch around the sleeping child.</context>
      <utterance>Get into the wagon, Mia. Crawl in quickly. We'll lie down, Mia, with Mikael between us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is the Angel of Death that's passing over us, Mia. It's the Angel of Death. The Angel of Death, and he's very big.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shivers as if she had a fever. They pull the blankets over them and lie closely together. The wagon canvas flutters and beats in the wind. The roar outside is like a giant bellowing.</context>
      <utterance>Do you feel how cold it is? I'm freezing. I'm terribly cold.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>KARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard from people who came from the crusade that you were on your way home. I've been waiting for you here. All the others have fled from the plague. The KNIGHT is silent. He looks at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The KNIGHT nods, silent.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you recognize me any more?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks closer and looks searchingly into his face. The smile lingers in her eyes and she touches his hand lightly.</context>
      <utterance>You also have changed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I can see that it's you. Somewhere in your eyes, somewhere in your face, but hidden and frightened, is that boy who went away so many years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's over now and I'm a little tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see that you're tired.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over there stand my friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all sit down at the table in the room, which is lit by torches on the walls. Silently they eat the hard bread and the salt-darkened meat. KARIN sits at the head of the table and reads aloud from a thick book.</context>
      <utterance>Ask them in. They will break the fast with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Three mighty knocks sound on the large portal. KARIN interrupts her reading and looks up from the book. JONS rises quickly and goes to open the door.</context>
      <utterance>"And when the Lamb broke the seventh seal, there was silence in heaven for about the space of half an hour. And I saw the seven angels which stood before God; and to them were given seven trumpets. And another ..."</utterance>
   <speaker>KARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the rain becomes quiet. There is suddenly an immense, frightening silence in the large, murky room where the burning torches throw uneasy shadows over the ceiling and the walls. Everyone listens tensely to the stillness.</context>
      <utterance>"The first angel sounded, and there followed hail and fire mingled with blood, and they were cast upon the earth; and the third part of the trees was burnt up and all the green grass was burnt up."</utterance>
   <speaker>KARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Steps are heard on the stairs. JONS returns and sits down silently at his place but does not continue to eat.</context>
      <utterance>"And the second angel sounded, and as it were a great mountain burning with fire was cast into the sea; and a third part of the sea became blood ..."</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was someone there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KARIN lifts her head for a moment but once again leans over the large book.</context>
      <utterance>No, my lord. I saw no one.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all lift their heads, and when they see who is coming towards them through the twilight of the large room, they rise from the table and stand close together.</context>
      <utterance>"And the third angel sounded, and there fell a great star from heaven, burning as it were a torch, and it fell upon the third part of the rivers and upon the fountains of waters; and the name of the star is called Wormwood ..."</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, noble lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am Karin, the knight's wife, and welcome you courteously to my house.</utterance>
   <speaker>PLOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am a smith by profession and rather good at my trade, if I say so myself. My wife Lisa -- curtsy for the great lord, Lisa. She's a little difficult to handle once in a while and we had a little spat, so to speak, but no worse than most people. The KNIGHT hides his face in his hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From our darkness, we call out to Thee, Lord. Have mercy on us because we are small and frightened and ignorant.</utterance>
   <speaker>KNIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, You who are somewhere, who must be somewhere, have mercy upon us.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could have given you an herb to purge you of your worries about eternity. Now it seems to be too late. But in any case, feel the immense triumph of this last minute when you can still roll your eyes and move your toes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet, quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I shall be silent, but under protest.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is the end.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is silent. He lowers his hand. His son, MIKAEL, has listened to his words. Now, he crawls up to MIA and sits down in her lap.</context>
      <utterance>I see them, Mia! I see them! Over there against the dark, stormy sky. They are all there. The smith and Lisa and the knight and Raval and Jˆns and Skat. And Death, the severe master, invites them to dance. He tells them to hold each other's hands and then they must tread the dance in a long row. And first goes the master with his scythe and hourglass, but Skat dangles at the end with his lyre. They dance away from the dawn and it's a solemn dance towards the dark lands, while the rain washes their faces and cleans the salt of the tears from their cheeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You with your visions and dreams.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screenplay by Ingmar Bergman</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
