<movie id="115" title="Butterfly Effect The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>If anyone finds this, then I guess my plan didn't work and I'm already dead...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fatigue overwhelms him, but he continues writing...</context>
      <utterance>But if I can just go back to the beginning of all this, I still might be able to save her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan quickly eyes the situation and grabs the 5/16" wrench from the toolbox.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, okay... what now?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna be late again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did you ever care about getting to school on time?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan impatiently watches Andrea turn the bolt.</context>
      <utterance>We're putting up pictures for Parent's Night.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Righty-tighty, lefty-lucy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The carburetor will not set properly. She bangs on it with the wrench.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Don't worry Evan, you'll have plenty of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Darn it!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... can dad come this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know the answer to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't he come out for one day?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been over this a hundred times. It's too dangerous for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea hands the wrench to Evan.</context>
      <utterance>But Lenny said that his dad's coming... and Tommy and Kayleigh's dad...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan beams as he climbs onto the bumper and screws the carb back together. Andrea, meanwhile, strips off her coveralls, revealing a spotless nurse's uniform underneath.</context>
      <utterance>Here, Ev... Finish this up for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the dads are gonna be there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get the point, kiddo. But I'm not so bad, am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan, disappointed, passes the wrench back to Andrea.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Because I've been waiting to see your art projects all week and I'd feel terrible if all you thought about was your father not being there.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea gets behind the wheel. She turns the ignition and the engine roars to life. Evan wears a proud smile.</context>
      <utterance>Done. Try it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're amazing, kiddo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan blows Andrea a kiss goodbye and runs into the school. As Andrea pulls away, MRS. BOSWELL, 35, taps the car window.</context>
      <utterance>Okay have a great day I love you I'll pick you up later gotta go...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BOSWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Treborn! I need to speak with you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Boswell's morbid expression stops Andrea.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but can it wait til tonight? I'm already late for work --</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BOSWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you really need to see this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MRS. BOSWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was going to show this to the principal, but I wanted to talk to you first.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BOSWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Boswell opens the bottom drawer of her desk and pulls out a drawing. Andrea turns to stone when she sees it.</context>
      <utterance>Yesterday I had all the children draw pictures of what they wanted to be when they grew up. Most of them made drawings of what their parents did, but this...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The drawing shows a child holding a bloody knife while standing on a heap of dead bodies. It's extremely sophisticated for a seven-year old. Some of the corpses have been cut open and the insides are surprisingly anatomically correct. Andrea sees Evan playing with Lenny, harmless as a bunny, and struggles to control her concern.</context>
      <utterance>I don't understand... Evan did this?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you for showing it to me first. I'll... I'll take care of it. Can I have the picture?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BOSWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course. There is one more thing, Mrs. Treborn. And I feel bad for mentioning it...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BOSWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea is visibly shaken now.</context>
      <utterance>When I asked Evan about his drawing, well, he didn't remember doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You put the mommy too far away. Mrs. Boswell has macaroni and glue if you wanna fix it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're such a retard!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy lives far away but she comes and visits.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what'd you do that for?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan takes the ruined picture and leans down next to Lenny.</context>
      <utterance>Fat little baby, crying for mommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lenny, unable to stop crying, begins hyperventilating out of control. His desperate gasps for breath are frightening. Evan, scared, looks around for Mrs. Boswell, but cannot find her. He reaches up to his own picture and quickly tears his own macaroni "mother" apart and places it over Lenny's picture. It's a nuclear family again. Lenny slowly is able to catch his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Lenny. It's not that bad. You can still see your mom a little.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can... can... Can I have this?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh helps Lenny glue a new "mother" in place and she smiles gratefully at Evan. As Evan smiles back at Kayleigh, Mrs. Boswell calmly enters the room in time to see Evan tacking up his butchered family portrait. She shivers.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. I was gonna make a new one, anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you say he doesn't remember any of it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not according to his teacher. It just got me thinking about Jason and what if Evan's inherited his father's condition?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea nods and forces a thankful smile.</context>
      <utterance>Hold it, hold it, Andrea. Let's not jump to conclusions. I'll run some preliminary tests, see what we can rule out.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you what, bring Evan here tonight and we'll run a CAT-scan series.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like this place, Mom. It's creepy. Please can we go? I promise I won't make any more bad pictures!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be fine. Dr. Redfield just wants to give you some tests. You'll like him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Evan. It's very nice to meet you.  He's as handsome as his father.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Dr. Redfield can answer, Andrea cuts him off.</context>
      <utterance>You know my father?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why I wanted you to come here, Evan. Dr. Redfield already has a background in memory loss.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father has a bad memory, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan raises an eyebrow at the doctor.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, tell you what, Evan. If it's okay with your mother, I'd like to run some tests. Nothing scary.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, it might be a little scary...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell me that Evan doesn't have Jason's illness...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Andrea, I'm sure he'll test negative for brain disorders. But there's something else you can try to monitor his memory.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A journal. Just have him write down everything he does.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It could be extremely useful to jog his memory. See if he remembers anything new the next day. And I'll have the test results back in a few days.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan puts down the journal and eats breakfast. He separates the green clovers from the cereal and drops them to the floor for Crockett to nibble.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, George. I really appreciate you watching him, he won't be any trouble at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These'll bring you luck, Crockett.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea hangs up the phone and walks into the next room.</context>
      <utterance>Great. I'll see you soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan sees her but remains expressionless.</context>
      <utterance>Evan?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Life suddenly springs into Evan's face. He seems stunned to find himself holding the knife and drops it.</context>
      <utterance>Evan? What are you doing with that knife?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey. What were you doing with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I don't remember.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea writes nervously on a piece of paper as Evan gets out.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Andrea.  Hello little man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks a lot George. Here's my work number in case there are any problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea nods thanks and nervously drives away. Evan walks up to Mr. Miller and momentarily reaches for his hand. Mr. Miller flinches his hand away and chuckles at Evan.</context>
      <utterance>Whaddaya kidding? We're going to have a great time today, right Evan?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan appears confused for a moment at Mr. Miller's unexpected rudeness, but walks inside.</context>
      <utterance>You waiting for an invitation? The kids are inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evan, guess what? Dad got a new video camera and we're all gonna be in a movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think Evan gets to be in it --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quit it, Tommy. Evan gets to be Robin Hood. I'm gonna be Maid Marian, and you're the Sheriff of Nottingham!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I was the bad guy!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Miller, holding a full glass of scotch in one hand, sets the circa-80's bulky video camera on a tripod and plugs it into the porta-deck.</context>
      <utterance>You are, silly. He's a bad sheriff.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're really gonna be in a movie!?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, Evan, and you get to be the star.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I was the star.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan nods and sticks his arms straight up in the air. Mr. Miller downs his drink and helps Evan off with his clothes. Suddenly --</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, moron. Now get in your costume, Evan. And you have to promise, your bestest super-duper promise, that this will be our little secret. Think you can do that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where am I? What happened? Where did we all go?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan backs up and awkwardly scurries around the basement, grabbing his clothes. Panicking.</context>
      <utterance>Calm down, kid. Stand still.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was just somewhere else -- how did I get here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quit acting like some retard or I'll call your mother and tell her what a naughty little shit you've been.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh's eyes are unable to leave the floor. She begins adjusting her disheveled clothing. Evan trembles.</context>
      <utterance>Kayleigh? What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy silently watches from the top of the basement stairs, absently wringing the head off one of his sister's dolls.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the good news is that the results are negative. I've found no evidence in the way of lesions, hemorrhaging, tumors...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the bad news?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately, we've got nothing to work with. It's harder playing detective now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you must have something to go on?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I had to guess, I'd say the blackouts are stress related.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he's seven. What kind of stress can he have?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Plenty. Who knows? Maybe he's got severe coping problems about not having a father. Did you say the last blackout occurred when he was with his friend's dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, I doubt the answer's that simple.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd be surprised how often they are.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, he has been pushing me to meet his father, but I've been putting it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's worth a shot. I can arrange a controlled meeting. A careful dose of sedatives for Jason, some security, you and I monitoring. Evan comes in for a quick visit and with any luck, no more missing father complex.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How soon?...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dad lives here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not in this wing, actually. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now your father may seem sleepy to you, but that's just because of his medicine, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk to the end of the corridor and come to a "Visitor's Chamber". Dr.Redfield leads Evan inside. Andrea begins to follow, but the doctor gestures that she stay outside.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. I won't bite. You've seen pictures of me, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh. Mom says I have your eyes and your --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, ORDERLIES tackle Jason from both sides and wedge a baton under his jaw to wrench him away. Andrea frantically struggles to rescue Evan from Jason's clutches.</context>
      <utterance>I... love... you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And ALARM sounds and Andrea tries to cover Evan's eyes, but through her fingers he can see a quick blur of a pool of blood spreading from Jason's head.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Evan. I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan watches the coffin descend, disappearing from sight. Kayleigh steps up to Evan and takes his hand. A moment. And she softly whispers in Evan's ear.</context>
      <utterance>Ashes to ashes... dust to dust.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A rumble of thunder. Evan looks up at the brooding dark clouds.</context>
      <utterance>You're better off anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tommy, I'm bored shitless over here. What's up already?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy absently chucks an old Playboy toward Lenny. Kayleigh seems uncomfortable by the sight of it.</context>
      <utterance>Hold your horses, man. It's here somewhere. I saw it when I was a kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should go soon. If Dad catches us smoking down here, we're dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan claps his hands and stands up, Lenny and Kayleigh join him. Finally, Tommy shakes an old army thermos and hears something rattling inside.</context>
      <utterance>So let's go. This place creeps me out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy opens the thermos, tips it over and a blockbuster (1/4 stick of dynamite) spills out. Tommy grins mischievously.</context>
      <utterance>I knew it had something to do with the army.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's blow the shit out of something!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys, slow up, would you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evan, did I tell you? My mother said I might be able to visit her this summer in Orlando with her new family.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I say about mentioning that bitch?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell are you taking us anyway? Just blow something up already.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now at the edge of the woods, Tommy spots:</context>
      <utterance>Just blow something up? Are you nuts? There's an art to mass destruction. Would you just paint the Mona Lisa? No. Besides, we're here already.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here you go, buddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? No frigging way, man. I'm not touching that thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell you aren't. Anyone of us does it, you'll puss out and narc for sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't gonna work this time, buddy. Look how small that fuse is! I'll get killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes turn to Evan as he takes his lit cigarette, breaks off the filter and jams the fuse into the unlit end.</context>
      <utterance>Not necessarily.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That should buy you ten minutes at least.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee, thanks friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally, Lenny throws the bomb in the mailbox. Then sprints like hell to the woods. Kayleigh shakes Lenny's inhaler and hands it to him when he gets back.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, for Christ's sake, just do it, Lenny.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan pats Lenny on the back.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The four watch the mailbox in intense anticipation. Evan smiles with the cigarette pressed tightly between his lips and places his hands over Kayleigh's ears. She smiles back at him and presses his hands against her head. Tommy catches this and seems disturbed, and quickly turns back to -- The mailbox. Tick-tock... tick-tock... It's like a staring contest...</context>
      <utterance>You got balls, man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry! Let's go! Get him up, Evan! Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God... what did we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, Lenny. What's happened to you! We've gotta get help!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it? What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were just building a fort in the woods when Lenny freaked out. One minute he was fine, then he just froze up. Right guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened, Evan? The truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I don't remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something must've happened! What set him off?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I blacked out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan looks helpless.</context>
      <utterance>Don't try to use your blackouts to get out of this one!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan shakes his head "no". Almost ashamed...</context>
      <utterance>You're not making this up, are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan breathes slowly. Deeply. Andrea watches nervously from the far side of the room.</context>
      <utterance>With every breath you exhale, you can feel all of the tension draining from your body like water through a faucet. Nine, ten, and you're completely asleep. Relaxed.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now I want you to go back to the time you were in the woods with Lenny. Think of it like a movie. You can pause, rewind, or slow down any details you wish. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you now?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm standing next to Kayleigh, my hands are over her ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you hurting her?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea suppresses the tiniest of proud smiles.</context>
      <utterance>No, protecting her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Then go a little forward in time. What do you see now?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan's eyes suddenly roll back in his head.</context>
      <utterance>I see a car.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan moans and begins shaking.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, tell me about the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on. Nothing can hurt you. Remember, this is only a movie. You're completely safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't... the car vanishes and all of a sudden I'm on the ground in the woods.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The car doesn't vanish Evan. The movie in your head has broken, that's all. But now I've re-spliced it and I want you to tell me about the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan moans and shakes on the couch.</context>
      <utterance>It's coming... argh! I can't!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blood begins to trickle from Evan's nose as a guttural sound is uttered from deep within him. Dr. Redfield bolts upright in his chair and redirects the session.</context>
      <utterance>Fight it Evan. Hurry. It's coming!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan moans in agony. Andrea darts into the room.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Evan. Listen to my voice! On the count of ten, you're going to wake up. Feeling refreshed and remembering everything we talked about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Redfield waves her away and concentrates on Evan.</context>
      <utterance>What's happening to him?? Make it stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea moves to stop the blood flowing from Evan's nose. She lifts Evan's eyelids and sees only the whites of his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>One. You're feeling more awake now. Two, your eyes no longer feel heavy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan is completely non-responsive.</context>
      <utterance>Five. Six. Refreshed and awake! Seven, eight. Come on, Evan, wake up, dammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evan wake up, oh please wake up!</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing but moans and blood. Dr. Redfield frantically opens some desk drawers until he finds smelling salts. He breaks a small capsule under evan's mouth, pinches his bleeding nose closed and lets Evan inhale the vapor through his mouth. Evan lurches forward on the couch and falls off. Holding his bloody nose.</context>
      <utterance>Nine, ten. And you're awake! Open your eyes, dammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan deduces the answer from everyone's horrified faces.</context>
      <utterance>What happened? Did it work?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wipe that sad-assed look off your face before you get us all busted. You see the way Evan's mom was looking at you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On "mailbox", Tommy suddenly grabs Evan's jacket and SHOVES him against a parked car. Tommy looks around to make sure nobody heard anything.</context>
      <utterance>Would someone just tell me already what the hell happened in the mailbox?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't ever bring that shit up again. Not ever. Not to me, not to Kayleigh, or even Lenny. The stupid fuck if he ever learns to talk again. Understand? Evan nods, scared. Tommy gives a final shove.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy's right. Kayleigh clearly doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>Ever.  She don't want to talk about it, anyway. Do you Kayleigh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh says nothing as Tommy sees the theatre playing SEVEN and whispers.</context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There it is. Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea's face looks haunted by the on-screen images. She shakes her head in terror and grabs the remote.</context>
      <utterance>The powerful explosion is believed to have been caused by a small quantity of dynamite.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She clicks off the TV, trembling.</context>
      <utterance>Police thus far have no leads as to the suspects...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some crowd members TURN around and give Tommy a SHUSH. Tommy whips M&amp;Ms at them.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit! Look at that fat fuck! You'd have to wipe his ass with a forklift!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh, repulsed, suddenly darts from the aisle and runs out. Evan follows.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up, faggot. No one's talking to you!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Kayleigh. This was a bad idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan shakes his head "no". She looks devastated.</context>
      <utterance>You really don't remember anything that happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She begins to cry. Evan makes sure no one's staring.</context>
      <utterance>You're so lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches to comfort her. But she winces.</context>
      <utterance>It's going to be okay. Lenny'll be fine. You'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls her sleeve up, revealing a large bruise.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not your fault. Mrs. Kagan called dad and blamed us for what happened to Lenny.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh pulls back her shirt collar to show an even larger, darker bruise.</context>
      <utterance>Damn. Your dad did this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I deserve a lot worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks into his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? What you deserve is a better brother and father. All they do is make you feel like shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She searches his eyes for sincerity. And finds it. They lean into each other for a TENDER KISS. After a moment, a ROAR from nearby.</context>
      <utterance>You really have no clue how beautiful you are, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They jerk back to see Tommy, shocked and betrayed, staring at them from across a small crowd. By now, some teens chuckle at Tommy.</context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you doing??</utterance>
   <speaker>TEEN PUNK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Tommy rushes through the small crowd at Evan. His hands in fists. Suddenly a FOOT reaches out and trips Tommy. Tommy falls to the floor and the crowd cackles at him. Tommy slowly gets up, locks eyes with Evan. Hatred oozing. Evan looks guilty, weakly shaking his head, it's not what you're thinking. Tommy suddenly lunges at the TEEN PUNK who must be at least a foot taller than he is. Tommy lands a flurry of punches before the Teen Punk can even defend himself, frequently taking opportunities to eyeball Evan. Evan, Kayleigh and even the punk's FRIENDS look on helplessly when TWO SECURITY GUARDS SEIZE TOMMY. Tommy valiantly struggles against them at first. But the moment he realizes it's hopeless, he allows his body to go slack. As Tommy is being dragged away, he turns to Evan, a sick smile on his face. Evan and Kayleigh look back, speechless.</context>
      <utterance>Buying popcorn, what the fuck are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE UP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVEAL she's driving Evan and Kayleigh home. Evan's up front and Kayleigh sits behind them. Everyone silent. Andrea stares through the rearview mirror into Kayleigh's eyes. Probing. Searching.</context>
      <utterance>Andrea's eyes. Tormented.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how was the movie?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea watches Kayleigh. A calculated beat.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh flinches at the question. And Andrea catches it. Evan can't help but look back at Kayleigh. Oh my god, she knows.</context>
      <utterance>Any exploding mailboxes?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea pulls the car over and stops. After a moment, Kayleigh realizes she's at her house. She exits the car in a hurry.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea stares at Evan, who keeps his eyes facing dead ahead. She finally shifts the car into gear.</context>
      <utterance>Goodnight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>We're moving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe Tommy's still pissed at me. He knows I'm moving away, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's been acting real strange lately. He won't even look me in the eyes anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As a station wagon rolls up the street, Evan and Kayleigh duck in nearby bushes.</context>
      <utterance>Duck, here they come.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did your mom say if Lenny was... okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The station wagon finally heads into the driveway. Evan puts on a smile and charges the car, pounding the window.</context>
      <utterance>He must be. They're letting him go, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Inside the car, Lenny jerks back in horror. Mrs. Kagan looks angry as she rolls the window down.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome home, Lenny!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. KAGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The smile fades from Evan's face. Kayleigh hangs back.</context>
      <utterance>I think your little homecoming's in bad taste.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome home. Thought you might like some fresh air for a change.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lenny twitches ever-so-slightly.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Lenny.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan shakes his head "no".</context>
      <utterance>Is Tommy with you guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lenny looks back at the model airplane. Needs to think.</context>
      <utterance>It's cool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what did you do in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Evan and Kayleigh absorb this in silence, they see a column of smoke billowing in the horizon.</context>
      <utterance>It was awful. You can't sleep 'cause everyone's screaming all night long. I never want to go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan and Kayleigh run toward the smoke. Lenny nervously follows behind. They exit the woods to find:</context>
      <utterance>Do you see that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan and Kayleigh rush toward the trapped, helpless dog. Tommy is ready for them. He drops the lighter fluid, picks up a wooden plank and SWINGS! Evan ducks back at the last minute and Tommy accidentally connects with Kayleigh's head. Knocking her unconscious.</context>
      <utterance>Crockett!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look what you made me do!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy, enraged, fakes a high swing, then goes for Evan's knee cap. BASH! Evan doubles over in pain and falls to the ground, clutching his knee. Tommy moves to the fire, Crockett squirming inside the bag and picks up the lighter fluid. Evan painfully looks up from the ground and his eyes dart from the sight of Kayleigh, unconscious, to Crockett, trapped in the tied gunny sack.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>Kayleigh! Wake up!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy squeezes the bottle hard, creating a flaming fuse from the campfire to the fluid soaked dog. As the flames near Crockett, Evan, seething with rage, stands up with clenched fists and CHARGES Tommy at FULL SPEED --</context>
      <utterance>Why don't you fucking kiss her, Prince Charming!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets no answer from Lenny, who stands in the exact same spot. Tommy is nowhere in sight and the sound is of Kayleigh weeping. Evan spins to face her.</context>
      <utterance>How long was I out?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh, her knees drawn tightly to her chest, is unable to answer through her tears. Evan struggles to rise but he becomes dizzy and falls back to the ground. Evan takes a quick glance toward the gunny sack, smouldering then moans and buries his head in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Kayleigh?! Are you okay? Where's Crockett?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN'S DIARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan waves back to her, trying nonchalantly to wipe away his own tears as she fades into the distance. When Kayleigh disappears from sight, Andrea looks over to see what he's written.</context>
      <utterance>"I'll come back for you."</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan returns the journal and begins writing furiously.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PROFESSOR CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan grabs his psychology textbook from under his seat, gets up and turns in his exam.</context>
      <utterance>Time! Please place your blue books on my desk before you leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan flashes a confident smile.</context>
      <utterance>How'd you do, Evan?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure. I might have gotten some stories mixed up. Did Pavlov condition his dogs to lick his nuts?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Typical psych major. A complete wise ass. And how's your project coming? Still planning to change the way we humble scientists view memory assimilation?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Professor Carter nods solemnly, obviously in the know.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, I got no choice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan opens the window and checks out his Psych project: a small maze has several flatworms at one end and a bowl of cornflakes at the other.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa. Smells like patchouli and... ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cricket puts on her Doc Martens as Evan watches the worms.</context>
      <utterance>Cricket, meet my well-mannered roommate, Evan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRICKET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you're the one who fucked up the bell-curve on my Anthropology final. Later, Thumper.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she leaves, Thumper takes the black T-shirt by his wallet and throws it on Evan's bed.</context>
      <utterance>Nice to meet you, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan nods thanks, picks up his journal. Reads something and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Here, bro. Found your T-shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get dressed, Thumper, you're taking me out for my birthday.</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were a December baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thumper pulls out a bong.</context>
      <utterance>This is bigger. Seven years to the day. No blackouts.</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's do this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>KRISTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thumper proudly steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>So... which one of you has a pet worm?</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worms, plural.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRISTEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thumper steps back, points to Evan.</context>
      <utterance>That's so gross.</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heidi sinks another ball and looks up at Evan strangely.</context>
      <utterance>Talk to him about it, he's got the fetish.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heidi misses her shot and passes the cue to Evan.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, they're for a psych project. A study on memory.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's an experiment with flatworms and a maze. You take a flatworm and run it through the maze until he's memorized it. Then you put a new flatworm in the maze. He's clueless. Banging into walls, getting lost, whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gwen giggles as Spencer throws popcorn at Thumper's head.</context>
      <utterance>Like Ozzy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPENCER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thumper seems oblivious to their taunts as Evan knocks the three-ball in the side.</context>
      <utterance>Ten bucks says he eats it off the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan walks past Heidi, putting his hand on her shoulder to squeeze by. The hand lingers longer than necessary and Heidi doesn't mind. He sinks another ball.</context>
      <utterance>You chop up the smart flatworm and feed it to the dumb one and presto, the dumb one suddenly knows the maze inside and out.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just by absorbing the first worm into its cellular structure, it gets all of the worm's memories.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's the point?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another barrage of popcorn hits Thumper's jacket. Although his hand clenches on the cue. He meekly shuffles away to the opposite side of the pool table from the cackling Greeks.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe if I can figure out how the memories of a simple worm function, it'll help me understand the complexities of the human brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thumper casually takes the pool cue from Evan.</context>
      <utterance>So are you planning on becoming a doctor or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Heidi digests this, Thumper carefully lines up his shot... The eight ball. CRASH!!! The cue ball intentionally jumps the table, rocketing into the pitcher of beer on the Greek's table. They're all soaked with beer and debris. Just as they begin to rise, Thumper smashes the cue stick on the table, WHISTLING innocently (while now brandishing a spear). They sit the fuck down. Kristin, impressed, casually wraps her arm around Thumper's waist. He smiles coolly, it's nothing.</context>
      <utterance>No, I just don't want to lose my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that's your game.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>HEIDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smells like sex in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thumper had a busy afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan drunkenly crosses the room, grabs two beers from the mini-fridge.</context>
      <utterance>You're kidding. He's so... big.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heidi takes one. Looks under the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Charisma and eyeliner go a long way, I guess. Wanna beer?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most guys tuck their porn under here, but all you have are... comp books.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I've been keeping journals since I was seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan chugs his beer and sits next to her on the bed and puts his arm around her. Very drunk.</context>
      <utterance>Wow... read something.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heidi teasingly runs her fingers over his smooth torso.</context>
      <utterance>No way, I'd be too embarrassed.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan stops short.</context>
      <utterance>Then keep drinking, worm-boy. You're too uptight.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freeze! No "worm-boy". No "Mr. Worm," and no "Worm-Master-General!" Once you get a nickname like that you can't shake it. And I don't want everyone thinking I've got tapeworms coming out of my ass or something, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heidi hands him a book marked "AGE 13". He flips it open to a random place and takes the beer from her hand.</context>
      <utterance>Deal. Now read me something.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan takes and finishes her beer and begins reading. As he reads, he seems more and more on the verge of passing out.</context>
      <utterance>For courage.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Color drains from Evan's face as he realizes what he's reading. He looks over at Heidi, who kisses him.</context>
      <utterance>It's like my mind refused to believe what it was seeing. Hearing Crockett make those awful screams... Just writing about it gives me the shivers.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, go on...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Evan reads, the world seems to ALMOST IMPERCEPTIBLY VIBRATE around him LIKE A TUNING FORK. His voice becomes distant and SOUNDS ECHO around him like distant memories resurrecting themselves...</context>
      <utterance>It was like Tommy was possessed or something. There was a hate in his eyes that I couldn't really call human.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before an answer comes, Tommy smiles at his good fortune and swings the plank, hitting Evan's head. Evan is sent sprawling backwards, his forehead bleeding freely. Tommy knocks Evan hard in the ribs with his boots. Evan writhes in agony, his face against the ground. Lenny moves toward the gunny sack, lifts it and tugs desperately on the rope that traps Crockett inside.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't undo the rope! Tommy spins around and flashes an evil smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if on cue, Lenny does exactly as he's told. His eyes begin to glaze over. Evan, beaten and bloody, reaches out with his last bit of strength, grabs Tommy's foot and holds on.</context>
      <utterance>Drop it or I'll slit your mother's throat in her sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lenny remains frozen in place. Tommy yanks his leg back, breaking Evan's grip. Evan groans on the ground in a writhing heap. Tommy's voice hitches. His eyes water from pent up frustration.</context>
      <utterance>I got him, Lenny. Help Crockett!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy smiles viciously at Lenny, traumatized to watch Tommy pick up the lighter fluid and spray a liquid fuse from the campfire to the soaked gunny sack.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me good, Evan. There's a million other sisters in the world. You didn't have to fuck with mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHOOSH OF FLAMES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Evan passes out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heidi rolls her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God! No! No!</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands and angrily puts on her jacket.</context>
      <utterance>Wake up, idiot. It was just a dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It didn't feel like a dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEIDI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan doesn't even hear her. After getting his bearings, he grabs his jacket and exits, leaving her dumbfounded.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe because they never do.  So Don Juan, you pass out on all your dates?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Lenny frowns.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, uh, it's me. Evan.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing.</context>
      <utterance>What's that you're working on? A model?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response. Evan picks up a model airplane from the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you look busy, so maybe I should make this quick. I'd totally understand if you didn't want to get into this right now, but that day at the junkyard, could you help me remember what happened? Any details?</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't cut the rope.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, good, what else do you remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan, startled, drops the model on the desk. An epiphany.</context>
      <utterance>Drop it or I'll slit your mother's throat in her sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lenny stares out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Christ. It really happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With lightning speed, Lenny jumps from his desk and unexpectedly shoves EVAN IN TO THE WALL. Squadrons of hanging planes crash to the floor. Lenny digs his fingers into Evan's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>What if I can get back all my lost memories with my journals.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan is terrified. Then Lenny suddenly moves back and begins working on the model again, his eyes a million miles away. Evan is speechless. The door bursts open. Mrs. Kagan looks at the smashed model airplanes by Evan's feet. Evan ignores her accusing stare.</context>
      <utterance>Make one peep and I swear it'll be your last, motherfucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Lenny doesn't respond, Mrs. Kagan hustles Evan back into the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Well, thanks for seeing me, man. I shouldn't have waited so long.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really think he wanted to kill you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finds something he's looking for, marks the page with a yellow post-it note marked, BLACKOUT and sets the book in a separate pile. As he sets the next journal on the bed, it automatically opens up to a place where the spine was bent. Staring up at him is the message:</context>
      <utterance>All I know is that I might be able to unblock some of my repressed memories.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN'S DIARY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Later that evening:</context>
      <utterance>"I will come back for you." Evan looks overcome by guilt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe it went out. Should someone check it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a car appears from down the street and slowly pulls into the driveway. MRS. HALPERN, 24, an attractive young mother, gets out of the car and walks to the mailbox. Across the street, Tommy digs his fingers into the nerves of Lenny's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, you do that, Lenny.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy's words make Evan flinch. From inside the car, a BABY begins to cry. Mrs. Halpern walks back to the car. Evan looks on in horror and suddenly clenches his teeth in pain and silently swipes the front of his shirt, sending the lit cigarette to the ground. He pulls up his shirt revealing a fresh BURN MARK on his stomach.</context>
      <utterance>Make one peep and I swear it'll be your last, motherfucker.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HALPERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Halpern picks her up and carries her to the house. As the mother unlocks the front door to the house, the kids break into wide smiles of relief. But wait... The mother remembers the mail and carries the baby back to the mailbox. Now Tommy is the only one left still smiling.</context>
      <utterance>How's my sweet girl? Awww, you need a change, don't you honey?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. HALPERN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The baby fumbles with the mailbox's door handle for a moment --</context>
      <utterance>You want to open the door, honey?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan and Kayleigh slowly back away in shock and begin to run a few steps when they realize that Lenny isn't with them.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon! Run!!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lenny? Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lenny doesn't seem to hear, his eyes fixated on the crimson road. Evan and Tommy double back and grab him. They try to make him break out into a run, but Lenny's feet drag limply against the ground. Both Tommy and Evan grab an arm and begin to run with Lenny through the woods.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God oh my God...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the next bed, Thumper's head, wrapped in a blanket, pops up from above a NAKED GESELA'S waist.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan sits upright in bed and begins writing in the margins of the journal.</context>
      <utterance>Christ, man. You wanna clean that up before I lose my appetite here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's obviously hung up on him. Suddenly, a HAND grabs his shoulder. It's PROFESSOR CARTER.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, hello, uh, Mrs. Kagan, this is Evan Treborn.  I know. I'm sorry about that. But I really need to speak with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Didn't mean to scare you, Evan. Just wanted to know how the flatworms project was coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, fine I guess. It's been kind of crazy lately with my mom coming up, so I haven't...</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan shrugs and forces a smile.</context>
      <utterance>I know, I know. Who can think of worms when your libido's in full swing, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just don't drop the ball, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carter waves to another student and her parents and walks away.</context>
      <utterance>I won't let you down, Professor Carter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, mom. People will talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't help it. I'm just so proud of you. You've got the highest grades in all of your classes.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did Da -- Jason --- get good grades?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. He got straight A's without ever touching a book. That was the one area where his memory never failed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea's smile fades.</context>
      <utterance>Ma? Did he ever say that he figured out a way to recall a lost memory years after he blacked it out for the first time?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you ask?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's just weird with him being such a brain and all, I just wondered if he was ever able to remember stuff he'd forgotten.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan tries not to react.</context>
      <utterance>When he was around your age... almost exactly your age. He said he figured out a trick to remember the past.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't tell if they were real memories or just phantoms. You know, he might only have thought he actually remembered them...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then, just before it got so bad that he had to be committed, he said that he could...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>What? What could he do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan nods, but something gnaws beneath the surface.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it. It's nothing. He was far too sick by then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never wanted to be in the movie anyway and it was cold so I wanted to wear my clothes but Mr. Miller took his shirt off --</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thumper jumps off the bed and snatches the journal away.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh! I need quiet for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you stupid or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thumper begins scanning the journal entry. A bitter laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Shucks, I dunno. But maybe there's a reason why you've repressed the one day when some old lecher had you in your tighty whities, dammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the journal back to Evan. Evan opens it and begins reading it silently. His hands begin to tremble and he slams the book shut in defeat.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, man. I'd think twice about this. You could wake up a lot more fucked up than you are now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, Evan! I never thought I'd see you again. How've you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, comme si, comme ca, you know...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Evan. I don't know. It's been a long time. Fill me in.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh nods and they walk down the street. She reaches into her pocket, pulls out a pack of smokes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to State now. Things are going okay. I guess. Mom's good...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not since we were kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've stopped a hundred times.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how's Tommy?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her face is betrayed by a slight tick.</context>
      <utterance>You still live with your dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I emancipated myself when I was fifteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. That must've taken some courage.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if you remember my dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couldn't you have moved in with your mom?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk in silence for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>She had a new family. Not enough space for me. Said I should have moved in with her when we were kids. But... whatever.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, Kayleigh, the reason I came back to town was to talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me? Are you kidding? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember when I was a kid I had all these blackouts?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, lately some of the memories have begun to come back and I'd kinda like to talk to you about one of them in particular. It'd be a big help.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sure. I'll try to remember. Shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we were kids. Your dad was making a movie. Robin Hood or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want to know, Evan?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just... did he... what happened in the basement?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that why you came all the way back? To ask a lot of stupid questions about Robin Hood?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh stops walking and crushes her cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>No, but I think something really bad might've happened to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan's features shift from inquisitory to tenderness. He steps closer to Kayleigh and softly strokes her face. She flinches at first, but remains in the same spot.</context>
      <utterance>Is there a point to any of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh begins to tremble. Tears flow.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever happened, it wasn't our fault. You know we couldn't have stopped it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She moves her face away from his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Kayleigh. This may sound like bullshit coming from a guy who hasn't spoken to you in seven years...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her face collapses and she turns away.</context>
      <utterance>But you were seven years old and there's nothing you could've done to deserve...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just shut up, Evan. You're wasting your breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't hate yourself just because your dad's a twisted freak.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh runs, stops and turns back to Evan.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you trying to convince, Evan?! You come all the way out here to stir up my shit just because you had a bad memory!? You want me to cry on your shoulder and tell you that everything's all better now? Well fuck you, Evan! Nothing's gonna be all better! Okay?! Nothing ever gets better!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and runs away. Evan looks sick with guilt.</context>
      <utterance>If I was so wonderful, Evan, why didn't you ever call me? Why'd you leave me here to rot?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan puts a towel under the door.</context>
      <utterance>Some dude left a message for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan hits "play" on the answering machine.</context>
      <utterance>You can smell it all the way in the bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANSWERING MACHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEEP. Thumper offers Evan a magnified frown of disapproval.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, Evan, this is Professor Carter. Just wondered why you didn't hand in your essay this afternoon. I was a bit concerned. Call me to schedule a make-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANSWERING MACHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say to my sister motherfucker?! Last night she cried on the phone for over an hour to me.  She said you came and saw her last night. Thumper coughs accidentally, tips the bong over on Evan's bed. Reacting quickly, he grabs a towel from under the door and wipes off Evan's comforter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANSWERING MACHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEEP. Evan stares dumbstruck at the machine.</context>
      <utterance>She... she fucking killed herself tonight. She's dead.  And so are you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa, bad news, bro. I don't think this is gonna come out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan slowly nods and begins to strip out of his clothes. Mr. Miller takes a quick peek at him.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up moron. Now get in your costume Evan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got an idea. Let's go downstairs, it'll look more like a dungeon down there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did I say about keeping that door closed, stupid?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I wanna see!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy sulks and closes the door. Mr. Miller lowers his voice and speaks to Evan and Kayleigh.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna see my fist in about two seconds unless you do what I tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh giggles and covers her mouth with her hand. Evan looks skeptical.</context>
      <utterance>Now in this part of the story, Robin Hood just married Maid Marian and they have to kiss and stuff like grown-ups do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh stops giggling. Evan says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>So take your clothes off Kayleigh.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Miller gets behind the lens. The room is dead silent.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, like when you take a bath. Don't make a deal out of it. You too, Evan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's time for you to stand where the hell I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mature speech seems completely surreal coming from a seven-year old. Mr. Miller looks around the room as if he's the butt of some sick joke.</context>
      <utterance>Wrong answer, fuckbag. This is the very moment of your reckoning. In the next thirty seconds you're going to open one of two doors. The first door will forever traumatize your own flesh and blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happened to -- How are you doing that?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll change your daughter from a beautiful child into an empty shell whose only concept of trust was betrayed by her own sick pedophile father. Ultimately, it'll lead to her suicide. Nice work, daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan impatiently waves the question.</context>
      <utterance>Who -- who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just say you're being closely watched, George. Your other option is to get your porn off the rack and treat Kayleigh like... oh, let's say like how a loving father treats his daughter. Sound okay to you, Papa?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The impact of the last sentence isn't lost on Mr. Miller.</context>
      <utterance>Listen close then, fuckbag. You screw up again and I swear I'll flat out castrate you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan leans over to whisper in Kayleigh's ear. Kayleigh stares at the floor, then looks up at her father and shivers. Kayleigh looks into Evan's eyes for support. Evan nods go on. His confidence brings a boldness to her lips.</context>
      <utterance>One last thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you ever touch me again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh summons her own new courage.</context>
      <utterance>I -- I won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he leaves to pick up her clothes, Evan grins.</context>
      <utterance>I'm cold. And I'm putting on my clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hiding at the top of the basement stairs, Tommy recoils in horror and picks up one of his sister's dolls and begins twisting the head back and forth...</context>
      <utterance>What you need to do is discipline your son Tommy, because the kid's one sadistic pup.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Evan whips around to see Kayleigh watching him. Not only is Kayleigh alive, but she's a ravishing beauty. Evan lurches back from the shock of seeing Kayleigh and falls to the floor. She sees Evan's nose bleed and her eyes go wide.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan, still stunned, can do little but stare from the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, Evan. You're bleeding! Look at you!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, Kayleigh, you're...  Incredible.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where... where are my clothes?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan frowns with distaste, grabs a towel and heads out.</context>
      <utterance>Those are your clothes, silly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is too amazing! Un-fucking-real!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Evan turns around and sees Gwen, one of the sorority brats from the bar, exit the shower naked.</context>
      <utterance>I wish I could get so excited about a nose bleed.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan blushes and turns back to the mirror through which Gwen dries herself with a towel while staring flirtatiously back at Evan.</context>
      <utterance>Whoops. Sorry. My bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan holds his temple in pain as another memory comes to him.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you were with those assholes who threw popcorn at Thumper.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your name is... Gwen!</utterance>
   <speaker>GWEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pats his ass and exits the bathroom.</context>
      <utterance>Seriously, Evan. Lay off the blow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, uh, don't go freaking out on me over this, but do you remember when your dad first got his video camera?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I remember he had one... but he, like, put it away after the first day. Why would that freak me out?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh playfully sweeps her leg around to kick him on the ass, then smiles as if a ghost must have done it.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno.  Just being weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh gives him a big unexpected kiss and walks away. After a moment of wow, Evan runs off to class himself.</context>
      <utterance>Such a goofus. See you tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Mom, be there!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANSWERING MACHINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Andrea,  Evan,  And Chuck,  Aren't home right now. You know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thumper eyes this strange preppy kid with distaste.</context>
      <utterance>Thumper! What time is it, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whasamatter? Lost your Rolex?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck off, frat boy. Thumper walks away, leaving Evan dumbfounded.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PROFESSOR CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, everyone! Only two weeks until your science projects are due.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I still owe you an essay from last week. Is there any way I could get an extension?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you are...?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evan Treborn.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR CARTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan walks up the aisle and takes a seat. As he sits down, someone puts his ARM menacingly around Evan's throat. Evan flinches, turns around and sees Hunter, the frat guy Thumper assaulted the other night at Dirty Hank's bar.</context>
      <utterance>The answer's 'no', Mr. Treborn. Now take a seat. The exam's about to begin.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunter bursts out laughing.</context>
      <utterance>Leave me alone, asshole. I didn't lay a hand on you, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evan, you're hysterical. You study for this?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll find out soon enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hunter surreptitiously hands Evan a cheat-sheet to the exam. Evan's face brightens.</context>
      <utterance>Me neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding. Are these the answers?!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, Evan, on the D.L.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Wow. Hey, I want to do something really special for Kayleigh tomorrow. If I said I needed some help from you and the brothers...</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan nods and smiles as exams are passed down his row.</context>
      <utterance>I'd say blow me. Get the pledges to do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my God, that was good. Where'd you learn all those new tricks?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So it didn't feel... weird?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She giggles and snuggles into him. He's grateful for her affection, but still looks uneasy. The PHONE RINGS and he automatically answers it.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, if you call multiple orgasms weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence on the other end. More silence.</context>
      <utterance>Yellow.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Evan hangs up, he and Kayleigh share a giggle and he resumes snuggle position.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think it is about us that makes us so perfect? Like, looking back, whatever gave you the nerve to sneak out and visit me after I moved away?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan smiles to himself. And hugs her tighter.</context>
      <utterance>As if my dad could've stopped me from seeing you. What's he gonna do to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For the first time she looks at him with concern.</context>
      <utterance>You think we'll always be together?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's in heaven, but plays it cool.</context>
      <utterance>That is the plan, right? Hell or high water?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just making sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Order, order. So all you rushes know what you've got to do for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>THETA CHI PLEDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pledges, Sir Brother Evan, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A buzz of excitement runs through the pledges.</context>
      <utterance>Pledges, rushees, same difference. Now this is a one-time deal. You do all this for me and I'll never give you shit again. Promise.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand, where are you taking me?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know what to say. It's beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As she takes a step toward the table -- FLOWER PETALS shower down on her. She looks up to see TWO MORE PLEDGES standing on ladders, delicately tossing pedals. Kayleigh looks overwhelmed as she sits down.</context>
      <utterance>Go on. Sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you doing all this for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hand reaches out to his and grabs it fiercely. Her eyes tell him she feels the same way. A magical moment. And they lean into each other for a kiss so enchanted it might as well be their first ever -- Hunter bolts up the stairs, two at a time.</context>
      <utterance>Simple math. When I woke up this morning and saw your smile... I knew that I wanted to spend the rest of my life with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We been lookin' all over for you, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR BROTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moment's gone. Evan and Kayleigh exchange worried looks.</context>
      <utterance>Someone trashed your car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one will answer with anything more than a shrug.</context>
      <utterance>Did you see who did this? You see anyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Kayleigh knows better. She stares at the collar.</context>
      <utterance>Probably them Pika fuckers.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SENIOR BROTHER angrily calls him from the lawn.</context>
      <utterance>How could he get away with this? Right in front of the goddamn frat house!</utterance>
   <speaker>SENIOR BROTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh shudders and Evan puts his arms around her.</context>
      <utterance>Frat house? Hey man, would you call your "country" a "cunt"?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't. He's probably watching.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my fault. I should have told you he was released a few weeks ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Might'a been nice.  Like this is gonna do any good. Maybe one of the frat guys has a gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Evan. Don't even joke. He wouldn't hurt you. He's just trying to scare you away from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, right. Tell that to Crockett.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not his fault, Evan. You knew how bad he had it when we were kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't give me this Oprah-book club bad upbringing shit, because you turned out fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My father never laid a hand on me. It's like the prick saved it all up for Tommy. Evan sits in silence for a moment, contemplating this. Kayleigh's eyes plead for him to have compassion.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, then. We'll let campus security deal with him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just... you've been acting kinda strange, you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like how?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. You seem... different. You make weird jokes. Your accents changed. You don't even walk the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I walk differently?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't put my finger on it, but everything's a bit off. Even the dinner tonight. It was beautiful, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy along the path gags loudly into the bushes. Kayleigh and Evan instinctively avert their eyes. Suddenly, Kayleigh's ears perk and she stops walking mid-stride.</context>
      <utterance>I know I've been actin strange lately. It's just that... I don't want anything to happen to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. Something's not right. Isn't that your jacket?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy, wearing Evan's brown suede jacket, suddenly springs to his feet, revealing his face for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy has grown in the last seven years. He has long, greasy hair and some tattoos. He holds a TIRE THUMPER (a short, steel bat for truckers) menacingly in his right hand. Evan stands frozen in fear, his hands rooted in his coat pockets.</context>
      <utterance>Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leave us alone you sick fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get this "us" shit. As if I was gonna lay a hand on my own sister. You've done nicely for yourself, Evan. Nice friends, nice life, not to mention you're fucking my sister. Not a bad piece of ass if I say so myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up, Tommy!</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy takes a few practice swings with the tire thumper.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, hey now, that was a compliment.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It wasn't enough that the whole world loves you, but you had to take away the last person on earth who didn't think I was a piece of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one thinks you're a piece of shit, Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy rushes Evan and bashes him with the tire thumper in the shoulder and ribs. Evan goes down. As Tommy prepares to bash his brains in, Evan whips out the Pepper Spray and nails Tommy in the face. Tommy reels back in pain, covering his eyes with this free hand. Evan struggles to his feet and circles around Tommy, keeping a distance as he douses Tommy with Pepper Spray. Kayleigh screams. Tommy blindly stumbles around, madly swinging the tire thumper. Evan charges forward in an uncontrollable rage, rips the weapon out of Tommy's hands and sprays a lethal dose of pepper spray into Tommy's open mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Right, Evan. I believe you just said "sick fuck."</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evan, stop! You're gonna kill him!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan knocks Tommy down with the tire thumper. Kayleigh screams and tries to hold Evan back, but he easily wrestles free of her. She runs to a blue streetlight on the quad.</context>
      <utterance>He's a fucking maniac!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan kicks Tommy hard in the ribs. Kayleigh pushes a button on the "Blue Light" lamp post and an ALARM WAILS.</context>
      <utterance>He ruined Lenny's life --</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan raises the tire thumper for a final attack and swings down OFF CAMERA.</context>
      <utterance>He killed Crockett --  Murdered that woman and her baby!  And he's trying to kill me, Kayleigh! He's trying to fucking kill me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan nods glumly.</context>
      <utterance>First time?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best not bitch up. Wind up someone's luggage that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you protect me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BUZZER SOUNDS. Carlos leaves the cell without another word.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus himself couldn't make me take on the Brotherhood. When they come, just put your mind in another place, man. Be somewhere else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I spoke to your new lawyer about the appeal. He's sure he can get you off on self-defense, so if you're patient.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long will I be in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. These things take time.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea's look tells him to look for hope elsewhere.</context>
      <utterance>How's Kayleigh doing? She all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea nods, holding up two comp books. "AGE 7" and "AGE</context>
      <utterance>What about my journals, Mom? Did you bring the ones I asked for?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found these. The others are still in storage.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it, Mom. I told you I need them all!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan looks as if he's about to disagree with her, but he closes his mouth and placates her.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. You'll get them, Evan. But I think it's far more important to focus on your case right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And officer signals Evan and points to his watch.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, Mom. You're right. Just try to tell Kayleigh I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at each other and Evan slowly lowers the phone. He hangs up, Andrea still pressing her phone to her ear.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not gonna lose you, kiddo. Promise me you'll hang on, Ev.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan stands there, stunned, unable to react when -- Another Neo-Nazi, RICK, swats Evan's journals out of his hands and onto the floor. Life springs back into Evan as he rushes for the journals. He and Rick grab the journals at the same time. A minor tug of war.</context>
      <utterance>Shit on my dick or blood on my knife.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rick tears them away, Evan coming up with only a few torn pages. Evan sees the damage and goes mental.</context>
      <utterance>Let go! They're mine!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan swings at Rick and misses. INMATES CHEER! It's on! Rick lunges for Evan, a brief and painful scuffle ensues, the journals getting trampled. Suddenly -- The sounds of COCKED RIFLES echo through the air. The fight stops instantly as Rick and Evan look up to see --</context>
      <utterance>Motherfucker!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're religious Carlos, you believe that bit about "the Lord works in mysterious ways?"</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Straight up.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I think he sent me to your cell on purpose. For you to help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. I knew you were crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carlos scoffs whatever.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't bullshitting. Jesus speaks to me in my dreams.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carlos is suddenly interested.</context>
      <utterance>Pack of smokes says I can prove it to you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So when I'm out, I need you to watch my face and hands closely.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their conversation stops when a convict rolls a mail cart by, Evan looking up expectantly.</context>
      <utterance>You need to see the prison shrink, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything today?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONVICT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Disappointed, Evan turns back to Carlos. Holds up his journal entry.</context>
      <utterance>Yep. Just not for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell me if anything weird happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weirder than this?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan studies the page.</context>
      <utterance>Marks, scars, I dunno. Anything could happen I guess.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MRS. BOSWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan, defeated, looks over at his blank piece of paper. He smiles mischievously, and grabs some colored pencils.</context>
      <utterance>No monkey business, Evan. Sit still and finish your drawing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BOSWELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Soon enough, an image emerges: Evan holding a knife, stands over a heap of several dead inmates Karl and Rick. When done, he sneaks over to Mrs. Boswell's desk, where the two paper spindles sit. The metal needles reach up and skewer a number of paper notes and messages. Evan looks over to see Mrs. Boswell holding up his drawing, horrified.</context>
      <utterance>That's great everyone! Just imagine anything you want to be. There are no limits.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks over in time to see Evan using all of his seven- year old strength to WHIP his hands down toward the spindles! The moment before his palms reach them there's a brief instant where SOUNDSCAPES COLLIDE and the world behind him VIBRATES.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Mrs. Boswelllllllll?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan looks up to see Carlos staring at him with reverence.</context>
      <utterance>Oh sweet Jesus. It's true. It's a miracle! A miracle!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan looks to see two scars in the center of each palm.</context>
      <utterance>Your hands. The stigmata!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you see? What did it look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARLOS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Signs of the Lord. They just appeared out of nowhere. I thought you were loco!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carlos simply stares at him, awestruck, and hands over a box of cigarettes.</context>
      <utterance>So you believe me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue to stare.</context>
      <utterance>Look. I'm new to all this but I think I get how things work. You gotta join a gang or else end up dead meat.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karl and Rick exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>Well it sure ain't gonna fucking be with no niggers or spics. So how do we do this? You gotta work your way up, and I'm the new guy.  So... should I... I mean, do I suck your dicks right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is your blood pure?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rick stands. All muscle.</context>
      <utterance>I ain't no fucking kike if that's what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>RICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>the fucking teeth or you'll be leaving without 'em. Evan nods reluctantly and peacefully drops to his knees. Karl and Rick lower their pants to their ankles. Evan looks miserable, about to do the deed when -- CARLOS bulldozes past the Aryans into the room, slamming Karl into the wall and jamming a shank into Karl's crotch! Rick instantly charges Carlos, but trips on the pants around his ankles. Evan, anticipating Rick's fall, stomps Rick's face before snatching his journals from Karl's shelf. Evan frantically flips through them, hunting for something, as the other WHITE SUPREMACISTS charge the cell.</context>
      <utterance>Let's see what you got. And watch</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Carlos drops Karl's writhing body to the floor and presses his girth against the cell door. Evan locates an entry and concentrates on the words just as the other supremacists force the door open -- Evan focuses on the words. Chanting quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Carlos!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WORDS from the entry begin to SHIMMER. REVERBERANT SOUNDS OF BARKING break the sound barrier and the image of Aryans storming the cell behind him become a FRENETIC BLUR</context>
      <utterance>We took the woods behind the junkyard just to make sure we wouldn't bump into Tommy. We hadn't seen the smoke yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh and Lenny, walking by his side, do a double take. Evan shrugs "just kidding" and looks around, getting his bearings. He whips his hand out and stops them.</context>
      <utterance>Rot in hell you fucking animals.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He suddenly notices Kayleigh who now no longer looks an awkward and unkempt tomboy, but rather a vibrant and feminine young girl. Whereas her clothes were loose and unflattering before, she is now radiant and wears fashionable styles. Evan remembers his mission and darts over to a JUNK PILE.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. Before we --</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh and Lenny stare at him, concerned for his sanity. Evan roots through the trash until he finds something: a razor sharp piece of metal about two feet long. Evan offers it to Lenny.</context>
      <utterance>We need something to cut open the sack!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want you to take this, Lenny. Today's your day of atonement. I know how guilty you feel about that woman and her baby --</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evan. Stop it. It's not the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now's the only time!  Today you get a chance to redeem yourself. Start over with a clean slate. Tabula rasa --</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're acting crazy!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan places the metal shard in Lenny's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Please. If you've ever trusted me before, trust me on this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lenny slowly follows Evan as he bolts away.</context>
      <utterance>Cut the rope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen to me good, Evan...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan's words hit home and Tommy's anger slowly dissipates. A look of understanding passes between them. Gratitude, even. Tommy looks at the sack and begins to untie it. Lenny comes screaming from nowhere like a bat out of hell! With all of the force he can muster, he jams the metal shard all the way through Tommy's throat! Tommy clutches his throat, gagging in blood. Evan surveys the scene in shock:</context>
      <utterance>I'll do whatever you want. You don't want me to ever see Kayleigh again, fine. Just let Crockett go. Besides, you kill him now and they'll stick you in juvy for sure. And I know you'd never leave your sister alone with your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lenny drops to the floor, Indian style, wipes the dirt in his hands and freezes up completely. Kayleigh wakes up and SCREAMS when she sees blood spurt from Tommy's throat. Meanwhile, Crockett escapes from the sack.</context>
      <utterance>Oh fuck, Lenny, no!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, doc. What's the damage? How much time have I got?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cute, Evan.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a little complicated. I haven't seen results exactly like these before.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Redfield and Andrea exchange looks.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure? Not even with my father?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, these tests weren't available twenty years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Redfield points to the CAT-scan slides, specifically, to the outer lining of Evan's brain.</context>
      <utterance>So what did you find.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is where we're finding most of the hemorrhaging. The outer lining of the cerebral cortex.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Redfield stares ahead. Transfixed by the slides.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme guess. Would that be where the memories are stored?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea stares at him blankly. Evan impatiently "pops wheelies" in the wheel chair.</context>
      <utterance>I've never seen anything like this. I've compared these to the ones taken last year, and there's evidence of severe hemorrhaging and massive neural reconstruction.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean for Evan?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea nods. Evan shakes Dr. Redfield's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Mind if I wait in the car? The lighting here bugs my eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea shoots Dr. Redfield an apologetic look. Evan heads out the door, accidentally knocking Dr. Redfield's jacket to the floor. He shrugs apologetically and re-hangs it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it's nice seeing you again. But you know, people to see, things to read...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing from Lenny.</context>
      <utterance>Is there anything you need? Anything I can get you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still nothing. Not even a glance in his direction. Evan sighs and gives up.</context>
      <utterance>What about the models, man? Bet I can get you a shitload of models up in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan turns around to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Lenny. Just wanted to say "hi".</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew the whole time, didn't you?  When you put the blade in my hand, you knew something big was going to happen. Didn't you?!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lenny's eyes seethe with hate.</context>
      <utterance>Y... yes. I guess I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan backs away, face guilt-stricken.</context>
      <utterance>Then you should be where I am. You should be where I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay? You looked like you were somewhere else for a second there.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason is completely thrown.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Jason, I need some fast answers if I'm ever gonna fix what I've done.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was praying this curse would have ended with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it didn't. And now I need info to make things right again and you're the only one who can give it to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no "right". When you change who people are, you destroy who they were.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason seems extremely upset to hear Evan say this.</context>
      <utterance>Who's to say you can't make things better?</utterance>
   <speaker>JASON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't play God, son. It must end with me. Just by being here, you may be killing your mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jason launches himself across the table, shackles and all, and grabs hold of Evan's throat.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. I'll send you a postcard when I've made everything perfect again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just get out, didja?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Just that my brother did a stint in the pen and he used to eat like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I come from a big family.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meant no offense.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None taken. Hey, uh, does Kayleigh Miller still work here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Never heard of her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Miller opens the door and sees Evan.</context>
      <utterance>Just shut the hell up already! Can't a man get a little goddman peace in his own home!  Oh, for Christ's sake, now what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In a blur, Evan grabs Mr. Miller's shirt and violently shoves him through the house and into a wall.</context>
      <utterance>Don't suppose you're here to sell cookies?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Miller goes slack, his eyes wide with horror.</context>
      <utterance>Good guess, fuckbag.  Remember me now? We had a great chat once when I was seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One question, fuckbag. Where can I find your daughter?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I thought you were my eight o'clock. Make it fast, I'm expecting someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks around, waves him in.</context>
      <utterance>Nice to see you, too. Can I come in?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I knew you were coming I'd have cleaned the stains off the sheets.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan can't speak. His eyes begin to water.</context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His sincerity touches her.</context>
      <utterance>I just needed to see... a friendly face.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan reaches for his wallet and throws it on her dresser. Kayleigh eyes the wallet. But makes no move to pick it up.</context>
      <utterance>Well, time is money, Evan. So you...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears fall freely from Evan's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I guess I can spare ten minutes for an old friend, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So how's tricks? Sorry, occupational humor.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get it. You can drop it now.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm sorry. Does my line of work make you uncomfortable, precious?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Just that you need to hurt me with it. I've been where you've been.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha! Where's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh watches Evan silently.</context>
      <utterance>The bottom. When you're just a piece of meat waiting for the next attack.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happened to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't believe me. I mean, people always say, "You wouldn't believe me", but in this case, it's not even worth trying.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen some sickening shit. I don't blink twice anymore, especially in your case.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you're... different.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Different? How?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you a question. Just a little one that's been gnawing at me for years.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the bridge. How did you know that Tommy had your dog? That was no fucking hunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan continues and Kayleigh listens with a mixture of intense interest and matched skepticism.</context>
      <utterance>Do you remember when I was a kid and I had those blackouts?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right, Evan, I don't believe you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never thought you would. That's why I've never bothered to tell a soul until now, and why I never will again.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the only person you've told? That's a great line. Does that make other girls swoon? Do they actually eat up this bullshit?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I couldn't give a shit if you believe me or not, and frankly I'm too tired to prove it to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh? There's proof now?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit. I dunno. How would I know about the twin moles on your inner thigh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone with fifty bucks could tell you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh's jaw drops.</context>
      <utterance>Then forget that. How about... you prefer the smell of a skunk to flowers, you hate cilantro because for reasons unknown to you, it reminds you of your step-sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh tries to conceal the surprise in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! And when you orgasm, your toes go numb. I'm sure your clientele aren't privy to that one.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just thought you should know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh flinches as if her should had been invaded, then her eyes fill with distrust and contempt.</context>
      <utterance>That I didn't leave you there to rot.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's one major hole in your story.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She opens Evan's wallet and leaves a twenty on the table.</context>
      <utterance>There is no fuckin' way on this planet or any other that I was in some fuckin' sorority.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure you don't want your wallet?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't think I'll need it where I'm going.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Off to change everyone's life again, is that it? Maybe this time you'll pop up in some mansion while I wind up in Tijuana doing the donkey act.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm over it. Whenever I try to help anyone it all turns to shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets up and puts on her coat.</context>
      <utterance>Well, don't give up now, Slick. You've already done so much for me. Hell, why don't you go back in time and save Mrs. Halpern and her baby. Then maybe Lenny wouldn't freak out and ruin my family.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tosses his wallet over her shoulder at him and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, here's one! Go back when I'm seven and fuck me in front of Daddy's handicam, you know, straighten me out a bit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out. Both of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THUMPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan's temper flares and he picks up a chair and SMASHES it against a wall above Thumper's head.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, dude. Just figured it'd be okay with you bein' sick and all.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thumper and the co-ed quickly cover themselves in the blankets and leave. Alone in the room, Evan looks under his bed and breathes a sigh of relief to see all of his journals are intact. He sifts through them again. He finally finds the passage he needs. Something catches the corner of Evan's eyes and he turns to examine it. To the left of Thumper's Buddha statuette sits a large VOTIVE CANDLE that bears a portrait of Jesus Christ.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not saying it again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Halpern, startled, stares at the young kid skeptically as she absently continues toward the mailbox.</context>
      <utterance>Lady, stay back! Don't go near the mailbox!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lenny comes running across the street to Evan's aid, and Tommy shrugs and follows after him.</context>
      <utterance>I mean it, woman! Get the hell back!</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy, still running, cringes to hear Lenny's stupid confession and rolls his eyes at the situation. Evan positions himself between Mrs. Halpern and the mailbox, frantically waving his hand at her to stay back, because she's STILL</context>
      <utterance>There's a bomb in the mailbox. Get away!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan's face falls as he hears a familiar voice, but not Thumper's.</context>
      <utterance>I thought I told you two to beat it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan is confused by Lenny's presence, but smiles to himself and shakes his head "no".</context>
      <utterance>What? Hey, sorry, man. We wake you up?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan yawns, bringing his hand to his mouth, but there's no hand. No arm, really, either. Just two FLESHY STUMPS! Evan bolts upright in bed and stares down at his amputations.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's cool.  Really cool.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to get you to Sunnyvale. You're having one of your famous hemorrhages.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop! Take me back!</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan launches his body forward and spills clumsily out of the wheelchair. Lenny must halt in order not to crush Evan. As Evan writhes about on the floor, his legs paralyzed, a</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, tough guy, no can do. Your mother would kill me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh turns to face the jeering crowd.</context>
      <utterance>Take me back, Lenny!  You owe me that much.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd breaks up and leaves.</context>
      <utterance>What are you geeks looking at? Must be nice to be so goddamned perfect, huh? Fucking losers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lenny pushes Evan past Thumper and Cricket. Their conversation stops and they stare at their feet as Evan gets wheeled by. Evan boils to be treated as if he were non-existent.</context>
      <utterance>'Sup, Sheila! We missed you at the party! Don't even think I'm giving you my lab notes either! Think I like getting up for "eight thirty's"?</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan spins around in fear. He sees Tommy, clean-cut, and handing out flyers in front of a banner that reads "Campus Crusade for Christ." Tommy seems good-natured now, working hard and soliciting names for his list. He looks up as Evan rolls along and his eyes brighten to see Evan.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, there's Tommy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did what you said, man! We're pooling our student funds with Hillel House and we're going to have an Awareness Dance.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy frowns and exchanges glances with Lenny, who shrugs and nods back to him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh goody, nothing like spinning my chair around to a techno mix of Hava Nagila til I puke.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, we should be getting to class now.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another exchanged glance. Kayleigh looks at Evan.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it. What's the point of Psych now? Tomorrow I could wake up as some dirt farmer in Bangladesh.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan allows Kayleigh to roll him away from the others. To the very spot where Evan once killed Tommy. Evan stares at his prosthetic hand which he can "magically" will to open, close, open, close...</context>
      <utterance>Let's go for a stroll.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh looks at him curiously.</context>
      <utterance>So Tommy's really into this Jesus kick, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how spiritual he's gotten ever since he saved Mrs. Halpern and Katie.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh, now by a bench. Stops and sits. As she casually uses her foot to turn his chair to face her, she pulls out a granola bar and hands it to him. His prosthetic hand crushes it. It crumbles to dust. She seems more confused.</context>
      <utterance>He saved Mrs. Halpern? Please, the twisted fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is something the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I think I gotta get these fixed or something. She leans into him, gently feeding him her remaining bar.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kayleigh? Do you ever think about "us?" I mean, wonder if it could ever have been different between the two of us?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure, Evan, why not? You were the first person I really ever cared about.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why when I was little I never went to live with my mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When my folks split, they gave me and Tommy a choice who we wanted to live with. I couldn't stand my dad, but I knew if I moved to my mom's I'd never see you again.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never knew that. So then you still sometimes think of us... together?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's crossed my mind from time to time.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well a lot of things cross my mind. I've always been a fast thinker, Ev. I can play out the movie of our entire lives in under a second. Boom -- we fall in love -- get married -- two kids, your keen analytical insight matched to my generous nature -- kids grow old as do we, relatively stable relationships, matching burial plots, the whole bit. It took a lot longer to spit out than to imagine.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you think it might have worked out?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks into his eyes and shrugs almost apologetically. Tears streak down Evan's face as he speaks in a pleading tone.</context>
      <utterance>Why not? But that's not how things wound up. I'm with Lenny, Lenny's your friend. And there it ends.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh shakes her head sadly, then suddenly looks up. Evan turns to see Lenny waving her over. She puts her hand on Evan's shoulder, stands and goes to Lenny. Evan can't take his eyes off her.</context>
      <utterance>Would it make any difference if I told you that no one could possibly love anyone as much as I love you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy casually turns off the water, then pops open the DRAIN. The water level lowers to Evan's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>You forgot to put the toaster on the edge.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tommy feels Evan's anguish and plops his ass on the wet floor by the tub. He lays his head onto Evan's shoulder. Evan bristles at first, but finally gives in to his hatred, ultimately resting his own head against Tommy's. Taking the comfort offered.</context>
      <utterance>But you, Kayleigh and Lenny like toast. And that's really all that matters now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get you changed. Visiting hours are almost up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan eyes her MEDICAL CLIPBOARD as he's wheeled by.</context>
      <utterance>Looking. Good. Kiddo.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lung cancer?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea flinches to hear this. Evan stares at her, eyes wide.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Mrs. T. He's been out of sorts lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan suddenly seems sick with guilt.</context>
      <utterance>Right... You started chain smoking after I blew myself up.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There must be a way to fix this.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fix?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A flicker of recognition registers in her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I just need the entry about the blockbuster. Wait, shit, no arms. I never even got the chance to write it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Evan... different?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's just going through some tough times.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mom. Don't cry. I can change this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'll go check out the chapel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're. Acting. Like your father.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea is shocked.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, Mom. Just 'cause Dad was my age when he started going crazy doesn't mean that I'm nuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How. Did you. Know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She uses her left hand to pinch off the air to her oxygen tube and forces herself to speak in a sick, GRAVELY manner.</context>
      <utterance>You told me that on Parents' Weekend. Remember? Wait, that wasn't me. Or you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just. Like. Jason.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes a lever and the mechanical wheelchair rolls itself out of the room. Andrea forces her loudest raspy scream.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I'm gonna get you out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop him. Stop him. Stop him...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure you even packed it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan watches Lenny eagerly as he dumps tons of Evan's junk on the floor. Old report cards, books, toys and photo albums fall on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>My mom packed for me. I think she sent everything I ever owned. So we'll see.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan beams when he sees Lenny holding his old journal. AGE</context>
      <utterance>Is this it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you need it for? I don't get you lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duly noted. Now I'm gonna ask you for one last favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhh. I need to concentrate on the blockbuster if I'm gonna destroy it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Destroy it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lenny, utterly baffled, sits back in silence and watches Evan begin reading his journal to himself for a beat.</context>
      <utterance>If I hadn't blown my arms off, Mom never woulda started smoking in the first place. Now shhhh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rummages through the utensil drawer and pulls out a large butcher knife and grabs it. He tucks it into his sock but it won't fit. He's still debating what to do when: ANDREA WALKS IN and is startled by the unexpected sight of Evan holding a huge knife. Evan sees her but remains expressionless. Andrea's face blanches.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Now how do I destroy the blockbuster?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evan? What are you doing with that knife?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh giggles. There seems to be a new glint of intelligence in Evan's eyes as he adjusts to his new surroundings.</context>
      <utterance>Now in this part of the story, Robin Hood just married Maid Marian and they have to kiss and stuff like grown-ups do.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Miller is puzzled, but watches Evan SKIP to the fireplace.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! I need my belt!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to crack it with his own hands, but his seven-year old body is too weak.</context>
      <utterance>Loo, loo, skip to my loo.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Miller finally turns around and sees Evan banging the blockbuster on the table. Shock registers in Mr. Miller's eyes and he takes a step towards Evan.</context>
      <utterance>Hey kid, don't bother with the belt.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Miller freezes on that, and Evan smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>Back off, fuckbag!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Miller takes a slow, non-threatening step toward Evan.</context>
      <utterance>Amazing. That word never fails to make an impression with you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy does it, Evan! Don't be a bad boy or I'll tell mommy you were naughty.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh's mouth hangs open with utter amazement at the scene. Tommy, hiding at the top of the stairs, slowly creeps down to get a better view. Evan rummages in the bureau and finds the wooden "strike anywhere" matches used at thirteen to light his cigarettes.</context>
      <utterance>And I'll tell the Child Protective Services about your kiddie porn endeavors. One step closer and I'll shove this up your ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's dangerous! You could blow your hands off!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan, standing near the fireplace, defiantly strikes the match with this thumb and lowers the flame to the short fuse. Mr. Miller charges Evan just as the fuse is lit! Mr. Miller knocks the blockbuster from Evan's hand and it rolls towards the other side of the room, resting peacefully against the video camera. Kayleigh's eyes are dazzled by the sparkling fuse and she bends down to pick it up --</context>
      <utterance>Been there, done that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. MILLER/TOMMY/EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kayleigh! NOOOOOooooo!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Evan. What's the big rush? We don't meet for another hour.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are my goddamn books?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Books?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doctor looks heartbroken, as if Evan has had a relapse.</context>
      <utterance>My journals! Where are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan looks stunned. Refusing to believe it.</context>
      <utterance>It kills me to have to go through this again. There are no journals. There never were. It's part of this fantasy world your mind created to cope with the guilt of killing...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think Evan. You've invented a disease that doesn't exist. Alternate universes with colleges, prisons, paraplegia...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I... I need those books.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remind me of your father. He always screamed for a photo album even though he never had one.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan's eyes roll back and he collapses lifelessly to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Photos?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DR. REDFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea, biting her nails, is unable to conceal her fear.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No dances, just tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Andrea wipes tears away, nodding in advance.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Mom, didja remember to bring those goofy old home movies we used to make?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, the world flutters as if it were attached to a paint- shaker. He takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>If anyone finds this, then I guess my plan didn't work and I'm already dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fatigue overwhelms him, but he continues writing...</context>
      <utterance>But I -- I can just go back to the beginning of all this, I might be able to save her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan slowly approaches Kayleigh, only five. She smiles bashfully at him. An old memory comes back to him.</context>
      <utterance>Go on, Evan. Introduce yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Evan slowly looks around the yard, taking in the reality of this distant memory. He even inhales the aroma of the place. Savoring the moment. He locks eyes with Kayleigh.</context>
      <utterance>When my folks split, they gave me and Tommy a choice who we wanted to live with. I couldn't stand my dad, but I knew if I lived with my mom, I'd never see you again...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDREA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>It's time. Evan leans over to Kayleigh as if he's about to kiss her. Then whispers in her ear:</context>
      <utterance>He's not usually this shy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kayleigh reacts predictably. Bursting into tears and runs into Kayleigh's mother's arms.</context>
      <utterance>I hate you. If you ever come near me again, I'll kill you and your whole family.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAYLEIGH'S MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan ignores them. He can't take his eyes off Kayleigh.</context>
      <utterance>What did you say to her? What happened?!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes well up.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Evan groans and shakes his head "no". He rides out the pain like a seasoned pro. When it finally subsides, he lowers the pillow and smiles feebly.</context>
      <utterance>You alright? Should I call the doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lenny nods, still concerned.</context>
      <utterance>I'll think I'll be alright this time.  I really do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LENNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evan nods. They silently dump tons of journals into the fire. Evan steps outside and returns with a box of home movies, photo albums, old report cards, etc. In they go.</context>
      <utterance>You sure about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Burning journals.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
