<movie id="526" title="Sting The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PHONE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Granger glances up and exchanges a token nod with Mottola, who plops down in a folding chair next to the radio. The phone rings.</context>
      <utterance>Beat it, Mottola.</utterance>
   <speaker>PHONE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Granger is a little apprehensive about talking to Chicago, but takes the phone anyway.</context>
      <utterance>8720...Yes, hold on a second.  Mr. Granger, Chicago on the line.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>COMBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Granger, this is Combs. Why haven't we heard from ya? Everybody else is in.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had a few problems with the Law this morning. The Mayor promised the Jaycees to get tough on the rackets again, so he shut everybody down for a couple hours to make it look good. Nothing serious, it just put us a little behind for the day.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You been making your payoffs, haven't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's nothing to worry about.</context>
      <utterance>Hell yes. He does this every year.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, finish your count and get it up here as soon as you can. I don't wanta be here all night.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe me, the Man's gonna be real happy. Looks like we cleared over ten grand this week.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We cleared 22 here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, hell, you got the whole Chicago south side. How do ya expect the eight lousy spots I've got to compete with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>COMBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They did 14 grand in Evanston, 16.5 is Gary, and 20 in Cicero. Looks like you're bringing up the rear, Granger.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just got the count. We'll put the take on the 4:15.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Combs hangs up, smiling to himself, proud of the way he gave the needle to Granger.</context>
      <utterance>We'll be waitin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mottola hustles out of his chair.</context>
      <utterance>Mottola.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mottola takes the money and slips it into his inside coat pocket with all the dramatic flair of the true flunky. No one would ever guess that he was just an overdressed messenger boy.</context>
      <utterance>Take this up to the city on the 4:15. They'll be waitin' for it at the clearing house. And don't stop for no drinks. You can get a cab down the street.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's got all the money.</context>
      <utterance>The wallet. You gotta go after him.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stranger opens the Black Man's coat to reveal a bloody wound at the top of his leg.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, we got the wallet. What happened? He get ya with the knife?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give it to me! Please. I gotta know it's all there!</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just sit tight, old man. We're gonna have to get you to a doctor.  I'll call a cop.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mottola has given him his wallet, which the black man now opens, disclosing a fat bundle of bills tied by a rubber band. Mottola and the stranger are amazed by the amount of money.</context>
      <utterance>No, no cops!</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanted by the law or somethin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, it's okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're crazy carryin' that kinda money in this neighborhood. No wonder you got hit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. I'm obliged to ya, but I gotta get goin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't goin' nowhere on that leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta! Look, I run some slots down in West Bend for a mob here. I got a little behind on my payoffs so they figure I been holdin' out on 'em. They gave me to 4:00 to come up with the cash. I don't get it there I'm dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It don't look good, gramps, it's ten of now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a hundred bucks for you and your friend if you deliver the money for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. That little mug that got ya is mad enough at me already -- what if he's out there waitin' around a corner with some friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>C'mon, you gotta help me out.</context>
      <utterance>He won't know you're carryin' it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, pal. I'll fix you up, call you a doc, but I ain't gonna walk into a bunch of knives for ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How bout you? I'll give you the whole hundred!</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you think you can trust him? He didn't do shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTTOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, butt out, chicken liver. I gave him back his wallet, didn't I?  How far is this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1811 Mason. Put it in Box 3C. You won't have no trouble. There's five thousand dollars there and here's a hundred for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTTOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mottola puts the bills in his inside coat pocket, right next to the numbers money. The stranger, who has now finished bandaging, watches him do it.</context>
      <utterance>All right. I'll make your drop for you, old man. And don't worry, you can trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that punk and his pals decide to search ya, you'll never fool 'em carryin' it there.</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a bag or somethin?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout a handkerchief?</utterance>
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stranger goes into the right coat pocket and pulls out a wrinkled handkerchief.</context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mottola takes out the Black Man's five grand and hands it to the Stranger. He puts it in the handkerchief.</context>
      <utterance>Let me have the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You better stick that other in here too, if you wanta keep it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mottola pulls out the numbers money and puts it in the handkerchief too. The stranger ties it all up.</context>
      <utterance>Just hurry, will ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Carry it down in your pants here.  Ain't no hard guy in the world gonna frisk ya there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTTOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(to the black man) So long, partner. Don't worry, everything's gonna be all right. The Black Man nods gratefully, but there's still a trace of worry on his face. Mottola trots off down the alley and out onto the street, glancing around cautiously for signs of trouble. He walks hurriedly down the sidewalk toward the cab stand in the distance. Suddenly the little man with the knife appears out of a doorway about 15 yards behind him. Mottola notices him and quickens his pace, finally breaking into a dead run. We follow him as he dashes headlong down the street, opening a big lead on the guy with the knife. He reaches the taxi zone. He hops in a cab and slams the door.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where to?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTTOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way is Mason?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About 20 blocks south.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTTOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, go north. The Joliet Station -- Fast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CABBIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTTOLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the bundle out from inside his pants in order to gaze upon his new-found fortune. He unties the handkerchief. It's full of toilet paper. Mottola looks like he's just been shot.</context>
      <utterance>I just made the world's easiest five grand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLACK MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, what a bundle. Did you know he was that loaded?</utterance>
   <speaker>STRANGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they split off, music begins, and we go into a</context>
      <utterance>Hell no, I just cut into him. I woulda settled for pawning one of them shoes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CRYSTAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, Hooker, you gettin' married or somethin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come into a little dough. You wanna get outa here tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRYSTAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't. I got a 10 o'clock show. I need the five bucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crystal looks at him a second and starts to giggle. We're pretty sure she's gonna get outa here tonight.</context>
      <utterance>I'll spend fifty on ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hooker!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How ya doin', Jimmy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thought maybe you took a fall.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't seen you in months, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, just a little hard times, that's all. It's all over now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Jimmy finishes his spiel, he starts the wheel spinning and drops in the ball. Betting is allowed to continue until the ball drops from the outer ring into the center.</context>
      <utterance>You gonna have a go here?  How 'bout a ten spot on the line here. The 4-9 been lookin' good today. Lotsa action on 28th Street down there, too. Pay ya 10-1.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy is stunned. The others at the table, used to dollar bets, look at Hooker like he's some kind of foreign dignitary.</context>
      <utterance>Three grand on the black.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you wanna start off that big? Bet like that could put a real dent in us.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel lucky tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, come on, Hooker, why don't you just...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy wants to argue some more, but the ball is getting ready to drop into the center. We see Jimmy quickly press a hidden lever under the table with his foot. The ball falls and settles into red 27 with a motion that is not quite right. The others at the table fail to notice, but Hooker is not fooled. He stares venomously at Jimmy, who knows that Hooker is on to him.</context>
      <utterance>Three grand on the black, Jimmy.</utterance>
   <speaker>JIMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy reaches for Hooker's money. Hooker stops him by putting his hand on it.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Hooker.  Good thing that ball came up red. Guy could get in trouble around here, losin' a bet that big.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy doesn't know what the hell to do. He gives Hooker a little head motion to indicate a small window high up in one of the walls. Behind it, we see a pair of eyes. Suddenly, Hooker understands why Jimmy had to cheat him, but it doesn't change his demand.</context>
      <utterance>Spin it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jimmy is beside himself. If he doesn't spin again, Hooker may expose him. If he does spin, and loses, his management will fire him. He pleads to Hooker with his eyes, but it's no use. Jimmy spins the wheel and reluctantly drops in the ball. This time there is no foot on the lever, and it settles into black 15. Hooker stares at the ball a second and then looks up at his terrified friend.</context>
      <utterance>Spin it anyway, Jimmy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker pushes the money over to Jimmy and walks out of the room. He's lost $3,000, but he's still working on a lucky night.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, pal. I knew it was my night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CRYSTAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks off down the street.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the evening, Hooker. I can still make the 10 o'clock. If you wanna spend 50 bucks on me again, mail it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey wait a minute.  Aw, the hell with ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GREER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They found Mottola. He was drunk in a dive in Joliet. Never got on the train.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't wanta hear about his day, Greer. What happened to the money?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He lost it to a coupla con artists on his way outa the spot.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>GREER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Combs sits in quiet thought for a second. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>Twelve thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Better get on the phone to New York. See what the big mick wants to do about it.  I gotta pretty good idea, though.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doyle, can I see you a minute?</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm busy, Floyd.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's important. We had a little trouble in Chicago today. One of our runners got hit for 12 grand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mottola.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure he didn't just pocket it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, we checked his story with a tipster. He was cleaned by two grifters on 47th.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They workin' for anybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Could be. We're runnin' that down now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, mark Mottola up a little and put him on a bus. Nothin' fancy, just enough to keep him from coming back. Get some local people to take care of the other two.  We gotta discourage this kinda thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="37">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Howdy, Louise.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn that down, Leroy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Johnny, Luther said you was somethin' to see today.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll never be as good as that mark, Alva.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leroy goes to get his jacket. Louise is finished putting the baby to bed.</context>
      <utterance>Well, we gonna hear all about it when we get back from church. Leroy, get your jacket on, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You goin' to church now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luther nods that he will. Alva, Leroy and Louise leave for church as Hooker strolls over and tosses two packets on the table. Luther doesn't pick his up, but the other man does. We now see that he is the thief in the opening sequence. He is called the Eirie kid and he is delighted at his share.</context>
      <utterance>They been havin' late bingo down there. I'm gonna call on the Lord for a little cash, while he's still payin' off. Luther, you look in on that child from time to time, will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Luther told me he was carrying a wad, but I didn't figure this much.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way did he do, Eirie?</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Straight north. He was gonna take it all and run.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're late. Where you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had some appointments.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much did ya lose?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You coulda been nailed.</context>
      <utterance>In one goddamn night? What are ya sprayin' money around like that for?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I checked the place out. There weren't no dicks in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a con man, and you blew it like a pimp. I didn't teach ya to be no pimp.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's eatin' you? I've blown money before.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No class grifter woulda' done it, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think my play is bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker sinks back, embarrassed that he misread Coleman's intentions.</context>
      <utterance>I think it's the best...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...It's the only reason I ain't quit before now.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gettin' too slow for this racket. I done the best I'm gonna do. You hang on too long, you start embarrassin' yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talkin' about? We just took off the biggest score we've ever had. We can do anything we want now.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's nothin' compared to what you could be makin' on the Big Con. You're wastin' your time workin' street marks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey look. You think I'm gonna run out on ya or somethin'? Just cause we hit it big. Luther, I owe you everything. If you hadn't taught me con, I wouldn't know nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw hell, you sound like some goddamn sucker. You know everything I know. You got nothin' more to learn from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you played the Big Con. You said it was nothin'. A game for flakes and mama's boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker knows it's no use.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm tellin' ya now, you're a fool if you don't get into it. A bigger fool than I was.  I been lookin' for this one all my life, Johnny. Now I got a chance to step out at the top.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell you gonna do with yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker just nods.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, I got a brother down in K.C., runs a freight outlet. I can go halfsies with 'em! It ain't too exciting, but it's mostly legal.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Straighten up, kid. I wouldn't turn ya out if ya weren't ready.  I got a guy named Henry Gondorff I want you to look up. There ain't a better insideman alive. He'll teach ya everything ya gotta know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll take a cut of what I make, won't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm out, Johnny.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's the way you want it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the way I want it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>After three years.</context>
      <utterance>How do you like that Coleman, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw come on, it was the only thing to do. He knew he was holdin' ya back.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were partners. If it weren't for Luther I'd still be hustlin' pinball down at Gianelli's. I don't need anything more than I got.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a depression on ya know.</context>
      <utterance>You ain't gonna have nothin' if you don't lay off them games of chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's always a depression on.</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you saved a little, you wouldn't have to grift so much.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like griftin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clothes, or a nice car...</context>
      <utterance>You could buy yourself some things.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What else ya got to sell, Eirie?</context>
      <utterance>I don't look any good in clothes and I don't know how to drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk on a few more feet, when suddenly a police car pulls up alongside them and two men jump out. The first, a uniformed policeman, grabs Eirie around the neck. Hooker makes a break for it, but the second Figure, a burly detective named Snyder, tackles him in the middle of the street, drags him back into the alley and plasters him up against a brick wall. The two have met before.</context>
      <utterance>Forget it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi there, Snyder. Things a little slow down at the Bunco Department tonight, eh? Somebody lose the dominoes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You scored blood money today, Hooker. You need a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snyder gives Hooker a swift knee in the thigh and follows it with an elbow across the head. Hooker flies into a row of boxes and garbage cans.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, find yourself a shoplifter to roll.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell ya what you did, smart boy. You tied into a loaded mark on 47th across from Maxies. You and Coleman played the switch for him and blew him off to a cab on 49th. If he hadn't been a numbers runner for Doyle Lonnegan, it woulda been perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're crazy. I'm not stupid enough to play for rackets money.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He'll swat you like any fly.</context>
      <utterance>Not intentionally maybe, but that don't make no difference to Lonnegan.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll square it with the fixer.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snyder lets go. Hooker sinks back against the wall. He says nothing; he's waiting for the price.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody can buy you a prayer, if I put the finger on ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figure your end of the score was at least 3 gees. I want 2 no matter what it was.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My end was only one.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker is beat and he knows it.</context>
      <utterance>Then you'll have to come up with another grand somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches into his coat, pulls out a stack of bills and counts out $2000 to Snyder. Eirie looks on in amazement; he didn't think Hooker had it.</context>
      <utterance>All right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snyder and his policeman friend get in their car and start down the street. Hooker and Eirie walk nonchalantly in the other direction.</context>
      <utterance>You're a smart egg, Hooker. No use dyin' for 2 grand.</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you blew all your money.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snyder and his partner disappear around a corner. Hooker suddenly takes off like a shot.</context>
      <utterance>I did. That stuff I gave him was counterfeit. They'll pinch him the first place he tries to spend it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell you gonna do when Snyder rushes his finger right to Lonnegan? You're committin' suicide, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw Christ, it doesn't make no difference now. If Snyder knows about it so does everybody else. He never gets anything first...Damn, there's no answer at Luther's.</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker, still getting no answer, slams the phone down and blasts out of the booth.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, Hooker. What ever you do, don't go back to your place tonight, don't go anyplace you usually go, ya hear me? Get outa town or somethin', but...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'd like to ask you a few questions.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, sir. Treasury Dept...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for? I haven't done anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't doubt that, but there's a counterfeiting operation passing bad money in the station. Have you made any purchases here today?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, a ticket to Chicago.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I'm afraid we'll have to impound your money until we're sure that it's all good. Can I see your wallet and your ticket, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I got a train to make.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll only take 20 minutes or so. You can pick it up at the window down the hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about all these other people?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Businessman is totally shamed.</context>
      <utterance>We'll get 'em! Give us a chance. I'm not the only agent in here, ya know. We go around advertising ourselves, how many counterfeiters do you think we'd catch, huh?  You think I'm wearin' this rag here 'cause I like it? Christ, everybody thinks life's a holiday or somethin' when you got a badge.  I been here since three this morning, Charlie, and I never knew there was so much ugliness in people. You try to help 'em and they spit on you. I shoulda let ya go and gotten yourself arrested for passin' false notes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, really I am, but my train leaves in ten minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, I'll give ya a break.  Down that hall there, there's an unmarked door on the left. Go on in there and wait at the window. I'll take this...  ...in the back and run it through right away. We'll have you outta there in a couple minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. You don't know how much I appreciate this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man goes off down the hall, more than grateful to be given a break like this. Hooker heads for the "back". We follow the Man down the hall to the unmarked door. He strides on through to find himself face to face with a wall of busily flushing urinals.</context>
      <utterance>Think nothin' of it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, I'm looking for a guy named Henry Gondorff. You know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billie stops and comes back down the stairs. It's the first time she's stopped chewing.</context>
      <utterance>Luther Coleman sent me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You Hooker?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes to a side door and unlocks it.</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you say so. I thought maybe you was a copper or somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker's not quite sure what that means, but there's something about Billie that makes him know that you don't ask.</context>
      <utterance>It's the room in the back. He wasn't expecting you so soon though.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn the goddamn thing off, will ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sober?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker makes no move to get up. Gondorff struggles to his knees, turns off the water, and slumps back against the wall. The two men just look past each other a second. Down in the bottom.</context>
      <utterance>I can talk, can't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad to meet ya, kid. You're a real horse's ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff wipes his face with his hand. His mood softens a little.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, Luther said you could teach me something. I already know how to drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry about Luther. He was the best street worker I ever saw.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What happened?</context>
      <utterance>He had you down as a big-timer.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw, I conned a Senator from Florida on a stocks deal. A real lop-ear. He thought he was gonna take over General Electric. Some Chantoozie woke him up, though, and he put the feds on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean you blew it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Luther didn't tell me you had a big mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He didn't tell me you was a fuck- up, either.  You played the Big Con since then.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker's disappointment is obvious.</context>
      <utterance>No, I lammed it around for a while while things cooled off. Philly, Denver, Baltimore, nuthin' towns.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker nods, unconvinced.</context>
      <utterance>But don't kid yourself, friend, I still know how.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna stay for breakfast, or do you already know how to eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I picked something up on the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lonnegan after you, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Haven't seen anybody.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We go to Hooker. He hadn't thought of that.</context>
      <utterance>You never do, kid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The nigger.</context>
      <utterance>We got word from Chicago. They got one of the grifters last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the other one?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're still looking for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's got the contract?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Combs gave it to Reilly and Cole.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hackers.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan regards Floyd patiently and then pats the bench beside him. Floyd sits gingerly.</context>
      <utterance>They staked out the other guy's place last night, but he never showed. They figure maybe he skipped town. You wanna follow 'em up?</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We cut to one of Lonnegan's foursome, a short, squat little Irishman in a red sweater. He was a good-time, friendly manner and a winning Irish smile. We like him immediately.</context>
      <utterance>You see the guy in the red sweater over there?</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name's Danny McCoy. No Neck McCoy we called him. Runs a few protection rackets for Carnello while he's waiting for something bigger to come along. Me and Danny been friends since we were six. Take a good look at that face, Floyd, cause if he ever finds out we let one lousy grifter beat us, you'll have to kill him and every other hood in Chicago who'd like to do the same thing. You understand what I'm sayin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan is called to the tee by one of his foursome. He exchanges a friendly smile with McCoy and belts the ball down the fairway.</context>
      <utterance>Good lad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feeling all right this morning, Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, Billie.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff waves okay.</context>
      <utterance>You mind opening the round a little early today? We got some business coming in before hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great little countess, that Billie. Runs a good house up there, too. One of the few left that Luciano doesn't own. Gondorff walks around on the carousel, checking straps, bearing and poles. Hooker follows him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gondorff, you gonna teach me the Big Con or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't act much like you wanted to learn it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna play for Lonnegan.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know anything about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff just sits tight and waits for him to cool off.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, he croaked Luther. What else do I gotta know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aw right, he runs the numbers outta the south side.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And a packing company, a chain of Savings and Loans and half the politicians in Chicago and New York. There ain't a fix in the world gonna cool him out if he blows on ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take him anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't do it alone, ya know. It takes a mob of guys like you and enough money to make 'em look good.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll get by without 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't like playin' winos on the street. You gotta do more than outrun the guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never played for winos.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta keep Lonnegan's con, even after you spent his money. And no matter how much you take from his, he'll get more.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sacred of 'em, aren't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right down to my socks, turkey. If I'da been half as scared a that lop-ear, I wouldn't a fallen asleep on 'em. Lonnegan might kill me, but at least he won't bore me to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you'll do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker nods. Gondorff switches on the carousel and steps back to admire his handiwork. The carousel makes a grinding sound, does a few lurches and stops cold.</context>
      <utterance>If I can find a mob that'll risk it. But no matter what happens, I don't want you comin' back to me halfway through and sayin' it's not enough... cause it's all you got.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are Combs' favorite torpedoes. Riley and Cole. We recognize Riley and Cole as the two guys who got into Mottola's cab.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We go to Hooker. He's real grateful. Billie, wearing an evening dress, enters the room and begins gathering up the empty beer mugs on the table.</context>
      <utterance>They do most of the small jobs, but Lonnegan might not wanna use 'em on you 'cause they're kinda messy. No class.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got reason to believe Riley was the guy who hit Luther. But if you see either one of these two, find yourself a crowd, or take 'em someplace you know you can handle 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker nods, but we know he hasn't really got that.</context>
      <utterance>But most of all let us know. If they got a hit on you, we gotta fold up the con. You're too exposed. You got that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure it'll be one of these two?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billie has finished gathering the mugs, and leaves the room with them. We follow her down the hall and into the:</context>
      <utterance>No. They're just the only ones we know of.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You the owner here?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant Snyder. Bunco.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Joliet badge, Snyder. Don't cut much up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm lookin' for a guy on the lam from a counterfeiting rap. Thought he mighta come in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't think so. I know everybody in the place and I always bounce the lamsters.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right if I look around your lobby?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billie grabs a bottle of beer, pours some in a shot glass and pushes it over to Snyder. He ignores the gesture.</context>
      <utterance>No, but you're welcome to a free beer before you go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We go to Billie. She knew that when he came in.</context>
      <utterance>I don't really need your permission.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lonnegan's a fast egg, Henry. He's not gonna sit still for a standard play.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody'll sit still for somethin'. What did ya find out about the train, Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's been taking the 8:10 Century Limited outa New York on Friday and getting in here early Saturday morning. He usually stays a day to check on his policy operations, and then flies back.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wonder why he doesn't fly both ways.</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The porters say he runs a braced card game in one of the cars. $100 minimum, straight poker. Last time he pulled in here ten grand heavier than he left New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fancies himself a gambler, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lotta plungers ride that train just to play him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See J.J., he's slowly down already.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way are the rooms?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told ya this guy was in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody. I just know what kinda women he likes. I'm gonna check all the joyhouses till I find him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I could help ya if ya told me his name.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Which way are the rooms?</context>
      <utterance>I think I'll keep that to myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(picks up the tray)</context>
      <utterance>Right through there. But I wouldn't go in there if I were you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are ya gonna do, call the cops?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to. You'll be bustin' in on the Chief of Police just up the hall.  Snyder is stopped cold. He calls after her.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep your nose clean, lady. He can't spend all his time here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we ought to play him on the Rag. It's the tightest game we got, and it's not all over the papers yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No good, J.J. You're not gonna con stocks to a banker. Lonnegan's too smart for that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do, con the payoff to a gambler?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff has nodded to Billie and now rejoins the conversation. She serves the others beer.</context>
      <utterance>Twist is right. It won't work.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll use the wire. Never known a gambler who wouldn't like to beat the ponies.</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The wire is ten years outa date.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why he won't know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure I know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll give him the hook on the train, and play him here. You think I can get in that poker game, Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All you gotta do is show up with some money and look like a fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Hooker. There is a challenge in their book. Gondorff smiles broadly, then casually, to them all.</context>
      <utterance>I also gotta win.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We go around the table. No reply.</context>
      <utterance>By the way, any of you guys been passing off any green goods lately?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Billie, if that Dick comes in again, stall him till I can get a look at him. And let me pay ya for these beers.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about? It's on the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hitches up Billie's skirt, and puts the bill in her garter.</context>
      <utterance>Naw, I want ya to have this.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billie smiles and leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>Don't look at it till ya go to bed though or it'll turn to paper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks all right. It's big enough and off the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. This is kinda short notice. I'm not sure we can get it all done by Saturday.</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Garfield thinks it over a little. He's taking another look at the place. We go to Twist and the old man by the door.</context>
      <utterance>Got to. Gondorff's ridin' the mark in from New York on the Century.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll take it.  You manage the building at the end of the alley?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For fifteen years.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll need a room over there that faces this way. How much a week?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only rents by the month. Two hundred and fifty for the two of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the last time I expect to see you down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We go back to Niles and Garfield.</context>
      <utterance>Never heard of the place.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been a while since I stocked a wire store. Not many mobs playing that anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All we need is the bookie setup for now. We'll worry about the telegraph office later.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, I'll rent ya everything I got in the warehouse for two grand. That'll give ya phones, cages, blackboards and ticker gear. You supply the guys to move 'em. If you want a counter and bar, that's another grand. I don't know where the hell I'm gonna get 'em though.</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We ain't no heel grifters.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, you can do better than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want the stuff tomorrow or don't ya? It's gonna take hours just to clean it up.  Besides, Gondorff's still a hot item. Where am I gonna be if he gets hit?</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Twist has rejoined them by now.</context>
      <utterance>Just give us what ya can, Benny. We'll send a truck down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanna work flat rate or percentage?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the mark?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doyle Lonnegan.</utterance>
   <speaker>GARFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flat rate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker looks and finally spots him in the crowd. We go back to Lonnegan, as he moves off from the cigar counter, toward his train. Hooker watches him with the intensity of one gazing on a religious object.</context>
      <utterance>Guy in the blue pinstripe and grey fedora.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not as tough as he'd like to think.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither are we.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear there's a friendly poker game on this train tonight. You know anything about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you could get me in that game?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff flashes a $50 bill.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. There's usually a waiting list.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff pulls out another fifty.</context>
      <utterance>That'll get you first alternate, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How ya doin', Lacey.</utterance>
   <speaker>LACEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good to see ya again, Twist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOUDREAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twist! When did you get back in town?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men sit down together, apart from the others.</context>
      <utterance>Coupla days ago. I'm workin' a big one with Gondorff on the North Side.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen Duke, we're setting up a wire store. I need a twenty man boost right away.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOUDREAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Take your pick.</context>
      <utterance>I got twenty or so in here tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These guys have gotta be the quill, Duky. We can't afford to rank the joint.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOUDREAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me the sheet, Jake. Let's see who's in town.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BOUDREAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twist, you know this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snyder walks all the way to the back, and then retraces his route. About halfway back, he stops at one of the tables, recognizing a grifter he knows. It's the Eirie Kid.</context>
      <utterance>No. Never saw him before. He's a dick, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Snyder. What are you doin' up here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on vacation. You seen your friend lately?</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snyder, in no mood for jokes, grabs Eirie by the hair and slams his face into the table. Eirie just stays there; he knows it doesn't pay to assault a detective. Twist is watching all this intently from the viewing port.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, he packed it in and enrolled in detective school.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eirie raises his head slowly, but says nothing. There is a slight trickle of blood from his nose. Snyder turns and walks slowly out of the bar. When he is a safe distance down the street, the chatter and drinking resume.</context>
      <utterance>You see him, you tell him to pay his debts before I get him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BOUDREAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paltrow, Sterling, Furey, and the Big Alabama are in from New Orleans. Fiskin and the Boone Kid from Denver, and Phillips, Barnett and Limehouse Chappie from New York. Those and the guys outside should give ya 30 or so to choose from.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, have 'em down at Stenner's old Pool Hall before 3:00. We're gonna run through the route tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOUDREAU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Twist, but you know if this blows up, I can't do ya no good downtown. Gondorff is Federal.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it, pal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You in?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, I think so. I gave the kay- ducer a C-note. You find out the deck?</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He usually plays with a Royal or a Cadenza.  I got you one of each. He likes to cold deck low, 8's or 9's.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Singleton slips out as Gondorff unpeels the packs.</context>
      <utterance>Nice work, J.J.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff nods, takes the money out, counts it.</context>
      <utterance>She got him clean. He hasn't missed it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes out his own wallet and puts the money in it, and tosses the empty wallet back to Hooker, and resumes his shuffling and dealing. Hooker sits back silently and watches him.</context>
      <utterance>Fifteen grand. Looks like he's expecting a big night.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's waitin' for you in the card room.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he deals, on the second pass he attempts to cut from the bottom, muffs it completely and sprays half the deck on the table. Hooker regards him steadily as he gathers them back up. Gondorff finally meets his gaze.</context>
      <utterance>Let him wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just worry about your end, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we ever get to it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell is this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. He said he'd be here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THE POKER ROOM AGAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody's itchy now.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Conductor hands him a sealed deck. As he begins to open it, Gordoff comes into the room, coatless, rumpled, unshaven and looking slightly tipsy. The others at the table, all men of high school or financial standing, are somewhat put off.</context>
      <utterance>All right, let's start without him. Mr. Clemens, give me the cards.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This bit of grossness does little to improve his image.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry I'm late boys. I was takin' a crap.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff nods and takes a seat, none too gracefully.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Shaw is a bookmaker from Chicago. Mr. Shaw, meet Mr. Clayton from Pittsburgh, Mr. Jameson, Chicago, Mr. Lonnegan, New York and Mr. Lombard, Philadelphia.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Straight poker, gentlemen. 100 dollar minimum, table stakes. We assume you're good for your debts.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Shaw, we usually require a tie at this table. If you don't have one, we can get ya one.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonneman.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, that'd be real nice of ya, Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins to deal, obviously not pleased that his evening seems to be peopled with drunks.</context>
      <utterance>Lonnegan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CURLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name's Curly Jackson. I worked for Gad Bryan outa Baltimore.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever played the Wire, Curly?</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Twist is taken with the man, despite his appearance.</context>
      <utterance>Used to rope for it long ago. I can shill, mark board, anything you want. I don't run with riffraff and I only drink on weekends.  Me specialty is an Englishman.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Get yourself a nice tweed one.</context>
      <utterance>All right, Curly, you're in. We got a rack of suits over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all right. I got all my own stuff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raise 500.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See ya and raise three.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See and raise five.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan lays down his hand, a solid two pair. Gondoroff turns out three tens. Lonnegan is beat.</context>
      <utterance>Five and call.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan burns, and the "boys" have no comment.</context>
      <utterance>Tough luck, Lonnihan, but that's what you get for playin' with your head up your ass. Couple more like that and we can all go to bed early, huh boys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>GARFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We bought ya a tap into Moe Anenberg's wire. He's got eyes at every track in the country. You'll get race results, odds, scratches, pole positions, everything; and just as fast as Western Union gets 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Does J.J. know how to use this thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GARFIELD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We go to Kid Twist, still conducting interviews in the office. A young, rather sullen man, Buck Duff, steps to the table.</context>
      <utterance>All he's gotta do is read.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buck Duff. I was in Maxwell's boost in Troy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You the Duff that didn't come up with his end when Little Jeff was sent up?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wasn't no problem a mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a con man, wasn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a tear-off rat. He got what he deserved. No sense helpin' pay his bills.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Duff stands there a second and then slouches away from the table. He stops however, by the door. The next man up is the Eirie Kid. Twist knows he's seen him somewhere before.</context>
      <utterance>Shove off, Duff.</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Twist waits for more, but it's not coming.</context>
      <utterance>Names's Joe Eirie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You played for any particular mobs?</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know the Wire at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...I never played no Big Con before. But Luther Coleman was a friend a mine. I thought maybe there was something I could do.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eirie nods a reluctant "yes."</context>
      <utterance>You get that nose in Duke Boudreau's tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eirie is so happy, he can barely blurt out a thank you. Buck Duff, enraged that Twist would hire a total amateur, turns in disgust and strides vengefully out of the store.</context>
      <utterance>You got moxie, Eirie. Get yourself a suit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raise 300.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raise 200.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jameson lays down two pair. Gondorff has a flush. Gondorff rakes in the chips, which now put him ahead of Lonnegan.</context>
      <utterance>Two and call.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry about it, pal. Lemongan here wouldn'ta let you in the game if you weren't a chump.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff grabs the whiskey bottle next to him, breaks it against the table and waves the jagged end in Lonnegan's face.</context>
      <utterance>I've had enough of your lip, Shaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jameson and the conductor step in between.</context>
      <utterance>Just take it easy there, Larrabee.</utterance>
   <speaker>JAMESON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan storms out of the room, followed by Floyd and Bodyguard.</context>
      <utterance>Let's take a break for a couple minutes and cool off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stack me a cooler.</context>
      <utterance>I've had it with that bum, Floyd.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've only been playin three hours, Doyle.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care. Load me a deck. Set it up for threes and nines. I'll cut it in on his deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do ya want the others to get?</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothin'. They gotta be outa there early. I'm gonna bust that bastard in one play.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raise 1,000.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff looks at Lonnegan very carefully for a second. Lonnegan meets his stare.</context>
      <utterance>Raise 500.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The spectators shift a little. It's the biggest bet of the night.</context>
      <utterance>Raise 2,000.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See and raise 1,000.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan fingers his remaining chips. He knows he's won, but he wants to bleed it for every bit of suspense.</context>
      <utterance>Raise 5,000.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan pushes in the rest of his chips. Gondorff, who is only required to match Lonnegan's total, throws in all his too. It's a showdown.</context>
      <utterance>See, and raise the rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan puts down his four nines. Gondorff just stares at them a second, lets out a deep sigh and lays down four jacks. Lonnegan is aghast. This just can't be. He glances at Floyd, who can do nothing but sit there with his mouth open.</context>
      <utterance>Call.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other players look at each other in disgust, and reach for their wallets, all of which are well stocked.</context>
      <utterance>Well that's all for me tonight, boys. I'm gonna leave ya some cab fare.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan, with a stare that could kill, reaches for his wallet. Suddenly the stare goes soft. He tries a few more pockets. No soap.</context>
      <utterance>You owe me 15 grand, pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I left it in my room.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan, having had all he can take, goes for Gondorff, but is restrained by the conductor.</context>
      <utterance>What! Don't give me that crap you little weenie. How do I know you ain't gonna take a powder.  You come to a game like this, you bring your money.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff stalks out of the room. We pick him up coming down the passageway to his compartment.</context>
      <utterance>All right, buddy, I'm gonna send a boy by your room in five minutes, and you better have that jack, or it's gonna be all over Chicago that your name ain't worth a dime.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd ya do?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff tosses his winnings on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Well we got some workin' money anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, kid, you're on. But I gotta tell ya, its a hard act to follow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FLOYD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know I give him four threes. We can't let him get away with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a knock at the door. Floyd goes and opens it. It's Hooker.</context>
      <utterance>What am I supposed to do? Call him for cheating better than me?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Floyd motions him in without a word.</context>
      <utterance>My name's Carver. Mr. Shaw sent me.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your boss is quite a card player, Carver. How does he do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan says nothing. He doesn't like smart asses. He looks Hooker over a second, as if considering whether to have him wasted or not.</context>
      <utterance>He cheats.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll have to take a check.  I couldn't find my wallet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, he knows that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan just holds the wallet. He can't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>He hired a dame to take it from ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were set up, Lonnegan. Shaw's been planning to beat your game for months. He was just waiting for you to cheat him so he could clip ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could have you put under this train for this, errand boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So could Shaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why the rat?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan looks at Hooker long and hard, as if the intensity of his gaze could separate truth from fiction. Lonnegan hadn't expected this, but now that it's here, it better be on the level. The silence is suddenly broken by the noise of the train braking into the station.</context>
      <utterance>Cause I'm tired of bein' his nigger.  I want you to help me break him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker hesitates, not sure whether to accept or not.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, I'll give ya a lift home.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter? You gotta get back to Shaw?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, he picked up some jane in the bar. Can't see him till morning anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why me? Shaw probably has lotsa enemies to choose from.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need somebody respectable...but not completely legit. What I'm gonna do isn't very legal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a banker, friend. That's legit in this state.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan is listening, but you'd never know it.</context>
      <utterance>All you gotta do is place a bet for me at Shaw's place. I'll supply all the money and the information.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you help me out, I'll pay ya back the money you owe Shaw, myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's worth fifteen grand to ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We go to Lonnegan. He's still not talking, but that last phrase has registered.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe a couple million.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're dreamin', kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>660 Marshall Street. Tomorrow at 12:30, if you're interested.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything go all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, it was easy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No signs of trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do ya mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, somebody tailin' ya. A torpedo or somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff has his doubts, but lets them ride.</context>
      <utterance>No, not a thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How 'bout Lonnegan?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gave him the breakdown just like ya told me to.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He threatened to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We concentrate on Niles, who's making up the "boodles" or fake bankrollls. He puts a real $100 bill on the bottom, then two inches of cut green paper on top, and then another $100 bill on top of that, so that it looks like he has a whole stack of $100 bills. The bundle is then bound with a sealed label, like those used in banks, that says $10,000. We see that he has already made several of these bundles.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, they don't do that and you know you're not gettin' through to 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then he drove me home. He tried to put himself away as legit, so I went right into the pitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he hold you up on anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>I don't know if he bought it or not.</context>
      <utterance>Naw, he just sat there and listened.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think he'll show?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he say he wouldn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll show.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker turns around to find that Lonnegan is seated in the booth directly behind him. His bodyguard is in the one behind that.</context>
      <utterance>Carver?</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should always look to the back too, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We haven't got much time.</context>
      <utterance>I was afraid you weren't gonna come.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get on with it then.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometime after 1:00 a guy's gonna call here and give you the name of a horse.  All you do is take this two grand across the street to Shaw's place and bet it on that pony. There's nothin' to it, but don't take too much time. We only have 3 or 4 minutes after you get the call.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not gonna break him with a $2,000 bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is just a test. The big one comes later. Be careful with that though, it's all I got.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you were gonna pay me back?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan says nothing. He's not sure he likes a man who's stupid enough to bet his last dollar on a horse race.</context>
      <utterance>I am after this race.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta get back before Shaw misses me. Good luck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that. He's got four apes with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everywhere there is activity. A bank of telephones buzzes incessantly. Sheet writers scurry from phone to phone, taking bets of tremendous size from prominent people.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I like about these guys, J.J... They always got protection against things we'd never do to 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHEET WRITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We reveal that the phones are controlled by a master switch, which one of the recruited con men operates from behind a partition. The boardmaker, wearing headphones suspended from a sliding wire, hurriedly chalks up races and odds on a huge blackboard. From the loudspeakers we hear the words "last flash." The odds on Bluenote settle down to 8 to 1. Lonnegan makes his way through the throng toward the betting line. His bodyguards fan out to various positions in the room. The betting crowd itself (known as the "boost") consists of close to twenty people, none of whom, of course are what they're pretending to be. There are brokers with pasty faces, sportsmen, tanned and casual, and financiers with goatees and highly tailored clothes. Large amounts of money are changing hands at the betting window. Boodles are in sight everywhere. Lonnegan slips into the betting line, feeling somewhat estranged from the general merriment around him. There are two men in line ahead of him. The first, Curly Jackson, slaps down several bundles of cash in front of Niles, who's the cashier, and places a $20,000 bet on War Eagle. Gondorff appears at the cashier's window and catches sight of Lonnegan.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. Ruth, 20,000 on Dancing Cloud.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never get enough, huh pal? I'd think you'd get tired of losin', Honnigan.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The name is Lonnegan.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He makes the bet on credit. Lonnegan steps to the window.</context>
      <utterance>Make sure you see cash from this guy, Eddie. He's got the name for bettin' money he don't have. The man in front of Lonnegan puts $5,000 on Dancing Cloud.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two-thousand on Bluenote.</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that all?</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bluenote's race is now up on the board. The race caller comes on the loudspeaker.</context>
      <utterance>That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see that the caller is Singleton, and that he's calling the race from a concealed booth next to the cashier's cage.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and Gentlemen. This is Arnold Rowe, your caller for the second race at Belmont in New York. A mile and 1/8. Four year olds and up. And they're off!</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan goes to the bar, orders a drink, and settles down at one of the tables. It happens to be the one the Eirie Kid is at. Gondorff and Niles watch it from the cashier's cage.</context>
      <utterance>Around the first turn it's a War Eagle first by a length, Jail Bate second by one and a half, Dancing Cloud third by a half on the outside, followed by Lucky Lady, Mojo, Wits' End and Bluenote.</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon War Eagle.  That Dancing Cloud's a hell of a finisher. War Eagle's gonna have to open up a little more on 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know anything about a horse named Bluenote?</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eirie excuses himself and heads for the bar.</context>
      <utterance>Naw, he's never done much. Probably in here just to round out the field. War Eagle's where you wanna have your money.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The heretofore chaotic energy of the parlor is now focused on the race. Several of the patrons begin to yell for their horses. Lonnegan remains seated. He seems bored with it all. Hooker comes over to clear some empty glasses from his table.</context>
      <utterance>Into the clubhouse turn, it's War Eagle by two lengths, Dancing Cloud has moved up to second by a half, Lucky Lady is third by three followed by Jail Bait, Mojo, Bluenote and Wits' End.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really picked a winner, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give 'em a little time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan perks up just a little. Bluenote, at least, has moved up. The rest of the people in the place are really rooting now. Few of them remain seated. Hooker arrives at the bar, with the glasses he cleared from Lonnegan's table. Eirie is already there, fortifying himself with a scotch.</context>
      <utterance>Into the backstretch it's War Eagle still by a length, Dancing Cloud closing on the inside, is second by two, Lucky Lady is third by one and a half, followed by Bluenote, Jail Bait, Wits' End and Mojo.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eirie nods, somewhat unconvinced, and heads bak to the table.</context>
      <utterance>You're doin' great, Eirie. He loves ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan is getting more intent now.</context>
      <utterance>Into the far turn, it's Dancing Cloud now by half a length, War Eagle is second by two, Bluenote is third by a half and moving fast on the outside. Lucky Lady is fourth by four lengths, followed by Jail Bait, Wits' End and Mojo.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The place is going crazy. Even Singleton is standing up to get the necessary excitement in his voice.</context>
      <utterance>Coming down the stretch, it's Dancing Cloud by one length, War Eagle and Bluenote are neck and neck by two. Now it's Dancing Cloud, Bluenote and War Eagle.  Dancing Cloud and Bluenote head to head...</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Most of the patrons collapse into their chairs like spent lovers. Eirie slams his racing form to the floor. Nobody had Bluenote.</context>
      <utterance>Dancing Cloud, Bluenote. Dancing Cloud, Bluenote. It's Bluenote by a nose. Dancing Cloud is second by two, War Eagle third by three and a half. Time for a mile and 1/8, 2:01 and 6/10 seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bloody awful. Who in blazes is Bluenote?</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eirie doesn't reply. He can't believe Bluenote won. Lonnegan looks to Hooker. Hooker gives him a wink. For the first time, Lonnegan permits a smile.</context>
      <utterance>War Eagle's where you want to have your money, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker hesitates a second.</context>
      <utterance>Don't bother to come back with a piker's bet like that again, Lonnegan. We got a $5,000 minimum here.  Show this bum out.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff gives Hooker a hard shove in the back with his foot, sending him into a table and sprawling to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Go on, ya goddamn ninny.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker, pretending to be humiliated, gets to his feet and escorts Lonnegan to the door. Lonnegan stops, gives Gondorff a derisive smile, and walks out. Once he's gone, the general clatter and hubbub in the room cease, like it had been turned off by a faucet. Most of the boost sit down and relax. Curly Jackson rips off his Van Dyke. It's been itching him.</context>
      <utterance>And tell him not to bring his garbage men in here no more. This is a class joint.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gaffed, kid. He should start coming to you now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Riley. What the hell happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We missed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't hired to miss him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Somebody musta wised him up.</context>
      <utterance>There wasn't any way he coulda known we was in there. We made a clean pick on the lock and didn't leave no footprints in the hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, and what does Cole say about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. He took it hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Riley gets up and drags himself out the door like a whipped dog.</context>
      <utterance>All right, get outa here. You're outta work.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll put Salino on it. I need somebody careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guy's a five and dime grifter.</context>
      <utterance>Salino? Why waste our best people on a small-time job like this? It ain't no heavy gee we're after.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why ain't he dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>COMBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They didn't think he'd be so cagey, that's all. They'll get him next time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Combs gives up. The second time's the charm.</context>
      <utterance>Use Salino. It'll take a little longer, but there won't be any holes in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And tell Cole I wanta see him when he gets in.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not comin' in. Not to get bounced off a job anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Combs keeps his mouth shut. There's no way to talk to Lonnegan when he's like this.</context>
      <utterance>He had his chance and all he did was shoot up a rooming house. Made a lotte noise and woke up a few cops, but didn't hit nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Salino's job now, Vince. If Cole wants to muscle in on it, that's his business. But he's breakin' the rules and when Salino finds out about it, I can't feel sorry for what's gonna happen to him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what did I tell ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a lucky man, all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lucky, hell. I could do it every day.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't ya then.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cause it's better to do it all at once.  We're puttin' down 400 grand next week. At 5-1 we make 2 million. Twenty per cent of that is yours if ya stick with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a system, Carver?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stayin' in or not?</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>forward again and pushes a pile of bills over to Hooker. Hooker smiles and begins to count the money.</context>
      <utterance>It's foolproof. We got a partner downtown runs the central office of the Western Union. Race results from all over the country come in there and go right across his desk on their way to the bookies. All he does in hold them up a couple minutes until he can call us and get a bet down on the winner. Then he releases the results to the bookies and we clean up on a race that's already been run. It can't miss, unless the Western Union Dicks get onto it. Lonnegan is amazed. He sits back a second, then comes</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got the 400 grand yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet, but...  Hey, there's only a grand here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we oughta place another bet tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You tryin' to muscle me?</context>
      <utterance>What is this? That's my money.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker's in a jam and he knows it.</context>
      <utterance>If your system's as foolproof as you say, you'll get even more.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta talk to me partner first. We can't afford to expose our game too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker says nothing for a minute, and then reluctantly nods his head.</context>
      <utterance>You want your money back? Try and get it in a court of law.  C'mon, don't be a sorehead. I'll make it worth your while. Migth even help ya finance the big play if this one works out.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four o'clock tomorrow. Pick me up at Dewey Lyle's.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twist? I told him the tale. He wants to see ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, when?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow, after 4:00. Stay inside, I'll come in and get ya. And be hard on him for a while; he's talking money.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker blows a mock kiss through the phone and hangs up. He turns to leave the booth, when suddenly he sees something that stops him cold. There looking through the glass is the smirking face of Detective Synder. Hooker is immobilized. Snyder puts his hand inside his coat and slowly draws out his gun. He points it right at Hooker's face and then violently smashes all the glass in the upper half of the door with the barrel. Fragments of glass spray into the booth, a couple of which imbed themselves in Hooker's cheek. Hooker quickly whips open the door, trapping Snyder's hand in the accordian and jarring loose his gun. Hooker sprints out of the booth as Snyder scrambles for his pistol and gives pursuit.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Tootsie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't you tell me about Snyder before?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought I'd lost him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What else haven't ya been tellin' me?</context>
      <utterance>Well you found him again and we're gonna have to do somethin' about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothin'. I told ya everything there is.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why'd ya move outa your room?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was too noisy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker doesn't reply. He knows Gondorff's on to him.</context>
      <utterance>You can't play your friends like marks, Hooker.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how easy it'd be for one of Lonnegan's guys to nail you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All we need is a couple days, Henry. A couple days and we'll get Lonnegan down and stomp on 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just won't learn, will ya. Hell, you come in here, I teach you stuff maybe five guys in this world know, stuff most grifters couldn't do even if they knew it, and all you wanna do is run down a bullet.  You're just like all them new jerks. Lotsa nerve and no brains. And ten years from now when me and the others are through and you dumb guys are all dead there won't be one gee left who knows the Big Con was anything more than a way to make a livin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A couple days; that's all I'm askin'. I can stay clear that long.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, they'll probably miss you and hit me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You done?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, I guess I shoulda had the meat loaf.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It isn't any better.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's June today?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>till I can get a train outa here.</context>
      <utterance>She don't work here no more. I'm fillin' in for a couple days...</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you goin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker looks for some sign that she's putting him on. He doesn't get it. He takes out some money, drops it on the table and walks out.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Depends what train I get on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harmon's office.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. We're here to paint Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Harmon's office? Hold on just a second.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She goes to get Mr. Harmon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to your face?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Had a little fight with a raggle down on 13th. She got me with her ring.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>HARMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brigham signed it all right. I can't understand why he didn't tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harmon looks around, hoping it's not true.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, he's like all them supervisors. They think they're too good for regular people. He says he was in here a while ago and the place was a mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll try and hurry so we don't keep you out of your office too long.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why can't I work with you in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look pal, we gotta cover the floor, the furniture, everything, so we don't spill on nothing. Now if you wanta sit in there with a tarp over your head, you're welcome to it.</utterance>
   <speaker>HARMON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, how long will you be?</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Harmon is resigned. Twist and Singleton pick up their gear and march into the office. Once inside, we notice that the office has an exit door which opens to an outside alley. Twist immediately removes his overalls, revealing the suit and tie he's wearing underneath. He takes out a picture of himself, a woman and three small children, and puts it on Harmon's desk, replacing a similiar picture of Harmon's family. Singleton, meanwhile, has spread a few tarps and begins to paint the walls.</context>
      <utterance>Hour or two at the most. We do good work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We follow Hooker and Lonnegan across the street to the side entrance which opens into:</context>
      <utterance>We'll go to the side door.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wants to see you a second.</context>
      <utterance>Les, I got Mr. Lonnegan with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We coulda met at a club or somethin'.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell's the matter with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it might be good for him to see the setup.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Barnes, I'm going home a little early today. Tell anyone that calls that they can reach me here in the morning. Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't do it. There're telegraph inspectors all over the place. I got 750 grand coming in from the coast, and I'm not gonna blow it for a lousy 14 gees. We'll get somebody else to do our betting.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could come up with 750 grand in a day if I had a reason to.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But who says you will. I got a guy I can depend on. He's liquidating everything he has for this. You wouldn't even give Carver his money back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anybody can get lucky once.</context>
      <utterance>I need more proof, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We'll keep the deal we got.</context>
      <utterance>On a 6-1 shot? The hell with ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it works again tomorrow, I'll have a half million in cash here by noon the next day. We split 60-40.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were getting 50 from our guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Twist hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>With 20% coming off the top for me laying your bet. Either way you end up with 40.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anything can happen. All of it bad.</context>
      <utterance>A week's a long time, friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right, Les.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, and what if we play tomorrow and he doesn't come up with the money. We risk our whole operation for nothing. I'll say when we make our bets.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not if you want me to keep makin' 'em for ya.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Twist says nothing for a minute, then:</context>
      <utterance>And what do we know about your guy. He says a week, but who knows if it's a month? Lonnegan here's a banker. He can get that dough with no questions asked.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker and Lonnegan smile at each other like life-long friends. They get up to leave, and we frame the shot with a coffee cup large in the foreground. As they go out the door, a black-gloved hand with four fingers enters the frame and puts a nickel down next to the cup.</context>
      <utterance>All right. Be at the booth at 1:00. I'll give you all three places this time, Lonnegan. That better be proof enough.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you Lieutenant William Snyder?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, what's up?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>F.B.I... The Captain'd like a few words with ya. Ya got a couple minutes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men show him to a waiting car.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this? I got work to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snyder doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down and shut up, will ya. Try not to live up to all my expectations.  We were told you know a hustle artist named Johnny Hooker.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do ya know him or don't ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, but I don't know where he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ring any bells?</context>
      <utterance>Well we do. He's chummin' around with a Big C named Henry Gondorff.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Every bunco man in the country knows Gondorff.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's word he's gonna run a con on the North Side here. We got a year-old Florida warrant on him, but it's a thin beef, and he can beat it in court unless we catch him cold. All we want you to do is pick up Hooker for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you pick him up yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cause the stoolies are used to street dicks jumpin' him. If word gets around that Feds are in on it too, Gondorff'll fold up the whole thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't that be too bad. You'd hafta move outa this nice office ya got.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't crack wise to me, flatfoot. I spent a lotta time in dumps like this, eatin' Gondorff's dust while the bunco squad gets rich tippin' him off. But it's not gonna happen this time. We're not even gonna let the police know we're here. If you keep your mouth shut and do a job, there'll be a promotion in it for ya. And you better take it, cause I can make ya work for us without it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell good is Hooker to ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gonna set up Gondorff for us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll never do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he will.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Visitation is still up by two at the three-quarters. Single Action second, Fasanella third.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the line on Visitation?</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>7 to 2. That ain't bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff appears at the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>He'll probably fall down.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How ya doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothin' yet. I got a good one on the lead at Hialeah, but he's fadin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Best we had was Cat's Eye in the second at Del Mar, and he was only 5-2. Not many longshots comin' in today.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billie prepares to write on her pad.</context>
      <utterance>Billie. You ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billie crumples up the piece of paper she's been writing on and chucks it in a wastecan.</context>
      <utterance>At the finish, it's Single Action by two, Fasanella second, Visitation third.  Line on Single Action... 3 to 2. Hell with it, that's no good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff leaves the room, as Singleton turns back to his vigil at the ticker.</context>
      <utterance>We don't need big odds on this one, J.J. Take anything you get at 3-1 or better.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, the Fairfield Stakes at Santa Anita. Mile and a quarter for 3 year olds and up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gonna hit ya with 20 grand, Eddie. How much cash we got?</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not enough to cover a bet that big.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Niles nods.</context>
      <utterance>Get a couple extra guys in the line, then. We'll give him the shut-out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billie snaps to and prepares to write as Singleton reads.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Billie, here we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>SINGLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billie and Singleton hustle out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>At the wire it's Wrecking Crew the winner by five, Grand Theft second, Wingless third.  Wrecking Crew was...4 to 1.  That's our boy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You think you can handle that?</context>
      <utterance>All right, Furey, your horse is Wingless. Paltrow, the Big Alabama and Phillips'll take Grand Theft. Rodgers and Eirie have Wrecking Crew. Jackson -- His Dandy, Cowan -- Change of Heart, Fiskin and Chappie -- Made to Order.  Eirie, he gets a bang outa seein' you lose, so we oughta use that on 'em. If you play the birds of a feather routine we worked on, it should steam him up pretty good.</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O.K., you guys in line take your time, and I wanta see lotsa joy on Wrecking Crew.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CALLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ladies and Gentlemen, this is Arnold Rowe, your caller for the $100,000 Fairfield Stakes at Hollywood Park in Los Angeles. A mile and 3/8 for three year olds and up. And they're off!</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-thousand on Wrecking Crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to a sign above the window, which says exactly that. Lonnegan grabs up his money in disgust.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir. We can't take bets after the race is started.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan wanders over to the bar in a funk.</context>
      <utterance>Don't take it so hard, pal. You probably woulda lost it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The assembled patrons are once again thoroughly involved in the race. Eirie comes up to Lonnegan at the bar.</context>
      <utterance>And around the first turn it's Wrecking Crew by a half length, Grand Theft second by one, His Dandy is third by one half, followed by Change of Heart, Back Flip, Made to Order and High Ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who you got?</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrecking Crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan nods and wanders away. Hooker comes over to him.</context>
      <utterance>Me too. Maybe it's our day.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't get the bet down in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jesus.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like he's sulking.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we're lucky, this'll bring him back stronger than ever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CALLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eirie explodes in a joyous frenzy. He grabs Lonnegan by the shoulders and shakes him.</context>
      <utterance>Coming for home, it's Wrecking Crew by six lengths, Made to Order is second by two and a half, High Ground is third by a length and Grand Theft is coming fast on the rail. It's Wrecking Crew, Made to Order and Grand Theft. Wrecking Crew wins it by five lengths, Grand Theft is second by a nose, Made to Order is third by two. Time for one and 3/8 mile, 2:11 and 4/10 seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>EIRIE KID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yeh, Lonnegan heard that. Lonnegan shakes loose, grabs his coat and heads for the door.</context>
      <utterance>We won! We won! You hear that! I won 30,000! You hear that!</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell your friend I'll have the money here by post-time tomorrow. We'll take the first race where the odds are 4-1 or better. And make sure I can get to that window this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How am I gonna do that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Meat loaf, apple pie and a cup of coffee.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker gives her a dollar. She goes to the register for change.</context>
      <utterance>Sixty-five.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time you get off work here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You doin' anything tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker figures that's enough of that. He pockets his change and starts out the door, when suddenly he stops short.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, sleepin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a back door to this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. What's wrong with the front?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I don't have time to fuck around. There's somebody out there I don't need to see. You got a fire escape or anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, do me a favor. Go into the bathroom, open the window and wait for me there.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell for?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cracks of concern begin to appear in Loretta's marble.</context>
      <utterance>Just do what I tell ya and everything'll be jake.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does this guy want?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loretta just looks at him a second. Realizing that this is no joke, she turns and walks slowly but steadily to the bathroom. Hooker waits until she's out of sight.</context>
      <utterance>He'd like to kill me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Mr. Hooker. Captain Polk,</utterance>
   <speaker>F.B.I...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker remains standing.</context>
      <utterance>Have a seat.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want a drink or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We want to talk to ya about Henry Gondorff.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't think I know him.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well give yourself a couple seconds, crumb. You wouldn't wanna lie to me. Lt. Snyder here says you done a lotta griftin' in this town.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Capt. Polk almost laughs, but he checks it.</context>
      <utterance>Lt. Snyder doesn't know shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got nothin' on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker says nothing, but it's not from defiance now. He's beginning to get the picture.</context>
      <utterance>We'll get it, and if we can't, we'll just make it up. Grand larceny, extortion.  Counterfeiting, anything you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I got nothin' against you, but you're in trouble here. All you gotta do is tell us when Gondorff's gonna play his chump. We come in at the sting, make the pinch, and you walk out free as a bird. No questions, no court appearance, nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've already done time twice, and judges don't like three time losers. You wanna sit in the can for forty years, startin' tonight?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll make parole.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker wants to come back with something, but can't find it.</context>
      <utterance>Like hell. You won't even get a review till you're seventy. And if the board starts to go soft, we'll let ya out in the yard some night with a hard-nose young bull who'll put fifty slugs in your face and ask what you were doin' there later.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker's thoroughly whipped. He sits down for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be a sap, kid. You could save us a little trouble. But Henry Gondorff is through whether you help us or not. There's nothin' left to do now but save yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you wait until the chump is played?</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell yes. We don't care about the mark. He deserves what he gets.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean completely played. Until he's beat and the score is taken. You come in before we beat him and I'll kill him. You'll have a tough time explaining that, won't ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, Hooker, but you take it on the lam, and we'll shoot you down on sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just as long as I get to finish the play.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter, kid? You're not sayin' much.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a little nervous, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billie appears at the door.</context>
      <utterance>Luther always told me to bite my toenails when I get nervous. You see yourself doin' that and you realize it ain't worth it. Hooker smiles feebly.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff takes out a set of keys and tosses them to her. She leaves to go start the merry-go-round. Gondorff settles back into the game.</context>
      <utterance>Things are a little slow tonight, Henry. I wanna open the round for the girls.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy, you won't lose him now. We had him 10 years ago when he decided to be somebody. Believe me, I've seen enough to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many guys you conned in your life, Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff chucks his cards on the table. He's through for the night.</context>
      <utterance>Two or three hundred I guess. Sometimes played two a day when I was in Shea's mob. We had it down to a business.  'Course Chicago was a right town then. The fix was in. The dicks took their end without a beef. All the Wall Street boys wanted to make investments for us. Even had marks looking us up, thinkin' they could beat the game.  Yeh, kid, it really stunk. No sense in bein' a grifter if it's the same as bein' a citizen.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I better do some packin'. I'm gonna be a hot number again after tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why you doin' it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's good enough. Hooker gets up to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Seems worthwhile, doesn't it? Maybe it's just for the cave-in on Lonnegan's face when we put in the sting.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Henry.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate your stickin' your neck out. I wouldn't have asked ya if it weren't for Luther.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker just nods and walks out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't nothin' gonna make up for Luther, kid.  Revenge is for suckers. I been griftin' 30 years and never got any.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like he missed ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loretta notices an old busybody peeping out at them from her room across the hall.</context>
      <utterance>Yeh, this time anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Hillard quickly closes her door.</context>
      <utterance>Good night, Mrs. Hillard.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, ah...thought you might wanna come out for a while. Maybe have a drink or somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You move right along, don't ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean nothin' by it. I just don't know many regular girls, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you expect me to come over, just like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loretta looks at him carefully. She knows it's not a line.</context>
      <utterance>If I expected somethin', I wouldn't be still standin' out here in the hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>LORETTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even know you.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know me. I'm just like you... It's two in the morning and I don't know nobody. The two just stand there in silence a second. There's nothing more to say. She stands back and lets him in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUNMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker is stunned. He can't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>She was gonna kill ya, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker wants to stay and try to figure it all out, but the gunman drags him away.</context>
      <utterance>Her name's Loretta Salino. Lonnegan's people set her up in the diner. C'mon, let's get outa here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She coulda killed me last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too many people coulda seen ya go in her room. She was a professional. Used to work in the Dutch Schultz gang.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gondorff asked me to look after ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I know you're tellin' the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUNMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We go to Hooker. No, he doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>Don't have much choice, do ya?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Niles is struck dumb. He's never seen that much money before.</context>
      <utterance>Five hundred grand on Syphon.</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Niles goes and returns with Gondorff.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on, I'll have to get the manager.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff looks at the money a second and then looks up at Lonnegan like he's gotta be crazy.</context>
      <utterance>He wants to put a half million on Syphon.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't lay that off in time. We lose a bet that big, it could break us.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If ya win it could make ya, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are the odds on Syphon?</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff looks at Lonnegan long and hard.</context>
      <utterance>Eight to one.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A half mill on an eight to one shot. You're dumber than I thought, Lonnegan.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words "Last Flash" are heard on the speaker. Gondorff looks at Lonnegan with utter contempt. He turns to Niles.</context>
      <utterance>You're more gutless than I thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Niles hurriedly writes out a slip for 500,000 dollars. Lonnegan, allowing himself a sly smile, picks it up and retires to a nearby table. He flashes a little okay sign to Hooker who acknowledges it with a nod.</context>
      <utterance>Take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan takes a deep breath and leans forward in his chair, the larceny boiling in his veins. Hooker looks to Gondorff. Gondorff gives him the "office." Hooker has to smile.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen, this is Arnold Rowe, your caller for the San Antonio Handicap at Pimlico in Baltimore -- A mile and 1/16 for three-year-olds. And they're off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unexpectedly, Kid Twist bursts in through the entrance. Barely able to control his enthusiasm, he hurries over to Lonnegan's table and sits down next to him.</context>
      <utterance>And around the first turn it's King's Image by a neck, Syphon is second by one, Key to the Vault third by one half, followed by Mr. Moonlight, Red Ridge, Moneyman and No Charge.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Did everything go all right?</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, but I just couldn't wait.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy. Everything's all right. I put it on Syphon, on the nose.</utterance>
   <speaker>TWIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan looks like he's just been stabbed. He vaults over the table to the teller's window and grabs Niles.</context>
      <utterance>On the nose! I said place. Place it on Syphon. That horse is going to run second.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You hear me? There's been a mistake!</context>
      <utterance>You give me my goddamn money back!</utterance>
   <speaker>NILES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lonnegan begins to shake him violently.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir. The betting's closed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff leaps to Niles' aid when suddenly there is a crash at the entrance door, and Polk, Snyder and eight federal agents burst into the room, guns drawn. The place falls silent except for the loudspeaker, the members of the boost afraid to move. Gondorff and Niles look at each other wondering how this could have possibly happened.</context>
      <utterance>You give me my money back. There's been a mistake, do you hear me?</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon. We gotta get you outa here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LONNEGAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My money's back there.</utterance>
   <speaker>SNYDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Snyder gets in beside Lonnegan, and the car speeds away.</context>
      <utterance>We'll worry about that later.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CALLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Polk walks slowly over to Hooker's body and bends down.</context>
      <utterance>And the winner is King's Image by four lengths, Syphon is second, by two, Moneyman third by two and one half. Time for 1 and 1/16 miles, 1:21 and 2/10 seconds.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hooker opens his eyes and slowly drags himself up off the floor, spitting out a little rubber bladder, filled with blood, that he's had in his mouth. Gondorff does likewise. Niles, Twist, Singleton and the rest of the boost begin to laugh and shake hands, as do the Federal Agents.</context>
      <utterance>He's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice con, Hickey. I thought you were Feds myself, when you first came in.</utterance>
   <speaker>HICKEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff turns to the others.</context>
      <utterance>No problem, Henry. Snyder went for it all the way.  You shoulda seen the rag he lit under Lonnegan.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff walks over to Hooker, who's wiping the blood off his face and hands.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's take this place apart and get outa here. You can get your splits from Eddie at Boudreau's tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You beat him, kid.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were right, Henry. It's not enough... But it's close.</utterance>
   <speaker>GONDORFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wanta wait for your share?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gondorff nods, and walks slowly to behind the bar. He comes out with his suitcase in one hand and Hooker's paper bag in another. He throws the paper bag to Hooker, who stops by the door. Eirie Kid is standing there. Hooker gives the "office" to Eirie, who beams and gives it back.</context>
      <utterance>Naw, I'd just blow it.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
