<movie id="375" title="Manchurian Candidate The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... this way --?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco is seemingly unflappable, completely engaged by life.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, well -- I see the Captain enjoys the road less travelled.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laurent swings his finger on the arc of approach.</context>
      <utterance>The Captain enjoys not dragging his ass down the highway for every Tom, Dick and Qadhafi to take a whack at.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>LAURENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And here. And here, here, here, here --</context>
      <utterance>Well. Of course it is very bad, here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mines?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tricky. Swedish-made.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He refers to some satellite surveillance maps --</context>
      <utterance>Dammit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody at Command said anything about --</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exxon and Global Petroleum hired private contractors to do the work in '86, as part of their asset security program.  Hired an Iraqi firm, in fact, who, now, well -- only they know where the little Nordic fuckers are planted.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And we RUSH TOWARD: A SOLDIER IN A LAWN CHAIR, face lifted to the heavens, sitting directly between the two armored vehicles. This is SGT. RAYMOND PRENTISS SHAW, late twenties, haunted and aloof.</context>
      <utterance>Sgt. Shaw! No response.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rolling in two minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAVOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- CPL. AL MELVIN grunts, then they all look up, almost in unison, at Raymond when he swings open the back door. PFC. BOBBY BAKER, a slender man, barely eighteen, a driver, ejects a CD from the onboard stereo. Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Yo Melvin. You gonna play that hand, or hatch it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. He shuts the door again.</context>
      <utterance>We're moving out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't I ever ride in the Bradley with the other enlisted personnel?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I enjoy your company, Sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I don't want to be singled out for special treatment because of my mother's position --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too late for that, Shaw. As a charter member of the Lucky Sperm Club your benefits include unlimited suck-up from High-ranking Officers hoping to curry Congressional favor for their future career moves. But. If you want to ride in the Bradley, hey, I got no objections.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me, sir, I don't wish to ride in the Bradley with the others, I'm just ...  The men don't care for me very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they don't. But. On the plus side, you don't really like them, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's absolutely correct, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. See? It, you know. Balances out.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco follows Laurent's gaze out the side window --</context>
      <utterance>-- Uh-oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>31</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Behind the podium. Takes a sip of water, then:</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and with complete disregard for his own life and safety, Sgt. Shaw single- handedly engaged an entire company of the enemy --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLASH FORWARD: MAJOR MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Behind the podium, repeating himself:</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- of the enemy --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>35</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Behind the podium.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and finally dividing and defeating an overwhelmingly superior force.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ANOTHER SCOUT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you wounded?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RESUME - AUDITORIUM - MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He blinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A disheveled man comes into the back of the room noisily, as:</context>
      <utterance>-- injured. I fell, had a, uh, concussion -- lost focus -- Sgt. Shaw took command --</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOUT DAD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did your unit sustain any casualties?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. No more questions. The disheveled man (MELVIN) coughs. Marco pointedly ignores him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Two. Two of my people were killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Medal of Honor is the highest award to which any soldier can aspire. From the jungles of Iwo Jima to the desert of Kuwait, what these brave men I've talked about today did will never be forgotten. Since 1917, only 827 medals have been given to a total of more than 30 million Americans in arms. Only three have been awarded in the last 40 years. Who knows? Maybe someday one of you fine boys will earn one yourself in defense of this great nation. A SCOUTMASTER, thin, bearded, stands up:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for listening. My family has claimed the Army as a trade ever since a young gunnery officer who grew up with Hernando De Soto left Spain for a look at the upper Mississippi.  My life is in service to my country.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever wish it'd been you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something causes Marco to hesitate. Then, as if he'd rehearsed it:</context>
      <utterance>Won the medal. Been the hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm just proud to have been there. He sits down. Spattering of polite applause.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco turns, stares blankly into the eyes of the bedraggled- looking man, who half-salutes.</context>
      <utterance>Major Marco.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco stares hard. Melvin looks like a homeless guy, his clothes rumpled, his fingernails stained and broken, his eyes wild with fatigue and paranoia.</context>
      <utterance>It's Al Melvin, Sir. Corporal Melvin. From your unit. Desert Storm.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Melvin. Jesus -- how are you --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have these dreams, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dreams.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Kuwait. You and me. Mavole, and Baker. Raymond Shaw.  See, I remember it happened the way you just said. And then I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we had a pretty rough time over there, Al, it was hairy, and -- it was a long time ago, now. Memories shift.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have dreams, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody has dreams, Corporal --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Marco stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Not these.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Melvin's face falls, disappointed. Fumbling in his clothes, he finds a SPIRAL NOTEBOOK, dog-eared, and fat with newspaper clippings -- tries to press it into Marco's hands.</context>
      <utterance>No I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's bad, sir. It's making me crazy. I write it down, every night, after I wake up, I try to get it all -- it doesn't always go together -- all of what I can remember, and --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Al, you know, maybe you should be going to the VA and talking to a doctor, I mean if these dreams are really --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The notebook DROPS BETWEEN THEM, and PAGES SCATTER on the floor. Both men go down to collect them --</context>
      <utterance>-- I've been to doctors!</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so stuck, sir. I mean -- I remember Shaw saving us, but it does not make sense -- it should have been you. And Shaw, he --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- Marco rocks back on his heels as he stares down at a SKETCHY PORTRAIT OF AN ARABIC WOMAN whose face is covered with intricate designs -- Marco stares curiously, as if he recognizes her --</context>
      <utterance>Well, that's -- it's over and done. We've got to move on --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't get my hand around it. I thought maybe, if you had the dreams ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need money --?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Self-conscious (people are staring) Melvin shoves the notebook back inside his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>No. No sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco already digging for a crumpled twenty. Melvin waves it off, backing away, suddenly pissed.</context>
      <utterance>-- here --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need your money.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Okay. Well, look, Al, I gotta --</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It was great seeing you. And good luck to you. Melvin just scowls sadly at Marco. Flash of glass, a door opens and closes, and Marco is gone.</context>
      <utterance>-- run, yeah. But.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco stops, looks at her blankly.</context>
      <utterance>-- Thirty seven.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the romance novels out of his grocery bag and hands them to her.</context>
      <utterance>From the landing. Every week it gets longer. I'm worried about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes the romance novels out of his grocery bag and hands them to her.</context>
      <utterance>From the landing. Every week it gets longer. I'm worried about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of these involve slave traders or sheiks, Abby. I checked.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I owe you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does.</context>
      <utterance>A smile.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOCKING on his door -- it opens, and Secret Service AGENT EVAN ANDERSON removes his key while SEN. ELEANOR SHAW, pretty and ageless, sweeps in -- closing the door on her aide (GILLESPIE) --</context>
      <utterance>... I am ... a professional politician. Not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- soft curves conceal razor claws and titanium backbone -- she kisses her son on the lips, straightens his collar, his tie, lets her hands smooth his shirt to his chest for a little too long, and never stops talking:</context>
      <utterance>Raymond? Darling, what were you going to do, make me stand out there like room service?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I asked downstairs and Miss Freeman, your 'wrangler' -- helpful Ms. Freeman -- said you were up here practicing your speech. Honestly, I don't understand why you insist upon isolating yourself, people adore you, Raymond, they crave your company and yet here you are, holed up, as if you were some kind of emotionally challenged individual like your father instead of Raymond Prentiss Shaw, a handsome, intelligent, people-loving war hero with a great deal to offer to his party and his country.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No what? Baby, I haven't even asked you a question. Your hair is too flat. And that tie. The tie is wrong.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No to the question you're going to ask. No to all the questions you pretend to want to ask --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something a little less busy.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and no you may not engage in your usual back-door political thuggery to shovel me onto the presidential ticket.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. You're not interested? I thought you were. Did I miss my cue?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I'm interested -- I wouldn't be here if I wasn't -- but not if it means attacking the reputation of a statesman like Thomas Jordan, which I'm sure was your plan. Let democracy run its course, mother. Let the people decide. Now Ellie stares at him, mouth agape.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, for a second there I thought it was your father speaking -- that dreaded Shaw blood rising -- and the stink of defeat made me nauseous.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And excuse me, when have I ever attacked the honorable Mr. Jordan, despite the shameful way his daughter misled you that summer at the shore.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother, you chased her away --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's how you want to remember it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- you ruined everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond stares at her.</context>
      <utterance>Honey, you're oversimplifying things somewhat -- but, yes, okay -- I promise, promise I will stay out of it. You have my word.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond rolls his eyes. She ruffles his hair again, heads into the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>After all, you're young and you have plenty of party conventions ahead of you in which to discover, as your father did, that democracy is an elusive and imperfect science, and the meek do not happily inherit the earth, but simply get eaten by the alpha dogs, chewed up, digested and deposited on the carefully mown parkways of American politics.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Raymond smooths his hair back down.</context>
      <utterance>One day, you will, I'm sure, tearfully memorialize me in your acceptance speech. Don't you have a different tie in here? Your grandfather always let me pick his ties.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>I'm wearing the one I have on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bluffing?</utterance>
   <speaker>GILLESPIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond's speech echoes incoherently through the corridor.</context>
      <utterance>That was the inference.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They should be down on their fat white knees thanking me for saving this party from committing political seppuku.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>UTLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The decision is final, Senator. Tom Jordan is on the ticket. We don't need your blessing, but we'd like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before we get started, I'm dying to know: which genius here hatched the scheme of pairing a Sound Bite from Nebraska with a relic who thinks keeping suicide bombers off our busses is unconstitutional?</utterance>
   <speaker>UTLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All the research indicates that an Arthur- Jordan ticket sits quite well with the American public and --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Sits quite well' translates into how many votes?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR WELLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your son is largely unknown outside of New York. His public service, his Congressional record, while commendable, is --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son is a war hero.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONGRESSMAN FLORES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cold silence. Ellie stands --</context>
      <utterance>Governor Arthur has agreed to consider Raymond for a cabinet post.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't come here to have a discussion.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENATOR WELLS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ellie, you don't have the votes to block this, or even push the nomination to a second ballot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even running against this cut-and-fold vice president, with his party's record of abysmal failure at home and abroad, Arthur is still unelectable without help.  Consider. The Governor is a corn-belt candidate who -- scratch and sniff -- looks and smells alot like the kind of liberal-labor-intellectual Dukakis was, but without, thank God, the helmet.  Assume our intrepid Arthur can carry the Northeast, plus his home ground, and California. We're still dead in the South, and Southwest, where they win by landslides. The mid-central is a toss- up. Tom Jordan actually becomes a liability in Florida because of his Castro-appeasement profile, and in the Carolinas, where he fumbles the military vote over his "terrorism isn't a war it's a social disease" nonsense. The room is surreally silent. Ellie spins and moves like a televangelist, preaching to the frightened faithful.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know this. Your own polls and surveys back me up.  You're counting on Jordan to help you get the black vote, women, college kids -- my gut instinct says he won't -- and Arthur holding the center -- where he's soft at best. And who's to say the President won't throw troops into another third- world skirmish, pushing his sidekick's approval ratings up into the eighties again, and the campaign off the front pages?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>UTLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're confident this is a winning ticket, Ellie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your margin of error? Five points? Three?  I can swing that, and you know it. I can swing seven away from you -- more than enough to split the party and --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>America is facing the greatest test of its history, gentlemen. Not just from terrorist organizations both outside and within our borders, but from covert alliances of disaffected nations so terrified of winding up on our shit list they believe the only way to protect themselves is to hit us with everything they can find before we get around to them. Am I the only one in this room paying attention to the NSA reports? We are on the brink of nuclear cataclysm, on our own soil, while our policies remain shackled by Jordan-style One Worlders who insist that human beings are essentially Good ... and that Power is something shameful, and Evil.  Make no mistake, the people of this great country are frightened. They know what's coming. They can feel it. And we can shovel them the same old shit and call it sugar, or arm them, with a young, vibrant, populist congressman, a war hero with heart -- forged by enemy fire, in the desert, in the dark, when American lives hung in the balance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REPORTER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TV50B A STACCATO FLURRY OF IMAGES -- Raymond and his mother, newsTV50B clips, still photos -- appear behind a MAJOR MEDIA ICON:</context>
      <utterance>-- like a long shot catching the favorite on the back stretch of the Derby ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEDIA ICON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco taking it all in --</context>
      <utterance>Raymond Shaw bears the lineage of the fabled Prentiss family dynasty -- grandson of legendary industrialist and diplomat Tyler Prentiss, son of controversial Senator Eleanor Prentiss Shaw, who took over the seat vacated by her husband, the esteemed John Shaw, when he died tragically over twenty years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>MEDIA ICON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT: NEWS FILE FOOTAGE of Raymond's personal history:</context>
      <utterance>For many, Raymond Prentiss Shaw is an enigma: millionaire Harvard honors student who enlists in the military --</utterance>
   <speaker>MEDIA ICON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- refusing the officer's commission to which he was entitled. The Medal of Honor winner beloved by the men of the 'Lost Patrol' he saved from an enemy ambush, and then guided back across the open desert to safety --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MEDIA ICON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PUSH IN on Marco. His eyes distant, glazed -- tranced:</context>
      <utterance>The war hero who dedicated himself to public service after Desert Storm ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MEDIA ICON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... the revolutionary science of bio- genetics, which has, literally --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- the supertomato slowly bisects itself -- opening, oozing viscous red liquid -- revealing an inner structure far more suggestive of the human brain than any tomato we've ever seen before.</context>
      <utterance>-- transformed the common garden tomato, through genome-level intervention, from that fragile, fickle, vulnerable fruit one must struggle to simply nurture to maturity --</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>52 MARCO'S DREAMSCAPE -- where the MYSTERIOUS ARABIC WOMAN from 52 Melvin's drawings -- henna tattoos on her face, as well as her hands -- thick, blood-red pulp of the supertomato dripping between her fingers -- glides dreamily across intricate, sun-bleached tile work through a gathering of similarly clothed Arabic WOMEN. A few OLDER, ARABIC MEN are off to one side, expressionless, hands in pockets.</context>
      <utterance>-- into a resilient, dependable, categorically superior individual in every conceivable way -- -- moving through</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MYSTERIOUS WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IMPRESSIONS of soldiers -- MEMBERS of Marco's squad -- flak jackets and BDUs, rifles at ease, some squatting, some leaning against the wall ... Cpl. Al Melvin preternaturally engrossed in the presentation ... We hear a SANDSTORM raging outside, causing LONG DRAPERIES to FLUTTER and POP! like sails ... STRONG IMPRESSIONS of PFCs ED MAVOLE and BOBBY BAKER ...</context>
      <utterance>-- strappingly resistant to parasite, disease, over-ripening and systemic failure -- while, at the same time, fiercely heat and water tolerant --</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTERIOUS WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IMPRESSIONS of the American Flag. IMPRESSIONS of SGT. RAYMOND SHAW -- he waits for the mysterious woman like an obedient schoolboy, dutifully holding his SERVICE REVOLVER in his hand.</context>
      <utterance>-- yet -- note the complexity of the frontal lobe -- nevertheless retaining a sweet, juicy plumpness reminiscent of the finest English Beefsteak or Italian Plum.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYSTERIOUS WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those of you with ties to the Intelligence community may recall the CIA's misguided MK-ULTRA program, the KGB's Novichok research, and similar half- assed ventures in Great Britain and China -- under the lay term of 'mind control.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MYSTERIOUS WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, creepy, puts a hand on Raymond's shoulder --</context>
      <utterance>Street-corner schizophrenics with tin foil on their heads offer sad proof of the failure of those endeavors.</utterance>
   <speaker>MYST. W./NOYLE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can assure you, this is a whole new ball game.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- when you're rescued and returned with your patrol to command headquarters, what will be among the first duties you will undertake? 56 ON MARCO all rigged up with his wires -- 56</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now the dreamscape visuals seem REAR-PROJECTED on luminous, rippling white fabric ... the Bedouin people, tomato/brain images, the mystery woman, appear as TWO-DIMENSIONAL FILMED IMAGES, flickering across draperies ...</context>
      <utterance>I'll recommend Sergeant Shaw for the Medal of Honor, ma'am. He saved our lives, terminated the enemy and led us across the desert to safety.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Brilliant. But there were casualties?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... the DREAM SOUNDS (wind, fabric, women chanting) emanate from audio speakers, the sandstorm's wind caused by huge, moveable FANS ... ... IMPRESSION of an OLD MAN shaking a percussive gourd, mesmerizing ... ... IMPRESSIONS of the squad all rigged up like Marco, with tubes and wires ... Laurent glides behind them -- lab coat, SURGICAL GLOVES on his hands ...</context>
      <utterance>There are always casualties, ma'am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IMPRESSIONS of RAYMOND -- hyper-alert -- frighteningly engaged, and agreeable.</context>
      <utterance>Our Candidate's course of treatment will, of course, involve considerably more sophisticated intervention over a sustained time period, to ensure that a stable mechanism is irrevocably in place. We employ a kind of neurocellular conversion. Psychological abreaction through genomic repurposing.  "But Dr. Noyle, all the literature -- all the literature says you cannot make an individual act against his deepest moral nature -- or his own self interest."  Hmmm. Let's see.  Sgt. Shaw. Ever killed anyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No ma'am.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not even in combat?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No ma'am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond's wires and tubes float with him as he circles, pleasantly exchanging greetings with Marco --</context>
      <utterance>Brilliant. Casualty time.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IMPRESSION of Raymond thrusting a plastic bag over Mavole's head --</context>
      <utterance>Raymond. Suffocate Private Mavole.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAVOLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- Raymond's hands twist it TIGHTLY -- Mavole's limbs in turmoil, hands fluttering, his SHROUDED FACE suffocating in the translucent fog of the plastic bag -- PFC. BOBBY BAKER -- intent upon Raymond's killing of Mavole, gaze unwavering, untroubled -- SOUND of the zaghareet, peaking --</context>
      <utterance>Whoawhoa -- wait -- wait a sec --</utterance>
   <speaker>NOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>RAYMOND SHAW -- all business -- focused and purposeful -- twists the bag even tighter -- the plastic bag steaming -- tubes break, spit liquid, blood -- wires SPARK -- while Noyle floats through the b.g., a blur --</context>
      <utterance>And at the instant he completes this, or any task, Raymond has already forgotten that he has ever been involved in it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Beat. Howard looks up at Marco.</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.  No sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm not sharp --</context>
      <utterance>The meds make me ... spongy. I float.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The meds help you sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I sleep, I dream. I don't want to dream, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're off your meds, sleep-deprived, you have an unexpected encounter with a member of your Gulf War recon team, Al Melvin, who mentions some dreams he's been having --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dreams like mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and suddenly your own bad dreams come charging back. Made worse by your chronic fear of them. Add in all the recent campaign news about Congressman Shaw, which is obviously rekindling your feelings of guilt and jealousy --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I'm not jealous of Raymond Shaw, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. How did you feel when you heard the news from the convention?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A shrug isn't a feeling.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I felt ... fine. No big deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.  Glad for him. He deserves it. Raymond Shaw is probably the kindest, bravest, warmest --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're fucking with me, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir. I wouldn't do that, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco says nothing. Holding back what he's thinking.</context>
      <utterance>What other conclusion can I draw?</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No reaction from Marco. The Lt. Colonel sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Look, we've been over this a million times. Until you forgive yourself for what happened that night in Kuwait, the loss of your men -- for what you did, for what you didn't do ...</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's Public Affairs?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It sucks, sir. I want to get back to Intelligence.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then for God's sake, Ben, go back on your meds. And stay on them, this time. Get some sleep. I'll see you in two weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir. Same time, same station.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GENERAL SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No offense, Major, but it chaps my ass we gotta have a babysitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The old generals laugh, appreciate this. Marco stops -- eureka -- he's found his target:</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I'm just here to keep you from getting into fist-fights with the Navy guys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GENERAL WILSON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major Marco --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO AND THE GENERALS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marco forced to pull his gaze away from Raymond:</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- this Army of Two's gonna do some recon on the no host bar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- billions of dollars, thousands of troops, sacrificed on behalf of a disastrous foreign policy which has only served to galvanize our enemies --</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They oughta put up a crossing guard.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or rig her with an air horn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean -- that's supposed to be the whole point of this great country, isn't it? That everybody matters. Not just the people at this party -- no offense -- but the people who can't afford to be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she's not. Slipping her arm through his and steering him away...</context>
      <utterance>Raymond --  -- sorry to interrupt --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must learn not to let yourself get cornered by the bottom-feeders.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Including you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...to join a lively group of corporate heavyweights. DAVID DONOVAN is a man possessed of a commanding presence, radiating charm, brilliance and stealth. J.B. (JAY) JOHNSTON is younger than the others, a three-sport letterman who graduated with distinction from Princeton and happily works until there's no one left in the office to give instructions to. MARK WHITING is gracious and warm.</context>
      <utterance>I devour everything in my path, darling, top or bottom, you know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellie greets Whiting with a fondness she reserves for old friends -- as a former Tyler Prentiss protg, he now stands comfortably at the fertile crossroads where big industry meets big government, and profits soar.</context>
      <utterance>Hello Mark.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eleanor! Congratulations, Raymond. Your grandad would be so goddamn proud of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The following flows, overlapping, easy:</context>
      <utterance>Nice to see you Mark. Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Raymond, this is J.B. Johnston, from Manchurian Global --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, hi --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and David Donovan, their Managing Director.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and co-chair of the U.S. International Policy Caucus.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond flashes a dazzling Kennedyesque smile, as the men chuckle appreciatively.</context>
      <utterance>Go away, mother. You've earned your fee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The plucky idealist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, how's business?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, Raymond. Business is good.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could always be better.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Careful. Any better, you'll be a monopoly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's the challenge. Maximizing the market share and potential of a company.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off their shared, collegial laughter --</context>
      <utterance>Or a country.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>REAR ADMIRAL GLICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every great civilization has been anchored by a great Navy.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL SLOAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco laughs deliberately, trying to diffuse the tension.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. You guys are sea chum, ripe for some raghead with a rocket launcher to put a hole in your bucket.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congressman -- Sergeant Shaw -- Raymond turning, but not stopping --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben Marco.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.  Hello Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- Marco frowns, watches Raymond weave through the crowd towards Jocie, at the entrance. Marco follows, passing:</context>
      <utterance>-- okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- the political extortion you committed in order to destroy my vice presidential bid so that --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- so that you might vicariously bask in reflected limelight from your son --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom, please, just because the party felt a younger, more dynamic man could help the ticket, I don't think it's fair for you to single me out and --</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, I have such contempt for you, Eleanor, that when I think of you, I actually fear for this country. Raymond is nothing. A riddle. A wild card at worst. But you, you are the smiler who wraps her dagger in the cloak of the flag and waits for her chance to strike. Which I pray will never come. He wheels away --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JOCELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... but Raymond, my God, it's been so many years -- I've been married and divorced --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've changed too.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what I -- but, yes, it's great, really -- I see that you have -- congratulations --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jocie starts to say something, is at a loss for words --</context>
      <utterance>-- But my feelings haven't. Changed, I mean ...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I guess I've never stopped -- feeling -- wondering -- how it might have turned out, you know, between us, if --</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raymond -- people can't rewrite their lives --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jocie, I haven't even been with another girl since we ... stopped seeing each other -- doesn't that say something to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond is staggered -- doesn't know what to say --</context>
      <utterance>That you must be just about the loneliest person on earth, and it breaks my heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOCELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hurries to a waiting limo -- her father's already inside -- Raymond still wants to say something, he wants to stop her, but --</context>
      <utterance>I've got to go -- good luck with the campaign.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant Raymond Shaw -- Raymond turns --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco slides in front of him with a disarming grin.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to talk to you too.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Not now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to move away, but Marco grabs his arm --</context>
      <utterance>-- I know you're busy -- I just have to ask you --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw Al Melvin the other day -- remember Corporal Melvin? Raymond yanks his arm away --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay -- sorry -- but -- Melvin, he's extremely disturbed about what happened to us, on the recon patrol, back in Kuwait --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Marco's eyebrows go up.</context>
      <utterance>Don't ever touch me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond's secret service agent, ANDERSON slips himself between him, smiling politely, easing Marco away:</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tried the Pad Thai, Major? I'm told it rules.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE - COLONEL GARRET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>tense and unsmiling.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sir, I overheard an exchange he --</context>
      <utterance>I don't know, sir.  It isn't so much what he said, or didn't say -- but his demeanor, his attitude.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL GARRET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you hoped Congressman Shaw would say, "yes, Major, I've had those same dreams. Tomatoes and sandstorms. You're not nuts, there's some crazy shit going down here." Marco says nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL GARRET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major, we've been down this road with you before, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir, not this road, sir. But I hear what you're saying, and I want to do this through the proper channels.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you back on your meds?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lt. Colonel Howard -- with respect -- I've had a dozen years of experts telling me I've got Gulf War Syndrome, or a stress disorder. Twelve years being a good soldier, denying what every nerve ending in my body tells me is more real than not. One dream, over and over. Not variations on a dream, the same one, night after night after night --</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Your guilt and your jealousy require you to construct this ... elaborate fiction, so that you --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- No sir. Something happened to us, in the desert, ten years ago. Not what we thought it was. And it happened on my watch. Beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL GARRET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you contacted any other members of the unit besides Shaw and Melvin? Asked them about the dreams?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Garret and Howard trade looks.</context>
      <utterance>Owens died of cancer in '97. Villalobos, a car crash. Atkins committed suicide. Jamison was at the Pentagon, 9-11, body never recovered. Wilson I'm still trying to track down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I know I can't ask you to talk to Congressman Shaw, not yet, but Al Melvin, it's a phone call, a quick q&amp;a -- look at his notebooks, hear what he's been dreaming -- and either he will support the credibility of what I'm saying, or he won't. And I'll shut up.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL GARRET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what is it you are saying, exactly, Major? That you misrepresented -- falsified -- what happened In Kuwait? About the Medal of Honor? In effect, committed perjury.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you just talk to Melvin --</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL GARRET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. Marco looks down at his hands.</context>
      <utterance>-- No, no, I'm sorry -- you're saying an entire squad of U.S. Army soldiers was hypnotized into believing that Raymond Shaw deserved the Medal of Honor. And somehow you're the only one who knows the truth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COLONEL GARRET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major Marco. You will stay clear of Congressman Shaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That is an order.</context>
      <utterance>And you will resume your meds, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Marco stands up, to leave, but --</context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL GARRET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major, do you ever take a step back and consider why you've remained at rank for all these years? Missed Bosnia, Afghanistan, Iraqi Freedom. While men of lesser promise and inferior talent have enjoyed the fruits of those campaigns and moved beyond you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every day, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>T.V. MODERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congressman Shaw -- your rebuttal?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Victor? Marco. How's it goin'?  Public affairs sucks, my friend. I miss you guys. Listen, favor: guy from my old unit, Melvin, Alfred R. -- I need an</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>THE SIDE OF A BUS with a HUGE SKIN of Gov. Arthur and Raymond Shaw and the ARTHUR/SHAW "SECURE TOMORROW" campaign icon -- it SLIDES away, revealing: MARCO -- crosses the street, walks along a row of dilapidated apartments --</context>
      <utterance>There are gaps in this country. Ugly chasms that we need to bridge ...</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>-- the area is desolate, depopulated, an economic wasteland. Under a crumbling awning and into</context>
      <utterance>... the gap between rich and poor, between government and people --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode>T.V.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... between what is real and what is not.</utterance>
   <speaker>DESK CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dontcha love this guy?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- returning to the door and handing Raymond his keycard. The PHONE BEGINS TO RING --</context>
      <utterance>The weasel is a weasel. Frog and Toad Are Friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, we'll be right outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the door after them. Breathes out. Glances at his watch. Then crosses to answer the phone:</context>
      <utterance>I know. Good night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have thirty seconds, Mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I this predictable?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have no idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond's second line flashes with another call.</context>
      <utterance>I'm calling to compliment you, Mr. Grumpy. I thought you were magnificent tonight. So do all the network campaign experts. "Presidential" was a word they used.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This compassionate vigilance thing is working quite well for you. I might have to convert.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I happen to believe in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you do. Now Raymond --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodnight, Mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond punches a button and puts his mother on HOLD.</context>
      <utterance>Raymond --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>punches the line, lifts the receiver --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant Shaw?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE on RAYMOND'S EAR --</context>
      <utterance>Who is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Raymond's puzzled. Cocks his head, eyes searching the corners of the room. SOUND: a distant desert wind, building. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant Raymond Shaw?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE on RAYMOND'S EYE --</context>
      <utterance>Yes ...?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- Raymond's senses appear to QUICKEN NOW, as the LIGHTING in the room changes, morphing somehow -- even as SOUNDS of steady percussion, and the zaghareet -- the wailing cry of the Arab women -- rise out of the wind --</context>
      <utterance>Raymond Prentiss Shaw?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- everything is brighter, sharper, more luminous -- more etched than it was just moments ago --</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE ON THE PHONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen:  Enter the bathroom, and go to the closet there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello Raymond. Do you remember me?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brilliant.  We have twenty minutes for our little check up from the neck up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BLINK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>83 Another call. 83</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>yes sir --</context>
      <utterance>... no, Mr. Villalobos, I'm just -- Army's got me running statistics on stress disorders, I'm trying to gather information on my old squad members ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No decay, no slippage. Everything appears to be in flawless working condition.  Raymond can you remember the deaths of Mavole and Baker?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LCD SCREENS show activity in areas of Raymond's brain.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Describe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still nothing. He checks the hallway, takes an Army utility knife from his pocket and forces the lock --</context>
      <utterance>... Al? You in there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LAURENT TOKAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>sitting down across from him. Smiling.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAURENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this seat taken?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Delaware.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. But, Maryland, it's a beautiful state anyway. He's staring at her, trying to figure out --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paper or plastic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>From the grocery store. You were wondering where, we, you know -- and right at the check-out stand, "paper or plastic," that's me. I see you all the time. Bennett Marco. Checks from the First National Bank, and you always put your spare change into the March of Dimes thing.  Romance novels, instant noodles, No-Doz and tomatoes.  Anyway, I'm on vacation, holiday in the City and so forth, I saw you sitting here ... I thought, okay, girl -- it's now or never.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You headed to New York City?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Business?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Guy I knew ... in the Army. He's in politics now. We've kinda lost touch.  What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eugenie.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Scuse me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Crazy French pronunciation and all.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess your friends call you Jenny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet they haven't, thank God. But you can call me Jenny.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do your friends call you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eugenie is, well, fragile.</context>
      <utterance>Rosie. My full name is Eugenie Rose. I've always liked the Rosie part better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still. When I asked you your name, you said it was Eugenie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FB94 FLASH: PFC. BOBBY BAKER -- stares back at him from where FB94 Rosie was sitting. Bullet hole in his forehead and a small, lost smile. Reaching out to him --</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Well. Maybe 'cause I was feeling fragile. At the time. Beat. Their eyes lock. Marco blinks --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco looks up at her blankly. She takes the vial, caps it, gives it back.</context>
      <utterance>My mother would tell you to wash these.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean to upset you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not you, it's me. I'm not -- my head --  -- nothing's ...  I wish I smoked.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at each other. Then:</context>
      <utterance>It's way overrated.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco ducks into the bathroom and shuts the door.</context>
      <utterance>Rosie, I'm gonna go in here, wash my face, take my pill, and get myself together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco stares at Rosie. Twenty minutes? The train SHUDDERS to a halt --</context>
      <utterance>Jesus. You've been in here twenty minutes. I thought you'd fallen off.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm okay, thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friend gonna meet you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>El Dorado 59970.  My cell phone, in case you -- you know. I like to say it the old way -- can you remember the number, or should I write it on your chest with a sharpie?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>I'll remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sweating.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco feels his shirt -- soaked. Long beat. She reaches out and feels his forehead. No fever. Sizing him up.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen. You got a place to go and get freshened up?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco puts down the suitcases and waits in the middle of the room while Rosie takes off her coat, turns on some lights.</context>
      <utterance>-- It's my cousin's apartment. She's in Cleveland with the road company of 'Mamma Mia.' There's ... a view of the park ... if you go out on the fire escape and kinda ... tilt your head ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm nervous. I'm sorry. I yak when I get nervous.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another awkward beat. She stands there. Studying him.</context>
      <utterance>Me, I get quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Catches himself. That's just how Melvin said it.</context>
      <utterance>Dreams, I've been having these --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what happened on the train?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Sort of.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could be dreaming you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Rosie smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>You'd be the best dream I've had in a long time, Rosie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's a line, Ben Marco, it kinda worked.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROSIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben?</utterance>
   <speaker>TIGHT - MARCO'S HAND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>turning off the shower, hard --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARCO -- rests his head on the cool tile, eyes far away. Defeated. Rosie crouches next to him. A little scared. She blots the blood from his back with the towel, and then presses her ice pack against it.</context>
      <utterance>-- Gone. Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rosie just stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me you saw that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't. You didn't see it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco closes his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>See what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Proof.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My sanity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This wasn't a delusion.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops, unlocks a door, and they go --</context>
      <utterance>That's what they all say, Marco.  Some wicked shit got sprayed on you guys during Desert Storm. Besides all the depleted uranium, I mean ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... I personally know of a coupla Rangers who swear that they see only in tertiary colors now --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Delp.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and can pick up sports talk radio in their cortical block if they get too close to a Con-Ed transformer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delp has known Marco too long, and too well, not to take him seriously.</context>
      <utterance>-- Delp. It's not GWS.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A dozen years ago, the Army did this tiny implantable I.D. thing -- you could imbed it under the skin, then scan it like a bar code for medical emergency information, blood-type, DNA. Pentagon ordered up half a million, and stuck about five thousand experimentally into high-risk soldiers and infantry. But the scanners proved skittish and field hospitals hated 'em, so the whole deal got eighty-sixed and forgotten.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Army never put one in me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That you know of, man. That you know of.  How'd you find me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I looked under Mad Scientists in the yellow pages -- there was a full page ad.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco stares down into a big pit. Among the racks of equipment are two primate-sized stainless-steel beds with restraints and I.V. trees waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Ha ha.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seriously believe somebody's messed with your mother board.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you studying here, Delp?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the Agency?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, CIA cut me loose in '97 during the Macedonian debacle. Now I got this little grant from Wal-Mart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delp just waits.</context>
      <utterance>Look, Delp. My experiences during the war, in Kuwait ... feel dreamlike to me. And my dreams? About what happened? Feel as real as you and me, here, right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like ... I feel like somewhere along the line, I've been ... brainwashed. Or something. You know? All scrambled up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And you would remember it.</context>
      <utterance>We've all been brainwashed, Marco. Religion, advertising, television. Politics. We accept what's normal because we're told it's normal and we crave normalcy. Hell, look at the Germans under Hitler. Disco, in the seventies.  And if you're really worried about somebody imbedding electric probes and computer chips in your brain to make you do things -- it's horseshit, man. Turns out Pavlov had it right from the getgo. Dogs and all. A little ECT and sleep deprivation will do the trick for a fraction of the price. Ask the Uzbeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about my dreams?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if all this is the fucking dream and you're still back in Kuwait?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not helping me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am. You're not helping yourself. Reality is consensual, man. You just gotta prove it up. Or play it out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REPORTER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congressman Shaw! Why do you and Gov. Arthur oppose deploying troops in Indonesia?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't clean up the world with dirty hands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guys, I gave up a long time ago trying to second guess my mother. I'm just surprised the rest of you haven't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heads turning to find Marco, folder under his arm -- strange looks -- Secret Service poised to react, but Raymond slows, looks -- sees Marco. A cloud passing over his features:</context>
      <utterance>Do you ever dream about Kuwait?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MORE QUESTIONS lobbed out, overlapping, but Raymond ignores them. Marco pushes through as Raymond assures Anderson:</context>
      <utterance>I can never remember my dreams.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- it's okay. I know him, it's okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw Mavole's Mom and Dad in St. Louis. I still visit them -- and Baker's mom -- when I can. Do you keep up with anybody from the unit besides Al Melvin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't keep up with Al Melvin. He found me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you ask me about Kuwait?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't. I asked you about your dreams. At the fundraiser -- why did you say you needed to talk to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Shaw, excuse me -- they want to know if you'll do an interview with Larry King at six.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.  What do you want from me, Captain?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major. Forty minutes of your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No to the interview, or no to six?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Marco --</context>
      <utterance>He wants to talk about my mother. No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Private time.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we've got about five minutes, right now. And this is as private as it gets for me anymore, so ... Beat. He waits. Anderson staring at Marco.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are these dreams that ... some of the men in our unit have been having.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Including you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a question of what actually happened the night our patrol was attacked --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's easy.  RPG incoming. Mortar fire, we're ambushed. Total chaos. I can't locate Baker or Mavole. You're knocked unconscious -- I find you and pull you to safety and then --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The limo pulls to a curb --</context>
      <utterance>-- Yeah, that's how I remember it, too.  But I dream something else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I in your dreams?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doing what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond steps just outside the entrance to his office.</context>
      <utterance>-- You know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PEDESTRIANS pass between them on the crowded sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>Saving everybody?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco reaches into his folder, pulls out one of Melvin's notebooks --</context>
      <utterance>It's more complicated than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- and Raymond's staring at the notebook without taking it, the way Marco once did with Melvin. Anderson and Mirella -- the staffers in the office -- are all staring at Marco the same way the Boy Scouts once stared at Melvin.</context>
      <utterance>People just don't have the same dreams accidentally --  -- Melvin made drawings, he wrote down what he dreamed, this is one of his notebooks -- it's all in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have dreams, Captain.  Maybe you should ... see somebody -- talk to somebody who specializes in this kind of thing --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been to doctors. ... which is exactly what Melvin said to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco nods again, numb, makes a vague resigned gesture.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Okay, I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jams the notebook back into his folder, starts to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not crazy, Shaw.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco stops, turns.</context>
      <utterance>Captain --  -- Major.  Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you hungry?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I kill Mavole?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a dream --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- could mean something else.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- could be I'm just supposed to think you did.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I killed the enemy. I didn't know them, either. So it was okay. And, anyway, I remember what we did in Kuwait, I remember it perfectly. But now that you mention it, I don't remember doing it ... exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now he picks up the dream book. Marco watches. Raymond flips through the pages for a moment, dismissively. Then stops at something Melvin has drawn. Frowns. Raises his eyebrows. Closes it, sets it down:</context>
      <utterance>NO. What a thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life is so bizarre, isn't it? This absurd campaign, the sordid world of politics, my whole public life and persona -- sometimes, occasionally, for an instant, the fog clears and I look and I think, what am I doing? I mean, what the fuck am I doing? Posing and grinning like a goddamn sock puppet, shaking hands with total strangers who must be blind if</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Raymond looks steadily at Marco ... who nods, interested:</context>
      <utterance>they can't see what I am, at the core. What my mother has made me.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Prentiss. Ferociously, a Prentiss -- but not a Shaw, God forbid -- I was molded by cold hard hands, every detail of my existence preordained. Can you even imagine, Ben, how it would feel never to have a say in what your life would be? I was twenty years old before I had a friend -- no, worse, a girlfriend -- well, almost -- but, yes, a friend, or I thought so -- outside my mother's circle of approved encounters -- and it didn't -- she wouldn't -- precipitating my one act of rebellion, storming off and enlisting --  -- in the Army. Which, ironically, only served ultimately to pad my gilded Prentiss resume. You know: "fluent in five languages, Phi Beta Kappa, Congressional Medal of Honor, blah blah blah."  And after the war I came back to her. And the family legacy. This. Mother calls it, "fulfilling my Manifest Prentiss Destiny."</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you come back, Raymond? What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seeming startled, Raymond's reverie is broken. His eyes harden as he refocuses on Marco.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weren't you listening? Mother happened.  You know, the truth is, I hate it. I've always despised it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The medal. The cloying adulation of the little people. Your pitiful jealousy --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who said I was jealous?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have the dreams, Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you not remember saving the unit?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do. I said I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you don't remember doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha ha, don't mix me up, I'm tired, and -- Fine. It's like this. It's as if I know what will happen, Ben, but I never get to the part where I feel that it actually did happen. But I think that's probably perfectly normal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever talk to anybody about this little discrepancy?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? No. Who would I ask? My old Army "buddies," who love and adore me for saving their pathetically unimportant -- present company excluded -- asses?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You ask Army Intelligence.  Look, we can go together, tomorrow. You tell them what you just told me, everything you do remember, what you don't "exactly" remember, about Kuwait, let 'em run some tests on you --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure the press would have a field day with that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raymond. They put an implant in me. I found it yesterday. Maybe they put one in you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody's put anything in me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. Let's prove it. We can go get an x-ray -- we can check it right now -- Marco moves toward him, Raymond backs away --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be supportive of you, Ben, I do, but --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just check your back, Raymond --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- this can wait until after the election.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you afraid of? See if there's a bump.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should leave. This is not, this is not --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- just check --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco LUNGES at Raymond -- they fall, together, over the desk, onto the floor -- Chinese food scattering.</context>
      <utterance>There's nothing there!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody was in your head, with big steel- toe boots, a couple of cable cutters and a chainsaw, and they went to town! Neurons got wasted, circuits rewired, brain cells obliterated -- KNOCKING at the door:</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congressman Shaw?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- where Marco (stronger, better-trained) wraps Raymond in a headlock, RIPS Raymond's shirt from the shoulder --</context>
      <utterance>-- you don't even know what they did! You don't -- you can't CONCEIVE what they did to you -- and you're worried about some lame-ass reporters!?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm wrong they can put me the fuck away --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ben --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INSISTENT KNOCKING at the door. Marco CLAWS AT THE SKIN on RAYMOND'S BACK -- sinks his teeth in -- -- Raymond shakes him off, and MARCO slams into the wall. The office door BANGS open -- Anderson and other agents SWARM Marco -- there's blood smeared on Marco's mouth, his jaws are clenched --</context>
      <utterance>-- there -- there's -- something --</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He bit him.  Sir, did he bite you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARCO -- shoved to the floor -- twisted -- handcuffed -- blood SMEARING across the carpet -- his eyes wild with adrenaline and fear -- RAYMOND -- his hand goes to his back -- his eyes LOCK with Marco's for an instant -- then Marco is hustled out the door.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. That'd be political suicide. Of course not. I want you to help him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't even imagine why.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I feel sorry for him. Because I said I would.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should we do? Make him a General?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother. Look. My campaign people are getting a restraining order, he's going on all the security watch-lists -- but I won't lock him up. I'm not pressing charges.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's complicated -- I don't know. It's just complicated and I don't want to talk about it, I want to get back to the campaign and focus on --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't actually believe his story?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But he does. And he's a fine soldier and ... my friend. And if his slim hold on sanity requires that I tolerate his delusions until he can get help, I'll do it. It doesn't diminish me. And I'm not afraid of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is why voters love you. Your humanity and everything. I've never projected humanity.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes I think telling people you want to "round up all the towelheads and throw</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>them in a deep pit" probably tips your hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Carpetbag steak.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to cut meat into child-like, bite-sized pieces and put them on a side plate, for Raymond.</context>
      <utterance>Stuffed. With oysters?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doesn't it look yummy?</context>
      <utterance>The steak part is mostly for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God. In the world's literature of food could there possibly be a more vulgar dish?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And eating it is an absolute sexual experience. Try some.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellie stops, sighs, puts her fork down and reaches for the oversized-satchel that doubles as her briefcase and purse.</context>
      <utterance>Promise me that you'll help him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellie finds two thick files and plops them down, as punctuation, in front of Raymond.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, Raymond, how much do you really know about your friend?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Across from him are three impatient FBI AGENTS (RAMIREZ, GOLDRING and JONAS). Ramirez has the notebook Marco took from Melvin's. Goldring pushes a tiny digital tape recorder closer to Marco:</context>
      <utterance>I went to talk to him. But he wasn't there.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT GOLDRING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco hesitates -- looks to Lt. Col. Howard, who sits grimly, off the one side, with Col. Garret.</context>
      <utterance>Talk about what?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT GOLDRING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A lone woman, SPECIAL AGENT VOLK, sits in a distant corner on a folding chair. She's implacable, staring intently at Marco. Ramirez holds up the notebook -- a page of crazy drawings and text.</context>
      <utterance>Dreams?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, there are hundreds more of those in his apartment. Did your people check out his place --?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel Garret kindly showed us the file on you, Marco, you're the shit: Special Forces. Rangers. Delta.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanted to talk to Corporal Melvin about some unanswered questions involving our reconnaissance mission in Kuwait, back in</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know this game. Will you explain to them that I know this game?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT RAMIREZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh right. Army Intelligence. Isn't that an oxymoron?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Kinda like 'special agent.'</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL GARRET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cut it out, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT GOLDRING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your obsession with Raymond Shaw?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT RAMIREZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man of his dreams.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Implant. The Feds just stare at him. Like he's nuts.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, you might want to advise your ME to check for an implant in Corporal Melvin's back -- under the skin, just shy of the scapula, left side ... if he's not looking for it, he won't find it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't have anything to do with Corporal Melvin's death.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco snaps, spins out of his chair and lunges at Jonas -- Lt. Col. Howard and the other agents step between the two men -- pull them apart --</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, that's your opinion, but judging from your file here, apparently you don't know your shit from your oatmeal, my friend --</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get this man out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco PUNCHES the agent so hard it knocks him down to the floor between the other two.</context>
      <utterance>Go ahead, nutball. Try it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- He hit me! Fuck!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colonel Garret shoves Marco back into a chair, stays in the middle of the fracas, while --</context>
      <utterance>He said I could.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Federal Agents retreat with their bloodied-nose, cold- cocked colleague, door slamming behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, OKAY --! That's enough. Gentlemen, I need a moment with Major Marco. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Only Agent Volk remains, unmoved by what just occurred. CLOSE ON - MARCO, catching his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Evidently this has been going on for years ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Sad little Tin Soldier.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Isn't it disgraceful the way troubled individuals are allowed to simply walk around with the rest of us until something horrible happens? Another failure of the HMOs. I'm thinking of sponsoring a bill, with Senator Friedman of Rhode Island --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I don't care.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, imagine how terrified your people were yesterday when Major Marco showed up at the airport and you invited him -- my God, invited him -- to tag along. Knowing what they knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know him. I served under him. He was a good man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond stares at an old PHOTOGRAPH OF MARCO: curled up in a fetal position, on a V.A. hospital bed.</context>
      <utterance>That's what the neighbors always say about serial killers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps we could arrange a promotion to a less stressful posting. Somewhere tropical.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AGENT GOLDRING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.  Get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's free to go?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT GOLDRING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Volk closes her notebook and moves past Goldring as he picks up the tape recorder. She glances at Howard, and leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>Shaw won't press charges, and he's got juice with important friends. It's today's daily double.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL GARRET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Marco, trying to process all this:</context>
      <utterance>Someone from Senator Eleanor Shaw's office called and intervened on your behalf.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL GARRET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major, you have reached the terminal end of the Army's patience. You're relieved of duty, effective immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a young neurologist at Walter Reed. Zahn. He's had considerable success with GWS -- I want you to get your affairs in order and report to him</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I know all about Dr. Zahn. Remember? He's that guy who --  Sir. Yes sir.  I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LT. COL. HOWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too, Ben.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARCO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- leaves the statement hanging --</context>
      <utterance>These are not supposed to exist, man. These are only theoretical.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you want to do this man?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- because I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll owe you one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'll still owe you for getting my sorry ass out of Albania.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Talk to me about the implant.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manchurian Global. Heard of 'em?  Private equity fund, specializes in military support services and weapons research ... including a certain Army implant project that went belly-up in the early 90s.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said the Army implants were for medical emergency data.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ones they publicized were. But, oh man, there was a parallel project of all kinds of scary implantable shit the Clinton watchdogs finally freaked out over, and closed down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cuz they funded me to make some of their scary shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it do?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I don't want to know. You don't want to know -- shit -- it's out of you, and you're still alive. That's the good news.  What are you doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm putting you on a cocktail of methohexitol to take the edge off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Edge off what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wires snake across the floor to the ECT [Electro-Convulsive Therapy] unit.</context>
      <utterance>'Getting clarity.' Or whatever you want to call it -- ECT not being the precise science that, say, leeching is.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think this is going to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the desperation move, man. But, hey. There is a school of thought, says a victim of induced abreaction -- or ultra-paradoxical brain activity, if you're at all correct about what happened to you -- can have it effectively dispersed by electroshock. Unscrambled.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- But?</utterance>
   <speaker>DELP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takes out a bite-guard and puts it in Marco's mouth:</context>
      <utterance>But the legions of naysayers will tell you that if the initial work's done correctly -- if the brain's been not just washed, but dry-cleaned --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco tries to say something, his mouth is dry.</context>
      <utterance>Blank again?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco stares, trying to orient himself. His arm comes up to shade his eyes -- nothing written on it.</context>
      <utterance>He said this would happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing.</context>
      <utterance>I don't remember a friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kind of like a computer system crash -- your brain goes down, then you boot up again, but you lose all your RAM.  Do you remember me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rosie smiles. Marco closes his eyes again and --</context>
      <utterance>Eugenie Rose.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCREEN GOES BLACK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then the SOUND OF A TELEVISION fades up:</context>
      <utterance>Silence. Two beats.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Wednesday.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Central Park was Monday. I came home Friday.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat. Marco stares at the t.v. as she sits on the edge of the bed, rubs her hair with a towel.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did I get here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You called me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>El Dorado 59970.  I remembered.  I remember, and I didn't dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been weird, talking to you. Knowing that you could fall asleep with your eyes open and wake up and have forgotten the whole conversation. I hope to God that part's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd we talk about?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stuff.  You said you "loved" me. Not to scare you. Out of nowhere, but more than once.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. She smiles. She leans in, kisses him lightly.</context>
      <utterance>I remember that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rosie opens her mouth --</context>
      <utterance>What else did we talk about?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCREEN GOES BLACK.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two beats of silence, then --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rosie, rolling off the bed, sleepy, crossing to where Marco is gathering the files --</context>
      <utterance>Ben?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sees the hard look on Marco's face. Newspapers over all the vents. Opens her mouth to explain but Marco SWINGS HARD, and hits her -- she partially blocks it with her forearm -- backhands her onto the floor --</context>
      <utterance>What are you ... oh God.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- then he's moving, out the door --</context>
      <utterance>You're part of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do this, Ben. It's not what you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to get past her again --</context>
      <utterance>How can you know what I think?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROSIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Not to scare you. Out of nowhere, but more than once.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WHIR of rewinding audio --</context>
      <utterance>I remember.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARCO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What else did we talk about?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCUT - MICROFICHE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>stories flip past ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raymond Shaw. And about what happened to you, after you were captured. Black helicopters, secret laboratories, mind drugs, mad scientists, shock-torture ...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't believe any of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's crazy. It sounds crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- maybe that's what they want. Maybe that's what they want.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARCO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I watched Raymond Shaw kill someone. I watched him kill Private Eddie Mavole. Like it was nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rosie puts her arms around him --</context>
      <utterance>And I think they made me kill someone too. One of my people. Kid named Bobby Baker.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- Marco doesn't react -- WHIR of audio fast-forward --</context>
      <utterance>Or they want you to think that you did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROSIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he have a name?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco stares at the photograph.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROSIE'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The doctor, Ben -- what was his name? Can you remember? A long beat. Marco racks his memory. Then --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PUSH in until Noyle is just a mass of pixels --</context>
      <utterance>Noyle. They called him Dr. Noyle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody will believe this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits down, opposite Jordan.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody believed Watergate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or Oklahoma City, or the World Trade Center. You wouldn't have believed Oswald before Kennedy got shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the Noyle file down, pushes everything away.</context>
      <utterance>On the advisory board of Manchurian- Global, should they ever publish a list -- which they won't -- you would find former Presidents, deposed Kings, retired Prime Ministers, Ayatollahs, African War-Lords, fallen Communist Dictators and an assortment of the Fucking Rich, who are distinguished from the merely Filthy Rich by factors of billions.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bring me rumors and conjecture.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I started with nightmares, sir. Rumors and conjecture are a giant leap forward.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>some of their subsidiary partners are engaged in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A cold silence. Marco stares at Jordan.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I don't give a rat's ass about Manchurian Global! That's not why I'm here!  I can't touch them, I get that, I'm not stupid, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan nods again, slightly. Lost in thought.</context>
      <utterance>I just want to try and stop this one thing -- this Raymond Shaw bomb -- from going off.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'd be lying if I told you I hadn't factored in huge that you've got a vested personal, political, and patriotic interest in how this shakes out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now they see Raymond, under the imposing Andrew Wyeth painting of Tyler Prentiss that dominates one whole wall of the study, and Ellie stops.</context>
      <utterance>The man is insane, Tom -- full-blown schizophrenia -- he's been stalking Raymond -- if you dare to use this --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your bipolar buddy has been sharing his dreams with Senator Jordan.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond smiles -- it's terrifying -- the fragile, forced, frigid smile of a man in pain.</context>
      <utterance>Hello Raymond.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jordan picks up a picture of Noyle and smoothes it onto the desk for Raymond to see, as:</context>
      <utterance>Hello Senator. How's Jocie?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we please not go down that road?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you recognize this man?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His name is Atticus Noyle. He is a South African physician, neuropsychiatric scientist and mercenary -- someone our CIA trained for covert mind warfare against the Soviets in Aghanistan -- someone who has sold technology to and done research for terrorist groups, and rogue states. Major Marco claims that this man --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, Ben Marco is sick. Delusional.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nevertheless he's pulled from his mad hat some remarkably lucid connections between his dreams of your exploits in Kuwait, and this Dr. Noyle, and the private equity fund Manchurian Global -- Raymond frowns, looks from Jordan to Ellie.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- your mother's primary political benefactor for the past fifteen years.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christ, Tom. They contribute to half the Senate, for God's sake. Silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the time of Desert Storm, Dr. Atticus Noyle was working under a research grant from Manchurian Global. Your mother's friend. The color suddenly drains out of Ellie's face.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rogue scientists. Mind control. Manchurian Global. Your mother. You. Connect the dots, Raymond. Possibly, your mother's blind to them, because they pay their way --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Possibly the Senator's motives are colored by his desperation to get himself back on the presidential ticket now that the heavy lifting is done --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't -- I don't --</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not about me. As far as I'm concerned, this should never come out -- it would shred what little remains of the fabric of our public trust -- think of the nation --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have the dreams.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He can't prove anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything you stand for is upside down! If this were to come out, true or no, it would be catastrophic for the campaign.  And it will come out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. The question hangs there.</context>
      <utterance>What are you saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances coolly at Ellie --</context>
      <utterance>You withdraw. You bow out gracefully. Personal reasons. An obscure illness. Yield your spot on the ticket, go into seclusion ...</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- and walks out. Raymond and Eleanor have hardly moved. Sound of the front door opening, closing.</context>
      <utterance>... and then surrender yourself to federal authorities who can help you address the damage that may have been inflicted on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel sick. Christ. What have you done to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raymond, remember when --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are actual tears in Ellie's eyes. Raymond just stares at her, coldly.</context>
      <utterance>NO, never mind -- don't bother. Don't lie. Don't say anything. No more lies.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can promise you that whatever you've done, I will undo it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know -- I know, baby --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never want to see you or speak to you again --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raymond --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond heads for the door --</context>
      <utterance>-- I mean it this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond slows -- curious to be addressed like this -- sound of the desert wind rises --</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant Shaw --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's turning -- the room coming alive -- light shifting, intensifying -- that terrible vividness -- and the wall of the zaghareet ...</context>
      <utterance>-- Sergeant Raymond Shaw --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's me, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait. Oh, don't do that, I can --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I came to apologize, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond catches the bow of the kayak, turns it.</context>
      <utterance>-- the water must be freezing. What are you doing? Raymond. Don't bother, I can --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>JORDAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With one motion, Raymond RIPS the two-blade paddle out of Jordan's hand, and FLIPS the boat over --</context>
      <utterance>I am too. But, your mother must --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- Jordan goes under, legs trapped in the kayak --</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JOCELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to shove Raymond away from the boat, but</context>
      <utterance>Raymond, what are you doing?! No! Stop it! Stop --!</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>turns, grabs her by the hood of her sweatshirt -- -- and whipsaws her out into the deeper water, shoving her under it. Jocelyn's hands claw at him, but he's stronger, and the water has no effect on him. She thrashes wildly ... and he looks down at her through the water, hair flowing, utterly beautiful ... as if in a dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhhhhhhh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, don't lecture me --</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't even ask us. You needed to ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom Jordan was going to destroy everything we've worked toward, and every one of us along with it, and you want me to call a meeting?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>David, if Jordan had gone public --</utterance>
   <speaker>DONOVAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellie stops, looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>In any endeavor, there are key players and role players, and Raymond -- or you, or me, for that matter -- I'm sorry -- we are role players, with fixed values and fixed agendas, that get weighed against other factors.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He just did what needed to be done.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit.  You can tell yourself that as you go to bed tonight, David, and I hope it helps you wake up tomorrow with a clean conscience -- but we are talking about my son and the future of this country.  My father, Tyler Prentiss, never asked.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He releases her throat, and she gasps for air --</context>
      <utterance>When. Where. How.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna stop this. We'll go to the Feds. You and me. And tell them a story.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who'll -- believe --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rosie bucks -- gets a hand free -- SLUGS, Marco, and they tumble off the bed in a tangle of blankets and limbs --</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I don't care any more. It's all I have.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the Feds. She coughs. Marco stares at her, dumbfounded.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been watching you, trying to sort this out. I mean, it's either you're telling it straight and we've all got something big-time to worry about, or you're crazy and dangerous -- either way we've had to keep you on a short leash, 'cuz if we lock you up we'll never know.  And we can't tell anybody because we don't know how deep this river runs.  If there is a river.  You got away from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raymond Shaw murdered Senator Jordan and his daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Ben. The thing is? I want to believe you. God help me, Ben, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- he's a time bomb, ticking --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody else wants you junked up on Thorazine and just not a problem any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am clearer on this than I've ever been. It's rich guys, funding bad science, to put a sleeper in the White House --</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. Silence, broken only by their breathing.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to yourself. You're a poster boy for paranoid fantasies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gets up -- Rosie's not going to shoot him --</context>
      <utterance>I screwed up. Jordan was my trump card, and I screwed it up.  Either help me, or shoot me, Rosie. There's no middle ground anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MIRELLA/ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- Raymond finds himself in the back seat of his limo, his campaign aide Mirella, her assistant, and Anderson, all startled and shouting too --</context>
      <utterance>Aaaahhhhhh --!</utterance>
   <speaker>MIRELLA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Yes. Bad dream.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond sits up.</context>
      <utterance>We've arrived, Congressman.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's your back?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It hurts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond locks the door, turns, takes in the room: tiny chairs and tables, walls covered with kids' drawings, and nearly every object in the room named and labelled with 3x5 cards.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been having the dreams, Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good? They're inside my head. They got inside, the way you said they would --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll get 'em out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're all ... twisted together -- and I dream things, terrible things, that can't possibly have happened. I'm gone, Ben -- I'm losing it --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- you could have had me locked up -- and you didn't. That's a sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That they don't control everything. We can fight it. I mean -- I'm still out here because you decided I should be -- which means there's a part they can't get to, deep inside -- the part where the truth is, and they can't touch us there. That's what we need to tap into, Raymond, that's the part where, you and me, we're gonna take them out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jocie's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and the Senator.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond looks up at Ben. Emotionless. Uncomprehending.</context>
      <utterance>I don't remember. I don't remember it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>KNOCKING on the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm all inside-out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANDERSON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Shaw?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond's cell phone RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Just a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I've ever done is what I was supposed to do. What I was told to do --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raymond -- focus --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- What others want me to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they tell you what they want you to do, Ray? We gotta know what's gonna happen, we gotta know when's it gonna happen -- you can help me do this --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't think they saw this coming? You don't think they factored you in?  I need to die, Ben.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? No -- no, man, they've got big plans for you --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the enemy, Major Marco, and the only way to stop me is to kill me. I thought you were smarter than this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can get the Feds, the police. Come on, Ray -- fight it --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we friends?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond takes the ringing phone from his inside pocket, and checks the number of who's calling.</context>
      <utterance>Raymond, you gotta work with me here --</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to believe we're friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Raymond, stay focused. The irrefutable fact is that Jocie was a mistake, and we're gonna make 'em pay for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dream you, Ben. You kill Private Baker.  Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A class BELL RINGS --</context>
      <utterance>Yes mother.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang up.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond extends the phone to Marco.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, he's right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco hesitates. Me? But takes the receiver --</context>
      <utterance>She wants you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this Major Marco?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it is, Senator.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco reacting quizzically -- sound of the distant windstorm building -- EXTREME CLOSE UP - MARCO - HIS EAR -- at the phone:</context>
      <utterance>-- Major Bennett Marco --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARCO'S EYES flicker to Raymond's eyes --</context>
      <utterance>Yeah ...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- Marco's senses are quickening -- the light literally changing around him -- that terrible LUMINOSITY -- as -- SOUND of fabric, in the wind -- the SANDSTORM RAGING -- Marco's eyes shining now, hyper-alert -- a warrior's eyes --</context>
      <utterance>Bennett Ezekiel Marco --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Listen:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>paranoid, lone gunman -- is trying to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She touches his bare shoulder, leaves her hand there.</context>
      <utterance>The Major is an excellent marksman.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what will happen to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs her hands through his hair. Tears fill her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure you will never entirely comprehend this, darling, and I know, the way you are right now, this is like trying to have a whimpered conversation with someone on a distant star ... but it must be said, Raymond -- I did this for you -- so that you could have what I could not, what your father didn't want -- what your grandfather dared to dream possible --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just enough to bring you back to me.</context>
      <utterance>-- when you ran away to join the Army, after that girl, after Jocie -- when you swore you'd never speak to me again, I felt your father's shadow pass across us, and I couldn't let him run you the way he ruined himself.  That's when Mark Whiting came to me with talk of extraordinary scientific breakthroughs ... Attitude adjustment ... Reconciliation ... Greatness. So I let them take you, and change you. Not too much. Not so much that you'd notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And look what you have, now! Look how far we've come! It's working, darling -- they think they own you, but they are very, very wrong. You're not something they can buy and sell, Raymond, not for</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>any price -- we're one, and there'll be no stopping us now, will there? We're going to save this country in the hour of its greatest need. Raymond is dazzled by Eddie's radiance.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAYMOND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She straightens his tie. Her hands caress her son's shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raymond moves to her -- their embrace is all consuming --</context>
      <utterance>How much you look like my father, now -- you have his hands, and you hold your head in the same proud way. And when you smile it's like I'm a little girl again, and --  When you smile -- when you smile --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-- there's Marco. The image slows. Marco moves herky-jerky through the security station, stop-action. Rosie pretends she's interested in somebody else -- then:</context>
      <utterance>Stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tape resumes triple-time --</context>
      <utterance>No ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DIRECTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUSIC starts: that lush, full orchestral rendition of "Here Comes the Sun" that sweeps through the ballroom.</context>
      <utterance>Now music --</utterance>
   <speaker>ABOVE THE BALLROOM - LIGHTING GRIDS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>change to rippling American Flags --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks to Rosie, who stands in an archway. There are SOLDIERS here, with weapons -- could be here to guard Marco. Could be here to protect him.</context>
      <utterance>You don't develop a technology like that and waste it on two guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROSIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco looks past her, to the water, which stretches out from here, as if to forever.</context>
      <utterance>We know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His arm is in a simple sling. He moves like a man who's been shot, and not quite recovered -- moves past Rosie, out of the broken-down ruins ...</context>
      <utterance>I remember running.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... Rosie motions the soldiers to stay back, follows him by herself ...</context>
      <utterance>I had to get out where the sky was.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL BACK as they walk down the beach to the sea. A few tumble-down buildings are all that remains of an ancient seaside town.</context>
      <utterance>I had to get to the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marco approaches the water's edge, staring out at the uncertain horizon. Nothing but water as far as the eye can see. PULL BACK. And back. And back ...</context>
      <utterance>I thought: if I can just get to the water, everything will be okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
