<movie id="425" title="Patriot The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up some of the wood, about to fling it across the room but stops as Susan shoots him a disapproving look. He calms himself.</context>
      <utterance>Damnation!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan gets down from the woodpile and puts the remains of the chair in the fireplace. As she climbs back up to her perch, Marion steps over to his wood rack, extracts a fresh dowel, fits it into the lathe and starts all over again.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, I saw a post rider at the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Did you finish the upper field?</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got it all cut and we bundled half of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion walks on without waiting for a reply from his contrite sons who jostle one another, trying to pass off the blame. Gabriel and Thomas walk out of the barn.</context>
      <utterance>Those swimming breaks cut into the day, don't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, a post rider came from Charleston. You have a letter inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. How's the spotted one's milk?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods and motions for Susan to go with Gabriel and Thomas to the house. She does so and Marion walks on alone toward:</context>
      <utterance>Better. She's near ready to calve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A soft wind blows some dry leaves along the ground. Marion pauses as if listening to a spoken reply.</context>
      <utterance>... and they bundled half... almost no trace of the boys you knew...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BREAKING, followed by the SOUND OF AN ARGUMENT rises from the house below. Marion shakes his head with an exasperated sigh.</context>
      <utterance>... no, she still hasn't spoken... Margaret was her age when you... I remember the time at the river when we couldn't find Catherine... you couldn't stop crying... and she was asleep in the wagon the entire time... Marion pauses, remembering. The CRASH OF A PLATE</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He heads down the hill toward the house, now glowing from the lights of candles and oil lamps.</context>
      <utterance>Your children.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I smell turnips...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, Samuel broke the blue plate...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did not...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion hands the apples to Abigail and steps over to open his mail and dispatches.</context>
      <utterance>Dinner...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>News of Boston, father?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hate turnips...</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>William knocked it right out of my hands...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion hands a packet of pamphlets to Gabriel and opens a letter.</context>
      <utterance>Samuel, William, both of you clean it up...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion's children go wild.</context>
      <utterance>The Assembly has been reconvened, I've been called to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charleston!</utterance>
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to Charleston!</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When, father, when?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children ERUPT INTO CHEERS and THUNDER into the dining room.</context>
      <utterance>We'll leave tomorrow...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion and Gabriel exchange a stone-faced look. Then Marion puts on a smile and inhales deeply.</context>
      <utterance>Charleston! We're going to Charleston!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion follows his children into the dining room.</context>
      <utterance>I love turnips...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan gazes up at the North Star. The girls notice Marion and climb into bed. He puts a chair against Susan's bed and kisses her. He pulls a blanket up around Margaret, who whispers:</context>
      <utterance>... now count five finger lengths up from the front two stars of the Big Dipper, and that's the North Star, that's her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods with a thin smile, kisses Margaret and walks out.</context>
      <utterance>It helps her to know Mother's there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The New York and Rhode Island assemblies have been dissolved...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The middle colonies?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rioting both sides of the bay, in Chestertown they burned the Customs House and tar-and-feathered the Customs Agent. He died of burns. In Wilmington they killed a Royal Magistrate and two Redcoats.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything about the convention in Philadelphia?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion shakes his head and sits down, carefully extracting a delicate pair of reading glasses from a wooden box. He begins reading.</context>
      <utterance>Poor Richard says they'll make a Declaration of Independence by July.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion hears but doesn't respond. Thomas looks up from his lead soldiers.</context>
      <utterance>Scott Higgins joined the militia.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's seventeen. A year younger than</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aunt Charlotte! Aunt Charlotte!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome! Welcome! Margaret, William, look at you...!  They're huge. What have you been feeding them?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're from good stock on their mother's side.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlotte hustles the children toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come, come, inside, wait until you see what I have...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Presents! For me? What do you have?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlotte sweeps past Marion who smiles and follows her into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Inside, inside...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look well, Charlotte.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Thomas and Samuel race through the doorway, forcing Marion and Charlotte together, their bodies close. They step back and exchange warm but uneasy smiles. The moment is broken by the SOUND OF CHILDREN. Marion and Charlotte gratefully turn their attention back to them.</context>
      <utterance>As do you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children turn to Marion with stricken expressions. Marion relents.</context>
      <utterance>Inside, all of you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children turn back to the mob. Marion joins them.</context>
      <utterance>Very well.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They see Gabriel making his way through the crowd. He sees them and waves, then enters the house. A moment later Charlotte steps out onto the balcony and sees: IN THE SQUARE, a pair of drunk Sons of Liberty, pull down one of the smoldering effigies, cut off its head, then start hacking at it's groin with a sword. Appalled, Charlotte shoots a glare at Marion and snaps at the children.</context>
      <utterance>Look! There's Gabriel!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children start to protest, but a glance at Charlotte's resolute expression makes them think better of it. They file into the house. Charlotte shoots a glare at Marion and shoos the children inside. Gabriel steps out and joins them.</context>
      <utterance>Children, inside! All of you! Right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What news?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The British army is barricaded in Boston. Harry Lee, is here from Virginia, recruiting for a Continental Army.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that why the Assembly was convened?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. He seeks a levy of troops and money.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the Governor?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He vowed that if the Assembly votes a single shilling to Lee, he'll dissolve the body.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which would force our delegates in Philadelphia to vote for independence.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And send us to war alongside Massachusetts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our governor is a bigger fool than I thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods thoughtfully without revealing what he thinks of Lee's expectations. Marion turns back to watch the mob.</context>
      <utterance>Lee is counting on your vote and expects you to be the first to enlist.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="67">
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our first order of business...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ROOM ERUPTS.</context>
      <utterance>And out last if we vote a levy...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ROOM SETTLES DOWN.</context>
      <utterance>ORDER! ORDER! Mr. Simms, you do not have the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An imposing figure rises and makes his way to the front of the assembly. He's COLONEL HARRY LEE, about Marion's age and cut from the same cloth -- strong, weathered, with a powerful bearing. The room quiets down. Lee sees Marion and offers a familiar nod, which Marion returns, stone-faced. Then Lee speaks, simply and clearly.</context>
      <utterance>Our first order of business is an address by Colonel Harry Lee of the Continental Army.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all know why I am here. I am not an orator and I will not try to convince you of the worthiness of our cause. I am a soldier and we are at war and with the declaration of independence we all expect from Philadelphia, it will soon be a formal state of war. In preparation for that, eight of the thirteen colonies have levied money in support of a Continental Army. I ask South Carolina to be the ninth.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel Lee, Massachusetts may be at war, along with New Hampshire and Rhode Island and Virginia, but South Carolina is not at war.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Massachusetts and New Hampshire are not as far from South Carolina as you might think and the war they're fighting is not for independence of one or two colonies. It's for the independence of a nation.</utterance>
   <speaker>WITHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robinson, one of the Patriots, stands up.</context>
      <utterance>And what nation is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An American nation. Colonel Lee, with your permission?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those of us who call ourselves Patriots are not seeking to give birth to an American nation, but to protect one that already exists. It was born a hundred-and-seventy years ago at Jamestown, Virginia and has grown stronger and more mature with every generation reared and with every crop sown and harvested. We are a nation and our rights as citizens of that nation are threatened by a tyrant three thousand miles away.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter. Marion rises.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Were I an orator, those are the exact words I would have spoken.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter from the Loyalists. Surprise from Lee and the Patriots. In the gallery, Gabriel winces.</context>
      <utterance>Mister Robinson, tell me, why should I trade one tyrant, three thousand miles away, for three thousand tyrants, one mile away?</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An elected legislature can trample a man's rights just as easily as a King can.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Captain Marion, I understood you to be a Patriot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Mister Marion.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More laughter.</context>
      <utterance>I understood him to be a Patriot as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Laughter.</context>
      <utterance>If you mean by a Patriot, am I angry at the Townsend Acts and the Stamp Act? Then I'm a Patriot. And what of the Navigation Act? Should I be permitted to sell my tobacco to the French traders on Martinique? Yes, and it's an intrusion into my affairs that I can't... legally.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion grows more serious.</context>
      <utterance>And what of the greedy, self-serving bastards who sit as Magistrates on the Admiralty Court and have fined nearly every man in this room. Should they be boxed about the ears and thrown onto the first ship back to England? I'll do it myself.  And do I believe that the American colonies should stand as a separate, independent nation, free from the reins of King and Parliament? I do, and if that makes a Patriot, then I'm a Patriot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room is quiet, the Assemblymen having been thrown off- balance. Gabriel is stunned and disappointed by his father's speech.</context>
      <utterance>But if you're asking whether I'm willing to go to war with England, the answer is, no. I've been to war and I have no desire to do so again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion glares at Robinson, then smiles.</context>
      <utterance>This from the same Captain Francis Marion whose anger was so famous during the Wilderness Campaign.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Robinson looks derisively at Marion.</context>
      <utterance>I was intemperate in my youth. My departed wife, God bless her soul, dampened that intemperance with the mantle of responsibility.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion bristles but before he can answer, Lee steps in.</context>
      <utterance>Temperance can be a convenient disguise for fear.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Robinson, I fought with Captain Marion in the French and Indian War, including the Wilderness Campaign. We served as scouts under Washington and I have no doubts about Captain Marion's courage or competence on a battlefield. There's not a man in this room, or anywhere, for that matter, to whom I would more willingly trust my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I stand corrected.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee's oratorical skills peter out.</context>
      <utterance>Nonetheless, I would like to know, Mister Marion, how... how... how...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn it, Francis! How in God's name do you expect to gain independence without going to war?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion and Lee drop all formality and become nothing more than two old friends, pissed off.</context>
      <utterance>Harry, Harry, Harry...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Speaker POUNDS HIS GAVEL.</context>
      <utterance>My hairy arse! You live in a cave if you think we'll get independence without war...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen! Please! This is not a tavern!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wasn't it a Union Jack we fought under?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A long time ago...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirteen years...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Speaker POUNDS HIS GAVEL again.</context>
      <utterance>That's a damn long time...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion and Lee ignore the speaker.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen! Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were an Englishman then...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The astonished Assemblymen and now even the Speaker watch the argument avidly, turning their heads in simultaneous anticipation of each rejoinder.</context>
      <utterance>I was an American, I just didn't know it yet...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't have to go to war to gain independence...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Balderdash!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are a thousand avenues, other than war, at our disposal...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name five hundred.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Royal petition, delegates to court, judicial redress, economic boycott, bribery...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's five, keep going...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... time, royal succession, regicide, bribery...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion speaks slowly and firmly.</context>
      <utterance>You said bribery twice...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee says nothing for a moment, then he speaks more seriously, quietly, grimly.</context>
      <utterance>We do not have to go to war to gain independence.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>himself unsteady and speaks far more honestly than he ever wanted to.</context>
      <utterance>Francis, I was at Bunker Hill. It was as bad as anything you and I saw on the frontier. Worse than the slaughter at the Ashuelot River. The British advanced three times and we killed over seven hundred of them at point blank range. And still, they advanced and they took the ground. That is the measure of their resolve. If your principles dictate independence, then war is the only way. It has come to that. Marion is silent for a long moment. He softens, finds</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee is stunned by Marion's honesty and his show of weakness. At first Lee has no answer, then:</context>
      <utterance>I have seven children. My wife is dead. Who's to care for them if I go to war?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wars are not fought only by childless men. A man must weigh his personal responsibilities against his principles.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm doing. I will not fight and because I won't, I will not cast a vote that will send others to fight in my stead.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your principles?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other Assemblymen, both Patriots and Loyalists, stare at him, appalled. Marion, feeling weak, sits down. Lee looks at his friend with more sympathy than disappointment. Then Lee turns to Robinson who addresses the chair.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a parent, I don't have the luxury of principles.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister Speaker, I call for a vote on a levy to the Continental Army.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Second.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The vote is taken on a roll call. Gabriel watches from the gallery.</context>
      <utterance>So moved.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Robinson.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBINSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Hamill.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Johnson.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOHNSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Simms.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nay.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Marion.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPEAKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Marion.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the gallery Gabriel turns and walks out. The roll call continues. Marion sits, eyes straight ahead.</context>
      <utterance>Nay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PAGE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Continental Captain motions to an assembled squadron. They raise their muskets and FIRE A VOLLEY into the air. Other soldiers, STRIKE UP A MARTIAL AIR ON FIFES AND DRUMS. Volunteers crowd around the recruiting table, YELLING and jostling for position. The delegates walk out. Both Patriots and Loyalists give Marion a wide berth. Marion sees Gabriel, standing near the crowd at the recruiting table. Marion walks up to him.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-eight to twelve, the levy passed!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, I've lost respect for you. I thought you were a man of principle.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you have children, I hope you'll understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion looks closely at Gabriel.</context>
      <utterance>When I have children, I hope I don't hide behind them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you intend to enlist without my permission?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They lock eyes for a moment, then Gabriel turns from his father and walks away, joining the crush around the recruiting table. Marion stands alone in the middle of the chaos. The FIFES AND DRUMS continue to play. Marion doesn't hear them. Harry Lee walks out of the Assembly hall with a triumphant group of Patriots who look at Marion coldly. Lee excuses himself, and steps over next to Marion. Lee sees that Marion is watching Gabriel at the enlistment table.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of yours?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gabriel.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I recognize him now. Is he as imprudent as his father was at his age?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, thank the Lord. He's more like his mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see to it that he serves under me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands. Then Lee walks over to the soldiers. Marion takes a last look at Gabriel, then heads off through the crowded square, moving against the tide of men headed toward the recruiting table.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet, Thomas.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion looks closely at his son, giving him the courtesy of really thinking about the answer.</context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seventeen.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it's already been two years and that's two more years. The war could be over by then.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas considers it, then nods.</context>
      <utterance>God willing.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion offers his hand. They shake firmly, like adults. Marion takes the coat off Thomas and puts it back in the trunk. They walk down the stairs together.</context>
      <utterance>Alright. Seventeen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it going to rain?</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SOUND BECOMES DEEPER, MORE OMINOUS. They all notice the change.</context>
      <utterance>That's not thunder.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six-pounders. Lots of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far away?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four, five miles.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Waxhaus?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just east of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion puts on a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Are we safe here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could go stay at Aunt Charlotte's farm. She's to the west.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas appears at the doorway with a pair of muskets. He gives one to Nathan and offers the other to his father.</context>
      <utterance>No, there'll be skirmishers on the roads. We're safer here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put those away.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But father, they might come this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, Thomas takes the muskets back into the house.</context>
      <utterance>Put them away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all nod. Marion walks off toward the workshop, followed by Susan. The others hesitate.</context>
      <utterance>Enough. I'll be in the workshop. Samuel, the cows. Thomas, attend to your studies here on the porch. Nathan, on the back porch. If you see anyone, come get me. Margaret, please keep William close to you. No one is to go past the yard wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They head off to do as they were told.</context>
      <utterance>Children.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He doesn't respond. Margaret, trailed by William, walks down toward Samuel.</context>
      <utterance>Samuel...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she sees it, too. The pale pink is turning redder and redder. And then the BODIES. First one, then more, many more. Torn apart. Missing limbs. Those with wide- open wounds, are already drained of blood. Others are still seeping, leaving trails of deep red in the paler red of the surrounding water. Samuel, Margaret and William stand frozen, appalled and fascinated. MARION steps out of the workshop and sees the children at the river. He can't see what they're looking at. Irritated, he walks toward them. Then, as he nears the river, he sees the color of the water and the bodies that have hypnotized his children. He quickens his stride, speaking calmly but firmly, careful not to frighten them.</context>
      <utterance>Samuel, get up to the house. You heard father...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up to the house, now. All of you, come on. Now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SAMUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're going to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to have to fight them off.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father will do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>SAMUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll probably kill us men and do Lord knows what to you women.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SOUND. They all stop. Something moved behind the kitchen. Margaret silently eases the others out of the room, through the darkened hall toward their father.</context>
      <utterance>Samuel!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel is wounded, battered and dirty. He carries a musket and a dispatch case. He sways. Marion catches him and eases him to a seat.</context>
      <utterance>Gabriel!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The battle, were you there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion checks Gabriel's wounds which are nasty but not life-threatening.</context>
      <utterance>Margaret, get bandages and water. Thomas, the porch, eyes open.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you seen any Redcoats?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margaret brings water and linen to Marion who expertly cleans Gabriel's wounds and applies field-dressings.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet. What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion's appalled.</context>
      <utterance>It wasn't like Saratoga. There, we stayed in the trees, but this time Gates marched us straight at the Redcoats. They fired two volleys into us and we broke like straw. I was given these dispatches... I saw Virginia Regulars surrender... as they laid down their weapons the British Green Dragoons rode into them and hacked them to bits... killed them all, over two hundred men.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel nods. Marion's stunned. Gabriel tries to rise.</context>
      <utterance>They had surrendered?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to get these dispatches to Hillsboro.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in no condition to ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel passes out. Marion catches him and carries him to a day-bed in the parlor. As Marion lays him down, they hear HEAVY MUSKET FIRE, VERY CLOSE. Marion hurries to the door and looks out into the night, the children cluster around him, seeing a strange sight.</context>
      <utterance>I have no choice, I...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion moves on to another.</context>
      <utterance>He's dead...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn over a young Continental and see a horrible wound on his back. Thomas, swoons.</context>
      <utterance>Thomas, help me turn him over...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hard glare from Marion strengthens his son. Together they bandage the wounded man.</context>
      <utterance>Thomas!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CONTINENTAL SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods, uncomfortable with the thanks.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Continental Sergeant knows what's coming. The Privates and Marion's children don't.</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant, there are seventeen wounded men here. Seven Redcoats and ten Patriots, counting my son inside. That puts me in a difficult position.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Privates are stunned at the request. The Sergeant looks at Marion's children and nods.</context>
      <utterance>You three are the least severely wounded. I have to ask you to leave and find care elsewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He struggles to his feet and jerks his head for the two Privates to do the same.</context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nathan, Samuel and Margaret are confused.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, boys.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father?</utterance>
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they're wounded.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion motions to a large, old scar on his arm.</context>
      <utterance>There are rules, even in war.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion's children are not convinced. The Sergeant and the two Privates gather themselves to leave.</context>
      <utterance>After the Battle of Ashuelot River, against the French, I got this and the one on my leg. I couldn't walk. Washington had to march north. He left me with other wounded men and a like number of French prisoners. Nine for nine. When the French found us, their surgeon gave me the best of care. We'll be safe this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wounded men nod grimly and start off down the road.</context>
      <utterance>Your best chance is in Bennington, seven miles east, along the river road.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion and his children watch them go.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're surrendering.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONTINENTAL SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What unit?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONTINENTAL SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First Virginia Regulars under Colonel Hamilton.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hesitate.</context>
      <utterance>Who cared for your wounds?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONTINENTAL SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We did.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton turns to his second-in-command, MAJOR WILKINS.</context>
      <utterance>With a lace table cloth?</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton rides off. Wilkins and several other Dragoons calmly FIRE THEIR PISTOLS, killing the three Patriots. The troops ride off, thundering past the bodies of the three men.</context>
      <utterance>Kill them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REDCOAT LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods. ONE OF THE REDCOATS emerges from the house carrying Gabriel's dispatch case.</context>
      <utterance>These men are of my regiment. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>REDCOAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel steps up.</context>
      <utterance>Rebel dispatches, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I carried those. I was wounded, these people gave me care, they have nothing to do with the dispatches.</utterance>
   <speaker>REDCOAT LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand. The SOUND OF HORSES HOOVES. All turn and see:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant, have a detachment take our wounded to our surgeons at Camden crossing. Use whatever horses and wagons you can find here.</utterance>
   <speaker>REDCOAT LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the dispatch case to Tarleton.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>REDCOAT LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton opens it and quickly scans the contents.</context>
      <utterance>We found this, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who carried this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion quickly steps between Tarleton and Gabriel.</context>
      <utterance>Take this one to Camden, he's a spy. He will be hung.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton ignores Marion and continues speaking to the Lieutenant.</context>
      <utterance>Colonel, he's a dispatch rider and that's a marked dispatch case.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fire the house and barns.</utterance>
   <speaker>REDCOAT LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel...</utterance>
   <speaker>REDCOAT LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the Rebel wounded?</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Redcoat Lieutenant and several of his men are shocked by the order. Marion is, also, but he's more concerned with Gabriel. He pushes past some Redcoats and stands at Tarleton's mount, looking up.</context>
      <utterance>Kill them.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton finally pays attention to Marion. He looks down at his anguished face and offers the barest of smiles.</context>
      <utterance>A dispatch rider with a marked case cannot be held for spying.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not going to hold him, we're going to hang him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton draws his pistol and points it at Marion. Gabriel tries to intercede but is held back by a burly Redcoat Corporal.</context>
      <utterance>But...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father...</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he's your son. You should have taught him about loyalty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton controls his shifting mount, keeping his pistol trained on Marion's face.</context>
      <utterance>Colonel, I beg you, please reconsider. By the rules of war, a dispatch rider with a marked case...</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion doesn't answer. He looks up at Tarleton coldly, taking his measure, waiting to see if he's going to pull the trigger. Tarleton walks his horse a couple of steps and shifts his aim, pointing the pistol among Marion's children.</context>
      <utterance>Would you like a lesson in the rules of war?</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The children are terrified. Thomas is more angry than frightened. Marion quickly steps between the pistol and his children and speaks quietly to Tarleton.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps your children would.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton sees the terrified expressions on the faces of Marion's children. He smiles at the effect. Then he holsters his pistol. Marion and his children watch as one of the Redcoats ties Gabriel's hands. Thomas is beside himself.</context>
      <utterance>No lesson is necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thomas grows increasingly agitated. He sees that his father is going to do nothing. He gauges the distance between Gabriel and the cover of the nearby woods. Then suddenly, Thomas SPRINGS. He RUNS, THROWING HIMSELF, into the two Redcoats holding Gabriel, KNOCKING THEM DOWN.</context>
      <utterance>Father, do something.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel is too shocked to take flight. A few of the Redcoats, including one of the ones knocked down, shake their heads with sad laughter at Thomas' ineffectual gesture. One of them grabs Thomas by the scruff of the neck and yanks him to his feet. TARLETON sees the commotion. Without pausing he DRAWS HIS</context>
      <utterance>Gabriel! Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton spurs his horse and rides off without looking back. His GREEN DRAGOONS THUNDER after him. MARION'S CHILDREN begin to cry. Margaret tries to revive Thomas' lifeless body, gently caressing his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Redcoats watch in silence. MARION LOOKS AT GABRIEL and turns to the Redcoat Lieutenant.</context>
      <utterance>Thomas, please, Thomas...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lieutenant wavers, but he looks after the departing Tarleton and his resolve stiffens. He turns coldly to Marion.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant, please...</utterance>
   <speaker>REDCOAT LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Redcoat infantrymen scatter, some to get horses and wagons from the barn, others to torch the buildings. MARION stands among the children, all of whom look to Marion with pleading eyes, waiting for him to do something.</context>
      <utterance>I have my orders. Sergeant!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Papa, look what they did to Thomas...</utterance>
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With stone-faced fury, Marion watches the Redcoats do their work. From the barns, they hear the sounds of MUSKETS FIRING and the SQUEALS OF THE LIVESTOCK being killed. Other REDCOATS TORCH THE HOUSE, BARN AND OUTBUILDINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Father, they're going to take Gabriel...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, you can't let them take him...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without breaking stride, Marion throws muskets to Nathan and Samuel who catch them.</context>
      <utterance>Nathan, Samuel...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Margaret, take William and Susan to the river shed. Hide there. If we're not back by dawn, go up the river to the Richardson's house. They'll take you to your Aunt Charlotte's farm. Nathan, Samuel, and I are going to get Gabriel.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what about Thomas?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion runs off toward the woods, Nathan and Samuel follow. Margaret hesitates, then herds William and Susan toward the river. The house is enveloped in flames.</context>
      <utterance>Leave him. Take care of William and Susan.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys go where they're told.</context>
      <utterance>Nathan, there. Samuel, there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stagger under the weight of the orders. Marion notices but continues.</context>
      <utterance>I'll fire first. Then, Nathan, kill whoever is standing closest to Gabriel. Samuel, kill the last man in the line.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys hesitate. Marion looks at them firmly.</context>
      <utterance>After that, Samuel, load for Nathan. If something happens to me, put down your weapons and run as fast as you can, that way, downhill. Hide in the brush by the river, then make your way home, get the others and go to Aunt Charlotte's farm.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boys... steady.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATHAN &amp; SAMUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion disappears into the underbrush.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, father.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stiffens, speaking formally:</context>
      <utterance>There, there... he's alright... he's with your mother now...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord, we pray that You accept this child, Thomas Marion and give him a place at Your side with his mother. We ask that You embrace him and help us to understand the manner in which Your mercy works. This we ask, in Your name. Amen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION'S CHILDREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion looks at Elizabeth's grave, then he gently eases his children away.</context>
      <utterance>Amen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion moves on to Nathan.</context>
      <utterance>Sleep, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father... I killed those men...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't blame yourself, you did what I told you to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion isn't. He turns to Samuel who's cried-out. Marion reaches out to touch him but Samuel recoils from Marion's blood-streaked hand. Marion sighs and tucks him in.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad I killed them... I'm glad...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion moves to take Susan from Charlotte who shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Try to get some sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods and leaves Charlotte with the children.</context>
      <utterance>I'll stay with them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion just shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>How are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods. Marion and Gabriel stand in silence for a long moment, neither one finding words. Then Gabriel speaks softly.</context>
      <utterance>Gates is at Hillsboro with the Continental Army. I'll leave in the morning to join him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves Marion alone.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tend my horse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion is silent. Charlotte pours water into a washbowl and motions to Marion. He takes off his shirt. She begins cleaning away the blood and tending the wound on his neck.</context>
      <utterance>They're asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did this... how did I let this happen?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You couldn't have known.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should have known... once I would have... I used to be wary... and today I watched my son killed before my eyes... your sister civilized me and I damn myself for having let her...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thomas is dead but you've done nothing for which you should be ashamed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him closely.</context>
      <utterance>I've done nothing and for that I am ashamed.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you go, I'll care for them as if they were my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares past her, looking at the flames in the fireplace. She tends his wounds.</context>
      <utterance>I'll leave in the morning with Gabriel.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When will you be back?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, William.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion winces. Margaret puts her arm around William.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion kisses them both, then moves on to Susan, trying to coax a word out of the silent four-year-old:</context>
      <utterance>No, not tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She just looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan shakes her head. He sighs, rises and turns to Charlotte. They hesitate, then embrace, hugging deeply but a bit awkwardly, holding each other just a moment longer than one would expect. She looks up at him... he kisses her on the cheek. Marion mounts up. And he and Gabriel head off, Susan, unnoticed and unheard, whispers:</context>
      <utterance>Just one word? Goodbye? That's all I want.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion and Gabriel ride away.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel stops. Marion points out brightly colored clusters of men behind each army.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The distant slash of red stops. Marion and Gabriel hear only a GENTLE WIND and some nearby SONGBIRDS. Then, from a black mass of the side of the red slash, a sudden, silent eruption of white smoke. An instant later, the blue slash quivers. A moment later the SOUND OF THE CANNONS, RUMBLES UP THE HILL and rolls over Marion and Gabriel. The RED SLASH STOPS moving. It darkens as thousands of Redcoats raise their muskets and the front ranks kneel into firing position. Marion's eyes dart. He knows what's coming.</context>
      <utterance>Command posts... Patriot... British...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MASSIVE ERUPTION OF WHITE SMOKE billows from the red slash. An instant later, the blue line starts to break up as hundreds of distant Patriots fall. The SOUND OF THE BRITISH MUSKETS reaches Marion and Gabriel like the pattering of rain. Then the SMOKE OF INEFFECTIVE, SCATTERED VOLLEYS erupts from the Patriot lines. The red line holds firm.</context>
      <utterance>Break for the trees... break for the trees...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the blue line of the Patriots stays in the open field. From behind the Redcoats, FAST-MOVING GREEN AND RED MASSES move quickly onto the battlefield. CAVALRY.</context>
      <utterance>Send them to cover! Goddamn you!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The British cavalry slams into the blue line, shattering it. Tiny bits of blue move in every direction.</context>
      <utterance>Father, we have to do something...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion watches, appalled. At this distance the moving slashes of color and billowing smoke are strangely beautiful. Marion turns his horse and heads down the hill, toward the rear of the Patriot lines.</context>
      <utterance>It's already over.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn you, Sergeant, don't move the wounded twice, put them straight on the wagons from the surgeons.</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRIOT SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant, detail men for outriders. We move out as soon as the wounded are ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lieutenant rushes off. Lee notices Marion and Gabriel, surprised to see them. He jerks his head for them to follow him into:</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Green Dragoons came to my home, killed my son, Thomas. It was Tarleton himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I wasn't here for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing you could have done, Gates is a damned fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We saw.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I begged him to stay in the cover of the trees but he insisted the only way to break Cornwallis was muzzle- to-muzzle. He spent too many years in the British army.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he now?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last anyone saw, riding hard, northeast, his staff a hundred yards behind, trying to catch up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's in command?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am, I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee gives Marion a tired smile.</context>
      <utterance>What are my orders?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee ROLLS OUT A MAP for Marion and Gabriel.</context>
      <utterance>If you want orders, I've got some for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're a breath away from losing this war. In the North, Washington is reeling from Valley Forge, running and hiding from Clinton and twelve thousand Redcoats.  Here in the South, Cornwallis has broken our back. He captured over five thousand of our troops when he took Charleston and today he destroyed the only army that stood between him and New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So now Cornwallis will head north, link up with Clinton and finish off Washington.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Patriots will start dying on the gallows instead of the battlefield.  Unless we can keep Cornwallis in the South until the French arrive. A treaty was signed at Versailles after our victory at Saratoga. The French are sending a fleet and ten thousand troops.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fall, six months at the earliest.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bigger problem is where, not when. The French fleet won't sail north of the Chesapeake for fear of early storms.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're going to try to keep Cornwallis in the South until then.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me, you. I'm going north with every Continental regular I can find to reinforce Washington or he won't last six weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You expect Cornwallis to be held here by militia?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not held, just slowed down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're nothing but farmers and you're asking them to try to keep a tiger in their backyard. They'd be better off letting it move on.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'd be better off, but the cause wouldn't be.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many men does Cornwallis have under his command?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the mention of Tarleton, Marion nods.</context>
      <utterance>Four thousand infantry and around six hundred cavalry...  ... including the Green Dragoons under Tarleton.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee quickly writes something.</context>
      <utterance>I'll do what I can.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm giving you a field commission as a colonel. He hands it to Marion. Gabriel steps forward.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel Lee, I request a transfer to Colonel Marion's command.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee scribbles another order and hands it to Gabriel. Then he turns to Marion.</context>
      <utterance>Granted.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods. They duck out of the tent.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What now, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We put out the word. We'll start along the south side of the Santee...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd cover more ground if we split up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel steps in front of Marion.</context>
      <utterance>It's safer if we stay together.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel, I didn't request this transfer because you're my father. I requested it because I believe in this cause and this is where I can do the most good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been doing this for two years. I'm the best scout in the Continental Army, the best horseman, the best shot, the best scavenger and I know every deer path and swamp trail between here and Charleston.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that so?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion looks at Gabriel closely.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.  My father taught me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did your father teach you humility?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion looks Gabriel up and down.</context>
      <utterance>He tried. It didn't take.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We'll meet at Snow's Island.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, Corporal, you take Bennington, Harrisville, Acworth and the farms along Black Swamp. I'll take the north side of the river.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They mount up.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, Corporal...  ... be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They ride off in different directions.</context>
      <utterance>Yes...  ... father.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking for John Billings.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion looks closely at the grim, suspicious men.</context>
      <utterance>He's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he comes back from the dead, tell him Francis Marion is looking for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Marion turns to leave he notices an open bottle of Madeira on one of the tables. He stops.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be sure to do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A stand-off. Then, a hulking FIGURE appears in the shadows at the back doorway. He's JOHN BILLINGS, big, coarse, about Marion's age. Billings jerks his head for Marion to join him in the back room.</context>
      <utterance>I'll wait. Miracles happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You expect to hold Cornwallis with militia?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I expect to try.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust you and Harry Lee. Remember that damned overland you two thought up in '62 to hit Fort Louis?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It worked. How many men can you raise?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion drains his glass and stands up.</context>
      <utterance>Not many. Dalton, Scott, they've got their reasons; Rev. Oliver, he believes in the cause; some of the young bucks; a few like me with nothing to lose...  What about you? You've got a lot to lose.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billings drains his glass. They walk out together.</context>
      <utterance>You coming, or not?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion doesn't look up.</context>
      <utterance>Father, this war is about more than Thomas.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're here only for revenge, you're doing a disservice to him as well as yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how old I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion puts some more lead soldiers into the pan. Gabriel shakes his head, turns away and goes to tend his horse.</context>
      <utterance>God help us all when you're forty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reverend.</utterance>
   <speaker>REV. OLIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion accepts his condolences. He notes GEORGE DALTON, a tough-looking, rustic man with an ice-cold, distant stare.</context>
      <utterance>I heard about your son. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dalton doesn't respond. Marion recognizes another face, ABNER BROWN, African-American, around thirty, rugged. Marion addresses the men who do not gather around so much as just give him their attention.</context>
      <utterance>Dalton.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion pauses and looks over at Gabriel.</context>
      <utterance>You all have your own reasons for being here. I lost a son and I intend to kill the man who killed him...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel nods, approvingly.</context>
      <utterance>... But I don't consider that man's life adequate payment for the life of my son, and killing him won't keep the sons of other men from dying...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion looks from face to face.</context>
      <utterance>Cornwallis has to move north. We have to keep him right here. If he's south of the Chesapeake when the French arrive, if the French arrive, we have a chance of winning this war.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion heads back to his campsite, passing Gabriel without looking at him, but very aware of his son's eyes on him.</context>
      <utterance>Eat, get some rest, we move out in two hours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officers gather around the map.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major, this is not an adequate map.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HUNTINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have better coming on the trailing supply convoy from Charleston.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A useful place for our maps.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HUNTINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton enters, followed by Wilkins.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir, it won't happen again.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My harrier. Join us, Colonel.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton and Wilkins join them around the map.</context>
      <utterance>Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, celebration is premature. We have a difficult campaign ahead of us. We are in predominately hostile country and we cannot rely on forage. As we move north, the bulk of our supplies will reach us by sea, through Charleston, which will give us a long and vulnerable supply line, one that can only be secured if the locals are loyal to the crown.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS' OFFICERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis turns to his field officers, paying particular attention to Tarleton.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton proudly holds Cornwallis' look.</context>
      <utterance>Nonetheless, we must remember that this is a civil war...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilkins shifts uneasily. Tarleton isn't cowed.</context>
      <utterance>These colonials are our brethren and when this conflict is over, we will be reestablishing commerce with them. Surrendering troops will be given quarter and unwarranted assaults on civilians will cease.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis looks at his other officers.</context>
      <utterance>I expect this war to be fought in a vigorous but civilized manner.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have I made myself clear, gentlemen?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis shifts his eyes back to Tarleton who was not among those who spoke. Tarleton pointedly pauses a moment, then says:</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis turns his attention back to the map. His men gather around.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe he was speaking to us, Colonel.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton jerks his reins and rides off. Wilkins laughs and follows.</context>
      <utterance>Did you know that Lord Cornwallis' father was a tenant on the estate of my grandfather?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Less than a mile. Forty-one wagons, a company of Redcoat infantry, horses at the rear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flanking riders?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods and motions to his men who check their weapons and pass the word. Gabriel ties up his horse and takes a position near his father.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't see any.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REDCOAT LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion calls to his men.</context>
      <utterance>Across the river! Covering fire! Double rank!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion and his men FIRE A WITHERING VOLLEY, KILLING ALL REDCOATS OF RANK -- two lieutenants, a sergeant and several corporals. The LEADERLESS REDCOAT PRIVATES take cover as Marion's men OPEN UP on the Redcoats on their side of the river.</context>
      <utterance>Epaulets first... Kill the officers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>REV. OLIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... two-hundred-sixty-six Brown Bess muskets, forty-one casks of powder, balls, tamping...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion checks out a wagon full of tools with DAN SCOTT and ROB FIELDING, a couple of sharp-eyed craftsmen. They overlap dialogue, rapidly speaking the private language of colonial artisans.</context>
      <utterance>We have enough arms for an army. Now all we need is an army.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reamer, boring tool...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Swage, broach, etching tool...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIELDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A rolling gunsmith's shop...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can rifle those musket barrels...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIELDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get another hundred yards out of 'em...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll need a forge...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Easy enough...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've got clay to make a chamber...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIELDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oak to make charcoal...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oil cloth and barrel staves to make a bellows...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scott and Fielding exchange an impressed look.</context>
      <utterance>And we can yank a wagon wheel, weight it, rig a piston and drive shaft and we'll have a flywheel to power the bellows...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dalton prepares to do so.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot them! Shoot the damn things!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put that pistol down!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCOTT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion steps forward, speaking softly but firmly to the dogs.</context>
      <utterance>They followed us from the bridge. They won't let anyone near the wagon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dogs waver between obeying Marion and ripping out his throat.</context>
      <utterance>Stay... stay... stay...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dogs decide to obey. Marion lets them sniff his hand, then firmly pats them.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you growl at me!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rev. Oliver and Abner join him. Billings eases past the dogs. Abner opens a large case and finds it filled with bottles.</context>
      <utterance>Now let's see what's in this wagon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rum, French Champagne, Madeira, Port...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel opens a trunk and finds it filled with powdered wigs, all perfectly coifed and stored on head-shaped wig- stands. Rev. Oliver opens one of several identical cases and finds it filled with papers.</context>
      <utterance>No wonder they were guarding it.</utterance>
   <speaker>REV. OLIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion grabs some papers, scans them, then finds matching cases on nearby wagons.</context>
      <utterance>My heavens, personal correspondence of... Lord Cornwallis.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These four wagons must be his.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the dogs, too, I'll wager.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say we drink the wine, shoot the dogs, and use the papers for musket wadding.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abner calls from another wagon.</context>
      <utterance>His journals, letters, maps, books...</utterance>
   <speaker>ABNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ignoring Abner, Marion, sits down on a stump with a pile of Cornwallis' papers and starts to read.</context>
      <utterance>Colonel, we got a wagon full of officer's uniforms and more powder and muskets here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion looks at Dalton, then turns to the other men as well.</context>
      <utterance>Today was hard earned but a good start.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the future wounded British soldiers will be given quarters.</utterance>
   <speaker>DALTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like they gave quarter to my family? My wife and three children were hiding in our root cellar when they came. The Redcoats locked the door and torched the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have my sympathy... but the order stands.</utterance>
   <speaker>DALTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That hits home but Marion remains calm.</context>
      <utterance>And who are you to give an order like that? We all know what you did after Fort Wilderness.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion looks from face to face. Most begrudgingly nod. That's enough for Marion. As he heads back to his own campfire he's intercepted by Rev. Oliver who speaks to him out of earshot of the other men, except for Gabriel and Billings who overhear.</context>
      <utterance>I'm your commanding officer. This is militia, not regular army. I can't hold you here, but as long as you stay, you'll follow my orders.</utterance>
   <speaker>REV. OLIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>REV. OLIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For trying to impose some decency on that sort.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion walks on. Rev. Oliver exchanges a look with Gabriel, then heads off. As Marion joins Gabriel and Billings at his campfire, Billings grips his bottle.</context>
      <utterance>Don't depend on my decency. I'm one of that sort.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I one of that sort?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billings considers that, then shrugs and takes a long drink. He hands the bottle to Marion who takes an equally long drink. Marion picks up his Pennsylvania rifle.</context>
      <utterance>You're the worst of that sort. You're the sort that gives that sort a bad name.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He disappears into the darkness leaving Gabriel and Billings at the campfire.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to check the watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He shouldn't make light. That Redcoat should not have been killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel shoots Billings a dubious look.</context>
      <utterance>He's not making light.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know him very well, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billings looks closely at Gabriel.</context>
      <utterance>He's my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know him well enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel looks at Billings, then turns back to the fire.</context>
      <utterance>Don't fault him for having grown up on the frontier. It was a harder time and a harder place than you know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've just been inside the mind of a genius. Lord Cornwallis knows more about war than I could in a dozen lifetimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheerful news to greet the morn.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all turn to Marion.</context>
      <utterance>His victories at Charleston and Camden were perfect, strategically, tactically, logistically. But he has a weakness.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord Cornwallis is brilliant. His weakness is that he knows it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men consider that.</context>
      <utterance>Pride is his weakness.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Personally, I'd prefer stupidity.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BEGIN MONTAGE: Series of shots as follows: -- A VOLLEY OF MUSKET FIRE erupts from some thick underbrush, cutting down half of a squadron of Redcoats on the march. The surviving Redcoats FIRE BACK into the trees at unseen targets to little effect. -- Marion rides with about fifty men. -- A British supply convoy makes its way through the woods. Suddenly, Marion's men appear, rising up from the ground as if by magic, having been camouflaged by leaves and brush. They OPEN FIRE on the convoy escort, which holds for a moment, then flees. -- Marion rides with about seventy-five men. -- Cornwallis finishes reading a dispatch and furiously flings it across the room. -- Marion rides with about one hundred men. -- Snow's Island. Marion and his men do an inventory of a large haul of stolen British supply wagons. The booty includes dozens of BRASS MUSICAL INSTRUMENTS, some of which Marion's men BLARE in celebration. -- Marion rides with about one-hundred-fifty men. -- Marion, Gabriel, and some of the other men watch as the flaming supports of a BURNING WOODEN BRIDGE collapse into a river. -- A seething Cornwallis stands at the same spot, looking at the charred, now cooled, remains of the bridge. Cornwallis angrily mounts up and rides off. His contrite staff officers mount up and follow. -- Snow's Island. Marion sits with his muddy feet on Cornwallis' campaign desk, reading Cornwallis' journal, with Cornwallis' Great Danes at his side.</context>
      <utterance>Pride will do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why am I here, Colonel Halbert?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis holds his temper.</context>
      <utterance>For the ball, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, after six weeks, are we still here to attend a ball. By now, we should be attending balls in North Carolina, not South Carolina.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our supply line, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The valet puts a dress coat on Cornwallis who looks at the garment with deepest disdain.</context>
      <utterance>Excellent guess, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what, praytell, is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... I borrowed it from Colonel North. I took it in at the back, added wider epaulets, a court sash and looped gold braiding on the cuffs...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a horse blanket.  First my personal baggage, then half the bridges and ferries between here and Charleston burned, a dozen convoys attacked. Colonel, if you can't secure our supply line against militia, how do you expect to do so against Colonial regulars or the French when they come?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL HALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, they're not like regulars, we can't find them and we don't know when or where they're going to strike.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How impolite. And who leads these clever, secretive fellows?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL HALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't know, sir. He's called, the Commander by some, the Swamp Fox by others.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel, I'm a civilized man but I'm finding to difficult to remain civil. Secure my supply line.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL HALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis looks at his reflection with dismay, sighs and strides out. Tarleton, amused, follows.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REDCOAT GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The drunken Redcoats look up, bringing their faces into the light -- THE DRUNKEN REDCOATS ARE BILLINGS AND DALTON.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, what you got there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got our own little party...</utterance>
   <speaker>DALTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To hell with the officers and their fancy dress ball...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billings and Dalton walk over to the Redcoats guards. As the guards reach for the bottles, Billings SLAMS one of the guards back against the building... Dalton DRAWS A KNIFE and PLUNGES IT into the second guard's belly and HACKS HIM OPEN... Dalton shoves Billings out of the way, SLITS THE OTHER GUARD'S THROAT. Billings is taken aback by the speed and ferocity of Dalton's attack... Marion and Scott duck into the shadows of the doorway, pull out hammer-less carving chisels and quickly and silently start gouging out the wood around the hinges of the heavy door. Billings and Dalton take the posts of the guards while the other men drag the bodies of the real guards out of sight. Everything appears as it should.</context>
      <utterance>Give us a nip, here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MRS. TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! The beasts took your dogs, as well?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine animals, a gift from His Majesty. Dead now, for all I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there no decency?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Among the rebels? We know the answer to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, we have learned.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MRS. TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem far away.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Talbot sympathetically sighs and touches her fingertips to her heart which is conveniently located inches above her stunning cleavage.</context>
      <utterance>It's the weight of command and the lot of a widower -- memories, loneliness...  ... and long gazes at the moon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MASSIVE EXPLOSION LIGHTS UP THE NIGHT as a FIREBALL erupts from the armory. British officers, including Major Halbert and Tarleton, RUSH OUT along with Mr. Talbot and other Loyalist civilians.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, you poor man...</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Talbot tears his eyes from the flames and looks at his wife, clinging to Cornwallis' arm.</context>
      <utterance>Good God!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. TALBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis registers the insult, glances at the hapless Major Halbert, then turns to Tarleton.</context>
      <utterance>These rebels seem to lack fear as well as decency, eh, General?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel Tarleton, you deal with these damned rebels.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton smiles grimly and strides off the balcony.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>GREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... four baskets of apples, salt pork, sweet potatoes, jerky, hard tack, salt and powder. It's not much, but I'll get you more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't pay for this...</utterance>
   <speaker>GREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Green's daughter, ANNE, very attractive, around sixteen, joins them. Gabriel sees her and sidles over.</context>
      <utterance>I'll give you what I can, when I can. You pay me what you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>GREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Francis, you remember my daughter, Anne.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel clears his throat. Anne looks at him coolly.</context>
      <utterance>Nice to see you again, Anne.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who you are, Gabriel Marion. The last time I saw you, I was nine and you put ink in my tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... uh... that wasn't me, it was Samuel... I mean Nathan...</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was you and it turned my teeth black for a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... uh... I...</utterance>
   <speaker>GREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Green heads across the square where some townspeople are giving Marion's men provisions. Anne and Gabriel follow. Marion turns to some waiting men, new recruits. Billings, nearby, reads A POSTED BROADSHEET that announces: "Reward Offered: For the capture or death of the rebel known as 'The Swamp Fox'". He tears it down and walks over to Marion.</context>
      <utterance>He's sorry. Come.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REED, the sturdiest of the lot offers his hand to Marion.</context>
      <utterance>... and your terms of enlistment will be month-to-month. Every thirty days you can re-enlist or return to your families.</utterance>
   <speaker>REED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others nod in agreement.</context>
      <utterance>I'm in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The recruits head off. Billings hands Marion the wanted poster which Marion glances at and crumbles up.</context>
      <utterance>Talk to Abner and Scott about provisions, powder and mounts.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty men here, seventeen in New Brighton, a dozen along the Black River. We'll pass three hundred by week's end if this keeps up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'd known you were going to look like this, I never would have put ink in your tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call that a compliment?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a bit of a smile. He checks out her teeth.</context>
      <utterance>It's a start.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to glare but she can't help but laugh. MARION AND BILLINGS watch as Anne gives Gabriel some apples which he tosses into the air, one-by-one, catching them behind his back, a cocky move, executed with a disarming smile that makes Anne laugh again. Marion smiles at his son's flirtation. Billings smiles as well.</context>
      <utterance>They look nice. As white as can be.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He reminds me of you before you got old and ugly.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billings nods.</context>
      <utterance>... the younger ones barely remember her but Gabriel spent more time with Elizabeth... she taught him well, guided him, she was his North Star and mine... her father was a minister, in Boston, did you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion hears himself and pulls his eyes from Gabriel, adopting a coarse, joking tone.</context>
      <utterance>... Gabriel's already a better man than I could ever hope to be...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean, old and ugly?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got me beat on both accounts.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They mount up, grateful to leave the sincerity behind. Gabriel sees Marion and his men starting to ride off. He says goodbye to Anne, then RUNS TO HIS HORSE, MOUNTING WITH A DRAMATIC LEAP. He GALLOPS up, taking his place at his father's side. Marion doesn't turn to look at him, but he knows he's there.</context>
      <utterance>The hell I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gabriel? Are you asleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're low on salt. I should go to Pembroke and get some.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got salt last week.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, right.  Baking powder, we need baking powder.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel sighs. They hear a SOUND APPROACHING, then see two British wagons round a curve with a guard of only SIX REDCOATS, commanded by a REDCOAT SERGEANT. The Redcoat Sergeant signals stop.</context>
      <utterance>We've got plenty of baking powder. You went to Pembroke and got five pounds two weeks ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>REDCOAT SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young Redcoat privates nervously UNSHOULDER THEIR</context>
      <utterance>Halt. Look alive, boys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant, this road is closed. Those wagons now belong to the Continental Army.</utterance>
   <speaker>REDCOAT SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion's surprised by the Sergeant's order.</context>
      <utterance>Ready arms! By twos!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sergeant, there's no reason for you and your men to die. Just leave the wagons and go.</utterance>
   <speaker>REDCOAT SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion sighs and lets loose with a PIERCING WHISTLE. The underbrush parts and more of Marion's men show themselves, MUSKETS LEVELED at the outnumbered Redcoats.</context>
      <utterance>Steady, boys...</utterance>
   <speaker>REDCOAT SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion exchanges a look with Rev. Oliver who, like Marion, doesn't want to kill these men. Seeing no other option, Marion turns to give the order, then stops, hearing a</context>
      <utterance>This is the King's highway and I advise you and your men to make way.  Prepare to fire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way?</utterance>
   <speaker>GASKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton makes his own choice... rides off... the Green Dragoons follow, the Loyalists bring up the rear.</context>
      <utterance>This way... no this... I think...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Marion spurs his horse to ride after Tarleton, Gabriel grabs the bridle. He YANKS HARD, stopping Marion's horse dead. THE HORSE BUCKS, nearly throwing Marion...</context>
      <utterance>Father, no...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARION SPURS THE HORSE which tries to respond but is JERKED BACK AGAIN by Gabriel. Marion angrily turns on his son...</context>
      <utterance>That's him. Tarleton.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel looks up at his father, never loosening his iron grip on the bridles but speaking softly, almost pleadingly:</context>
      <utterance>Damn you! Let go!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion looks down at Gabriel. Then Marion looks over at Billings and the three wounded men... One bleeds from an ugly neck wound... their shared mounts are nearly spent... Marion takes a last look in the direction of the departing Tarleton. Then he dismounts and hurries over to help the wounded. Gabriel watches his father for a moment, then joins him with the wounded.</context>
      <utterance>Father, please...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fourteen dead, eleven wounded, eighteen captured.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should have killed him when I had the chance?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When was that? In the swamp at the expense of your men? Or when he killed Thomas at the expense of your family?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion is silent.</context>
      <utterance>Or perhaps tomorrow at the expense of our cause.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The parental-sounding formality of Gabriel's words brings a thin smile to Marion's face.</context>
      <utterance>There will be a time and a place for revenge but killing Tarleton at the expense of your duty serves no one but yourself.  Stay the course.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay the course... your mother used to say that to me when I'd get drunk or lose my temper.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'd say it to me when I picked on Thomas or Nathan.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You learned her lessons better than</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next time we'll bring more blankets.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we'll be lucky this winter and have just rain, no snow.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a pot off the campfire and pours him a cup of tea.</context>
      <utterance>That would be nice, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods and takes a drink of the tea. She smiles. Gabriel smiles back to her, revealing a mouthful of ink- stained, black teeth. Before she has time to laugh... ROLLINS RIDES HARD INTO CAMP. Marion hurries over, accompanied by the Great Danes. The other men gather around.</context>
      <utterance>Just because the French didn't come this fall, doesn't mean they're never going to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROLLINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're to be hung!</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion isn't as surprised as Gabriel. He is, however, taken aback by Gabriel's black teeth. Gabriel notices everyone looking at his mouth. Anne is embarrassed and regretful, seeing her joke fly in the face of the troubling news.</context>
      <utterance>But they're prisoners-of-war!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>REDCOAT SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis reads the message.</context>
      <utterance>General, a message from the commander of the rebel militia.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems our Swamp Fox wants to have a formal parley.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to meet with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most certainly. Arrange it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAJOR HALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord Cornwallis will be with you presently.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You may, of course, keep your weapons, but I must warn you that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm familiar with appropriate behavior at a military parley.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, quite, but you should know that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That will be all, Major. I'll wait for Lord Cornwallis.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAJOR HALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... you will wait. Major Halbert turns and starts to stride out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Major Halbert stops.</context>
      <utterance>One other thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Major Halbert sneers and strides from the room. MARION ALONE, EXCEPT FOR THE DOGS, allows himself a fleeting smile. Then he looks around the room. He notes a rocking chair. Curious, he hefts it. Too heavy. He puts it down, sits and rocks. The dogs walk over and lay at his feet.</context>
      <utterance>The proper form of address to a superior officer, even one of an opposing army, is "Yes, sir."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="42">
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dogs just look at Cornwallis. He holds out his arms, waiting for them to rush to him. They look up at Marion who nods to them.</context>
      <utterance>Jupiter! Mars!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dogs run to Cornwallis and nuzzle him in a friendly but not enthusiastic manner. Cornwallis pats them vigorously, too vigorously for the moderate level of joy the dogs are showing at their reunion.</context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My boys... my boys... you seem to have been well fed. Thank you for that, Colonel.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My pleasure, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please forgive me for keeping you waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apology accepted.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Colonel... I'm afraid I don't know your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel will do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TARLETON ENTERS with four Dragoons, all armed... Marion freezes... Marion and Tarleton lock eyes. Marion searches for some sign that Tarleton recognizes him. There's none.</context>
      <utterance>As you wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton nods.</context>
      <utterance>Colonel... Colonel Banastre Tarleton.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion, like ice, looks Tarleton up and down. Then he slowly turns and looks at the four Dragoons, two on either side of Tarleton. Marion measures the odds and finds them wanting. With a supreme effort of will, Marion forces himself to turn from Tarleton to Cornwallis and the matter at hand.</context>
      <utterance>Colonel.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shall we proceed?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let us. Unless you object, I would like to deem this meeting a formal negotiation and, as such, there are certain customary practices. Perhaps I could explain them to you...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm familiar with how a formal negotiation is handled.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I served in His Majesty's army in the French and Indian War.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. Very well, then. Would you, as the initiating party, like to begin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis is surprised. He exchanges a look with Tarleton.</context>
      <utterance>Unless you would like to claim aggrieved status.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are familiar with how these things are done. In fact, I would like to claim aggrieved status.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well, proceed, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First, you have in your possession certain belongings of mine, including clothing, private papers, furniture and personal effects of a non-military nature which I would like to have returned to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis is surprised.</context>
      <utterance>I will do so as soon as possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please accept my apology for not having done so sooner.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apology accepted. Now, on the matter of the specific targeting of officers during engagements, this is absolutely unacceptable.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That one is a bit more difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Certainly you must know that in civilized warfare, officers in the field must not be accorded inappropriate levels of hostile attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what are inappropriate levels of hostile attention?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel, imagine the utter chaos that would result from un-led armies having at each other. There must be gentlemen in command to lead and, when appropriate, restrain their men.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Restrain them from the targeting of civilians, including women and children?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is a separate issue.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I consider them linked.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg to differ. One is a command decision on your part. The other represents nothing more than the occasional over-exuberance of field officers attempting to carry out their duty in difficult circumstances.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis sighs.</context>
      <utterance>As long as your soldiers attack civilians, I will order the shooting of your officers at the outset of every engagement.  And my men are excellent marksmen.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very well, let us move on to...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prisoner exchange.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have eighteen of my men. I want them back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do have eighteen criminals under sentence of death, but I hold no prisoners-of-war.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's your position, then eighteen of your officers will die. Nineteen, if you hang me with my men.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion steps to the window, checks the view. A wooded hillside is visible in the distance. Marion reaches into his jacket... The Dragoons move on him... Marion extracts not a weapon, but a spyglass, which he hands to Cornwallis.</context>
      <utterance>What officers?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis looks through the spyglass.</context>
      <utterance>In the clearing, just down from the crest, to the left of the dark pines...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Their names, ranks and posts?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis glares at Marion.</context>
      <utterance>They refused to give me their names. Their ranks are nine lieutenants, five captains, three majors and one fat colonel who called me a cheeky fellow. Their posts? We picked them up here-and-there last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion can't help but laugh at the insult.</context>
      <utterance>You are not a gentleman.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis turns to Colonel Huntington.</context>
      <utterance>If your conduct is the measure of a gentleman, I take that as a compliment.  Get my men.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colonel Huntington leaves to do so.</context>
      <utterance>Arrange the exchange.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion salutes Cornwallis who doesn't return the salute. THEN MARION TURNS TO TARLETON. He walks up to him and looks him in the eye.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, General. I'm sure your officers will thank you, as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton examines Marion's face, finding him familiar, but unable to place him... then Tarleton remembers...</context>
      <utterance>You don't remember me, do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton calmly holds Marion's glare.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, yes, that boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ugly business, doing one's duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion takes a step closer to Tarleton, then speaks very softly, very slowly, very clearly.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, ugly business.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion locks his eyes on Tarleton to make it perfectly clear that he means what he says. Tarleton tries to cover his reaction but it's apparent that he's taken aback by Marion's icy words. Marion turns and walks out. The two Great Danes start to follow, but Cornwallis SNAPS A COMMAND:</context>
      <utterance>If you are alive when this war is over, I'm going to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE DOGS FREEZE, looking after Marion, who doesn't turn back. The dogs reluctantly sidle over to Cornwallis' side.</context>
      <utterance>Jupiter! Mars!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GASKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's been here for months.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But now we have a name for our Colonel... Francis Marion. And with a name will come a family.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They follow Aaron, down an alley to A SHACK. Small. Barely standing. The children stop in their tracks, knowing this is to be their new home. Charlotte sees their hesitation. She walks up to the little structure, examining it with a critical eye. She looks on the doorway, seeing a single room, a dirt floor, wax-paper instead of glass in the windows, a rude, chimney-less fire-pit against the back wall. She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>It's all set.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to Aaron and Abigail.</context>
      <utterance>This will do fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlotte walks inside without looking back. The children hesitate, then follow her inside.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So he's the one they talk about, the Swamp Fox.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought it might be him, the bits and pieces we heard, a veteran, fought in the French and Indian War, knows the swamps.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They won't stop looking for you and the children.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel searches for an honest answer.</context>
      <utterance>We'll be alright, here, for now.  How is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel steps over to his saddlebags, opens his pack and pulls out a stack of letters which he hands to Charlotte.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know... I'm his son.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sense someone behind them.</context>
      <utterance>These are for you and the children.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel is astonished to hear words coming from his heretofore silent sister. Charlotte nods, smiling.</context>
      <utterance>Why didn't father come?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speaking for months now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why didn't he come?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wanted to, Susan, but he couldn't leave his men.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He left us.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan says nothing. Gabriel continues, hopefully.</context>
      <utterance>I know he did and he's sorry. He'll come back as soon as he can.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are some letters here from him. Some are just to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't care. I hate him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't hate him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel kneels down and embraces her. She stands coldly with her arms at her sides.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do. I hate him and I hope he never comes back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She spoke? Susan spoke?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Full sentences. As if she had been speaking all along.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cloud passes quickly.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it... and I wasn't there for it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me everything she said, word for word.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said... she loves you and misses you but she understands why you can't be there with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel nods.</context>
      <utterance>She said that? Oh, my Lord, she said that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion shakes his head at the thought, smiling to himself. Gabriel, uncomfortable with the lie, changes the subject.</context>
      <utterance>Isn't that something.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, there's something else I need to talk to you about.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods and curiously follows Gabriel.</context>
      <utterance>Come with me. I'll tell you when we get there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion is stunned but recovers quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Father, I'm looking for a best man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They share a moment, then head down the aisle. Marion greets Anne's parents, shaking hands with her father and bowing to her mother. Abner, at the door, nods that the coast is clear.</context>
      <utterance>I'd be honored.</utterance>
   <speaker>REV. OLIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARION feels every word, looking straight ahead but knowing that he's standing next to his son.</context>
      <utterance>Dearly beloved, we are gathered here in the sight of God to join this man and this woman in holy matrimony...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two days?</context>
      <utterance>Sir, I'd like to request a furlough.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Granted. Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheraw Falls.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's beautiful there. Your mother and I were there once, before you were born.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're silent for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel nods, then turns to his horse, unnecessarily checking his pack ropes. Anne joins them. Marion embraces her and gives her a fatherly kiss.</context>
      <utterance>She would have been pleased.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry we didn't give you more warning.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He helps her mount up. Abner, on guard near the road, motions them on. They all watch as Gabriel and Anne ride off.</context>
      <utterance>It's alright. I'm very happy for you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a good measure of a woman that she'll have her honeymoon under the stars.</utterance>
   <speaker>REV. OLIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods. They ride on.</context>
      <utterance>For richer, for poorer, in sickness and in health, 'til death do they part.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From General Clinton in New York...  "... your request to move north is denied until you have properly dealt with your militia problem."  He underlined, 'militia'.  "You have spent over six months dealing with a six-week problem. It is essential that you quell the militia..."  Underlined again.  "... insurgency, particularly because of the likely move south of Washington and the inevitable arrival of the French. Militia, as you have so often pointed out, is not worth the attention of a significant army, hence it is mystifying why militia has bedeviled you for so long..." Tarleton smiles slightly, enjoying the show.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"... it is my fervent hope that the vigor of your campaign comes to match the vigor of your correspondence with your Parliamentary and Court patrons. Only then might you share in the victory, on the verge of which I now stand."  "Your guardedly respectful Commander, General Sir George Clinton." Cornwallis grows eerily calm and turns to Tarleton.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I fail, you fail.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And if I triumph, you triumph.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can we end this madness?</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis takes a moment, then speaks simply.</context>
      <utterance>Difficult, sir. This is, as you pointed out, a civil war.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Civility is a secondary virtue. It is superseded by duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton salutes, yanks his reins, turning his horse, and rides off.</context>
      <utterance>I understand, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GASKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton sighs, irritated.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir. He died.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gaskins and a couple of his men step into an attached woodshed where Billings sits, bound. They roughly grab him and drag him into the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>Very well, get one of the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn your eyes. Do your worst.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They tie Billings to the table.</context>
      <utterance>I intend to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DALTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion doesn't answer. Gabriel GALLOPS up. He reins back his lathered horse and speaks to them without dismounting.</context>
      <utterance>You still want me to give wounded Redcoats quarter?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tarleton has a list of our men, most are on it. A regiment of dragoons is going to the homes on the list, burning them, killing whomever resists, women and children, as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rollins doesn't pause. He rushes to his horse, mounts up and rides off. Marion and the other men mount up and ride off fast after him.</context>
      <utterance>Seven homes along the Black River so far...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARGARET</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>MARION'S CHILDREN RACE OUT OF THE SHADOWS to Marion. He's practically bowled over as Margaret, Nathan, Samuel and William fling themselves into his arms.</context>
      <utterance>It's him! I told you it was him!</utterance>
   <speaker>NATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father!</utterance>
   <speaker>WILLIAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHARLOTTE STEPS OUT OF THE SHADOWS, watching the reunion as Marion covers the children with kisses, trying to hug all of them at once as they cling to him as if they'll never let go. MARION AND CHARLOTTE LOCK EYES over the heads of the children.</context>
      <utterance>Papa...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Charlotte smiles. Then Marion notices SUSAN peeking out from behind Charlotte's patched and mended skirt. He kneels down and opens his arms to her but she doesn't move. He smiles to her and speaks softly:</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks coldly at Marion, tightens her grip on Charlotte's skirt and retreats further behind her. Marion looks to Charlotte who nods with guarded reassurance. Then his attention is drawn away by the demanding embraces of his other children.</context>
      <utterance>Susan...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>Good apple.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cuts a slice and offers it to her. She doesn't take it. He puts the slice between them. After a long moment she picks it up but as she's about to eat it, she stops, seeing something on it. She puts it back. Marion looks at the apple slice and sees a dark red splotch on it. He looks at his knife and realizes that it's dried blood. Off-balance, he turns to Susan who stares straight ahead, a thousand miles from Marion.</context>
      <utterance>Very good. Sweet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion finishes with the knife and puts it away without explanation.</context>
      <utterance>May I ask you a question?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She speaks with a sly, withheld smile.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think Frances with an "e" is too manly a name for a girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think Francis with an "i" is too womanly a name for a boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anne smiles and walks away. Marion figures out what she just told him.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Late summer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion laughs at the thought.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Startled, Marion turns to Charlotte.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not my sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said, I'm not my sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns from him. Marion, tries to figure out what just happened. After a long moment he gets it. Stunned at first, his gears turn. After a very thoughtful moment he turns to Charlotte and offers a tentative smile. She rolls her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Very well, then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan remains silent, standing with her arms at her sides, not responding to the embrace. Finally, Marion lets go of her. She just stares at him. Marion stands and turns to Charlotte.</context>
      <utterance>Just a little goodbye? One word? That's all I want to hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Charlotte.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace. Though the hug is chaste, their eyes tell a different story. Only Anne and Margaret notice, but to them it's as clear as a bell. They exchange a knowing look. Marion and Charlotte break apart, self-consciously. Marion and Gabriel mount up and start to ride away. As they're about to round a curve and disappear, SUSAN CRIES</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With halting steps, then faster and faster, she runs down the path toward Marion.</context>
      <utterance>Papa!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion stops, turning in his saddle to see Susan running after him, her eyes filled with tears.</context>
      <utterance>Papa, don't go, I'll say anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion yanks his reins, turning his horse.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Papa, I'll say anything you want!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion spurs his horse straight toward her, GALLOPING toward the running, crying child.</context>
      <utterance>Just tell me what to say! Tell me what to say!</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, Papa, please don't go.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION RIDES TOWARD HER...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MARION LEANS OVER IN THE SADDLE without slowing down...</context>
      <utterance>Charlotte, Anne and Marion's children watch as:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion envelopes the sobbing wisp of a girl, holding her, letting her cry, fighting his own tears... He reins back the horse, stopping in front of the others... He pleadingly looks to Charlotte who steps up to the horse... to take Susan... Marion gives Susan a final embrace, and covers her face with kisses...</context>
      <utterance>... I'll talk to you, I'll say anything you want, just tell me what you want me to say, I'll say anything, I promise, please, Papa, just stay...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion hands the still crying Susan down to Charlotte... Marion, in agony, averts his eyes, yanks his reins, and spurs his horse... As he rides away the children take off after him, running. Susan seeing the others running after Marion, struggles out of Charlotte's arms, and runs after them as well... Marion rides, now joined by Gabriel, faster and faster, leaving a trail of dust... The children slow, then stop, one after another, watching as they ride away.</context>
      <utterance>I'll come back... I promise...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many came back?</utterance>
   <speaker>REV. OLIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods. He and Gabriel join some of the men under one of the lean-to's.</context>
      <utterance>About a hundred and twenty. Less than a third.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>REDCOAT SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, Ma'am, everyone has been requested to gather at the church.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANNE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone?</utterance>
   <speaker>REDCOAT SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Redcoat Sergeant deferentially motions for Anne to follow him and his men. She sees several other townspeople, with Redcoat escorts, already heading down the street. She follows along.</context>
      <utterance>Colonel Tarleton wants to address, the whole village.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>REDCOAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Into the church, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER REDCOAT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tarleton sees the last of the townspeople enter the church. He nods to the Redcoats near the door. The Redcoats CLOSE THE DOORS, chaining them shut. The DOOR IS POUNDED ON from the inside.</context>
      <utterance>Colonel Tarleton wishes to address all of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open this door!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANOTHER VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TARLETON NODS TO GASKINS who, along with several rough- looking LOYALIST MILITIAMEN, disappear into the blacksmith shop. They reappear a moment later with FLAMING TORCHES and approach the church. Several Redcoats see what's about to happen and are appalled. Even some of the Green Dragoons, including Wilkins, are troubled. Wilkins rides over to Tarleton.</context>
      <utterance>By what right are we made prisoners?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gaskins and the Loyalist Militia stop around the church, torches ready, waiting for the final go-ahead from Tarleton. The POUNDING AND CALLING from inside the church grows louder.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Major.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, there is no honor in this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Redcoats turn to the Redcoat Officers. The Redcoat officers turn to Wilkins, who struggles with himself. Tarleton calmly watches Wilkins' distress. Finally, Wilkins accepts it. Weakly steadying his horse, he takes his place next to Tarleton. The Redcoats and Dragoons follow his lead and watch as Gaskins and the Loyalist Militiamen light the church on fire, heaving their torches onto the roof, through the windows and under the raised foundation. SCREAMS are heard from inside. The DOOR THUDS with the shoulders of men trying to escape. The CHAINS HOLD. As the FLAMES RISE, another group of Loyalist Militiamen and some Redcoats drag half-a-dozen young women out of a side-street... Among the women, desperately pleading, kicking and screaming, is ANNE... The men drag her and the other women into the livery stable... Tarleton watches them carried off, stone-faced... Then he turns and watches the church go up in FLAMES... A WINDOW SHATTERS, with a chair heaved from inside... SOME MEN TRY TO CLIMB OUT, but waiting Redcoats FIRE THEIR</context>
      <utterance>The honor is found in the end, not the means. This will be forgotten.  Proceed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Gabriel gets to the entrance of the livery stable, Marion walks out and intercepts him.</context>
      <utterance>Anne...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it her? Is Anne in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel understands... he reels... growing faint... Marion grabs him... keeping him from falling... Marion holds Gabriel who begins to weep...</context>
      <utterance>She is. Don't go in there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, tell me what happened at Fort Wilderness?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone knows. It's what made me a hero. Me, Harry Lee, all of us. I got a medal. Men bought me drinks. They still do sometimes. Everyone knows what happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me what everyone doesn't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what do they know?</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That the French and Cherokees captured the fort and when you retook it, you took revenge on them for what they did during the occupation.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not enough. Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion shakes his head to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Your mother asked me the same question around the time you were born. I was drunk and I was foolish enough to answer her.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why it was four years between you and Thomas. It took me that long to regain her respect.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion's quiet for a moment. Then he speaks:</context>
      <utterance>I'm not my mother. I can't have the respect without the knowing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion grows quieter with the memory of how bad.</context>
      <utterance>It was in '63. It was a bad time. The French and the Cherokee had raided along the Blue Ridge. All the English settlers took refuge at Fort Wilderness but the French captured it. We were sent in relief. Harry Lee, Billings, sixty of us. We already had something of a reputation for being... harsh. When we got there the fort was abandoned. Not a French soldier or Cherokee anywhere. They had left a week earlier. What we found was... bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion's silent for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>They had left the settlers there. The men had been burned alive, the women were in pieces and the children were on stakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We buried them, then we went to track. It was a cold trail and they were moving fast. We went faster. We caught up to them at Kentucky Ford.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel is silent. Marion looks at him closely.</context>
      <utterance>We took our time with them and gave every one of them worse than they had given at the fort. It was two weeks before they were all dead, all except two. We put the heads on a pallet and had the two we let live take it to the French at Fort Ambercon.  The eyes, fingers and tongues we put in a basket and sent that down the Asheulot to the Cherokee.  The French stayed east of the Blue Ridge after that and the Cherokee broke their treaty with the French and stayed out of the fight.  That seemed to make a difference. The war went another year, things went better... and men bought us drinks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was a different time, son. And you're a better man than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see, do as I say, not as I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hear HORSES HOOVES. Abner rides in from the opposite side of the village from the church, not having seen the results of the massacre. Excited, he dismounts.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If this war is about more than Thomas, it's about more than Anne, as well. Stay the course.</utterance>
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Marion can answer they see HARRY LEE RIDE UP TO THEM. He dismounts, excited, voluble. He strides over, pleased to see Marion, oblivious to his and Gabriel's mood.</context>
      <utterance>As you did at Fort Wilderness?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee laughs, picks up a bottle and takes a big pull.</context>
      <utterance>Look at you! I knew you could do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel rises and walks away. Lee finally tunes into the pall hanging over Marion and the just departed Gabriel. He turns to Marion.</context>
      <utterance>We have a chance! Better than a chance! Cornwallis is running to the Chesapeake, probably to meet his fleet at Yorktown. I wish I could see his face when he sees a dozen French ships floating there. And Washington should be a day or two behind him.  And on top of everything, I have a son! Born last month in Alexandria.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His wife was killed yesterday. She was with child.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion nods. They stand in silence. Lee hands Marion the bottle. He takes a drink.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, I didn't know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DALTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gabriel and at least a dozen others. They must have left right after the watch change.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion strides to his horse. The other men follow him.</context>
      <utterance>That means they have two hours on us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GABRIEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries to stand...</context>
      <utterance>I'm alright, I...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gabriel weakens in Marion's arms... falters... Marion watches the life drain from Gabriel... He tries to hold the blood in, to no avail... Dalton plants himself next to Marion, defending him and Gabriel... Marion caresses Gabriel and watches as...</context>
      <utterance>Let me help you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>REV. OLIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>May I help you try to find solace with the word of God?</utterance>
   <speaker>REV. OLIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel, let us help his soul find it's place with the Almighty and...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He looks as if he's sleeping, doesn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>REV. OLIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rev. Oliver pulls up a camp stool. He and Marion sit in silence.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, he does.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No response.</context>
      <utterance>You have to bury him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee moves toward Gabriel's body.</context>
      <utterance>I'll help you bury him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't touch him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many men have we seen die?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two. Gabriel and Thomas.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're gone. And there is nothing you or I can do to bring them back. But there is something you can do to help end all this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is ended.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion doesn't respond. Lee waits for a long moment, then he hears the SOUND OF THE DEPARTING TROOPS OUTSIDE THE</context>
      <utterance>No. It's not over yet. Two days ride, Yorktown, Virginia. Washington, the French, Cornwallis and Tarleton. It will end, one way or another.  Francis, nothing will replace your sons but helping us will justify their sacrifice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RUNNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion reaches into his pocket and pulls out a single WALNUT which he hands to the boy.</context>
      <utterance>You called for me, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy looks at the walnut and then looks at Marion as if he's joking or crazy. He's neither. The boy shrugs and runs off with the walnut.</context>
      <utterance>Take this to General Washington.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you bring me this?</utterance>
   <speaker>RUNNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Washington scribbles something on a piece of paper and hands it to the boy.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take this to Colonel Marion.</utterance>
   <speaker>RUNNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy runs off. Washington smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gray.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Washington holds out a small bag to Marion who reaches in and pulls out a walnut.</context>
      <utterance>Earned.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Washington turns to his staff officers.</context>
      <utterance>Come. I have something I want to show you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Washington and Marion walk off with Washington's officers and aides.As Washington and Marion walk, they both CRUSH THE WALNUTS SHELLS BETWEEN THEIR THUMBS AND FOREFINGERS, a prodigious display of strength that both men take for granted. They eat walnuts as they walk.</context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was sorry to hear about your son.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He was only fifteen.</context>
      <utterance>I lost another a year ago, Thomas.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look out at the vista, knowing that they're looking at the sons of thousands and thousands of other men.</context>
      <utterance>I've had no sons to lose, nor daughters.  I lose the sons of other men.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They walk on, joining the others on the crest of the hill. The officers are looking out, some with spyglasses, at the British emplacements.</context>
      <utterance>Life was easier when we only had ourselves to get killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen, what do we see?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mortars, center, with two lines of enfilading trenches.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More along the right flank and behind the forward redoubts.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAFAYETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Very formidable.</context>
      <utterance>A formidable defensive position.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Washington nods and turns to Marion.</context>
      <utterance>They could hold out for weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Francis, tell me about General Cornwallis.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember Braddock?</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Washington sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Proud, priggish and competent. A very bad combination in an adversary.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That hits Washington's officers hard.</context>
      <utterance>For those of you who don't know, we intercepted a British dispatch this morning. General Clinton has sailed from New York to relieve Cornwallis.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAMILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long before they arrive?</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Less than a week. Sixteen ships and over nine thousand Redcoats.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAFAYETTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sooner or later that message will get through to Cornwallis.</utterance>
   <speaker>PINKNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when it does, he'll just wait us out.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion speaks up.</context>
      <utterance>And when the British ships arrive, the French ships will flee. And when the French ships flee, General Rochambeau and the French troops will flee as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all turn to Marion, most of them looking at him as if he's insane.</context>
      <utterance>Then you must let the message go through.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If Cornwallis receives news that Clinton is coming, he'll simply hold tight and wait. He'll fight a purely defensive battle and he'll win that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he won't. There are two things you need to know about Cornwallis. First, he is a very proud man, He would rather risk defeat than share a victory.  If you give him what he thinks is an out, he'll take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion pulls Cornwallis' journal out of his haversack and leafs through it.</context>
      <utterance>And what is the second thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll let him tell you himself...  "... but it is this colonial militia that is the most irksome. Not worthy of my attention, but demanding it; not worthy of British blood, but taking it; and not worthy of a soldier's honor, but sullying it. Those nights of mine that are not sleepless, are filled with dreams of a cavalry charge on the heels of fleeing farmers..." Marion closes the journal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Washington nods, considering it.</context>
      <utterance>He has no respect for citizen soldiers. That's your bait... militia.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MAJOR HALBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis takes the dispatch and reads it. It staggers him. He sits down.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, a dispatch from General Clinton made it through the rebel lines.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILKINS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis fumes. His jaw sets with anger. He slowly crumples the dispatch and speaks with quiet fury.</context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call a general staff meeting.</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They listen closely.</context>
      <utterance>The British army believes in officers. I believe in soldiers. After we engage, there will be no more orders. Every man here must know what I'm about to tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They gather around closer.</context>
      <utterance>We are the bait in a trap. We're militia. Cornwallis thinks we're rabble, nothing more than a bunch of undisciplined farmers. And if he thinks that's what we are, that's what we're going to give him. Listen up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you see that, Colonel?</utterance>
   <speaker>TARLETON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornwallis and Tarleton exchange a pleased look.</context>
      <utterance>Unless I'm dreaming, I think I see irregulars at their center.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORE DRUMS...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The men around Marion wait.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLEE...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON A RISE BEHIND THE BATTLEFIELD, CORNWALLIS, watches through his spyglass, trying to get a sense of what's happening before the spreading cloud of musket smoke obscures everything. He barks to his SIGNALMAN...</context>
      <utterance>Some Redcoats laugh...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNWALLIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Signalman raises his semaphore flags and snaps the message. MARION AND HIS MEN are caught in the middle of the chaotic retreat... THE BRITISH LINE advances at a quickstep, bayonets fixed... From behind them, THE GREEN DRAGOONS appear, at a full gallop, Tarleton at their head...</context>
      <utterance>Fix bayonets... dispatch the Green Dragoons.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Francis.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion reaches down. They shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Harry.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And congratulations on the birth of your son.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Maybe all of this will buy him some peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Marion starts to ride off, he reins back and stops, speaking back to Lee over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I hope so.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your son, what did you name him?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marion smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Robert. Robert E. Lee.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lee nods. Marion rides off.</context>
      <utterance>A good name for a farmer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two pounds, fourteen ounces.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHARLOTTE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles and make a minute adjustment in the chair's position. Then he sits down, settles back and begins rocking. Not a creak. Marion and Charlotte watch Susan run out of the yard, calling as she joins the other children.</context>
      <utterance>Lovely.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the CAMERA CRANES UP, Marion and Charlotte disappear beneath the overhang of the porch roof. Suddenly, the</context>
      <utterance>Wait for me...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
