<movie id="459" title="Relic The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>American?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITTLESLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Thank Christ somebody speaks English. I'm Dr. John Whittlesley. You have some crates of mine on board. They were shipped by mistake to the Natural History Museum. We have to get them off the boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whittlesley runs a trembling hand through his hair, trying to keep control and appear reasonable.</context>
      <utterance>You have I.D.?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITTLESLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whittlesley's fists clench spasmodically. Franco looks to his men.</context>
      <utterance>No. Let me explain. I was on an expedition for the museum on the Upper Xingu. Something horrible happened. I'm the only one who got out alive. I lost everything, my I.D., everything. I have to make sure no one else dies. The crates, the crates were sent out before we knew. There's something unspeakable inside. If your boat leaves harbor with those crates on board, I can't be responsible. My God, if they reach New York...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Loco.</utterance>
   <speaker>WHITTLESLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Franco barks an order and several sailors grab Whittlesley by the arms. They start to lead him back to shore.</context>
      <utterance>No! I'm not crazy! As God is my witness, I'm telling the truth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SMALL TOWN COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One of the locals found it at dawn. Didn't believe him 'till I saw it myself. Even then I didn't believe it. Scared my men shitless. Me too. I mean... hell... You could smell it a half mile away, Mr. Pendergast.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any of your men go on board?</utterance>
   <speaker>SMALL TOWN COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast nods his approval, resumes humming along with a particularly intricate harpsichord riff. As always, the man is unflappable and totally calm as he drives.</context>
      <utterance>No sir. No way. None of us wanted to, I'm the first to admit it. I said, "Don't get within a mile of this thing. It's way to big for us. I'm calling the FBI."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. BEASLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ignoring Mrs. Beasley, TWO BOYS charge past Margo. HENRY and LARRY. Henry has a buzz cut; Larry has rasta dread knots. Both are 8 years old, wear high top sneakers and shorts so big they graze their ankles.</context>
      <utterance>Don't run, children! Stay with your partner and do not run! If anyone runs they will be sent back to the bus!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BEASLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, Henry and Larry slow to a rapid race-walk as they reach the huge doorway flanked by two Northwest Coast Indian totem poles. Above the doorway WORKMEN are hanging a LARGE BANNER. It reads:</context>
      <utterance>Henry! Larry! What did I just say! You walk right this minute! Did you hear me?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning, Dr. Green.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry watches Margo pass through the turnstiles without paying. He swaggers over.</context>
      <utterance>Morning Joe. Beautiful day.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You work here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm an Evolutionary Biologist. What do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I'm in third grade. What's a revolutionary what ch'a ma' callit?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evolutionary Biologist. I study how life on earth evolved over millions of years.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Way cool. Then you know where the dinosaurs are.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. Beasley heads into the museum and Larry and Henry merge with the rest of the kids. Margo turns towards the stairwell, passing... IAN CUTHBERT... Museum Director... a pudgy man in wire rim glasses who dresses and thinks like a banker. Hired for his amazing ability to raise money, Cuthbert is one of a new generation of Museum Directors whose focus must always be on the bottom line.</context>
      <utterance>Fourth floor, West wing, but stay with your class.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Ian. Everything ready for the opening of the Superstition Exhibit?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on my way to get the last piece out of storage right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd wish you luck but I'm not superstitious.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cuthbert waves merrily. A workman uses a LADDER in the stairwell. Cuthbert is about to walk under the ladder, stops and carefully walks around it instead. Margo smiles, goes on upstairs.</context>
      <utterance>You will be after tomorrow night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cuthbert feels gently through the packing material, lets out a sigh of relief as he pulls out a figurine. It is a small, beautifully carved statue of A MONSTER crouched on all fours. The room falls totally silent as Cuthbert studies THE RELIC. It's a truly frightening piece... massive, razor sharp claws, large round nostrils, enormous teeth and red rimmed eyes. Suddenly Cuthbert sees a DROP OF BLOOD on his hand! He's been CUT!</context>
      <utterance>No, it can't be.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cuthbert rises, shakes his finger in pain. Blood drips on the floor. He pulls out his pocket handkerchief and wraps the wound. The handkerchief rapidly soaks through. Suddenly a HAND CLAMPS on Cuthbert's shoulder! He's not alone! He lets out a YELP, almost dropping the Relic and spins to see... A MUSEUM GUARD standing behind him. His nameplate reads... BEAUREGARD. He's a gentle young fellow with white blond hair and a rolling southern accent.</context>
      <utterance>Damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beauregard! You scared me half to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAUREGARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, sir. You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone broke into this room.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAUREGARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything missin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cuthbert holds up the RELIC of THE MONSTER. Beauregard stares.</context>
      <utterance>Doesn't look like it. We're damned lucky. This statue is priceless.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beauregard sees Cuthbert's cut finger.</context>
      <utterance>Mbwun. A South American warrior deity. He carries a powerful curse. Every member of the expedition that found this statue, died.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAUREGARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like the curse is still at work.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beauregard studies the door as Cuthbert heads out with the figurine.</context>
      <utterance>The claws are sharp... I must have cut myself.  Better move these crates to the secure storage area where they'll be safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAUREGARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cuthbert.</context>
      <utterance>Don't know if it'll do any good, Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAUREGARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one broke into this room, sir. Someone broke out. That lock was torn off from the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The fly zooms across the room and lights on the shoulder of the third skeleton from the end, labeled "Aleut, provenance unknown." Margo rolls her eyes and Kawakita smiles with pride.</context>
      <utterance>Third from the end! Right shoulder. Aleut, provenance unknown.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I spent half the time on my Fractal Evolution thesis that I spend on this fly rod, I'd have my PhD.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kawakita reels in his line as Margo drops her backpack on her large desk. An enormous MICROSCOPE stands by the equally imposing computer topped by a tiger skull. A screen saver of an animated pterodactyl plays. Margo unpacks boxes of fossil teeth, hits some keys revealing columns of seemingly indecipherable chemical equations on the computer screen.</context>
      <utterance>But at what a price.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frock. He wanted a demonstration.</context>
      <utterance>I have the species identification on these teeth. We can extract DNA and start running tests on the extrapolator program. Call Dr.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Margo, you haven't heard?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo straightens, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>Frock's been fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo is already out the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to be the bearer of bad tidings, but you know me. Telegraph. Telephone. Tell Kawakita. I got the definitive word from Cuthbert's secretary. This is Dr. Frock's last week.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>DR. FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Margo. Sorry about the mess.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it true? Greg said you'd been fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Bit of a shock. But as Cuthbert so tactfully put it, the museum needs new blood. And since I've been here since the Mesozoic Era --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now Margo, don't overreact. Cuthbert has to cut costs somehow. My leaving makes perfect sense. This isn't exactly early retirement. I've overstayed the party a bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't do without you. You're one of the foremost authorities on primitive pharmacology. You're practically an institution around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frock goes back to his work packing to hide his emotion and Margo moves to his side. She pulls Frock's books back out of the box, returns them to his desk.</context>
      <utterance>That, apparently, is the problem. I'm yesterday's news. Who needs a Curator of Plant Biology in a museum with one exhibit on plants? Monsters and dinosaurs, cannibals and shamans are the new currency of the realm.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts for the door and Frock wheels into her path. Now for the first time she sees what he's been carefully hiding... the deep pain in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>"Phyletic Transformation and the Tertiary Fern Spike" is not going anywhere. I'll talk to Cuthbert and put a stop to this right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Don't humiliate me further.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me help. I can take care of everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Margo. This is one problem you can't solve. You have to stay out of it. The fact is, I want to retire.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can you say that? You know it's not true.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes it is. I'm tired and I'm no longer needed --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My work on fossil intermediates would be crippled without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With all due respect, dear, that's bull. You dance rings around me with your new technology. You've left me in the dust.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your work is highly relevant. What about your display on Primitive Pharmacology? Cuthbert told me himself he was going to feature it prominently in the Superstition Exhibit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frock reaches out and squeezes her hand gently with a look that says the discussion is over.</context>
      <utterance>Healing plant use among the Ki tribe of Bechuanaland has been cancelled to make room for Tibetan Erotic Art.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. I'll walk you back to the elevator.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not giving up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't a death sentence. Greg has promised to teach me fly fishing. I'll garden. I'll write.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are this museum. It won't be the same without you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo gets in the elevator reluctantly. He smiles and meets her eye.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone needs a change of scenery. I've been rolling down these halls for forty-odd years. That's quite enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves her off merrily. But once the doors close and Margo's out of sight, Frock's smile fades and his shoulders sag. He ducks his wheelchair quickly into the Hall of African Mammals.</context>
      <utterance>I'll see you at lunch.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Beasley, it's almost time to go and we still haven't seen the dinosaurs!</utterance>
   <speaker>BEASLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts to lecture about horseshoe crabs in a droning monotone. Henry and Larry hang back.</context>
      <utterance>If you ask me about the dinosaurs once more, I'II strangle you both!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This room sucks.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's never going to take us to see the dinosaurs. That lady said they were on the fourth floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They dart off down a side corridor and up a wide stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Let's ditch and find them ourselves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Larry checks out, the huge, dragon-like reptile, which has just sunk its Jaws into a stuffed boar. Henry points to a stuffed Gecko climbing vertically up the side of its case.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this. A Komodo dragon.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry already has his eyes on the far end of the hall where temporary barricades have been put up to prevent access to the next room. Painting is in progress. Scaffolding just begs to be climbed. Henry runs over and starts up the scaffolding. Larry hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>Check out this one. It can walk up walls.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not supposed to go back there.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry drops on the other side of the scaffolding and Larry follows. In a moment both disappear from sight.</context>
      <utterance>Chicken. This is a great short cut.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to go this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys continue onward more slowly, their footfalls echoing in the silence.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be a wuss. Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry disappears behind the barricade leaving Larry completely alone in the dark room with the Shaman masks.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, there's a secret staircase back here. Cool.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry doesn't respond. The lights in the cases throw strange shadows. Larry starts to sniffle, falls to hiccuping, sits down. He pulls on a little flap of rubber that's coming off the toe of his sneaker, all bravado gone.</context>
      <utterance>Henry, come back!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Larry rises and peeks behind the barricade. He sees the circular stair. It descends into total darkness. From below comes a strange smell that makes Larry's nose wrinkle.</context>
      <utterance>Henry! Henry!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Larry puts his first foot on the stair.</context>
      <utterance>Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With no other option but staying alone in the dark, Larry follows Henry down.</context>
      <utterance>Henry! Come up! Please!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry takes another step. Another. And another. He stops. Below him he hears SNUFFLING, rather like a large dog. Larry freezes, starts to cry.</context>
      <utterance>Henry? Where are you? Henry?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Larry can barely see a dim hallway stretching out in two directions. He pauses near the bottom of the stairs, eyes wide, holding his breath. There appears to be a darker area of SHADOW at the end of the hall. It's gliding TOWARDS THEM! Suddenly something CLOSES on Larry's leg and he YELPS. It's HENRY. Henry pulls Larry the rest of the way down the stairs. They stand alone together in the darkness. Henry hisses.</context>
      <utterance>Henry! Henry! It smells awful. Answer me! Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quiet!</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They keep their eyes locked on the shape at the end of the hall as they back up, step by step. Move in as their faces suddenly TWIST WITH FEAR. THE BOYS... SCREAM BLOODY MURDER... The sound echoes in the darkness as we...</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. But I think it's bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ID.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Worried, Margo hands it over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All employees are to go to the IMAX room for a briefing, Dr. Green.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COP ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that? Six?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo glances past them to see an OLDER MAN wearing the badge of a NIGHT WATCHMAN, leaning over a sink. He wipes his mouth. Margo's eyes move down to see... THE MAN'S SNEAKERS are soaked in blood.</context>
      <utterance>Lost count.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you? The undertaker?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Special Agent Pendergast. FBI.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vince D'Agosta. Am I out?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men shake hands. They couldn't be more different. Pendergast is an elegant intellectual... D'Agosta a working class spark plug who operates from the gut. Pendergast gestures to the form on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Not at all. I think we may be working on the same case. If so, I could use your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The body?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's left of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta calls to A POLICE PHOTOGRAPHER who comes down the staircase carrying lights, a donut stuffed in his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Mind if I have a look?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need light in here, stat.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta points to a lump the size of a bowling ball that's in the corner.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the head?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Careful. That mess on the ground is brains.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose footprints?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The photographer is finally ready and he floods the dark room with light. And now everyone (but not</context>
      <utterance>Night watchman who found the body. Sweet old man. Been tossing his cookies for over an hour. Not a likely suspect.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'd say we're definitely working on the same case.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Greg Kawakita sits in the chair next to Margo...</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Frock, I just saw a man back there who'd been wading in blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For once I'm glad you're rumor central. What in the world is going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone's been murdered. Not shot, strangled or stabbed, either. Torn limb from limb. There's talk of a psychotic killer or even an animal.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this everyone falls silent and IAN CUTHBERT steps forward to address the crowd. He appears drawn and grey.</context>
      <utterance>For heaven's sake, Greg, someone's been killed. Look, it's Cuthbert. Let's hear what really happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>IPPOLITO... rises in the back and nods to the crowd... He's an imperious looking, pompous man with shifty eyes. Right now he's defensive. Overnight, his job is on the line...</context>
      <utterance>This has been a tragic and upsetting morning. I have terrible news for us all. A member of our security force has been found murdered. The police have just informed me it was Daniel Beauregard.  Quiet. Please. With the help of our head of security, Mr. Ippolito... the museum has been secured.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ippolito raises a hand.</context>
      <utterance>The police are satisfied we're in no danger, that we're all perfectly safe. We've been asked to remain in the Gem Room and be available for questioning for the rest of the day. Obviously, we will all do everything we can to cooperate. Are there any questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The party for the opening of the Superstition Exhibit... I imagine in the light of what's happened it will be pushed back.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ippolito registers surprise. The audience buzzes again.</context>
      <utterance>No action has been taken yet. The opening of the exhibit is crucial to the financial health of this museum. So for now, we expect that the Superstition Exhibit will open on schedule, tomorrow night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That Cuthbert. What a piece of work. Someone's dead and all he cares about is his Superstition Exhibit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cuthbert's counting on the exhibition's success. The museum is in debt. Contributions and public funding have dried up. Admissions no longer cover overhead. The last big infusion of cash we had was the King Tut exhibit. Cuthbert was hired to get us out of the red. If the Superstition Exhibit isn't lucrative, he'll have to start auctioning off some of these gems.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They glance over and see Cuthbert in the corner. He appears ill, is compulsively fingering his watch chain from which hangs a RABBIT'S FOOT. Frock goes over to speak to him, followed by Margo and Greg.</context>
      <utterance>With all this bad publicity, it's no wonder he looks like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ian. Are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beauregard. I can't believe it. I may have been the last one to see him alive. He was with me just yesterday, when I got out the statue of Mbwun.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mbwun.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo frowns, suddenly uneasy. She and Dr. Frock exchange a look.</context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Warrior deity of the Kothoga, an extinct South American tribe. Dr. John Whittlesley led an expedition that found the only known representation of Mbwun. The statue is said to carry a curse.  Every member of Whittlesley's expedition died.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got the relic out yesterday to put on display. Beauregard was there. The crates had been broken into and the contents were strewn about. But nothing was missing. It was downright weird. We joked that it was the curse of Mbwun. I'm not laughing now.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come, Ian. We all know you're superstitious. But you're among scientists here. We deal in facts. That statue had nothing to do with what happened to Beauregard.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I know is, everyone who has come in contact with that relic, is dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast is looking closely at one of the large paintings of birds that line the walls.</context>
      <utterance>Get a life.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An original Roger Tory Peterson of a Red-Breasted Merganser. Amazing. I have a copy of this in my office at home.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't really focus on birds at the moment, Pendergast. I'm tryin' to keep my breakfast down.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In this violent world, I believe the only way to stay sane is to take time to notice beautiful things.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I drink. After hours of course. On duty, I smoke.  Do you mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not at all. I enjoy the smell of a good cigar.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bites off the end, spits it out on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Then you won't like this one. It's a piece of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant --</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call me Vince.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you read about a boat that washed up outside of New Orleans about four months ago? Twelve bodies on board.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who didn't? Big news. Out of Brazil, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. That's my case. Now it's yours. All the corpses were badly mutilated in a very particular way. Decapitated. Brains extracted. Limbs torn to shreds. It looked like the work of a large animal, but there was no sign of an animal on board.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the method of death is the only connection?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BAILEY enters, interrupts.</context>
      <utterance>No. There's more. There were crates from this museum in the hold of the boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh, Vince. Sorry. This won't wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It better be good.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are a couple of kids who were lost yesterday near the site of the murder. Claimed they saw a monster. They're pretty determined to tell you their story. You want to see them?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't mind, this could be important.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately, no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm Lieutenant D'Agosta. You can call me Vince. This is Special Agent Pendergast. You can call him...  Special Agent Pendergast.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEASLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Henry Weiss and Larry Bowers.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... Tell us about this monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were lost and trying to find a short cut to the dino-- Henry elbows him hard. Larry shuts up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were just lost, okay? And we went down this curvy staircase. At the bottom was a big shadow.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big as a house.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that big.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henry makes a low GROWL in his throat. D'Agosta suppresses a smile, shoots Pendergast a look. But Pendergast watches the kids intently.</context>
      <utterance>Well almost. Depends which house. It smelled like old hamburger, and it made this weird noise.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it snuffled the ground like a dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes on hands and knees, sniffs the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It had a long tongue, teeth this big and yellow eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were green eyes and they were slit like a lizard's.</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were yellow!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're color blind.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEASLEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boys, please!  These two get in a lot of mischief and they tell some amazing whoppers.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast now moves forward, pulls up a chair as if deeply interested.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't a whopper! It's the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you get away?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ran and screamed and stuff. And we got through a little door just in time. There was a guard there and he went back to check.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A guard? Do you remember his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>badges. His name was Bo... something.</context>
      <utterance>He was wearing one of those I.D.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beauregard?</utterance>
   <speaker>LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got to admit, that was a damn sight better than "the dog ate my homework".</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you explain the part about Beauregard?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They heard the victim's name and wove him into their story. Nice touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta stops, stunned.</context>
      <utterance>I believed them.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think what we've got here is a monster as big as a house that smells... like hamburger?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I think what we've got here is a psychotic killer wielding some kind of unusual weapon... who wants us to believe he's a monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>DR. ZIEWZIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're late, Vince.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry Dr. Ziewzic. This is Special Agent Pendergast. Pendergast, Dr. Ziewzic. She runs the best chop shop in New York.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've met. The Hacksaw Murders. '89.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ZIEWZIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes! Who could forget. Afterwards you sent me that amazing case of Chateau Lafitte.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope you liked it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ZIEWZIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As I recall we split the check.</context>
      <utterance>Lovely bouquet. After our last case, Vince took me out for a draft beer.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been one of those days.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ZIEWZIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Gross wheels the gurney over to the morgue bank and slides open a drawer. The shape under the plastic seems too small to be human. To the side of it is a large bump, presumably the head. The two pieces of cadaver are slid onto the gurney and wheeled under the lights. A stainless steel bucket is placed under the gurney's outlet pipe. Dr. Ziewzic fiddles with a microphone hanging above the body, she taps it and it gives off the proper static.</context>
      <utterance>Shall we get down to it, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ZIEWZIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pull off the sheet and D'AGOSTA swallows hard, closes his eyes to keep his stomach in check. The photographer goes green, but is determined not to clutch this time. PENDERGAST leans closer, totally impassive. He puts on a small pair of wire rim glasses, assumes an expression much like a man reading a menu in a restaurant.</context>
      <utterance>This is Dr. Matilda Ziewzic, assisted by Dr. Frederick Gross. It's Oct. 28, six fifteen p.m. We are joined by Lieutenant Vincent D'Agosta of the NYPD, Special Agent Pendergast of the FBI and a police photographer. Let's see what we've got.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ZIEWZIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Caucasian male. Age about 27. Blond. Height well I can't give a height because Mr. Beauregard has been decapitated. The state of the body is such that other identifying marks are out of the question. There are numerous lacerations proceeding from the left anterior pectoral downwards through the sternum and terminating in the abdomen. This is a massive wound, two feet long and a foot wide. The head has suffered severe trauma and the occipital portion of the calavarium has been crushed and removed. It almost looks like...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. GROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ziewzic turns to Pendergast.</context>
      <utterance>A bite.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ZIEWZIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we talking about here?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone who makes the Hacksaw Murderer look like Mother Teresa.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ZIEWZIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gross passes over a grey, watery mass that sits in a stainless steel pan. Ziewzic studies Beauregard's brain, or what's left of it...</context>
      <utterance>Right.  The entire brain appears to have been extracted. May I see it, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ZIEWZIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Curious. There's something missing.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The thalamus and the hypothalamus, perhaps?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ZIEWZIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Two organs the size of a walnut have been removed with what looks like surgical precision.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to them?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ziewzic, Gross and D'Agosta look at Pendergast. The photographer is staring at the wall, silently mouthing multiplication tables to keep from woofing all over the place.</context>
      <utterance>If you don't mind a suggestion, you might try a saliva test.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saliva test? You mean, you think someone ate part of the brain?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long moment of silence, then... Zwiezic uses a swab for the saliva test, puts the result in a petrie dish.</context>
      <utterance>Correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ZWIEZIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. One saliva test. Now... let's look at these lacerations. They start wide and then converge.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Long fingernails? Scratches?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ZWIEZIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The photographer gathers his courage, steps forward with D'Agosta and Pendergast. Zwiezic rinses the object off in a beaker of sterile water. It turns brownish red. She holds it up. They all stare in astonished silence. D'Agosta swallows.</context>
      <utterance>Too extreme. Perhaps some kind of weapon. I'm now probing the wound and... there's a piece of foreign material deep in the muscle, lodged on a rib. Photograph.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweet Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. ZWIEZIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The photographer's flash goes off.</context>
      <utterance>It's a claw.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't like animals. Never have. Dog bit me when I was little. After that I gave up on pets. Animals are irrational. Give me a psychotic killer any day. If there's one thing that makes me queasy it's being part of a food chain. My first case as a rookie, two brothers climbed a fence at the zoo. It was late August. Over ninety. The polar bear was inside his cave. Kids didn't know he was in there. All they saw was the pool. They got to swimming and splashing. The noise woke up the bear. By the time I arrived, both little boys were in pieces. The bear was dragging one kid around by the foot. I can still hear the mother screaming --</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't an animal, Vince. I've been on this case four months, remember? I've learned a few things.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast looks over, nods quietly.</context>
      <utterance>You've been holding out on me Pendergast. You have a suspect capable of this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you about it, Vince.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. Has Dr. Green left?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast nods his thanks.</context>
      <utterance>Before eight? You must be joking. She's in the physical anthro lab making up for lost time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Pendergast glances at the computer screen, sees graphs and complicated notations. He scrolls down, leans closer. He can't figure it out. He slides into Margo's chair, fascinated. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Green?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>Pendergast leaps up. Margo has appeared in the doorway behind him, a cup of coffee in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>You have a warrant to look at that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What is this?</context>
      <utterance>Special Agent Pendergast. FBI. Forgive me. I guess I was snooping.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An invention of mine. It's a computer program designed to describe the characteristics of a given species from a reading of its DNA. I call it the Genetic Sequence Extrapolator.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does it work?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With a DNA analysis from a fossil you can use this program to tell the species and sex of the animal, whether it was nocturnal, what it ate, how it hunted, how big it was...  You aren't here for a lesson in DNA.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo turns to put down her coffee. She takes a moment to compose herself. When she turns back, her voice is quiet.</context>
      <utterance>No.  I came to talk about Dr. John Whittlesley.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somehow, when all this happened... I knew it would come back to John. Is he really dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he were alive he'd have contacted me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have time to talk?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Whittlesley was last seen in Belem, Venezuela a week after the rest of his expedition disappeared. A taxi driver drove him to the harbor where he boarded a cargo boat. That boat washed up in my district. Everyone on board was killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And John?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Disappeared. His body wasn't among the victims.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo pales.</context>
      <utterance>The people killed were mauled and their brains were eaten. Just like Beauregard. One part of the brain was extracted with surgical precision. The hypothalamus and thalamus to be exact.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>John couldn't have anything to do with a horrible thing like that. He was a fine man despite his problems --</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You loved him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Once. We met at Columbia. John held the Cadwalader Chair in Statistical Paleontology when I was a grad student there.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were going to be married.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I ran an internet search on Dr. Whittlesley. Got a list of his scholarly articles and the engagement announcement in the Times. I also found a record of your restraining order.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was two years ago. John was still in love with me.  He wouldn't leave me alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were afraid of him, weren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was afraid of himself. He tried suicide once. He was ill. Manic depressive. He had wild emotional highs and lows. Not a happy affliction for a scientist. He'd been revered in our community. By the end he was a joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What was he looking for?</context>
      <utterance>Tell me about the last expedition.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A legendary monster called Mbwun.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A monster?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. He developed his own theory that he called the Calisto Effect. It held that evolution wasn't always gradual or driven by natural selection. The environment would sometimes cause sudden and grotesque changes which could result in a "monster species". It made no sense. But he felt he had evidence that Mbwun was such a monster, living in isolation on the tepui for thousands of years.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo's voice catches again. Pendergast reaches for his handkerchief but she shakes her head, determined to keep control.</context>
      <utterance>No one knows. The Kothoga who live on the tepui are cannibals.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I'm all right. I won't let this affect me anymore. John wouldn't get help. His ego endangered the lives of others. His theory came first.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if Whittlesley arrived on the tepui and no monster was there? Was he desperate enough to create one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something came up in autopsy tonight. Imbedded in Beauregard's body we found a claw.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God. Then it was an animal.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so. I think we were meant to think it was Mbwun. Did Whittlesley's monster have claws?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. He sent back a statue that's supposed to be an exact representation. But I've never seen it. It's in the exhibit.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you mind showing it to me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where would we find it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure. We should split up. You take that hall and I'll take this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Without further discussion, Margo takes the right fork leaving Pendergast behind.</context>
      <utterance>All right. I'm as macho as you are. Perhaps.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. She turns, tries again, louder.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Pendergast! I found it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice catches as she stops and sniffs the air. A STENCH rolls over her. She covers her face, backs up, holding her breath.</context>
      <utterance>Pendergast! Over here --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She steps directly into a nasty statue of the Tibetan lord of the Dead. Margo starts, steadies the statue. The room is silent once more. But then, unmistakably... she hears it. An odd rustling sound. Slow. Deliberate. Maddeningly soft on the thick carpet. And another wave of THE SMELL. Margo looks in the direction she came, down the long dark hall. Her voice comes out a bit frightened as she calls...</context>
      <utterance>What the...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But now she freezes. At last she's truly scared. A shadow, black against black, is gliding stealthily towards her, moving over the display cases and grinning artifacts! Margo stands stock still, her eyes on the shadow. She lets out a small gasp of shock. She can't believe her eyes. It defies reason. Slowly, she backs up. She slips quietly through the exhibit and out the other side. In the next room she pauses again, listens... now hearing a distinctly animal, SNUFFLING SOUND! Something large is TRACKING HER! There's no doubt. Overcome by a blind panic, Margo turns and runs. She passes through a display on mythical creatures, disappears down another winding dark hall. Behind her comes... THE POUNDING OF SOMETHING IN A HEAVY, LOPING RUN! Whatever it is, it's charging after her! She turns another corner. And another, tearing as fast as she can! But now the walls up ahead are narrowing, leading to ... a DEAD END! Margo slams up against a locked door with a window of glass. The hall features displays of terrifying totem poles. All around the ghoulish carved faces seem to leap out! She pounds on the door but it's useless. She's trapped. And the thing is coming behind her! It's just around the last bend when it stops! Silence again envelops her. She's afraid to turn. She can hear HEAVY BREATHING, and something like a low growl! Reflected in the glass of the door in front of her is the long dark hall. Margo starts as a face appears IN THE REFLECTION... The image is wavering and unclear. It's a large, hulking form behind her! TWO GLOWING SLIT GREEN EYES in the dark! Margo SCREAMS as the thing leaps forward, hitting one of the totem poles. Margo sinks to the ground, unconscious. At last we hear Pendergast calling as darkness falls.</context>
      <utterance>Pendergast?  Who's there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Green! Dr. Green!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard you calling and I ran after you, but you kept disappearing and I couldn't keep up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast nods. As Margo rises he tries to help her but she waves him off, collecting her thoughts.</context>
      <utterance>You were behind me? Running after me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay, I'm all right. I remember now... It was an animal. Something large! I could smell it. It was hunting me. I saw two green eyes in the dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where did you see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo turns and points behind her to... A large NORTHWEST COAST INDIAN MASK. It's carved out of wood in a horrible grimace, inset with two glowing green eyes. Pendergast sees it too, says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>Behind me. Over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what I saw.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans against the wall, touches her forehead, panic overcoming her again.</context>
      <utterance>All right. If you're positive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't think straight at the moment. I know how crazy this seems. Please, Mr. Pendergast, I need some fresh air. Could you get me out of here?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to DOYLE, an older red-haired cop who takes up a post outside the exhibit. Pendergast hands Doyle his walkie talkie.</context>
      <utterance>Stay in formation together. Take it room by room. Check for footprints, any signs of disturbance. If you see or hear anything the least bit suspicious, I want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doyle nods. Pendergast and Margo walk out.</context>
      <utterance>Bailey's going to be in the guard house outside. Officer Van Dorn is right down that hall. When McNitt's done, he'll relieve you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Green...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't imagine it. I know what I saw. Are you sure there are enough men in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're all heavily armed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. This is hard for me. I'm a scientist. I like order and logic. Sometimes too much. There's got to be an explanation. There can't be an animal in there. But I saw something.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.  Mr. Pendergast. Do me a favor. Get me a DNA readout on that claw.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bailey? Doyle here. I'm still waiting outside the exhibit. Where the hell is McNitt?</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should be there any minute. They came out a side door a while ago. Said the exhibit's clear. McNitt's headed back to spell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on double over-time, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doyle shuts off his walkie talkie, frowns. He fidgets, looks at his watch once more.</context>
      <utterance>I know. You can go home if you want to. I'll come relieve you myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns, takes off the walkie talkie and leaves it, but then he hears something, stops. It's a low SCUFFLING from inside the exhibit, coming from behind the closed doors. Doyle freezes, turns.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. Doyle pauses. His hand goes to his gun for reassurance as he hears a footstep and a muffled thump. He moves to the door of the exhibit, opens it and takes a step inside.</context>
      <utterance>McNitt?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence meets him. The shadows of the exhibit loom. Doyle takes one more step inside, scanning the darkness with his gun. Does he hear BREATHING? He freezes. Yes, he does. The hair on his neck rises and he loses the spit in his mouth. He takes a step backwards, but he's half a second too late. The door SLAMS BEHIND HIM and a HUGE DARK FORM</context>
      <utterance>McNitt? Cut the crap. I know it's you. You're not scaring me. Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McNitt here. I'm outside the exhibit. All's quiet. But I don't see Doyle.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He called a minute ago looking for you. He starts vacation tomorrow and he wanted out. I said you were on the way. He could split.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well he's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any sign of a green-eyed monster?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McNitt shuts off the walkie talkie, settles at his post.</context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had no idea the Museum had a complete collection of Piranesi's Forum sketches.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you like them, they're for sale. Another day like yesterday and half the collection will be on the block.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've read about the Museum's financial troubles.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been operating in the red for years. That was the whole idea behind the Superstition Exhibit. It was designed to pull people in. We've spent every penny we have on advance publicity, betting everything on the opening's success. If we postpone at the last minute... No. I don't want to think about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all love the museum. I come here myself with my kids. We're trying to work with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I appreciate that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the party goes forward, and that's a big if... I've arranged for a large police presence.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do they have to wear uniforms?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to scare people.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cuthbert looks grim.</context>
      <utterance>I understand. But Mr. Cuthbert, we've got bigger problems. Depending on what we find today, we may have to shut you down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you make of it, Margo?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I think it's reptilian.</context>
      <utterance>It's not mammalian, that's for sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands them a computer read-out. Margo checks it quickly as Kawakita looks on.</context>
      <utterance>That would jive with what we got from the preliminary DNA read-out. Here, have a look.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to this, twenty-five percent of the claw DNA is unidentifiable, about a third is homo sapien, and the rest is Hemidactylus Turcicus.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo pulls off her glasses.</context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turkish Gecko, I believe. A lizard.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lizard DNA and human DNA on the same strand? Impossible. The sample must be contaminated.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's another possibility. A lot of repeated base pairs could suggest a high level of genetic damage.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Genetic damage?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When DNA is defective, it often uncontrollably replicates long repeating sequences of the same base pair. Viruses can damage DNA. So can radiation, certain chemicals. Even cancer. Let's let the G.S.E. sort it out. I have to get started. This will take several hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need someone to take us to the secure storage area.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try Dr. Frock. He's the curator of Plant Biology. All the curators have keys. And he knows every inch of this museum. The rest of us still get lost.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you for taking the time to help us with this, Dr. Frock.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Happy to be useful. It's rare enough these days. According to security, Beauregard put the Whittlesley crates in storage area 1012.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many storage areas are there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They fill seven floors. We have the largest collection of mammals and dinosaurs in the world. Just to give you an idea, there are more than three million insects specimens. Not to mention amphibians, reptiles, birds, anthropological artifacts, meteorites, minerals and gems. Only about five percent of the museum collection is actually on display.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place is a maze.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm one of the few who know every inch it, now that John is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mean Dr. Whittlesley?</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frock heads through a double door that leads to a FREIGHT ELEVATOR that's as big as a small room. The operator, KARL has it decorated with a table, chair, and PICTURES.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. John made quite a study of the whole museum. He had a copy of my original plans.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doors creak closed. They are now inside...</context>
      <utterance>Osteo prep, Karl.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Karl, who is sixty and wears a red toupee, leers.</context>
      <utterance>My kind of art.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They keep me company. Gets kinda lonely sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My favorite is the two camels.</utterance>
   <speaker>KARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Finally the doors open and they exit to a hail, enter another set of doors. Now they are in</context>
      <utterance>Really? I'm partial to the skunks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever wonder where we get all our skeletons? This is the laboratory where animal carcasses are reduced to bones.  What's cooking today, Don?</utterance>
   <speaker>DON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frock looks into a large maceration tank with Pendergast and D'Agosta. A zebra carcass can be seen under the muddy surface, its flesh and soft tissues falling off.</context>
      <utterance>Zebra.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frock now opens the door on a humid closet adjacent to the main room. Inside on a stainless steel table lies the corpse of a fox. It's crawling with BLACK BEETLES which are devouring it. D'Agosta and Pendergast watch the grizzly scene, properly impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Man, that's ripe.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Don casually peels back the gorilla's whole face exposing the skull...</context>
      <utterance>Dermestid beetles. The second method of preparing a skeleton, used in Natural History Museums world wide. Bugs are clean and highly efficient. They'll polish that fox off in no time.</utterance>
   <speaker>OSTERBAAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Want to have a look at a gorilla brain? Got one right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks Don. We're in a hurry. Some other time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast reaches up above them and TAPS THE LIGHT BULB. It comes on and they all see the heavy steel door of the storage area. D'Agosta's jaw drops and his toothpick falls out. The door has been scored from top to bottom by long, vicious, CLAWS!</context>
      <utterance>This should be it. Can you read the number?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frock stares in amazement, shaken. He runs a finger down the deep ruts.</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something tried to get into this room!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And failed. These doors are solid steel.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This means there must be an animal loose in the museum!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast takes Frock's keys and opens the door. It swings wide on oiled hinges. D'Agosta turns on a light.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't be so sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast removes the lid and hands it to D'Agosta, pulls out a BLOW DART GUN, SEED PODS, a CARVED STONE. D'Agosta takes the lid and turns it.</context>
      <utterance>This must be the one that held the statue. Let's see what else is inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As D'Agosta studies the lid, a brittle, water damaged envelope slips out. D'Agosta picks it up. The envelope bears an imprint of</context>
      <utterance>The lid of this crate is scratched with claw marks, just like the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta hands the letter to Frock.</context>
      <utterance>May I see that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's from John. Those two arrows were his insignia. It's addressed to Louis Moriarty, a patron who financed his expeditions.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Read it out loud.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frock stops, looks up at D'Agosta and Pendergast. His face flushes with the thrill.</context>
      <utterance>"Dear Louis, Tomorrow we go to the south end of the tepui where we'll be in the greatest danger, so I'm sending Carlos back with the crates. You always believed in me, Louis, even in the darkest days. So it gives me great pleasure to tell you your faith has been rewarded. We've made an incredible find. I enclose a representation of Mbwun. Note the exaggerated claws, the reptilian attributes, the hints of bipedalia. It's beyond belief, but this statue is accurate. I know because I've seen the beast."</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear that? My God. He says that Mbwun is real!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon my French, but bull shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This on top of the scratches... isn't it proof!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast looks out to the dark corridors.</context>
      <utterance>I think the scratches were put there to scare us. Perhaps even lead us to this note.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said John Whittlesley made a study of your blueprints of the museum.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are there any hidden rooms or staircases? Places where someone could hide?</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta and Pendergast exchange a look.</context>
      <utterance>Not really. Just the sub-basement.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It was walled over. No one's been down there in years.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said you had plans of the museum. Could we see them, please?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frock continues to unload boxes, scattering things right and left. It's the most amazing assortment of paraphernalia. A collection of wildflowers, soil samples, a stuffed owl. Finally he pulls out some very old blueprints and flashes a triumphant smile.</context>
      <utterance>I know they're here somewhere. It's a good thing we caught the movers in time. They're nineteen century blueprints from when the museum was built. I remember the sub-basement was below the regular basement, linked to the city sewer. I only know about it because it flooded all the way up to the museum during the hurricane of '49. I lost so many precious books.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eureka. Who says it doesn't pay to be a pack rat? Now please be careful with these. When you're done, I'd like them back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How big is the sub-basement?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apparently it's huge.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I should come with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We haven't got time. You have to meet with museum security so we can make a decision about tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They move carefully down the dark corridor which we remember from the time we last saw it with Henry and Larry. Unknown to Jonathan or Pendergast, the dogs are walking directly towards the spot where the boys faced the monster.</context>
      <utterance>These plans indicate there's a walled over entrance to the sub- basement right around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dogs start barking in animation, sniffing the wall. Pendergast studies the blueprints with a flashlight, moves to the spot. There's nothing to be seen. He shines his flashlight over the water-stained, uneven stucco between two steel beams. The dogs sniff furiously at the point where the wall meets the floor. Pendergast moves his fingers to the joint between the stucco and the beam, shoves hard. The wall pushes back. It's a door!</context>
      <utterance>The dogs are picking up something, Mr. Pendergast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This huge police presence tonight isn't necessary, Lieutenant. You'll just scare people off. I can handle the security behind scenes with this system. It's state of the art.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cops are non-negotiable, Ippolito. Why don't you just tell me how this space station works.</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's fool proof, basically. I designed this whole thing myself. Every valuable object in the Museum carries a small electronic chip. If anything's moved so much as an inch, we get an alarm pinpointing the exact location of the attempted theft.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's great if you're stopping a burglar. Not our goal here. Are there motion detectors?</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In every exhibition room. The museum's divided into five cells. The reception and exhibit are in cell five. We could arm the motion detectors in cells one to four, then seal the perimeter with our fire doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would leave one exit for hundreds of people. You'd be violating every fire regulation on the books. We'll guard the perimeter with my men and engage the motion detectors in the other cells. One more question. I see a big hole. If this entire thing is run by computer, what happens if the power fails?</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know much about computers, Lieutenant. There are safeguards built in. We have back-up systems with redundancies. There's no way these computers can fail.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't help thinking there's something that Pendergast overlooked. If the scratches were made by whatever killed Beauregard, it wants something that's in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A blow dart. Seed pods. A plant press. Pretty unimpressive stuff.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frock opens the plant press and sees a specimen inside.</context>
      <utterance>Let me see the plant press.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure. As you know, the Kothoga lived outside civilization on the tepui for thousands of years. Species flourished in isolation when man and pollution rendered them extinct. This could be one of the last remaining samples of an unknown plant.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever it is, it must be common on the tepui. John used it as packing material.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kawakita lifts out a bit of the fibers, as does Frock.</context>
      <utterance>You're right.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're curiously fleshy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kawakita TAKES a NIBBLE.</context>
      <utterance>And they smell delicious.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Taste great.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't put that in your mouth until we do a chemical analysis, Greg.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kawakita rises and exits with some of the plant.</context>
      <utterance>I can handle that for you while we're waiting on the G.S.E.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about those seed pods? Are they from the same plant? Frock takes a moment to study them, looks up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Margo, these aren't seed pods.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they?</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're eggs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard to read in this light. The ink is so faded.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The dogs have lost the scent, Mr. Pendergast. Maybe we should head back.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men reluctantly shoulder their shotguns and push on. The hounds walk ahead, carelessly nosing the ground. The flashlight beams illuminate lime-encrusted, cave-like walls.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet. Let's try the fork to the left.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this the dogs begin to WHINE. The HAIR on their backs rises in a ridge. Pendergast turns as a BREEZE stirs his clothes.</context>
      <utterance>This place gives me the creeps.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They've got something.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dogs strain and pull forward, sniffing the air ahead. The deputies raise up their shotguns as they all move deeper into the darkness. The flashlight beams streak crazily in all directions, barely penetrating the gloom. Suddenly the dogs break into a terrifying BAYING which bounces off the walls.</context>
      <utterance>Keep the light up. I can't see.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut them up!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The dogs drag Jonathan forward, paying no attention, foaming at the mouth. Jonathan is now frightened.</context>
      <utterance>Heel Argo! Hobbes! Heel!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Too late. As Jonathan tries to grab the collars, one of the dogs LEAPS forward, and the leash slips through Jonathan's hands.</context>
      <utterance>They're going crazy! I need help!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Argo BOLTS into the darkness. The men start after the dog, following the frantic barking which echoes farther and farther in the distance. Pendergast is in the lead. Suddenly he throws out his arms, halts.</context>
      <utterance>He's loose! Argo!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A goatish odor envelops them all.</context>
      <utterance>Holy mother, what is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smells God-awful. Like rotten meat.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Argo! Come!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SCUFFLING sound of claws dragging on brick is heard followed by a ROAR. The men all freeze. The other dog leaps and twists with excitement. In the confusion it also breaks free! It tears after the first dog, disappearing into the darkness. Now Jonathan is wild-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The deputies are terrified, retreat. The darkness is stifling, claustrophobic. The flashlights are small help. Pendergast alone remains dead calm. His voice is cool and commanding.</context>
      <utterance>No! Hobbes!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The deputies regain control and follow Pendergast's orders. They fall into position, pump their shotguns and aim them down the hall. In the echoing darkness ahead of them, the barking falters and stops. There is a moment of silence, then a terrible, unearthly SHRIEK. The deputies quail, frozen in their tracks. Jonathan leaps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Forget the dogs. You two, get back here. Don't point that gun at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Argo! Hobbes!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment a SHAPE hurtles at them from the darkness! The men YELL in terror. There are two stunning BLASTS from the shotguns, two FLASHES of light accompanied by a deafening roar. The rumble echoes and dies and there's an intense silence, followed by a sob.</context>
      <utterance>Get back! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hobbes lies five feet from them, a black shadow of death. Jonathan kneels by the dog, tears in his eyes. Down the animals side is a GASH.</context>
      <utterance>You shot my dog!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dog...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the distance they can hear a terrified howl. It's the second dog, hurt or frightened. It's a pitiful sound.</context>
      <utterance>He was coming right at me...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get out of here!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast grabs at Jonathan who slips from his grasp. Jonathan inches back down the hallway calling desperately.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going anywhere! Not without my dog!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hobbes!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan shakes his head no.</context>
      <utterance>Get back!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something out there! Let's go get it now! That's why we came down here, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the two deputies are terrified. They cling to the wall, inching backwards, sheer horror in their eyes.</context>
      <utterance>He's right. Follow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY ONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. I say we get help. A lot more guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm ordering you! Cover me!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEPUTY TWO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan is disappearing in front of them. Pendergast has no choice. Grim faced, he pulls his Colt .45 Anaconda from a shoulder harness. It's a narrow and evil-looking gun. From a pocket comes a handful of 255 grain wadcutter and 147 grain FMJ flatnose ammunition. He loads up, goes after Jonathan, who's no longer in sight. Pendergast passes down a long, sloping hallway into cavernous blackness ahead. At the bottom Pendergast stops. He has to stoop down as he goes through an archway and into...</context>
      <utterance>We'll cover you from here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. It's Hobbes! He's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on. Let's get back to the others. We can't leave them alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's alright. I can tell by the way the dog's acting that whatever was out there is gone. What is this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast calls back down the tunnel for the deputies.</context>
      <utterance>Not on the map. Looks like it connects with the city sewer.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The words go unanswered. From the hall comes a loud REPORT. It's the shotguns, blasting desperately. Something flies up all around them as the sound echoes. BATS! Pendergast and Jonathan shield themselves from the flurry of beating wings. Finally the animals settle and Pendergast and Jonathan exchange a look. The silence is filled by a soft RUMBLING SOUND. They stand together, waiting. Pendergast points his gun at the hall leading back to the deputies. A ridge of hair on the dog's back rises and it growls.</context>
      <utterance>We're coming back!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. The rumbling continues, growing louder. Then a dark object appears. It comes rolling out of the hallway, bounces in front of them and stops. Pendergast shines his light on... DEPUTY ONE'S HEAD! The mouth is open wide in terror. Across the cheek is a vicious claw mark.</context>
      <utterance>Identify yourself! Who's there?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh... my... God!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now they hear a GUT WRENCHING SHRIEK that's abruptly cut off, followed by a second rumbling sound! Jonathan grabs Pendergast by the shirt, panicked.</context>
      <utterance>Quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They head quietly for the exit at the other end of room which seems to slope up. After they're gone a few moments the head of DEPUTY TWO rolls to a stop.</context>
      <utterance>Stay calm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you, something's wrong. I still haven't heard from Pendergast. I think you should call it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too late now. Guests are arriving. The Mayor's car is pulling up.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll go down and speak to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't got the authority. Only Pendergast can pull the plug.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pendergast may be in trouble. Don't you understand? He still hasn't come back. It's been over three hours --</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll be back. Relax. We're in good shape. Your security is air tight. There've been no more incidents, nothing suspicious. There's no reason to call off the opening now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of egg is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's reptilian.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like the claw.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's not jump to conclusions. This egg could belong to any number of reptiles, Dr. Frock.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Margo. We're on the verge of something huge. Let's consider the possibility, just the three of us, alone in this room. What if John was right. I mean, what if? And he sent back an egg of his monster in the crates. When it got to the museum, it hatched.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frock has no answer. Greg gestures to his computer screen.</context>
      <utterance>Several problems with that theory. For one thing, this egg is intact. For another, according to Pendergast, the crates were shipped here on a boat. Everyone on board was killed like Beauregard. If the thing hatched in mid-ocean, where did it go?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess you're not interested in this plant anymore, but the chemical analysis is done. Frock reads the computer over Greg's shoulder.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Genus: Unknown. Family: Unknown. Order: Unknown. Phylum: Unknown. Cripes, Margo, what did you give me? Is this an animal or one funky shrub?"  I see you've been programming the computer vocabulary again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at this. An ambyloid reovirus protein. That explains why the computer's confused. The plant's infected with a virus.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not so unusual. Many plants carry viruses. Like the burls on Maple trees.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But a virus normally codes for other viruses. This one's making human and animal proteins. Listen to this.  "Glycotetraglycine collagenoid. Weinstein's tropic hormone. 4- monoxytocin supressin hormone."</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These plant fibers are loaded with hormones!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kawakita pulls a heavy book from the shelf. The Encyclopedia of Biochemistry, thumbs to a page and reads.</context>
      <utterance>What kind of hormones?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>4-monoxytocin is... "A hormone secreted by the human hypothalamus gland."</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tension is rising in the room. Frock takes the book, looks this one up, reads silently and removes his glasses.</context>
      <utterance>Try Weinstein's tropic hormone.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kawakita and Frock look puzzled. Margo rises in agitation.</context>
      <utterance>A hormone secreted by the human thalamus gland.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is it. This is what he, or it... is after! The plant has high concentrations of the same hormones found in minute quantities in the human brain!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pendergast told me the killer extracts and eats the hypothalamus and thalamus of the victim's brains!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eats them?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Whatever killed Beauregard may have lived on this plant. When the crates were put in secure storage, they were out of reach. The killer couldn't get them, so it got the next best thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a moment of stunned silence. Then a LOUD BUZZER makes them all jump.</context>
      <utterance>Beauregard's head.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right. That means the G.S.E. has finished analyzing the claw DNA. Greg, you go find Pendergast and Lieutenant D'Agosta now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DRUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, where 'za little boys room?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Down that hallway. But don't stay long. You don't want to be here alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>"Quadrupedal."</context>
      <utterance>All right, assuming the program is accurate, this is a description of the animal with that claw.  "Species unidentified. Genus: unidentified. Phylum unknown. Male, weight in excess of 240 kg. Brain capacity, 900 centimeters." That means it's highly intelligent.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo and Frock exchange a look. Holy shit. Margo swallows and keeps reading.</context>
      <utterance>Quadrupedal! The other name for Mbwun. "He Who Walks on All Fours."</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Nocturnal. External hair and bony plates. Locomotor speed 60-70 kilometers. Reduced optic chiasm"... poor eyesight. "External mucoid nasal glands,"... very keen scent... "Morphological characteristics: Highly robust. Aggressiveness: extreme."</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So the claw came from a huge creature with a preternatural sense of smell and poor eyesight that hunts at night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the intelligence of a human being, the speed of a greyhound, and the strength of a grizzly bear.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Margo, what you've just described is a killing machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's hungry. It's been two days since it's eaten. There are five hundred people arriving right now. The animal hunts at night and it has a keen sense of smell! All those people in one enclosed space...</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like ringing the dinner bell.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mayor takes a bow. More applause.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you everyone and welcome. We're glad all of you were willing to brave the inclement weather to be with us tonight. Our special thanks to his honor, the mayor and his lovely wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode>CON'T</mode>
      <context>Everyone laughs, applauds again as Cuthbert and the Mayor lead the way inside. Kawakita is making his way over to D'Agosta. The crush at the entrance is incredible.</context>
      <utterance>Some people have questioned whether a superstition exhibit belongs in a Museum of Science. Spells, incantations, demons, magic... these are forces that defy the natural laws. Superstition provides answers to the great questions based on fear. Science provides answers to the great questions based on truth. Science and superstition, then, are polar opposites. Mortal enemies, if you will. And that is why we are here tonight. We have come to learn more about the enemy, and thus to bring about its defeat. For every good, there is an evil, for every dark, a light. And so tonight... my friends, I give you ignorance, terror, unreasoning fear, pure evil.  Have a great time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant! It's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Green has to see you!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got my hands full here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta pulls out his walkie talkie.</context>
      <utterance>It's important. Please. You have to come! Pendergast, too. She's found out something.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>McNitt? D'Agosta here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah Lieutenant? I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm heading to the Evolutionary Bio labs. Any sign of Pendergast?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this moment a NOISE comes from the adjoining room. McNitt's head SWIVELS. It's a LOUD THUMP.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold on Lieutenant.  What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George is playing an elaborate computer game and not paying attention. McNitt returns to his walkie talkie as the THUMP comes again. Now he looks distinctly nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Probably just something wrong with the air conditioning. There's a shit load of electrical rooms back there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant? There's something wrong in the computer room.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context>George rises.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it. I'll get Ippolito and send him up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McNitt watches uneasily as George opens the door, disappears into the next room.</context>
      <utterance>You're over-reacting. Sounds like the air conditioning to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we have a very rare sacrificial table from Mesoamerica. The priests would kill the victim on this slab, cut out the heart and eat it while it was still beating.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cuthbert laughs right on cue. They pass a Congo power figure with its bulging eye sockets and torso riddled with sharp nails. Several people recoil from it, looking repulsed. The MAYOR's WIFE sees it and looks distressed.</context>
      <utterance>I could use one of these things in City Hall.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR'S WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're letting kids see this? I should think they'd have nightmares.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass a MUMMY dripping in BLOOD. The Mayor gestures to it.</context>
      <utterance>Kid will love it. They're our target audience. Nothing here is as violent as what they see on T.V.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON... the MAYOR'S WHITE CUFF as he extends his hand to point at the mummy. The pristine white of his cuff is suddenly colored by a falling RED DROP OF BLOOD. Cuthbert sees it. So does the Mayor and Ippolito. They look up as another DROP OF BLOOD falls right on Cuthbert's face. And yet another droplet falls on THE MAYOR'S WIFE'S white bosom, exposed by her low cut dress!</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. That could be a little over the top. It's not even scientific. Mummies don't bleed. Cuthbert's smile fades as he sees the mummy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THEIR POV... above the mummy's head, the top of the case is cut away, exposing a ceiling crawling with steam pipes and ductwork. A hand, a watch, and the cuff of a blue shirt protrude over the edge of the case. A small icicle of blood hangs from the middle finger. And another drop FALLS. CUTHBERT SCREAMS AT THE TOP OF HIS LUNGS! Conscious of the panic factor, Ippolito yells.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... my... God...</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But it's too late. The room is packed with people. And D'Agosta himself is just pushing through the door as another woman cries out...</context>
      <utterance>Quiet everyone!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A ripple of fear goes over the faces in the room, titters as people wonder if it's a joke. At that moment from the darkness above, the ceiling buckles and something FALLS! It's OFFICER DOYLE'S HEADLESS TORSO, dripping blood! UTTER PANDEMONIUM breaks loose! The close space ECHOES with screams and shouts. People claw at each other, stumbling desperately trying to get to the door. A YOUNG WOMAN falls and D'Agosta runs to her to keep her from being trampled in the stampede.</context>
      <utterance>There's a body up there!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McNitt looks around, desperate. But George still isn't here. The door to the electrical room is still open. The ceiling shudders from thundering feet. McNitt can hear distant SCREAMS! It's raising the hair on the back of his neck. He calls out.</context>
      <utterance>George! Get out here, now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. He moves to the open door, a new fear in his eyes. He looks inside.</context>
      <utterance>George! Where are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McNitt edges into the darkened rooms. The first one's empty. He tries the next.</context>
      <utterance>Hey you? George! Damn it. Where are you? No response.</utterance>
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly there's a HUGE THUMP and a scuttling to his left! It's a terrifying sound! McNitt drops to his knees and pumps three rounds, each with a light and a deafening blast! A SHOWER OF SPARKS and a gout of flame licks upwards, illuminating the room with orange light. A HUGE DARK SHAPE ducks out the door!</context>
      <utterance>George! We've got an emergency! Are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gunpowder hangs in the air like a blue fog. On the far wall, a mounted metal box is smoking from three large, ragged holes! With a sudden pop, an electrical arc slices across the ruined box, followed by a crackling and a shower of sparks. McNitt ducks back into the computer room, slams the door and locks it, breathing hard.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God. Oh God!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George remains still, his back to McNitt, staring at the computer game on the flickering screen.</context>
      <utterance>George! I saw something in there! I fired but I think I missed it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MCNITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>McNitt puts a hand on George's shoulder, swivels his chair around. ON GEORGE... His face ripped off.</context>
      <utterance>George, for Chrissake answer me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ippolito runs over to join them.</context>
      <utterance>There's a dead body in the exhibit! People are panicking, trampling each other trying to get out.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Above them THE LIGHTS dim again and come back on.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is going on?!</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The whole system is shutting down! We have to get out quickly before the fire doors fall!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What doors?</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you! They seal off all the cells. They were designed to fall automatically in a system failure --</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this there's a low rumble from above. D'Agosta looks up and sees A LARGE METAL DOOR IS DESCENDING from a slot in the ceiling, and not in an orderly fashion. It's falling fast. Below are crowds of people, all pushing to get out! Officer Bailey, near the door, sees it.</context>
      <utterance>You said the system couldn't fail!</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice is lost in an ocean of screaming. Kawakita stands in total horror a moment, then joins Bailey and D'Agosta. All of them try to restrain people from trying to beat the door. Ippolito, on the other hand, elbows his way to the front of the fleeing crowd!</context>
      <utterance>Above you! Look out!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ippolito! Get back here!</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ignoring D'Agosta, Ippolito pushes past. He barrels over an OLD MAN who stumbles and falls DIRECTLY BENEATH THE FALLING DOOR! Ippolito jumps over him and is out! The old man looks up at the descending wall of steel and SCREAMS! D'AGOSTA runs forward, dives for the old man but he's not in time. Kawakita covers his eyes, unable to watch as the lights flicker a third and last time. The room is plunged into darkness. And over the screams we hear the rumble and CRASH, the horrifying cries of the old man, as the door comes down.</context>
      <utterance>Like hell!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some kind of power failure. Maybe it's the storm. Do you have a flashlight?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets one from a cupboard.</context>
      <utterance>I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greg's been gone over a half hour. We'd better get out of here. Get the crate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Frock. Did you hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up ahead they hear METALLIC RUMBLING and a CRASH! They round a corner and come up against a huge STEEL DOOR.</context>
      <utterance>Don't stop now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's one of the fire doors. Good Lord, Margo. We're trapped!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taking a pen knife from his pocket, Pendergast places it into the plaster and gently twists the blade. A piece of plaster the size of a dinner plate falls, revealing the tracings of another doorway. Pendergast shoves the door open to reveal a dark, dusty room.</context>
      <utterance>I know where we are now. We're getting out, Jonathan. This should be another door.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hallelujah, Pendergast. Where the hell are we now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, what is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast tries the light switch to no effect.</context>
      <utterance>Another storage room.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They cross the room to the main door and exit. Now they're in...</context>
      <utterance>Something's happened. The power's out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With these words, the dog GROWLS. Jonathan freezes and sniffs the air.</context>
      <utterance>All right. I know where we are. This is the osteo prep lab. I was in here earlier. We're safe now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no. I smell it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan kneels by Hobbes as Pendergast listens, every nerve on end. A sound comes from the adjacent hallway that leads to the secure storage area. It's unmistakable HEAVY BREATHING and the creeping movement of claws. Pendergast lifts his gun.</context>
      <utterance>Keep the animal quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan doesn't have to be told twice. He takes the dog and exits from the other side of the lab leaving Pendergast alone. Pendergast waits a moment until Jonathan's safely out of sight. He switches off his flashlight, backs up slowly, step by step. He opens the door to the alcoholics storage. As he slips inside a DARK SHAPE appears.</context>
      <utterance>Go out the other doorway. There's a stair at the end of the hall. Up five flights is a corridor that leads to the Hall of the Heavens. Find Lieutenant D'Agosta. Bring help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo points her light in the distance and illuminates the beast! It's descending like a freight train. One split second of sheer amazement, then...</context>
      <utterance>Look!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frock, immobilized in his wheel chair, stares at the monster, like a trapped rabbit looking at a descending hawk. Margo grabs his keys from him, fumbles desperately to open the door. It swings wide at last. She grabs the handles of the wheelchair, tugs with all her might. The wheels bump into the door frame but somehow she wrestles the damn thing inside.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Frock! Quick!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pendergast? Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The storage door opens slowly and Margo looks out.</context>
      <utterance>No. I think I'm hallucinating.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not. Where is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wounded?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. A chromium alloy tipped .45 caliber bullet bounced off that thing's skull like a spit ball. I think it was bothered by my light.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quick. Come inside.</context>
      <utterance>That would fit. It's nocturnal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Manual overrides aren't working. I'm getting nothing, Lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank, the father of the teenage girl, Lauren, steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd starts to murmur. One man yells.</context>
      <utterance>There's no power. The whole system's down.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're trapped! And there's a killer in here!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MAYOR stands. His wife's forehead is bleeding.</context>
      <utterance>We'll get out safely if everyone stays calm. Is anyone else hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. My wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The distinguished grey haired man with a cane comes forward. DR.</context>
      <utterance>Is there a doctor?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>POUND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Dr. Pound.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pound moves off. Everyone spins now at the incongruous sound of a DOG BARK. D'Agosta pulls his gun. The door to a stairwell at the far end of the room opens and Hobbes bounds into the hall! He's followed by Jonathan, who is filthy and wild-eyed.</context>
      <utterance>Check this woman and see if anyone else needs you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant D'Agosta! Don't shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Pendergast?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta makes a quick sweep of the room with his flashlight. The remote corners of the hall are so black the light seems to disappear. In the center, two men are bending over a still form. One of them is Dr. Pound.</context>
      <utterance>Five flights down. We were lost in the sub-basement. Something's down there. It killed our two deputies. When I left Pendergast it was coming back. He sent me for help. We have to hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Both of you. Get back here.</utterance>
   <speaker>POUND</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he's still alive --</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The urgency in D'Agosta's voice gets everyone's attention. The Mayor brings his wife over. Cuthbert comes too. They huddle apart from the others. Cuthbert's white with fear.</context>
      <utterance>Get back now!</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta speaks low.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's some kind of animal loose in the museum. Pendergast's alone. He needs help. I want volunteers to go with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BAILEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd do it gladly but someone needs to stay with these people.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank steps forward.</context>
      <utterance>All right. You're elected. Bailey, get all the guns and flashlights, give the mayor your walkie talkie so we can keep in touch. Cuthbert, keep everyone together and make sure they stay quiet.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was in the Marines. Give me a gun. I'd go with you, too, but I've got my daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta gives Frank his service revolver.</context>
      <utterance>All right. You guard these people and your daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR'S WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The remaining crowd begins to whimper. The Mayor rises.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you going? Don't leave us alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bailey and D'Agosta carry shot guns. They quietly move to the back stairwell at the far end of the Hall of the Heavens. Everyone else bunches together and watches.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone quiet. The Lieutenant's in charge.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan gives Hobbes' leash to the Mayor. D'Agosta hands Greg Kawakita a shotgun, tightens his grip on his own. Then he gives the signal and Bailey yanks open the door to the stairwell.</context>
      <utterance>Bailey, we'll go first and check the stairwell. Jonathan, you and Greg guard the door.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. Could you tell me how this thing works?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta heads down the stairs in the lead, with Bailey close behind. The stairwell is windowless and dark. D'Agosta shines his light and it cuts into the blackness. He moves quietly, makes the first landing and stops. Bailey watches his back from several steps behind as D'Agosta signals for him to wait. The flashlight flares into a glass door one flight down. D'Agosta raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus. Don't point it at me. Just aim and shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa... You smell that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Too late. At this something DROPS FROM ABOVE! A huge dark shape LEAPS INTO THE STAIRWELL, descending two floors! It lands, pounces on BAILEY and the marble walls echo with a ROAR.</context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant! Get back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is it?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta pumps two shells in the shotgun. Screams can be heard from the people crouched together at the edge of the room. Hobbes is barking wildly, foaming at the mouth. It's too dark to see what's happening.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know! It hit me hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody tell me! Where is it now?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kawakita stumbles to join them, tries to join in. The barrel of his shot gun still swings wildly. He steadies it by taking it in both hands.</context>
      <utterance>On three.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All three fire. There's a loud report. The kickback knocks Kawakita backwards. Screams erupt from the huddled group. Hobbes abruptly shuts up. The men fire and fire until there's nothing left. D'Agosta reaches for more shells, comes up empty.</context>
      <utterance>One, two... three.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan moves. D'Agosta sweeps his light across the room but already the shape is gone. Cuthbert hides behind the Mayor, calls out in a terrified squeal.</context>
      <utterance>Jonathan! Get everyone behind me!</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta runs across the room to a set of double industrial doors. There's a noise in the darkness beyond and he just manages to slam both doors. He picks up a metal chair and jams it through the handles. Backs up. The doors shudder as something hits them hard.</context>
      <utterance>It went out the door to the rotunda!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan, the Mayor, Cuthbert and Kawakita together herd everyone towards the stairwell. They move inside.</context>
      <utterance>Get everyone into the stairwell!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweet Jesus!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get his gun and his walkie talkie, Jonathan. Move.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My office is on the third floor! There's a walk-in safe and a portable phone! We can lock ourselves in the safe and call for help!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to help Pendergast. Kawakita and Jonathan stay with me. The rest of you can go with Cuthbert!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we should stick together!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No one follows.</context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving. Whoever wants can come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cuthbert's gone.</context>
      <utterance>Wait!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan grabs Hobbes' leash from the Mayor and bounds up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Jonathan, go with him! He isn't armed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone else follows D'Agosta. Together, they head down.</context>
      <utterance>Good luck!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the security men, WATERS, rises.</context>
      <utterance>All right everyone. I'm in charge. Status report.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ippolito pulls out his walkie talkie.</context>
      <utterance>Swat teams are on the way. Fire trucks with them. Everything's slowed down because of the rain. We're bringing in portable generators. They'll get the emergency lights working but they won't pump enough power to lift the doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>D'Agosta? Ippolito. Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made it outside. I'll co-ordinate the rescue efforts from here. Help is on the way. Just sit tight.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context>A long moment as the men look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>It's a little late, you son of a bitch. There's a friggin' monster loose in here! Get the FBI, the fire department. Find metal cutters, cut through. And bring a cannon. The damn thing is huge.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he say monster?</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Panic attack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>D'Agosta passes the walkie talkie to the Mayor.</context>
      <utterance>D'Agosta, put on the Mayor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mayor Jordan here.</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode>ON RADIO</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Ippolito, head of museum security. Relieve D'Agosta and take command.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mayor shuts off the walkie talkie and they round another corner and disappear from sight.</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me what to do you chicken shit bastard. I saw you cut and run! Lieutenant D'Agosta stayed with us. He is in charge. There is a monster. I saw it. Cut through those doors and get us out of here, now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. The steel doors are designed to retard cutting. We can go through them, but it would take hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The quickest way in would be to go through the roof, sir. Cell two goes up to the fifth floor. There are sky lights up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Co-ordinate with the fire department and SWAT teams. Move.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how to deal with this. It's hellish. Like nothing I ever saw. I'm not trained to deal with a monster, a supernatural creature like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not supernatural. Mbwun is an animal. Part lizard, part human, a genetic freak of some kind, like the half-goat, half-sheep they found last year in the jungles of Vietnam.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But this isn't the jungle! This is New York. How did it get here? A thing like that crossed two continents. It makes no sense!</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We think it may have something to do with the eggs we found in the crate.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of that matters now. The people upstairs need us. We have to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't. We've managed to get inside the one place that's safe. I think we should sit tight and wait for reinforcements. If we go outside, we're risking more lives. You have to accept it, Margo, there's nothing we can do. The building must be swarming with police by now. It won't take long for them to get through the doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That thing could kill ten people in a matter of minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what can we do? Our guns are useless --</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have the fibers. Don't you see? The creature is hungry. It wants the hormones in these plants. It would take hundreds of human brains to supply what's in these fibers. We're just a poor substitute. To make it stop hunting, we have to give it what it wants.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cuthbert scurries to his desk and pulls out a Ruger .38 Magnum.</context>
      <utterance>Solid oak. Two inches thick. Tell me they'll hold.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it after I was mugged in the subway last spring.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the walk-in safe?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Behind you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the combination?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rummages in the darkness, going through his desk.</context>
      <utterance>I'll do it. Just let me find my portable phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cuthbert flips the phone open and turns it on.</context>
      <utterance>Calm down. I found it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Battery's dead. Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cuthbert crosses to a huge wall safe, starts frantically turning the tumblers. Jonathan follows with the dog.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That thing won't come after us, right? It's going for bigger game. The group blundering around in the basement. Poor fools.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry up!</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cuthbert fumbles to hand over the Ruger. As he does, something drops.</context>
      <utterance>Just a minute. I'm shaking! Take the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cuthbert drops to his knees, groping in the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God! I dropped my rabbit's foot!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For Chrissake, I'll do it. What's the combination?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To the left twice then five no... sorry... I think it's fifteen... it's been a while...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan starts again, sweating. The tumblers fall with agonizing slowness. Cuthbert continues groping frantically for his good luck charm. Meanwhile, unnoticed by Jonathan, the dog is staring at the oak doors. We see the HAIR ON HIS BACK rise!</context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifteen... what's next?</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTHBERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clutching the rabbit's foot like a talisman, Cuthbert leaps up just as the last tumbler falls. At this the oak doors behind them CRASH OPEN, splintering like so many match sticks. Cuthbert SCREAMS in a high pitch whine at the sight of the beast. The dog barks wildly at Mbwun! Jonathan lifts his shot gun. But the monster barrels past him and zeros in on Cuthbert! A HUGE RED TONGUE LICKS OUT and encircles Cuthbert's waist! It squeezes him horribly, drags him towards the open jaws! Cuthbert bellows like a lamb being led to the slaughter. He opens his hand and the rabbit's foot drops! The last Jonathan sees of Cuthbert is his head disappearing down Mbwun's throat. Hobbes barks and whines in terror. Jonathan takes the leash and drags the animal out.</context>
      <utterance>Eight to the right! Look! I found it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo and Frock quickly come out. Margo holds the crate. Frock tries to follow in his wheelchair.</context>
      <utterance>All clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm coming with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Dr. Frock. You can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd slow us down and put Margo in danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unlock one of the other storage rooms. We're going upstairs. We'll leave a trail back to 1012 and try to trap the monster in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Margo, this is too dangerous. You always think you can solve everything. This time you don't have enough information. The animal might behave in unexpected ways.  Leave her here with me. Don't put her in danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You'll need me -- At this a LOUD SOUND comes from upstairs!</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Footsteps!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All three know this ends the discussion. Frock opens the door to room 1010. Inside are shelves of priceless ivory tusks. Margo takes Pendergast's handkerchief and wraps her hand. She quickly sprinkles some of the fibers inside the door to room 1012. Before Dr. Frock disappears into room 1010, he looks back to Margo one last time.</context>
      <utterance>No, not footsteps! People running for their lives!</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come back and get me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will.</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember, it has poor eyesight. It hunts with its sense of smell. So for God's sake, Margo, don't get those fibers on your clothes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's still back there!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now a voice is heard in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>Everyone stops. D'Agosta shines his light into the large space. Above them constellations glow. D'Agosta calls out...</context>
      <utterance>Where are you? Who's there?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pendergast!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was D'Agosta.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The planetarium!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vince!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>There's a double steel fire door at the end of the hallway. Pendergast and Margo run for it. Pendergast shoves at the door. It won't budge. There's a small glass window. In it, D'Agosta's face appears.</context>
      <utterance>Over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pendergast! Help! It's right behind us!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This door's locked. Try shooting the hinges off.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta, Frank and Kawakita aim their guns at the door and shoot repeatedly. The shots echo wildly. The sound is terrifyingly loud. The small glass window shatters. Then the men lean heavily on the door. It still won't budge. D'Agosta looks through the window.</context>
      <utterance>Step back!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kawakita hands his walkie talkie through the window. Margo takes it.</context>
      <utterance>It's no use. We have to get out of here!  Give them your walkie talkie.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Dr. Frock safe!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, he's fine. Greg... take care of yourself!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there another way around?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast returns to the window.</context>
      <utterance>No. The planetarium is in the next cell. This is one of the fire doors...</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vince? There's no way we can get to you with the fire doors down. There's an entrance to the sub- basement in the hall off the north side exit.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sub-basement?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta turns to the others.</context>
      <utterance>I've been down there. It links up to the old sewer system. I can guide you out.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much ammo do we have to make a stand?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're asking me? I don't even know how to load this thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a movement of air... and a ripe, fetid smell.</context>
      <utterance>Four rounds...</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta pumps his shot gun.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I smell it. It's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go out the north exit! There's a hallway and a false wall by the Greek vases. Run!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others move past. D'Agosta, Frank and Greg Kawakita hold the rear. The group runs to the side exit to the planetarium and in a moment, disappears.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody. Get behind me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hide quickly!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast checks his gun, totally calm.</context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo turns and looks around at the looming dioramas. There's a plain door at their end of the hall. Pendergast faces the broken window. HIS POV... the beast is slinking away after D'Agosta and the others, headed to the north exit from the Planetarium! PENDERGAST calls out...</context>
      <utterance>Buy them some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast puts his palms up at his ears, wiggles his fingers and makes a face through the window.</context>
      <utterance>Hey you big tub of lard! Over here! THE BEAST PAUSES, turns.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A LOW surprised GROWL comes from the beast. It crouches as if to pounce. Pendergast makes more faces, sticks his tongue out. The beast watches in silence, its evil eyes fixed. ON MARGO... watching Pendergast. She can't leave him yet.</context>
      <utterance>Come on, you smelly pile of refuse. Come get me. I dare you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leaves the crate behind as Pendergast dives inside with her. Margo shoves the door shut hard as Mbwun, still blinded, leaps into the hall. But now, suddenly, all is quiet. No sign of Margo and Pendergast. The beast moves forward, snuffling slowly. It starts for the door which hides Margo and Pendergast, but stops as it finds... THE CRATE! The beast moves to it, clearly surprised. It pokes at the crate carefully, inhales the fragrance and grunts. The monster seems to be struggling with itself! It sniffs the fibers, lifts a few out carefully, then SHOVES THE CRATE AWAY HARD. Then it rises on its haunches and squints into the dark. On all sides are glowing displays of stuffed buffalo, gazelle, wild horses, wolves, giant elk, sabre tooth tigers. Mbwun moves close to one after another. Suddenly we notice, in the back of one of the dioramas... Margo and Pendergast! They stand frozen, crouching behind mannequins of native Americans riding horses across the plains. The beast sniffs RIGHT AT THEIR WINDOW, then turns away. Confused, it heads back towards the Planetarium and slinks from the room. INSIDE THE DIORAMA... Pendergast and Margo exchange an astonished look. They whisper.</context>
      <utterance>Drop the fibers!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Its eyesight is worse than I thought. It couldn't see us. And it couldn't smell us through the glass.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It didn't want the fibers. What does that mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think... it means it's full.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then it won't go after the others?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's still hunting, but not for the hormones.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think... for the pleasure of the kill.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. Kawakita, cover the rear.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta nods. Frank expertly reloads. D'Agosta holsters the walkie talkie and they plunge down the left hand passage. Kawakita takes charge of Lauren, who is confused and terrified. The tunnel has a slight downhill grade, and the water begins to move faster, tugging at everyone's legs. People slip and slide as they half make their way down the hill. D'Agosta calls behind them.</context>
      <utterance>No, Lieutenant. He's not a good enough shot. I'll do it if you take care of my daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON FRANK... back not far from the first fork. He looks towards the head of the tunnel, calls out...</context>
      <utterance>Damn. It's getting deep. See anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank turns and plunges after the others. But then suddenly, he stops. ON D'AGOSTA... he reaches the second fork and takes a right. This tunnel is narrower and consequently the water is even deeper. Slimy plants hang down and slap at their faces as they push on. D'Agosta pulls out his walkie talkie.</context>
      <utterance>You'll be the first to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But before Pendergast can answer, D'Agosta hears the loud report of Frank's gun! Everyone freezes in the darkness. The walkie talkie cackles and D'Agosta shouts!</context>
      <utterance>Pendergast? I made the right hand fork. We're already in about three feet of water. Where should we go?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>OS</mode>
      <context>They hear SPLASHING in the water. Lauren SCREAMS, tries to run back. Kawakita grabs her. There's more thrashing water and then silence.</context>
      <utterance>Sweet Jesus, help!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta starts for Frank but the Mayor catches his arm and holds him.</context>
      <utterance>Frank! Are you all right!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone waits, staring into the darkness. Still no answer. Lauren</context>
      <utterance>It's too late!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta turns his flashlight on the water. It's running red! He spins to the Mayor, points down the tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>Dad!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>People start to cry and whimper as the Mayor urges them on. He takes charge of Lauren. Only Greg Kawakita stays with D'Agosta. They stand shoulder to shoulder and completely alone. Thrashing in the water can be heard as the beast comes closer. There's a low, pleasurable growl! Both men lift their guns.</context>
      <utterance>Run!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kawakita nods. Behind them in the tunnel is total blackness. Ahead is equally dark. The noise of their friends gets ever fainter. The water now rushes half way up their thighs. Kawakita's teeth start to chatter. He bites them shut, steadies his gun.</context>
      <utterance>On three.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence as the water murmurs. D'Agosta holds the count. A long, agonizing moment. Kawakita takes his eyes away from the tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>One... two...</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a HUGE CLAW snakes out of the water right in front of them and the beast roars up! It was beneath the surface, directly before them! The claw closes on D'Agosta and his shot gun goes off. D'Agosta screams as the beast lifts him towards its mouth! For one horrible moment, Kawakita is frozen. Then he leaps forward, shoves the barrel of his gun behind D'Agosta, right in the beast's open jaws! He pulls the trigger and the shotgun explodes, the recoil throwing him back, ass over tea cups in the water. With a roar of pain the monster drops D'Agosta and retreats in the dark. D'Agosta grabs Kawakita.</context>
      <utterance>I think it's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They haul ass down the tunnel, firing behind them as they go. Ahead is another fork. The group is waiting. When they see D'Agosta and Kawakita, a cheer goes up.</context>
      <utterance>I think you took its tonsils out!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he runs up, D'Agosta grabs for his walkie talkie. The holster IS EMPTY, the walkie talkie gone! Without missing a beat he registers what's happened, then covers it up with the next breath. He points to the right as if there's no doubt and says...</context>
      <utterance>Which way!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta exchanges a look with Kawakita, who understands exactly what happened. As they plunge into the right tunnel, Greg mutters...</context>
      <utterance>This way!</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing but static comes in response. Margo paces in agitation.</context>
      <utterance>Vince? Can you hear me? Vince!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to try and draw it off!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to one of the dioramas. It shows a bird being stalked by a fox.</context>
      <utterance>The answer's right in front of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a ptarmigan, feigning a broken wing. The bird pretends to be injured to draw the fox away from its nest!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo heads for the Planetarium, calling...</context>
      <utterance>It's deceptively simple. Like a Bruckner Symphony or a Matisse.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They disappear down the hall with the Greek vases, both calling with all they've got.</context>
      <utterance>Help! Please someone! Help!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JENNINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're ready. We've got enough firepower to turn a herd of lions into a fine red mist.</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jennings nods, goes off. As Ippolito watches the S.W.A.T. team break the glass skylights, gets ready to go in.</context>
      <utterance>Then do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly he sees something. What appears to be a BODY lying on a glass case! Jonathan pumps his gun, approaches slowly. The man wears a tuxedo, is lying very still. As we get closer we see it's THE DRUNK Kawakita ran into in the stairwell so long ago! He suddenly HICCUPS. Jonathan starts. Now the man gently snores. Jonathan moves to him, shakes the drunk's shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay, Hobbes. We'll be all right. Help has got to come eventually... We'll make it. We'll be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man snorts, opens his eyes and frowns.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Wake up!</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan helps the drunk off the glass case. The man's a little unsteady as he tugs at his tux.</context>
      <utterance>You first.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got lost tryin' to find the bathroom. I was walkin' in circles. I lay down for a nap. What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hobbes has started to wag his tail and tug at the leash to draw Jonathan's attention.</context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't believe me if I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From above comes the beating of a distant HELICOPTER and then the sound of breaking glass. Hobbes pulls Jonathan back to the staircase. Jonathan grins, follows behind with the drunk.</context>
      <utterance>What is it, boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DRUNK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think we're going home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They run across the long hall and wait as the the men descend. The first one down is Jennings.</context>
      <utterance>Hello! We're over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sling suspended on ropes is lowered down.</context>
      <utterance>We're fine. I don't know about the people downstairs. In the Hall of the Heavens. The basement... you'll need help. There's a monster down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JENNINGS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jennings signals to a group of five men, heavily armed and in flack jackets. They prepare to get the drunk out.</context>
      <utterance>The rescue workers will lift you out one at a time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help someone!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They suddenly hear the sound of splashing. An updraft rustles their clothes. Margo sniffs the air, turns to Pendergast.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God! Help!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You smell that?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's coming. Run.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all press forward in the low vaulted darkness. As they move steadily upwards the water recedes. Kawakita's flashlight flickers and he bangs it. It comes on again.</context>
      <utterance>At least we'll be dry.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe in you a hundred percent, Vince, but that's the second time we've been at that intersection.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta shines his light forward and they see that the shaft ends in a large round PIPE.</context>
      <utterance>Not so loud.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kawakita and D'Agosta move past the shivering people who are strung out along the sides of the tunnel. D'Agosta touches each person as he passes.</context>
      <utterance>All right everybody, hold up!</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't know what's in there. Let me go first.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it say?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. John Whittlesley.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Whittlesley died in South America.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I thought Dr.</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>D'Agosta shines his light down and everyone freezes. Then one woman</context>
      <utterance>What is that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dear God. Where are we, Lieutenant?</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd say we're in its home.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not going to make the storage room!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AT THIS THEY ROUND A CORNER AND MBWUN LEAPS OUT! It circled ahead and was waiting in front of them! The animal swipes at Margo and Pendergast. The force of the monster's blow sends Margo reeling and slams Pendergast into the wall. He falls, crumples and drops his gun! The case beside him SHATTERS spewing relics, as Mbwun pushes past. Pendergast groans and gets to his knees with difficulty. MARGO is frantically crawling away in the dark! The beast makes a low sound of pleasure and reaches out one claw, easily pins her down. Pendergast looks frantically for any kind of weapon! ON MARGO now PINNED BENEATH the heaving body of the monster! Powerless, she looks up into the horrible face of death as Mbwun raises an enormous claw! Pendergast, desperate, cries out --</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, Pendergast. Mbwun's DNA is part homo sapien. In primates, the eye is a direct path to the brain! If you get a clean shot, there's only one place you can kill it. Shoot it in the eye!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oddly enough, the beast pauses for once. Talking to the damn thing is the one tactic no one has tried! The claw halts in mid-air. The beast blinks once and looks from Pendergast to Margo. Margo sees a flash of something</context>
      <utterance>Please, no! Don't hurt Margo!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A strange noise comes out of the monster. A low, confused growl. He doesn't loosen his grip on Margo, but he leans down to look at her closer with one green, unblinking eye. She struggles not to turn away in revulsion. His enormous jaws are right near her throat. Everything is very still. And then... A BARRAGE OF FIRE breaks out! The S.W.A.T. team is in the doorway, laying down everything they've got. The creature ROARS as if betrayed, leaves Margo and LEAPS UP. It barrels down on the S.W.A.T. team, picks up Jennings and SPIKES HIM TO THE GROUND. Jennings hits the floor with his neck at a crazy angle. It snaps like a twig. The other men drop back. Mbwun follows, tearing through the men, cutting a deathly swath! Pendergast moves to help the S.W.A.T. team. Margo struggles to her feet and her hand touches the wall. Beside her is a FIRE HOSE in a cabinet! In a split second Margo hauls it out, throws a switch and gets a BLAST OF WATER. She turns it on the beast as it grabs for Pendergast. The force of the water is enormous. It pushes the monster out the end of the hall. Pendergast runs towards her, takes the hose and holds it.</context>
      <utterance>Please let me go. We won't hurt you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes off blindly in the maze-like room. From somewhere behind her she hears a horrible HOWL. ON MARGO... as she twists and turns through the rows of display cases, tearing blindly in the dark. Ahead is a door. She dives through it and finds she's in...</context>
      <utterance>Run!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The name is a knife through the monster's heart!</context>
      <utterance>Oh Jesus. John?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The last piece of the puzzle falls. The monster is John Whittlesley! Margo, still desperately frightened, tries to keep control.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's not possible!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The monster shakes its head no and releases her. As she watches he moves away, quickly limps out the door.</context>
      <utterance>John? If it is you... I can help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Don't kill him! Pendergast, you were right. It's John!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast looks over and sees the monster. His eyes show disbelief. Mbwun looks back at both of them briefly, then it disappears up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>That thing is John Whittlesley. I should have seen it before! The fibers are infected with a virus. You eat them, and the virus alters your DNA! He became addicted to them in South America, followed the plants back to the states. He probably entered the country as a man. It would have taken several months for the change to take place. That's how he got from the boat to the museum!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to! Listen! All viruses pass on their own DNA. Instruct the cells of the host to make more viruses! This one was different. It inserted a whole array of genes into John. Reptile genes, sixty five million years old. Those genes remade him! It's not his fault!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo tries to stop him, but he shrugs her off.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever that thing is, we have to kill it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WATERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ippolito eyes are fixed on the room below them.</context>
      <utterance>We can't raise the S.W.A.T. team. No one's answering! What do you want to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lightning throws horrible shadows of the hulking dinosaur skeletons all around as MBWUN LIMPS INTO THE HALL! The men on the roof stare down astonished. Their mouths hang open at the sight!</context>
      <utterance>Holy shit. Pull him up.</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men get the drunk up and abandon the sling, leaving Jonathan trapped below.</context>
      <utterance>Get more guns! Now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Margo runs forward.</context>
      <utterance>Get back! We're going to shoot!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Wait! Let me talk to him first!</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill that thing! Kill it now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MBWUN... turns and sees Margo. She speaks desperately.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mbwun seems to consider for a moment, but then its eyes gleam and it ROARS. With renewed vigor it leaps to the wall and starts to WALK UP IT like a GECKO, ON ALL FOURS! ON THE ROOF... Some of the S.W.A.T. team fall back in terror! Now that the monster is on the wall it's out of range of their fire!</context>
      <utterance>John... you can give up now! Just lie down where you are!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit it's coming this way!</utterance>
   <speaker>IPPOLITO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ippolito turns and takes off once more in sheer terror. Astonished, Waters tries to regain control.</context>
      <utterance>It's headed for the roof. Run!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the men are terrified, retreating like Ippolito. Waters shouts.</context>
      <utterance>Get back here, you asshole! We can't let it get out!  Surround the opening and kill it!</utterance>
   <speaker>WATERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the team is in chaos and losing precious time.</context>
      <utterance>Back, everybody! That's an order!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just like John. He won't listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have to shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pendergast raises a HIGH POWERED RIFLE with a laser sight. He aims the red laser beam directly at Mbwun's left eye.</context>
      <utterance>Do it, quickly. Please. Aim for the eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has to look here or I won't get a clear shot. Call him, Margo.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't!</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo takes a moment, her eyes streaming. She has no choice, she calls out.</context>
      <utterance>You have to. Do it now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The beast looks down, sees Pendergast's rifle. There's a long, awful, moment. Suddenly it emits a sound like a wail. ON JONATHAN... staring, stunned. PENDERGAST... steady... MARGO... She's crying as she raises her arm as if to say good-bye. And the gun EXPLODES. ON MBWUN... its head shoots back in pain, and it falls... sixty feet straight down to the ground. Silence. Thunder rolls. It's over. Pendergast turns to Margo and quietly folds her in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>John! John, look at me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Margo Green. Have you seen her?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Greg turns to see Margo come out of the Rotunda with Frock, Jonathan and Hobbes. Her face is devastated. He moves to her side. She reacts as she sees him, and teacher and pupil hug. D'AGOSTA is lost in the swirl of people. And he likes it like that. He rests against a large stone lion, pulls out a cheap cigar in cellophane, unwraps it carefully and tries to light it with a wet match. He's struggling hopelessly. Finally he tosses the useless pack of matches, sighs. But then a flame lowers right before his face. He looks up to see Pendergast holding a silver engraved lighter. D'Agosta smiles, takes a nice long hit.</context>
      <utterance>She's over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice to see you, Lieutenant.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We go to a wide shot of the museum as we slowly pull back...</context>
      <utterance>The sub-basement, huh? Great idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Greg looks up from his work and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>No time for fishing anymore?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got to finish this thesis sometime.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about lunch?</utterance>
   <speaker>KAWAKITA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not today. Besides, I think the director of the museum is expecting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo exits. Greg returns to his work.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Frock?</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PENDERGAST and D'AGOSTA rise out of two high-backed chairs. Margo smiles for the first time, takes Pendergast's hands.</context>
      <utterance>Look who's here, Margo.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad to see you. What's the occasion?</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in town on a case. Dropped by to see Vince and we thought we'd see the new display.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Frock, I was wondering. What happened to the rest of Whittlesley's plants?</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were sent to the Center For Disease Control in Atlanta.</utterance>
   <speaker>D'AGOSTA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shouldn't a drug that powerful be destroyed?</utterance>
   <speaker>FROCK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The virus itself might have positive applications. They'll keep the plants in secure lock up while the studies are made.  Greg isn't joining us?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pause on a NEW DIORAMA. It's huge, filling one entire end of the hall. In the center is a life-sized representation of MBWUN standing on the tepui amid the plants. Behind is a painting of John Whittlesley as he once was. He wears the necklace with the two arrows, of silver and gold. As Margo looks, she touches her own. Pendergast turns to her, sympathy in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>He's changed. He's always working on his thesis. He comes in early, stays late. I tried to get him to join us, but he never takes a break.</utterance>
   <speaker>PENDERGAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Margo smiles warmly.</context>
      <utterance>We did the right thing, Margo.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARGO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
