<movie id="441" title="Postman The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>As The Postman continues to cross, the CAMERA PULLS BACK. He's soon lost in the massive vista.</context>
      <utterance>The last of the great cities died when my father was a child. Another victim of yet another war. The plagues followed. And the terrors. The living hid themselves away in tiny hamlets in hopes of surviving whatever new madness conspired to rob them of the little that remained. The Earth itself had fallen prey to chaos. For three years a dirty snow fell that even summer could not erase. The ocean was barren. Poisoned. Near death.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A RUMBLE of THUNDER. RAIN begins to fall. The earth just sucks it up at first, but it's coming hard. Rivulets run. Puddles form. We begin to get the feeling that soon these boats will be tugging at the mooring chains once again.</context>
      <utterance>Sixteen long years passed before the great lungs started working again. My father said it was as if the ocean breathed a great sigh of relief...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They near a sign: "Thank You For Visiting Utah." The Postman waves, shouts to the sign as he passes it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. And if you ask me again, I'm going to slug you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been fun, hasn't it, kids?  You're welcome!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill hangs his head. The Postman digs through his pack. He removes an old Tupperware container and replaces its contents -- a tiny sheaf of litmus papers and several small bottles -- with stream water. He adds a few drops from each bottle. Swirls it around. Then dips a tiny strip of paper into the water. The paper turns a vivid purple. The Postman is dubious.</context>
      <utterance>Damnit, Bill, you know I need to check it first!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill drinks.</context>
      <utterance>Better than turpentine.  Tastes about the same. Your call, Bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman takes his carbine and a burlap sack and crosses to the 76 Station. An old extension ladder on the ground. The pole holding up the 76 ball has a 30-degree bend in it, like someone once tried to pull it over. Beyond the 76 ball, the sun sets -- but we here in the 20th Century have never seen such a wild riot of color before. The Postman tries the station door. Locked. Smiling ironically, he steps in through the blown-out window.</context>
      <utterance>You ain't picky, Bill. I like that about you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tossing it, he turns, stops. There, resting on a pile of trash is a bashed-in portable TV. The Postman smiles.</context>
      <utterance>'Running on Empty'? Tell me about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps over, switches on the set. Nothing happens, but The Postman pretends just the same. He mimics static, then:</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Bill! We got TV! 147 channels. Everything from Jesus to 'Jeopardy'.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman stops suddenly. Click.</context>
      <utterance>'Like sands through the hour- glass, so are the days of our lives...'  'Michael Shields, come on down, you're the next contestant on...'The Price is Right'.'  I'll take Domestic Nuclear Disasters for two hundred thousand, Alex...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman stares at the blank screen a moment. There's a sudden, panicked RUSTLING from behind the service manager's desk. The Postman wheels around, raises the carbine.</context>
      <utterance>We interrupt our regularly scheduled program to bring you the Second Civil War... Well, shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sudden MOVEMENT. The Postman shouts in surprise as a Doe dashes out from behind the desk. Scared, it bounds back and forth between the walls. Then freezes in the corner. The Postman sighs in relief, lowers the carbine.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want any trouble... I bet you don't either... Let's just call it a draw, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look out, Bill!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lead Bandit pokes at The Postman's shoulder with the muzzle of his rifle. The Postman knows why.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just passing through. I don't mean anyone any harm.  Water's good.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lead Bandit pokes again. Harder. The Postman opens his shirt, reveals his bare left shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not a Holnist.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They just stare at him, none saying a word. Creepy.</context>
      <utterance>Okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rose. Somewhere west of Portland.</context>
      <utterance>I'm headed for a town called St.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LEAD BANDIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Portland's under twenty feet of water.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I heard different.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAD BANDIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mouthin' me?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The third BANDIT, a HULKING brute, has been quiet.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's just that it's hard to get good information.</utterance>
   <speaker>HULKING BANDIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He is mouthin' you; I say we kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAD BANDIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be in such a rush, Martin.  Now I see a pack mule over there, but I don't see no packs.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is all I got.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAD BANDIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hulking Bandit, raises his shotgun. The butt end. He's going to bludgeon The Postman to death.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... Kill him, Martin.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The 76 ball is twenty feet above the ground. In the gloom you can just see a hole has been punched through the side.</context>
      <utterance>Okay! My stuff's up there!</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lead Bandit swats Bandit 20 upside the head.</context>
      <utterance>What do you got in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAD BANDIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up.  What do you got in there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cigarettes.</context>
      <utterance>Dried peas. Beef jerky.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALL THREE BANDITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cigarettes!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. There's the ladder.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lead Bandit is about to smack Bandit 20 again -- then he sees the logic out of it. The Postman shakes his head, but isn't that convincing.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe he's got it booby-trapped.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAD BANDIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You go up and get it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going to take a second. I got my stuff bolted in.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Lead Bandit takes a cautious step back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAD BANDIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put some buckshot through it, Martin. Just to hurry him up.</utterance>
   <speaker>HULKING BANDIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only got three shells left.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAD BANDIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hulking Bandit picks up the carbine and aims. CLICK. It isn't loaded. The Hulking Bandit tosses the gun aside, pulls a knife from his boot. Grimly, he begins to climb.</context>
      <utterance>So use his gun.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill bolts from the station as the Lead Bandit raises the RIFLE and FIRES at The Postman. Losing balance, The Postman lands on his butt just before a bullet splinters the utility pole above his head. Wobbly, he tries to gather his packs. The Bandits charge, quickly closing the ground, but Bill is there first. Holding as much as he can, The Postman heaves himself over Bill's back. As the mule gallops away, the Lead Bandit aims the rifle. He's got The Postman in his sights. He's about to fire when -- Bandit 20 stands up INTO the SHOT. He's got a fistful of cigarettes in each hand and he's laughing like a hyena!</context>
      <utterance>Bill!</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're rich!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks off stage for someone, but no one appears.</context>
      <utterance>They said, 'Fear not, MacBeth, 'til Birnam Wood comes to Dunsinane'!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bill trots on-stage. Covered with twigs, BILL is Birnam Wood. He BRAYS lustily. The audience laughs in delight. The children clap. Only Woody seems unaffected.</context>
      <utterance>I said, Birnam Wood comes to Dunsinane!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shaking off the twigs, Bill takes one of the swords in his mouth. The two of them dash back and forth pretending to fight off an imaginary attack. Finally, The Postman looks out at the audience, remembers the words the best he can.</context>
      <utterance>Arm, arm yourselves! If the witch's words are true, there'll be no running or hiding here!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The audience erupts in applause. But Woody stands still as stone. The Postman takes a bow. Even Bill does a cross-legged dip. Knowing when to quit, he steps off the stage to many hearty handshakes. Woody watches his every move. MRS. THOMPSON, one of the town's leaders, steps up. She's accompanied by crotchety old CURMUDGEON LARRY.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow, and tomorrow, and the day after that. Out brief candle! Life's but a walking shadow, a poor player that struts his hour upon the stage and is heard no more. It's a tale told by a moron. Full of sound and fury, signifying nothing.  But blow, wind! Come wrack! At least we'll die with the harness off our back!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The children have never heard Shakespeare before.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Curmudgeon is still clapping.</context>
      <utterance>They still haven't.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. You're very nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURMUDGEON LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm clapping because you stink.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think you understand how it works.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURMUDGEON LARRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I was young, I tried to be an actor. I was awful. But now I won't die thinking I was the worst one.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad I could help.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Larry, stop it.  You were very good.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before she can answer, a SENTRY cries...</context>
      <utterance>Good enough to get something to eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes look down the road leading into town. A raiding party of Holnist Cavalry are on their way in. Mrs. Thompson sees The Postman's concern.</context>
      <utterance>Holnists! Holnists are coming!</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay. We give them food and supplies. All the towns do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just take a woman sometimes.</context>
      <utterance>They hardly kill anyone lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman gathers his stuff, slings packs onto Bill. The forty Holnists in orange and black uniforms ride in. They're armed with mostly pistols and rifles. Some carry bows, knives, spear guns and swords. On their bare shoulders, branded into the flesh -- the number "8."</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'd just as soon not give them anything of mine. Let's find the back door, Bill.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The Postman freezes, turns, is relieved to find Bethlehem's not talking to him at all. The General looks down from his horse at children playing an impromptu game of "Birnam Wood." The children stop, stare at their feet. Bethlehem affects a "kindly" smile to accompany his gentler tone.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meantime, The Postman continues his surreptitious escape. The MAYOR hurries forward to greet Bethlehem.</context>
      <utterance>I said, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just a game, General Bethlehem. Something they saw in a play. No harm in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One BRAVE BOY finds his voice, barely.</context>
      <utterance>A play?  Show me. It's all right, children, show me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRAVE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arm, arm yourselves! No running from the witches!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shakespeare, is it? Well, I'm sorry I missed it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should know, sir, we haven't nearly stocked the game we thought we would.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Head down, The Postman makes for "the back way." But it's guarded by three daunting Holnist soldiers. No getting by them. The Postman does a quick 180, goes back the way he came. Bethlehem looks at the frightened townsfolk.</context>
      <utterance>Really? But you had time for a play?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mayor nods in acquiescence. Bethlehem looks to a Holnist officer. The officer, IDAHO, steps up and addresses the town.</context>
      <utterance>I'm taking three conscripts from each town. They will have the honor of serving in the Holnist Army until such time as I see fit.  Three men. You suppose you could do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Holnist soldiers fan out, prodding any likely or unwilling candidates forward. The Postman is now walking behind Bethlehem. Some of the Townspeople cast him a furtive glance as he makes his way toward the open courtyard and, ultimately, the gate out of town. Three conscripts are hustled before Bethlehem. He looks over the first -- Woody. Smells him. Not much of a decision here.</context>
      <utterance>All men between 15 and 50 and of suitable ethnic foundation are required to show themselves now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Acceptable.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Acceptable, Captain!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The third -- an innocuous man. Or so we think. Bethlehem stares hard at his olive skin, traces a finger over the bump on the man's nose.</context>
      <utterance>You'll need to put some meat on, but I like an impressionable mind. Acceptable.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Soldiers shove the man back into the crowd. The Brave Boy that was playing Birnam Wood allows himself a tiny smile when he sees that The Postman might make it.</context>
      <utterance>Mongoloid. Unacceptable.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem notes the Boy, turns to see the object of his attention, and spots The Postman leaving out the front gate.</context>
      <utterance>I want pure blood. Someone like...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Idaho and another soldier are on it. The Postman tries to back away as the two dismount and come toward him.</context>
      <utterance>That man.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Idaho and the soldier aren't programmed for explanations -- they grab him.</context>
      <utterance>You don't understand...</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were required to show yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Idaho silences him with a rifle butt to the head. Everything falls OUT OF FOCUS</context>
      <utterance>But, I'm not with these people. I'm just passing through. I --</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take the mule.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman steps toward him, Bandit 20 backs off quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Hi?</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well... I mean, we know each other, kind of...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kind of.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what did you guys do with my cigarettes?</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We traded them for a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wonderful. What happened to your partners?</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They traded me to the Holnists.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>General Bethlehem approaches on horseback. Colonel Getty follows behind. Bethlehem looks his new recruits over. Dismounting, he enters the pen and walks among them.</context>
      <utterance>Ten hut!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts down the line, looking the men over. He stops in front of a GANGLY RECRUIT. The Postman is alongside.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome, gentlemen, to your new life. You have been born again as soldiers in the army of the United Clans of Holn. The strong have been sapped by the whimpering propaganda of the weak. Men, strong men, have been denied their destiny. You men have been saved from that fate. Redemption is within your grasp.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You. What did you do before you were given this opportunity?</utterance>
   <speaker>GANGLY RECRUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem regards him benevolently.</context>
      <utterance>I had a shovel. I digged holes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You digged holes... Well, now you're going to fill them.  And you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there any question in anyone's mind that I was talking to you? Yes, you. You look like a dangerous man. Are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakespeare. Stuff like that.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just a performer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shakespeare?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a writer. He --</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know who Shakespeare was... 'Cry "Havoc!" and let slip the dogs of war.'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem nods. The Postman thinks a moment...</context>
      <utterance>I, um, you want a line?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem looks at his men as if to say, "Is this all this guy's got?" Bethlehem eyes The Postman; he wants a contest.</context>
      <utterance>'To be or not to be: That is the question.'</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Holnists clap, they know their General can best this guy.</context>
      <utterance>'We few, we happy few, we band of brothers.'</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Now is the winter of our discontent made glorious summer by this son of York.' Bethlehem claps The Postman on the back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman doesn't answer. Hesitant, he doesn't want to get into any more trouble than he's already in.</context>
      <utterance>You're pretty good. You're also a fighter. I see it in your eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem sounds sincere. He seems like a good guy.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you agree? Come on, a man's got to speak his mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't mean any disrespect, sir, but you'd be better off just letting me go. A fighter is about the last thing I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman gasps to catch his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you think I should be the judge of that, soldier?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman staggers to his feet. Blood trickles from his nose as he stares across at Bethlehem.</context>
      <utterance>Get up. I said, get up.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put up your fists.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem looks to Getty. CLICK. Getty shoves a PISTOL is into The Postman's ear. The Postman reluctantly raises his fists. Bethlehem gives him a satisfied nod.</context>
      <utterance>You'd win.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman takes a tentative step forward. Bethlehem drives him back with a flurry of blows. The Postman is dazed, nearly out on his feet. Bethlehem holds him up.</context>
      <utterance>Now fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That said, Bethlehem delivers one last blow to The Postman's face. Everything goes BLACK...</context>
      <utterance>You're right. You're not a fighter. But you will be. I'm giving you a chance at a life that means something. A life worth living.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody shakes his head "no."</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Did I win?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried to tell him...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it again.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say what?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Say it again.</context>
      <utterance>The words you said in town. About the wind blowing. And the rest...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Blow, wind. Come wrack. At least we'll die with the harness off our back.'</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody and The Postman scramble to fall-to with the other conscripts. Idaho surveys the ranks.</context>
      <utterance>Live free or die.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, girls. We're gonna run. Twenty miles. With packs. You got three hours. Everybody makes it. Or nobody eats.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The line has almost passed. Just The Postman left and Bandit 20 bringing up the rear. Idaho looks at The Postman, addresses the COOK.</context>
      <utterance>Eat up! You got meat tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you tell Shakespeare what kind of meat that is.</utterance>
   <speaker>COOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Probably Bill -- and The Postman knows it. He stares in revulsion at the putrid meat ladled into his pail.</context>
      <utterance>Mule.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bandit 20 holds out his pail. But the cook won't fill it.</context>
      <utterance>A godawful animal. The sterile offspring of a horse and a donkey. Can you imagine that?! There's no room in this new world for a bastard like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh uh.  Any man last in line ain't hungry enough. You show up last, you don't eat! Bandit 20 steps away in disbelief. Not knowing what else to do, he sits down beside The Postman, the only man with food who isn't eating.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll die before I'm last in line again.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds his pail out to Bandit 20.</context>
      <utterance>That's what they're hoping for.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lost in despair, The Postman stares out at the skewed palette.</context>
      <utterance>Serious? This isn't bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These were supposed to be the best years of my life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the mention of this name, the RECRUITS shout as one.</context>
      <utterance>The laws of eight, gentlemen. That is the legacy handed down to us by Nathan Holn.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECRUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God rest his soul!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's not going to bust him on it.</context>
      <utterance>May he burn in hell. Getty looks over at him. He heard him. The Postman swallows hard. Getty stares hard. Then he turns away.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem nods at Idaho who pushes up his own sleeve to reveal the branded 8.</context>
      <utterance>These are the laws that we live by. The eight is our symbol. Each man will bear it with pride.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men move to sit in one of the three rows. Only then does it become apparent that there are 18 men and only 17 chairs. One SLOW RECRUIT is left standing. It doesn't take him long to realize that he's in trouble.</context>
      <utterance>Only then will you be part of the clan. Sit down, gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Law One. You will obey orders without question.  I told you to sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOW RECRUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There weren't enough chairs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Slow Recruit moves to do so.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't specify chairs. You could've sat down on the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Idaho and another soldier step up beside the Slow Recruit.</context>
      <utterance>You disobeyed a direct order. You broke Law One.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They hustle the Recruit to the tree. Idaho unslings a coil of rope, throws it over a tree limb. They quickly slip a loop over the Slow Recruit's ankles and haul him upside down into the air.</context>
      <utterance>Law Two. Punishment shall be swift.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are no takers.</context>
      <utterance>Law Three: Mercy is for the weak. Four: Terror will defeat reason. Five: Your allegiance is to the clan. Six: Justice can be dictated. Law Seven. Any clansman may challenge for leadership of the clan. Does any man here wish to challenge me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The conscripts stand like jackknives snapping open. Without a word, without a look -- Bethlehem reaches out and draws a sword from a sheath that Getty holds. Bethlehem steps to the Slow Recruit -- who slowly twists around.</context>
      <utterance>On your feet!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem raises the sword.</context>
      <utterance>Law Eight: There is only one penalty: Death.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLOW RECRUIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please, I'm begging you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem turns and walks away. Getty following behind. The Postman watches as they go. Idaho steps up to him.</context>
      <utterance>You will get out of this army what you put into it. Work and you'll be fed. Fight and you'll be respected. Die and you'll be remembered. It's up to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You thinking of challenging for leadership of the clan?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir. I'm a follower not a leader.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman looks back to see Bethlehem and Getty disappear into the gloom. Idaho grins, likes how this affects a new man. The Postman moves on. Idaho stops Woody as he passes.</context>
      <utterance>You see Colonel Getty? Always following the General? He's the only man who ever challenged. Fight lasted six seconds, but the General didn't kill him. He cut off his tongue and he cut off his balls and old Getty's been following him like a dog ever since.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody clenches his jaw, but wisely doesn't answer.</context>
      <utterance>The General don't see it, but I say you got some nigger in you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem wants an answer. The Postman clears his throat.</context>
      <utterance>They're yours. A solitary man, aren't you? Binoculars. To watch life from a distance. And Shakespeare. To read about it instead of living it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No offense, General, but you seem to have read some Shakespeare yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he wishes to rise above mere thuggery, a military commandeer must be classically educated. Philosophy, history. Even a sense of the dramatic.  Do you know what I did before the war? Do you think I was in the army? I sold copying machines. I was a salesman. The talent to lead men and devise and execute a battle plan were locked away inside me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to a dog-eared page in the book.</context>
      <utterance>If Nathan Holn hadn't come along, I'd still be selling copying machines. Can you imagine the wasted life? Can you imagine the magnitude of it? But war... War gives men like me a chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman leaves. Idaho stands at the ready.</context>
      <utterance>Here... 'The prize is often left unclaimed. Have the courage to grasp it. For fortune always favors the bold.'  It always inspires me.  I have a design for the future. A master plan. I'll need able officers to carry it out. You have the intelligence. If your heart matches, you'll go far.  We'll talk more in the weeks to come. Dismissed.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Issue the binoculars to a scout.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the book, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Idaho leaves. Bethlehem goes back to his painting. He considers himself in the mirror. After a long stare-down, he shouts:</context>
      <utterance>Burn it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quit moving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Troubled, The Postman doesn't answer. He heads for a corner where Woody stands alone. Relentless, Bandit 20 follows.</context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he say anything about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach the quiet corner; it's just the three of them.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got to get out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bandit 20 looks scared, Woody unreadable.</context>
      <utterance>Escaping.  You ever hear of St. Rose? It's on the coast. They say it's a paradise. They've even got electric lights.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Between the three of us, we could --</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman can't believe what Bandit 20 just said. Bandit 20 turns, hurries away. The Postman looks to Woody who doesn't tip his hand either way. He moves away as well.</context>
      <utterance>No, no. I can't. I like it here. I like being a part of something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Idaho points to the thicket as he proceeds down the line.</context>
      <utterance>One of you dogs has earned himself a treat. Over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No volunteers, except the zealot Bandit 20.</context>
      <utterance>Those men hunted themselves a lion this morning. Must've been a zoo around here before the war. Anyhow, they shot him and he crawled into that thicket. A third man went in after him. We don't know if he's dead or alive. I need a volunteer. Someone's gotta go in and get our boy out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Idaho ignores him, stops in front of Woody.</context>
      <utterance>I'll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess size ain't a measure of courage, is it? Shakespeare! The fix is in. The Postman steps out of line.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Bethlehem nods to Getty. Getty takes a hunting knife from a belt-sheath and tosses it, blade first, into the ground between The Postman's feet.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hefting the knife, The Postman stares at the west ridge.</context>
      <utterance>Come out alive and you got yourself a lion steak.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman looks to Bandit 20 who stares back defiantly.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you'll find your St. Rose up there.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bandit 20 can't contain his giggling, so Idaho backhands the sound out of him -- then looks back to The Postman. Grim The Postman starts forward, looks from the rotten bridge to the water and back again as he moves. All eyes on him as he starts across...</context>
      <utterance>What are you waiting for, Christmas?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you stopping?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Clearly he is not.</context>
      <utterance>He alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The Postman heaves the corpse onto his back. Rising, steadying himself, he looks back over his shoulders at a GUTTURAL GROWL. He hurries forward.</context>
      <utterance>Bring him out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody dives in the water. Bethlehem looks to Idaho who dives in as well. Conscripts buzz with nervous excitement.</context>
      <utterance>In the water. Come back without him and you and another man will die in his place.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONSCRIPTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go! Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off running across the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get him, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman gestures with his knife.</context>
      <utterance>My army. I like the sound of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't --</utterance>
   <speaker>BANDIT #20</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman lunges, digs into Bandit 20's gut. He blinks in surprise, then sags to the ground. The Postman takes a step back. A shadow falls over him. It's Woody. Staring down at The Postman. They can hear others approaching from the river.</context>
      <utterance>I got him! Over --</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They sent me to kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, Idaho and the second soldier come into the clearing. Idaho grins, relaxes his grip on his gun when he sees the mismatch between Woody and The Postman.</context>
      <utterance>Come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good, boy. Get him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's you or me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>IDAHO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Woody circles The Postman, until he's facing Idaho and the soldier. Woody takes a long look at The Postman, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Finish it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As The Postman realizes what he's doing, Woody flips his knife through the air and into the soldier's throat.</context>
      <utterance>No harness on my back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to open it, looks at the skeleton and shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>'Jerry Ball, Pine View.'</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tossing it aside, he takes a drink, opens another. The words are in crayon -- a child's scrawl.</context>
      <utterance>So, arrest me.  Here's a piece of good news. Jerry's decided to go to school to get his contractor's license.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He swallows the last few drops, then sets the flask down as a headstone. What now?</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for being there for me.  Here's to you. I consider my taxes very well spent.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All dressed up. Nowhere to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO SENTRIES appears from the gate house. They aim arrows.</context>
      <utterance>Greetings, Pine View, Oregon!</utterance>
   <speaker>SENTRY #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment of truth is here. Finally, with authority:</context>
      <utterance>Just head back the way you came. Pine View ain't buying, ain't listening and don't give charity.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Civilian, I'm on official business. I demand entry into the town of Pine View.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENTRY #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More silhouettes appear on the palisade. One is SHERIFF BRISCOE, a big, no-nonsense man.</context>
      <utterance>I'm through talking to you, buddy boy! Now get somebody with authority to open this gate!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Sheriff Briscoe. Who the hell are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a representative of the United States Government -- An uproar. He makes himself heard above it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Authorized by order 417 of the restored Congress to reestablish a communication route to Idaho and lower Oregon. Now open that damn gate!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does that mean in English?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a silent hush.</context>
      <utterance>I'm your postman!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hand me your gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Understand that tampering with or obstructing the mail is a federal offense. Furthermore, the Bolin Act requires you to provide all mail carriers with sanctuary and nourishment.  Now open that damn gate!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got three seconds to get your ass outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Briscoe pumps his shotgun, aims it at The Postman.</context>
      <utterance>Is Jerry the contractor here?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman dumps the pack over, frantically shuffles through the letters.</context>
      <utterance>Wait! I'm going to get something out of my bag.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Paul Davis! 124 Vernon Street!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never heard of him. Two!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lois Kent! 14 Weymoth Lane!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He fumbles for the last letter. Briscoe takes aim.</context>
      <utterance>Three!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's an absolute stunned silence. Like a switch was thrown.</context>
      <utterance>Irene March! 478 River Road!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MRS. MARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sense of hope is palpable as the gates are swung back. Two TOWNIES hurry Mrs. March out to meet The Postman. They're followed by a throng. As he sees she's blind...</context>
      <utterance>Did he say my name?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Too late now. They stop Mrs. March in front of him. She stares off just to his left, a little afraid.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Irene March.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He presses it into her hands, but she won't take it.</context>
      <utterance>I have a letter for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you read it?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure it's personal.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please. Someone has to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're delivering the old stock piles, but I'll accept all new correspondence as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Excited, the people move closer. Someone holds up a torch and The Postman starts.</context>
      <utterance>Just read it, will ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mrs. March reaches out a trembling hand to take the letter.</context>
      <utterance>'Dear Irene. Sorry I haven't written. Everything's so crazy. The strange weather. The food shortages. That farmer Nathan Holn causing all that trouble. It's hard to understand. David's home from the Army. The war was over before he even got there. Thank God for that. He's still my baby no matter how big he gets. We're going to miss you for Christmas, but maybe next year. All our love. Donna.'</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The populace erupts with excitement. Mrs. March takes The Postman's hand, clasps it tightly.</context>
      <utterance>My sister in Denver. Fifteen years ago. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman pulls his hand back, rejects the title.</context>
      <utterance>You're a Godsend. A savior.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An almost awesome silence. Too much for The Postman.</context>
      <utterance>No. I'm just... a postman.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been on the road a while. I could use a little something to eat --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. MARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The townspeople welcome him with cheers. The Postman raises a silencing hand. As they quiet...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes, absolutely... Is there anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Only The Postman laughs. No one else reacts. Briscoe watches dubiously from the wall as the people surround The Postman and sweep him through the gates and into town. One couple watches The Postman closely as he makes his way into town. She is ABBY -- a sweet-faced, pretty woman. Her husband, MICHAEL, is a decent-looking sort, tall and strong.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, there is! If there are dogs in this town, you have to leash them while I'm here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. Didn't somebody say something about dinner?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman just nods, hoisting himself out of the tub and hurriedly wrapping a towel around himself.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm supposed to take you to Foster's.  My name's Ford. Ford Lincoln Mercury.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hoping to impress, Ford reaches into a pocket, pulls out a worn, creased flyer for a "Ford Lincoln Mercury" dealership. Ford finds The Postman just staring at him, waiting for the uniform he's still got in his hand. Embarrassed, Ford quickly hands it over.</context>
      <utterance>Used to be John Stevens, but I changed it on account of I want to drive cars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I live in that car. A 2003 Pontiac Sinatra. With a nine- banger and a Q-eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>V-eight. Eight cylinders. That means an eight-banger.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were they fast?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A buck seventy-five on a strip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is the last thing he expected to hear out of this kid's mouth. A moment, then...</context>
      <utterance>A buck seventy-five? I thought maybe I could fix some of them up. It's nothing compared to what you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ahead, people are gathered inside an old Foster's Freeze.</context>
      <utterance>The important thing to remember about cars is, you can't eat 'em.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell us about the government!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Startled, The Postman doesn't quite know what to say. They seat him at a table -- but the food looks miles away.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, tell us everything!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there a President?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But these people won't be denied. Finally...</context>
      <utterance>You know, I'm pretty hungry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's warm applause at that. Several people try the expression out on each other.</context>
      <utterance>His name is, uh... Richard Starkey. From Maine. He has a saying. 'Things are getting better, getting better all the time.'</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He a Democrat or a Republican?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ellen sets a steaming bowl of stew in front of The Postman. Famished, he digs in.</context>
      <utterance>Parties are over with. The individual is what counts. You vote for the best man.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman tries to speak through a mouthful of food.</context>
      <utterance>What about Europe? Any word?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lady Di's in charge. Sixty years old and she still kicks ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Nathan Holn still alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's sure good news to everyone. But...</context>
      <utterance>He died. Skin cancer.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN #4</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman looks at the desperate faces -- he'd rather get back to his meal -- but this may be the most important question of all. He doesn't want to lie.</context>
      <utterance>And the Holnists? They're still out there. What's the government going to do about them?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The government's just getting started. You're on your own for at least eighteen months.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAN #5</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A clamor of Holnist questions.</context>
      <utterance>What about the Marines Corp?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The people nod and The Postman finally gets to eat. He catches sight of Briscoe watching him from the door. After a moment, Briscoe leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Be quiet, everyone! Can't we just let this man eat?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's cut off by the sight of a silent, little boy. The kid's looking up, staring intently at something.</context>
      <utterance>Never thought I'd hear myself say this, but I can't eat anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy just stares.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy nods. The Postman shakes his head and smiles to himself. He takes off the cap, sets it on the kid's head.</context>
      <utterance>This?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy's eyes go wide with wonder. His stock's gone up 1000%. Before he can rush off to impress his friends, ELLEN -- his mother -- steps over and gently chides him.</context>
      <utterance>Almost fits.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not a toy, honey. That's very important. Give it back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you like to dance?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs. Abby says nothing.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know if I can, I think I'm still on duty.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby holds out her hand like a promise.</context>
      <utterance>It's been a long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All you got to do is hold on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How tall are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About six feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you smart?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smarter than some I guess. Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just wondering. Did you ever have the bad mumps? The Postman smiles. She's odd, but beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never had the bad mumps.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head "no." They continue to dance.</context>
      <utterance>Have you ever had herpes or syphilis or anything like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So as far as you know, you have good semen?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a trick question?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stunned, The Postman stops dancing. Abby takes this moment to grab Michael.</context>
      <utterance>I don't mean to be nosy. I'm only asking because I want you to make me pregnant.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby takes Michael's arm, introduces him proudly.</context>
      <utterance>It's got to be the uniform.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael smiles, shakes hands with a grave-digger's grip. The Postman doesn't know what to think.</context>
      <utterance>This is my husband. Michael.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman just stares at them. Abby looks to Michael.</context>
      <utterance>We've been trying to have a baby for three years. We can't on account of Michael had the bad mumps when he was twelve. So we need a body father. We could ask a man here, but it could cause trouble. I've seen it happen. Things go okay until the woman starts to show. Then it can be bad. But you'll only be around once in awhile with the mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He hasn't said 'no'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you say, mister? You'd be doing us a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman excuses himself with a nod and turns away, shaking his head at the strangeness of this new world. But no rest for the wicked, as soon as he's free from Abby and Michael, he's running smack into another group of well-wishing TOWNIES. Mrs. March is among them. She's holding an envelope.</context>
      <utterance>I'll have to think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOWNIE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. March wants to give you something.  He's right here, Irene.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How can he lie to her?</context>
      <utterance>It's to my daughter Annie. She left five years ago. She was only fifteen. The last I heard, she was living up north... The Postman swallows hard, looks from the envelope to the faces around him, to Mrs. March. She looks blindly back.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, Mrs. March, you should know that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Know what?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she stops him, grabs for his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Know that...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MARCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her hand leaves his and she disappears into the crowd. She's left him with her letter and no choice at all.</context>
      <utterance>I have a feeling about you. I know you'll do what's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got to get out of here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>An OLD MAN sits on his porch across the street.</context>
      <utterance>It's right around the corner.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Man winks knowingly, then heads inside. As The Postman turns the corner, he finds himself in front of the post office. An old brick building. Chiseled in the granite facing: "UNITED STATES POST OFFICE. EST. 1884."</context>
      <utterance>What you're looking for.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you'd come here.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford nods. A sage sixteen-year-old.</context>
      <utterance>You did, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you get to be a postman, anyhow?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to be in the right place at the right time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How could I do it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you wanted to drive cars.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not anymore. That was kid's stuff. This is real. So, where's the right place?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could be anywhere. Anytime. Only another postman can make you a postman.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kinda like vampires, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford raises his right hand, palm out, ready to take the oath. It takes The Postman a moment to realize.</context>
      <utterance>Something like that. You have to be sworn in.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It might not last.</context>
      <utterance>The organization's kinda shaky.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'd meet a lot of people who don't believe in you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll set them straight.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a lonely job.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This response strikes a chord. The Postman sees how badly Ford wants something to hold onto. He sees himself.</context>
      <utterance>I've been lonely all my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman looks up at the creed on the wall. Finally...</context>
      <utterance>So have I, Ford. So have I.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell? Repeat after me.</utterance>
   <speaker>POSTMAN/FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither snow, nor rain, nor heat nor gloom of night stays these couriers from the swift completion of their appointed rounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay then.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They shake hands. The Postman doesn't realize, but this is the most important moment in Ford's life.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, no, I'm saying that. You just listen... By my authority you are now empowered to carry the mail.  Congratulations, you're a postman.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford's intensity takes The Postman back. But the moment is broken when...</context>
      <utterance>I want you to know I'd die to get a letter through.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ford bristles at "Johnny," looks to The Postman.</context>
      <utterance>Johnny, why don't you run along. I need to speak to this man.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see you around.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford exits.</context>
      <utterance>Sure thing, Ford.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johnny's real impressed with you. Whole town's real impressed with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I take it you're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smarter than you look.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can I do for you, Sheriff?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can clear out. Or I can throw you out. Either way suits me fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid you don't understand, Sheriff. I'm a government employee. Authorized by --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not authorized by shit. You're nothing but a drifter who found a bag of mail. And I want you out of my town.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is going in my report.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Briscoe exits, leaves The Postman alone in the post office.</context>
      <utterance>These people don't need dreams, Mr. Postman. They need something real. They need help with the goddamn Holnists. Are you going to bring them that?  Didn't think so. All you cost us so far is a few bowls of soup and maybe later a few broken hearts. I aim to keep it that way. You can stay till morning. Then I don't ever want to see you again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a pause. And then, ANOTHER KNOCK.</context>
      <utterance>Just leave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens. Surprise. Abby stands in the doorway, her hair held up by an old red ribbon. He sits up.</context>
      <utterance>I said leave it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Abby.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll be leaving tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everybody's up late writing letters for you to take. We're not supposed to waste candles like that, but they're so excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about you? Do you have a letter?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have anybody to write to.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby laughs. The Postman is charmed.</context>
      <utterance>I'll find you a pen pal. Someone with interests similar to your own. Dancing, checking for mumps.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're funny. Hardly anyone's funny around here.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two of them just look at each other a moment. Abby fingers the ribbon in her hair.</context>
      <utterance>I guess no one feels much like laughing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you decided yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Abby lets her shift drop to the floor, then slides under the sheets alongside him.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, well, I've been thinking about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They lie there awkwardly for a moment. He looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, you're beautiful. Sorry, I know you'd probably like to keep things more clinical.  You don't even know my name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods he understands. She stares into his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I don't want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman closes his eyes. Abby slides her hand away from his mouth. And as they start to make love...</context>
      <utterance>It would be easier for me if you closed your eyes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about those?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman scans the crowd. Looking for Abby maybe?</context>
      <utterance>These are going to Blue Jay. About twenty miles east. I thought I could take them.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Briscoe rides up, regards The Postman sternly.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. They're yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Some of the town's CITIZENS lead up a saddled mare.</context>
      <utterance>I'm your escort out of town.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CITIZEN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We took a vote, Mr. Postman. We want you to have this horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITIZEN #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now don't say no. A man on horseback can cover ten times the territory of a man on foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He ties his mailbag to the saddle, swings himself up.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITIZEN #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a bedroll, some oats and a week's rations.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CITIZEN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do you figure you'll go from here?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>uncomfortably. The Postman looks out at the crowd. They crave hope. He should probably just keep his mouth shut.</context>
      <utterance>Go?... Oh yeah... I'll head west, then work my way back here in a sort of figure eight. "8." Everyone's quiet a moment. They shift</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The people consider him and then each other. By God, they do feel hopeful. Suddenly, Ellen, her little boy by her side, begins to sing. It's weak at first, but one-by-one the others join in. Soon the whole town is singing:</context>
      <utterance>Times seem hard right now. But you have to believe it's getting better. Birds are migrating again. The rains are back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLEN &amp; TOWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman looks around. They sing their hearts out. The guilt is overwhelming. He digs his heels into the horse's flanks and rides out of town.</context>
      <utterance>'Oh beautiful for spacious skies, for amber waves of grain. For purple mountain's majesty, above the fruited plain. America...'</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman doesn't rise to the bait.</context>
      <utterance>You got a helluva nerve, whoever you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Abby around?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Briscoe reins up -- he's gone as far as his duty commands.</context>
      <utterance>She and Michael are working the north meadow this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman tips his cap and continues riding by "Pine View - Population 132." Briscoe watches a moment, then calls after him:</context>
      <utterance>Well, you're on your own.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! Are you really who you say you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman continues. Caught in an inner turmoil, Briscoe reaches into his pocket, and pulls out a letter. He turns it over in his hands, looks off at The Postman.</context>
      <utterance>If I come back with some mail, you'll know!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Briscoe urges his horse forward, catches up. He hands The Postman the letter, then rides back for town. The Postman watches Briscoe. The people lining the wall. And he realizes just what effect he's had. There's nothing to do, but shrug his shoulders and ride. Strains of "AMERICA" still ECHO hauntingly OVER:</context>
      <utterance>God damn it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He considers the letter, looks around as if someone may be watching. He just begins to tear the corner, then stops.</context>
      <utterance>Eugene. Benning. Portland.  Boston!  Seattle. Boise... St. Rose, Paradise on the Pacific...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The HORSE SNORTS. Smiling, The Postman shoves the envelope into his bag. As he does, he finds something else. The red ribbon. He runs it through his fingers, thinks wistfully of Abby. Then, like a knight of old representing a lady's honor, he ties it to his mailbag and rides on.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe one thing can still be sacred.  All in all, not a bad gig, huh?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you looking at?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps over and they're in each other's arms. This is love. But as Michael kisses her, we hear a familiar alarm:</context>
      <utterance>Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holnists! Holnists are coming!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holnists, Johnny. You gotta stay out of sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Briscoe grabs him by the shirt, hauls him out the back way.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a postman. And I'm not hiding from anyone. I --</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stay out of this, or I'll lock you up myself damnit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael walks out into the square. One of the soldiers returns with a burning torch, gives it to Michael. Bethlehem looks at the town, then at Michael.</context>
      <utterance>You. You'll be responsible.  Get him a torch.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Set that flag on fire.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Briscoe steps forward, attempts to diffuse the situation.</context>
      <utterance>The United States doesn't exist. That flag is an abomination.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem decides not to kill anyone, looks to Getty.</context>
      <utterance>General Bethlehem.  We're gathering the tribute, sir. Can I take your wagons?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears on his cheeks, Ford watches the post office burn.</context>
      <utterance>Make sure that fire doesn't go out. The General joins Briscoe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the men hurries off. It's concern for Abby, not for his manhood that makes him step forward.</context>
      <utterance>Tell the Sheriff I want to be introduced. She does not belong in a mudhole like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You again?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my wife, General. She's a married woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know what system of government we have here, son?  A feudal system. Like the Middle Ages. With lords and vassals. That's you and me. Those lords, they had some ideas. If a vassal got married, it was the lord's right, his right, to sleep with the bride on the wedding night.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me and Abby have been married for three years.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, but I wasn't invited to the wedding. Now, you've already done me one favor, son. Don't let this be a black mark on an otherwise perfect record.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll be civilized about this. I want you to give me your blessing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MICHAEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, I can't. You can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Michael looks to Abby as she starts across the street.</context>
      <utterance>Can't? I'm tired of can't. We had a great nation once. Do you know what made it that way? I can! Till the weak came along. The 'I can'ts' destroyed us. But I'm going to make us strong again. I'm going to be the father of a new nation.  Do you know why it will be me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SWORD WHISTLES down. Accompanied by an anguished cry:</context>
      <utterance>Because I can!</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby rushes forward, but she's blocked by Getty and another man. She cries out again and again. Filled with impotent fury, Briscoe squeezes out the words.</context>
      <utterance>Michael!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't have to --</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Three Holnist soldiers draw down on Briscoe. Bethlehem circles, menacing on his horse.</context>
      <utterance>Didn't have to what, Sheriff?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Briscoe stares down at Michael's crumpled form. Abby wails.</context>
      <utterance>Your people seem seditious. You seem seditious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Briscoe might go after Bethlehem despite the odds.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, Michael...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What am I seeing here? I'm waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man came through here. With mail. Said he was a postman. Said the government had been restored back east.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From out of the crowd -- a voice. Ford.</context>
      <utterance>What government?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem whirls his horse at the noise.</context>
      <utterance>The United States government.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not waiting for an answer, Getty charges the crowd, knocks one of the onlookers down. A dead silence. Bethlehem frowns, thinks it over a minute.</context>
      <utterance>Who said that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which way did he go?  Do not make me ask again.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>East.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Send a patrol east. Send three more south, north and west.  They'd better find him east.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I managed to save these.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take that thing off, Johnny. You want to die, too? Ford shoves the letters in a makeshift bag, then climbs onto his waiting pony.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm headed south. With the mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't be a damn fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford digs his heels into the pony and is off in a flash doing damn near a buck seventy-five.</context>
      <utterance>What kind should I be?... Haw!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rachel Clark!  Charlie Sykes!  Graham Druitt!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman nods, sticks the letter back in his bag.</context>
      <utterance>G.D. died last winter of flu.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it for now, folks. There'll be more once a real system is in place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell us about President Starkey!</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about New York City? Did they survive the plague?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An older woman sheds a happy tear -- this is wonderful news.</context>
      <utterance>Survive? They got Broadway up and running again. There's a kid doing Andrew Lloyd Webber like you wouldn't believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much is it to mail a letter?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A buck seventy-five.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That sounds awful cheap.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The moment is split by a SIREN.</context>
      <utterance>The catch is the only currency recognized are silver American coins minted before 1964 and two dollar bills. Look for Thomas Jefferson. Of course, food is always acceptable as barter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They won't open the gates, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chubby Sentry answers from the top of the palisade.</context>
      <utterance>They say they got a representative of the restored United States in there. They say this army is illegal. They say --</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBY SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chubby Sentry disappears back behind cover. Bethlehem remains controlled, but his manner becomes deadly.</context>
      <utterance>Drop dead and go to hell!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Romans had an expression they used to scare their children. 'Hannibal ad portas!' -- Hannibal is at the gates. Do you know who Hannibal was?  Of course not. A pretty girl like you wouldn't know a thing.  Colonel Getty, get some men up there and open that gate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Open the gates!</context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SKINNY SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Government's restored! We don't have to take their crap anymore!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Idiots!</utterance>
   <speaker>CITIZEN #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mayor peers out through an observation hole. The Postman and several others join him.</context>
      <utterance>They're gonna kill us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBY SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! Let's fight them!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman watches the Holnists prepare for attack.</context>
      <utterance>With what? We got five guns maybe 20 rounds of ammo in the whole town! How do we fight them with that?!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men look at each other. Sounds reasonable enough.</context>
      <utterance>You don't. Negotiate a settlement. Give them extra supplies.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The look on The Postman's face says it all.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. You're a government rep. You go tell them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make it quick. I've got an attack to coordinate.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The last time he and Bethlehem were face-to-face, the Postman had a shaved head, was dressed in rags, and was covered with cuts and bruises. Bethlehem can't place him, but there's something familiar all the same.</context>
      <utterance>General, um, they've asked me to negotiate a peace treaty.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think so, sir. I --</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the Postman, aren't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Although he wants to confess everything, something tells The Postman he has to try to brass it out.</context>
      <utterance>The restored United States. Do these people really believe that shit? Who are you really?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am a United States Postman. Authorized by order 417 of the restored Congress to --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was at the Battle of Georgetown. I watched the White House burn to the ground. Don't try to sell me on any restored U.S...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The new capital is based in Minneapolis. Inside the Hubert Humphrey Metrodome. You know, where the Vikings used to play?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're funny. Now, what are the terms?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem thinks this over.</context>
      <utterance>They'll open the gate and give you double what they usually give. Just don't hurt anybody. This was all a misunderstanding.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem turns his attention to the battle. A CAPTAIN steps forward with gun raised.</context>
      <utterance>Law six, justice can be dictated.  Kill him. And kill the restored United States with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two soldiers move forward. Suddenly The Postman's HORSE comes THUNDERING -- trampling the Holnist nearest him. The other Holnist hears, looks back, sees The Postman coming and takes aim just as The Postman brings his gun to bear.</context>
      <utterance>Get her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel Getty!</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman's head lolls forward. She feels something on her hand, pulls it back smeared with blood. The Postman's shot in the belly. The horse is failing. Near death. We hear the sound of PURSUING CAVALRY. Abby urges the horse off the road. When the thicket grows too dense, Abby jumps down. She catches The Postman as he slides off, easing him to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>We can't stop now. They'll be coming after us.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby shushes him. She pulls on the horse's bridle to force him farther along. But it's no good, the wounded horse goes down on its knees. And five RIDERS THUNDER past. Fooled. All but the SIXTH, who pulls up to listen. In the deep b.g., flames lick at the billowing black smoke. The town is burning. The HORSE WHINNIES: in its death throes. Abby panics, tries to quiet the horse.</context>
      <utterance>Abby...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates at first. Then dismounts and moves toward her. Abby cocks the rifle.</context>
      <utterance>Don't move.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIXTH SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Moving closer still, he doesn't see the BRANCH pulled back in The Postman's hand until it SNAPS hard into his face. He stumbles back.</context>
      <utterance>If you'd had a bullet, you'd a used it by now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby dashes out, rifle in hand. She swings for the bleachers. The butt catches the side of the Sixth Soldier's head. He falls hard. The Postman's eyes flutter. Dazed, he watches as Abby pilfers through the Soldier's gear. She takes everything of value: a knife, bullets, a canteen. His eyes flutter closed.</context>
      <utterance>You're right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes about her business in silence.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think I ever had water soup before. Maybe next time we could try it with a little sand?  Dirt? Wood?  A twig garnish?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You used to think I was funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They killed Michael.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a spoonful of soup and she comes to him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How sorry are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her right hand flashes out, holds a knife up under his chin.</context>
      <utterance>What's that supposed to mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long beat. Finally, he swallows the soup in his mouth. The action presses his Adam's apple against the blade.</context>
      <utterance>You got the mark of eight on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A mark doesn't mean I'm a --</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a liar. I should've let you die.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If she knows, she's not ready to say yet.</context>
      <utterance>Then, why didn't you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby considers this, The Postman's gaze flickers down to the spoon he still holds in his hand. Taking one last stab at a joke.</context>
      <utterance>You were with Bethlehem. Does that make you one of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby doesn't laugh. But she does relent. She steps away.</context>
      <utterance>Don't make me use this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wind's come up.  Getting colder too. Must be another storm -- Abby gets up and throws a log on the fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean for you to --</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your legs are going to rot off if you don't try to walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm hurt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're lazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the two of them glare at each other for a moment. Abby starts to put on her coat.</context>
      <utterance>Lazy?! I got a hole in my stomach. I'm weak. The two big meals around here are grass and snow. And we're running out of grass.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby doesn't answer. She picks up the rifle and starts to lead the horse outside.</context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby is out the door without a word.</context>
      <utterance>You're not leaving me here, are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks with the bowl past The Postman -- who sits on his cot with arms outstretched -- and pointedly sets the bowl on the table.</context>
      <utterance>This is the last of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby starts putting on layer after layer of clothing.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a break...</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to check the pass.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you in such a hurry to get out of here? I can think of worse places. And worse company to -- And with the SLAM of the DOOR she is gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you that's all there was.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why you should have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew you could walk.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're weird, you know that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We walked on the moon once, Abby.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? What good is that now?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby looks up.</context>
      <utterance>Obviously you've forgotten Tang and microwave ovens.  Your face looks pretty.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not so bruised.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, there's something you'd better know. You're going to find out soon enough. I'm pregnant.  It's Michael's baby. You're just the body father.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know it's mine and not Bethlehem's?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He tried with me almost every night. He couldn't do it. So he beat me. Said it was my fault.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman whips around to see her standing there.</context>
      <utterance>Abby.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it? What's wrong? Is it the baby?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind her, he sees the cabin is on fire. Takes off running.</context>
      <utterance>The pass is clear. It's time to go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's nonplused to find Abby standing beside a pile of their neatly-packed gear.</context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got our stuff out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course? I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I set the fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I missing the point here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman has all but forgotten.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't think we'd stay here forever, did you?  I'd appreciate if you'd walk with me long enough to find someplace safe for the baby. Then we can split up.  You shaved.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can respond, she's heading off toward the pass, leaving The Postman to shake his head at the absurdity of it all. He shouts after her.</context>
      <utterance>It looks nice.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really weird, you know that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you ever heard of St. Rose, Abby?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've heard people talk. I've heard lots of names. Bliss. Hesperia. New Eden. Sheriff Briscoe says it's a fantasy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's wrong. St. Rose is out there. And I'm going to find it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you're The Postman.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can come clean -- they see a distant RIDER coming hard. The Postman unslings the rifle, slides a round into the chamber.</context>
      <utterance>Look, I'm nobody, Abby. I'm just...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Rider pulls up short, wearing a blue home-made uniform.</context>
      <utterance>This is what I hate. Strangers. Do you say 'hi' or do you blow their head off? Do they want to share what they got or take what you have? And if they want to take, how far are you willing to go to stop them? Damn it.  All right. That's far enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't want any trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman is taken aback. The Rider, a girl, pulls off her cap, mops it across her brow. Maybe 14, we'll always know her by her Ponytail. Abby registers the uniform first.</context>
      <utterance>Me neither, mister.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode>RIDER</mode>
      <context>Lowering the rifle, The Postman looks over at Abby, back to Ponytail.</context>
      <utterance>Carrier 18. U.S. Postal Service. Got any mail?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's impossible.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ain't you heard of The Postman?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, tell us.</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's only the greatest man who ever lived. He crossed the wasteland, shook his fist at the enemy and spit in the eye of General Bethlehem himself. He's back east with President Starkey right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who told you all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Postmaster Ford Lincoln Mercury. He's in direct contact with the restored congress.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Direct contact... I don't believe this.</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have mail, or don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said Carrier Eighteen. That mean there's eighteen of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-two. As of midnight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More recruits?</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford looks them over in satisfaction.</context>
      <utterance>Seven of them. They're coming from everywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford smiles, reaches into his pocket. He pulls out a creased sheet of paper. Chubby grins.</context>
      <utterance>Did you get a letter or didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buzzing with excitement, the carriers gather around Ford.</context>
      <utterance>Gather 'round, everybody. Got another letter here. Came in last night.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG CARRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's gonna read it.</context>
      <utterance>Postman sent Ford another letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Hello, all postal carriers.'</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A buzz goes through the crowd. Ponytail looks over.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here in Minneapolis with President Starkey, but my thoughts are with you. Remember, nothing worth doing can be done overnight. Keep your chins up and do your best not to get shot. Signed, The Postman.</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby and The Postman exchange a look.</context>
      <utterance>His letters are always kind of short.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>RED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be H.S., Chubby.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman takes the letter, reads.</context>
      <utterance>I seen him once when I lived in Benning. It's The Postman! Word goes through the crowd like a wave.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford shrugs sheepishly.</context>
      <utterance>P.S. Ford knows what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman takes Ford by the elbow. They disappear into the tent. The carriers just staring after them, awestruck.</context>
      <utterance>Guess you want to talk about this?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They clamor around her.</context>
      <utterance>I found him! I found him!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford knows what to do?</context>
      <utterance>President Starkey? Minneapolis?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? I'm not making the connection. What's all this then?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lied. I told people you were in contact with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I didn't want it to end.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know how long I can stay, Ford. President Starkey will send word one day and I'll have to move on. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman can't answer, just turns and walks out of the tent.</context>
      <utterance>Sure. But you'll stay till he sends word? Right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their hands go down in one crisp military move. The Postman looks at Abby, to Ford as he exits the tent. The kid is craving reassurance.</context>
      <utterance>Aw, don't do that. Hands down.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll stay 'til President Starkey sends word, right? Right?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford smiles, gestures to the carriers.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, till he sends word, right.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman looks over at the carriers. They quiet under his gaze, immediately respectful. The problem is, he has no idea what to say. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>Could you say a few words?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cheering is tumultuous. The Postman picks Abby out of the cheering crowd -- the look on her face says it all.</context>
      <utterance>Two plus two equals four.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You spelled tyranny wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, he's smart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PONYTAIL/RECRUITS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they finish, The Postman and Ford pass by. The Recruits salute. Shaking his head, The Postman's about to salute back when he spots Old George. George has a faded purple "AIRBORNE" tattoo on his arm and a twinkle in his eye. There's an old crow on his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Neither snow, nor rain, nor heat, nor gloom of night...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How old are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman looks over at Ford, who shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Seventy-five, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope. Can't walk too good, either.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman looks at Ford again. Then:</context>
      <utterance>I know stuff.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did you get that?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>1970. A girl with eyes as big as saucers did me in a little town called Saigon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Abby --</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's got her attention, just doesn't know what to do with it.</context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Said it's the best one.</context>
      <utterance>Ford wants me to have his trailer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on the other side of town.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head, and then walks away. The Postman watches her disappear into the bustle of the camp.</context>
      <utterance>I got plenty of room here.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So much for the uniform theory.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think, Lieutenant?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't tell what it is if you stand too close. The colors all kinda run together, don't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem looks away from his painting to see Gibbs and Getty flanking a scared, blue-clad mail carrier. For an instant, mistakes him for:</context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, if it isn't our old friend the U.P.S. man.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Realizing, Bethlehem turns the face from side-to-side.</context>
      <utterance>We captured him on the Oregon border.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIER</speaker>
      <mode>PRISONER</mode>
      <context>Getty sets some of the Carrier's anti-Holnist propaganda onto Bethlehem's field table. Bethlehem picks it up. It's hard to say what he's thinking. Finally:</context>
      <utterance>Carrier Twelve. United States, um, Postal Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're moving north.</context>
      <utterance>I want the camp struck at dawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem looks back to Carrier Twelve.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You spelled tyranny wrong.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's annoying him. As Chubby rides up. The Postman catches his right wrist as he attempts to salute. So Chubby salutes with the left hand instead. As they line up:</context>
      <utterance>I wish they'd stop saluting.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just stay safe and remember. The mailman's more important than the mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sun just peeks up over the horizon. At that signal, the carriers thunder off, the ground trembling under them. The look on their faces. The glory of it all. They're alive! The Postman hesitates, watches after them a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, he's smart.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Urging his horse forward, he rides after them. With them. And then, like an exploding firework, each postman shoots off in a separate direction. Headed for all points of the compass and some in between.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's the name of this town?</context>
      <utterance>For President Starkey and the First Congress of the Restored United States, I officially declare Postal Station 10...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG LEADER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We never named it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I officially declare Postal Station 10 in Elvis, Oregon, open for business!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm back! And I got mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be damned.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bethlehem is offering a 1000 pounds of gold to whoever brings you in. Dead or alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank God it wasn't a carton of cigarettes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd have shot you myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman smiles, reaches in his bag for an envelope.</context>
      <utterance>Things are getting better. Getting better all the time.  I don't know who you are, but I do know I was wrong about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Briscoe turns it over in his hands, looks up in wonder.</context>
      <utterance>Got a letter for you, Sheriff.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's from my sister. I thought she was dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Births and deaths, the weather, gossip. There's nothing here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gibbs hurries away, leaving Bethlehem and Getty alone.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing? Everything is here. Am I the only one who sees that?  Get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem sees Getty waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Give the people back their hope and their dreams won't be far behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Getty hands Bethlehem a sheet of paper -- something Gibbs missed. It's a propaganda sheet featuring a caricature of The Postman leading a few carriers against Bethlehem and his army -- represented as Hitler and the Nazis. The caption underneath reads: "Ride Against the Holnist Tide!"</context>
      <utterance>What is it, Getty?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who do you talk to?</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman steps to a telescope pointing up through a hole in the trailer ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Not a soul in seven years of trying. But I will.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go ahead. Take a look.  Want some?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>George nods and goes on playing with the dials -- searching for a voice in the void. The Postman focuses on the moon.</context>
      <utterance>No. No thanks. Hey, don't let the kids see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's an urgent KNOCKING on the trailer door. Ford appears.</context>
      <utterance>I was an aerospace engineer. I helped design the Galileo space station.  I dream it's orbiting Earth forever. With a dozen human skeletons all grinning at each other. Laughing at us down here.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's Red. He's overdue.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That makes five. All on Southern routes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As fresh-face starts away, The Postman calls after him.</context>
      <utterance>Get this mail sorted. Bring me a fresh horse. Something to eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman watches as Ford shakes the hands of the new recruits. The Postman reaches for his canteen. Empty. Damn. A tin cup filled with water appears from nowhere. Abby. The Postman takes it, too tired to acknowledge the gesture.</context>
      <utterance>And all the mail going South!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They changed the oath.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ford's idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He drains the cup and hands it back to her. Just then, one of the new recruits, LUKE, steps over.</context>
      <utterance>Figures.  They don't think to ask who they're replacing. Or why.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A farmboy-type, Luke looks like a younger version of Woody. The Postman sees this, is lost in reverie. Luke still holds his hand out.</context>
      <utterance>Sir? It'd be an honor if I could shake your hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look like... Do I know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nodding in awe, Luke heads off.</context>
      <utterance>Well, good luck to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice kid. Probably be dead in a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're exhausted. You need rest. There's food in the trailer -- Ponytail rides by; two sacks of mail hang from her saddle pommel. The Postman grabs her horse's halter, stops her.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Route twenty-two. I'm already an hour late.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're grounded. Get off the horse. You know the rule.</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What rule?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty-two's too far south.</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But they're waiting on their mail down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shocked, she does. At the same time, fresh-face comes up leading a second horse laden with mail.</context>
      <utterance>Get off the goddamn horse.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fresh-face goes about tying the second horse to the first.</context>
      <utterance>Tie him off to this one.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't keep doing this.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doing what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman climbs on Ponytail's horse, looks at Abby.</context>
      <utterance>Riding all the routes. You're not saving anyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman digs in his heels. The horse gallops away, the second one following behind.</context>
      <utterance>Did I ever tell you how I got to be a postman, Abby?  I don't know if you'd laugh or cry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The only building not on fire is the post office. A SOLDIER rides up, carrying a torch, meaning to burn it.</context>
      <utterance>Ready!</utterance>
   <speaker>SOLDIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The post office, General?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Let it stand. All by itself. So it can remind them what it cost them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rifles are aimed.</context>
      <utterance>Aim!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shock and dismay from the townsfolk as SHOTS RING OUT.</context>
      <utterance>Fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON BLOODY CARRIER'S FACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL BACK to reveal nine bodies lying on the ground. Only the Bloodied Carrier is still standing. Bethlehem points at the Bloodied Carrier, crooks a finger for him. He staggers up. Bethlehem smiles.</context>
      <utterance>as he realizes he's still standing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you can ride?  Then today's your lucky day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BLOODIED CARRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman motions it's okay as the Carrier struggles.</context>
      <utterance>Bethlehem says...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOODIED CARRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman is puzzled. But Ford knows what and why.</context>
      <utterance>... he's... headed north. He's gonna kill ten people in every town. Then burn it to the ground. For what you did...</utterance>
   <speaker>BLOODIED CARRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I wish they would have...</context>
      <utterance>He said to tell you Pine View's on his way. He said he'd wait there, but not for long.  I was so scared, sir... I thought they were going to kill me, too...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to stop this.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get out of my way, Ford. All of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman starts to ride through them. Luke, Chubby and Ponytail move their horses to block. Ford maneuvers his horse in close and grabs The Postman's harness.</context>
      <utterance>They'll kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman jumps off his horse. Ford tackles him. The Postman shoves him away, continues on. Luke and Chubby pounce on him. With Ford's help, they hold him down.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit --</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't help them!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman struggles. They're genuinely having trouble holding him down.</context>
      <utterance>There's still time, Ford!</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But there's no let-up.</context>
      <utterance>You're hurting him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a moment of shocked surprise.</context>
      <utterance>No, this is all my doing. I went against your orders.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Holnists we killed. You told me to bury them. But I didn't. I sent Bethlehem the bodies.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because Bethlehem has to know that we're not going to stop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God damn you, Ford. Those people down there are dying because of us. Because of what we did.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A terrible SCREAM gives them all pause.</context>
      <utterance>Bullshit. They're dying because of Bethlehem. They're dying because this is a shitty world. And if we're ever going to change it, then somebody might have to die. If I could make it be me down there I would. But I can't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment of stunned silence.</context>
      <utterance>We know their names. The little one's my brother. His name is Billy.</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What Ford did was wrong. But it doesn't change anything for any of us. Does it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Briscoe follows his gaze. He doesn't see anything, but maybe gets the same feeling. Bethlehem looks to Briscoe.</context>
      <utterance>He's out there somewhere. Watching. I can feel it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You feel it too, don't you? Didn't have to end like this, Sheriff. He knew where I'd be if he wanted to face me like a man. Instead, he's hiding like a rabbit. So much for your Postman.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rifles are raised. Briscoe seems to grow as he throws his shoulders back and shouts...</context>
      <utterance>Ready! Aim!</utterance>
   <speaker>BRISCOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ride, Postman! Ride! You hear me? I said ride!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ford thinks you're going to do something.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman watches as, outside, the mail carriers begin to assemble.</context>
      <utterance>I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I don't, those kids are going to keep on getting themselves killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ford doesn't know what it means to be a kid. He doesn't have your memories. None of them do. All they've got is the lousy world we gave them. And this is the only decent thing in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Being a postman? It's all bullshit, Abby. All of it.  I took this uniform off a skeleton to stay warm. I made up the rest to stay fed. There is no restored United States.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman fingers the brim of the cap, softens.</context>
      <utterance>I knew it was something like that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weird thing is, being a Postman was almost the best thing that ever happened to me...  Remember this? You left it behind that night.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby doesn't answer. She leaves instead.</context>
      <utterance>I always liked to think you left it on purpose. But maybe you just forgot it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this everybody?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rest are on the overdue list.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An excited murmur among the carriers. Only Ford eyes The Postman suspiciously. The Postman reads:</context>
      <utterance>This is everybody.  Got a letter from President Starkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Greetings all carriers.'</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Greetings, President Starkey!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'I've been in contact with The Postman. I've received all the reports. I'm proud of you all.' He looks at them, doesn't need to read what's in his heart.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hushed silence. The Postman walks away. The carriers exchange tired, defeated looks. Abby just sighs, knows he's not necessarily wrong. Ford catches up with The Postman. He stares at The Postman; The Postman stares back.</context>
      <utterance>In dark days, in a weary world, you gave everything and asked for nothing. You beat back despair and replaced it with hope and for that your country can never repay you. But the price is too high. I won't see anymore of my bravest die. It is my duty to hereby disband the Postal Service of the restored United States. You are to burn your uniforms and The Postman is to return to Minneapolis at once. Thank you and that is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The President never wrote that letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford gestures to the second letter.</context>
      <utterance>If he could've that's what he would have said.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the other letter to?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bethlehem. I'm taking it to him in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it say?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mail's private. You know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it say?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says it's over. It says we quit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says you quit. What about the oath?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman starts to walk away again.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me something, Ford. How much mail can a dead postman deliver? It's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I'll take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford gathers courage and confronts The Postman.</context>
      <utterance>I can't trust you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If this is the end. If this is the last piece of mail that ever gets delivered. I'll take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford thrusts out his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Whoever takes this letter probably dies for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman hesitates, studies the intense young man. Gives him the letter.</context>
      <utterance>I'm still a postman. You owe it to me... I owe it to me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thought I recognized you.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General Bethlehem said...  ... You should be on your knees when I do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't give a damn what that asshole said.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The general is a great man.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman steps forward. Stops when the barrel of the pistol is right against his own chest.</context>
      <utterance>The general is a fucking lunatic.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman turns to watch as Ford starts out of camp.</context>
      <utterance>You don't own a thought in that goddamn head of yours, do you?  You want to see a man?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman turns, sees Luke's face fraught with confusion and emotion.</context>
      <utterance>That's a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luke stares back into The Postman's eyes. A frozen beat.</context>
      <utterance>You don't understand, do you? You never will until you can think for yourself and be willing to pay the price for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good lord, what do we have here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a representative of the restored United States -- Bethlehem backhands Ford.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got a letter. Says The Postman sent it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem tears open the letter and starts to read:</context>
      <utterance>A letter?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem eyes Ford with undisguised contempt.</context>
      <utterance>'Bethlehem. This letter is my testimony to the fact that there is no restored United States and there is no Postal Service.'  Then who the hell have we been fighting...?  'My carriers are returning home. In exchange, I'm asking you to let them be. The Postman.'</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He expects me to believe this?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Ford turns blazing eyes to Luke -- he's been standing there all along.</context>
      <utterance>It's true, sir. I was there. He disbanded the carriers and rode west.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It takes a moment for the news to sink in. But it does.</context>
      <utterance>Traitor...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the assembled Holnists congratulate each other, Bethlehem looks at Luke.</context>
      <utterance>Then I've won. I've won.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were supposed to kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem looks Ford over.</context>
      <utterance>I couldn't get close enough.  This one's his second in command.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford stares back. Proud. Bethlehem looks to Getty.</context>
      <utterance>Why doesn't that surprise me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A frightened CARRIER is brought up. He wears a purple uniform with CALI sewn on the shoulder. Neither we nor Ford have seen him before. As a firing squad assembles, Ford is shoved over with him.</context>
      <utterance>Bring out the one we found yesterday. They can die together.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAL CARRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford looks at him a second, can't help but laugh. From Gibbs; the shout of "ready!"</context>
      <utterance>Name's Clark. Postal Carrier of the restored Republic of California. Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Postmaster Ford Lincoln Mercury.</utterance>
   <speaker>CALI CARRIER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem watches as Clark holds out his hand. Ford shakes it. "Aim!"</context>
      <utterance>It's an honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute... wait a minute!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold your fire! You don't know each other?  This will never be over. It'll go on except I'll be fighting a goddamn ghost.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we fire, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem crumples the letter, tosses it.</context>
      <utterance>No goddamnit.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I won't fight a ghost. Tabula rasa, gentlemen. A clean slate. I want all mail carriers hunted down. I want The Postman found. I want him dealt with.  Colonel, organize the scouts.  He rode west?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SQUATTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Howdy. Welcome to sunny California.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SQUATTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little accident. The ground started to shake big time and the Hanford nuclear plant went...  ... 'Poof.' Destroyed everything for miles. But the sunsets are beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Rose?</context>
      <utterance>You ever hear of a city called St.</utterance>
   <speaker>SQUATTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Squatter laughs and laughs -- like it was the funniest thing in the world. The Postman and Abby exchange a look, continue on their way.</context>
      <utterance>Friend, I've never heard of St. Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SQUATTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, don't go! I got Monopoly in the house! Boardwalk, Park Place and the Reading Railroad!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you so sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drew and Chubby exchange a look. That makes sense.</context>
      <utterance>President lives in a white house. That guy's place is gray.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out of the corner of his eye, The Postman catches a blur of movement. He turns his head quickly, but he's barely in time to see a wooden basket, attached to one of the high wires, swing from a distant tower. There's a sentry inside it. The basketed sentry whistles away at 40 mph, heading straight for an adjacent tower. In a matter of seconds, he's lost from view. The Postman looks back at Abby. She's shivering.</context>
      <utterance>We can rest in there. Abby is quick to agree.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman guides her toward the train tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>I'm hungry, Postman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Set the rifle on the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BRIDGE CITY MAYOR, a middle-aged retro-hippie, steps up.</context>
      <utterance>This old thing? It isn't even loaded. Where are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman sets down the carbine. The Guard steps over to scoop it up.</context>
      <utterance>You're in Bridge City. Where we don't allow guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman stares at the Mayor a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Sentry said you were coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you. You're famous.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was once. Not anymore.  Are you looking to cross?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will be. Right now, we'd just appreciate some food.  I got some kids behind me, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three.  Hey, guys, come on in! I know you're out there!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBY SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As they stand, show themselves.</context>
      <utterance>Boy, is he smart...</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For you and your wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The exchange cuts Abby like a knife. She gets up and leaves. The Mayor keeps his council -- not sure what to make of this arrangement.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks. She's not my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me ask you something, have you ever heard of a town with electric lights?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>St. Rose?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah!</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never been. But they say it's a ways down on the coast.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's the discovery of a lifetime. The Postman looks to the west end of the bridge, where Abby stands alone.</context>
      <utterance>Couple hundred miles at least. I couldn't say for sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem like a decent man. And these seem like decent people.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We try to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this seems like a safe place.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman looks back to the Mayor, then slowly nods.</context>
      <utterance>You want to leave her?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of them. I'll give you the horses and my gear. Abby's special. She's strong. Probably end up running the place.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you take the night to think. Decide if that's what you really want.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're looking for The Postman.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No such thing anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little BOY steps forward, sings out.</context>
      <utterance>Man on the horse says there is. Says he thinks he's here. Says he's coming back with friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A silent moment. It's been so long, no one's sure how to answer. The Postman looks down at the ground. The carriers exchange deflated looks. Then...</context>
      <utterance>What's a postman?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head "no." Seems a shame. As The Postman looks over at Abby, she takes a page from his book.</context>
      <utterance>You never heard of a postman?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes to The Postman's gear, returns with his postal cap. Sets it on the boy's head.</context>
      <utterance>There used to be a postman for every street in America. They wore uniforms. And hats. Like this one...</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Several other listeners nod -- they're completely with her.</context>
      <utterance>My postman knew the name of every kid on my street. He knew our birthdays. He'd even find the baseballs you'd hit down the street. I can still see the smile on his face. The tip of his cap -- when he had a letter in his bag with my name on it. Mine always came just after school. You could set your watch by him. Unless you were waiting on something special -- like a present from somewhere far away or a letter from your sweetheart. Then it seemed like he'd never come. I used to think they could make time stand still.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a moment before anyone speaks.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think we ever really understood what they meant to us until they were gone. Getting a letter made you feel like you were part of something bigger than yourself. No place was ever too far away for the postman. So nobody ever had to be alone. The postman was someone you could count on. Things just made more sense when they were around.  That's the kind of world we used to have. A world a lot of us took for granted. And now we've got this one. And it makes me wonder -- what kind of world do I want my child to live in? I want my child to live in a world where hopes and dreams aren't just lies you tell yourself to get through another day. I want my child, and I want my friends -- I want all of us to live in a world where you still get your mail.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you The Postman?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've heard of you, man. You're famous.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as he puts on his cap, he accepts the mantle as well.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I guess I am. And all of a sudden, I'm not wearing the right clothes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're not stupid, after all.</context>
      <utterance>Fact that we don't allow 'em doesn't mean we don't have 'em.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry I've brought this on you.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No need to be sorry. Long as we get our mail on time.</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The Postman looks over to see Ponytail, Drew and Chubby ride up. Like him, they are back in uniform.</context>
      <utterance>Ready for duty, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The carriers look away -- sheepish.</context>
      <utterance>The order was to burn all uniforms.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what to do then?</utterance>
   <speaker>PONYTAIL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk to the people. Gather who's willing. Tell them it's important. Tell them we can make a difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBY SENTRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And tell 'em we're going to kick ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, tell them that, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes start to tear and he takes her in his arms.</context>
      <utterance>This is hard for me.  Michael was the best man I ever knew. I never thought there'd be another man I could love the way I loved him.  I don't know why I've been so blessed. And I've tried to find a way to be thankful, but I swear, if I lose you...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Abby, do you think a lie can become the truth?</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, but I believe in you. You have a gift, Postman. I saw it back in Pine View.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He starts to speak. She stops him, taking his hand.</context>
      <utterance>You made Mrs. March feel like she could see again. You made Ford feel like he was part of the world. You give out hope like it was candy in your pocket.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman lets go of her hand and starts for the basket. The Mayor gestures to the line of towers extending into the distance.</context>
      <utterance>When you come back, we'll be waiting here for you. So you can take us to St. Rose.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As The Postman steps into the basket, he makes the mistake of looking over the edge. It's a long, long way down.</context>
      <utterance>There's three good-sized towns up that way. Enough folks to be a big help to you. If you can convince them to come.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman looks at the contraption with more than a little trepidation. The Mayor grins.</context>
      <utterance>A lot higher than it looks, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He winks and as he reaches for the release pin. The Postman's hand meets his there.</context>
      <utterance>Don't tell anybody, but I like to ride the damn thing just for the hell of it. Being a city official has its perks.</utterance>
   <speaker>B.C. MAYOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me, man. This'll get you there a lot faster.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But it's too late. The Mayor releases the pin.</context>
      <utterance>How do I stop --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="145" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLD GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as Gibbs steps up, all hope is gone.</context>
      <utterance>Steady, boys, steady.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In accordance with Law Eight...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD GEORGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see the faces of the young carriers. Defeated, bitter. But there's a sudden spark in Old George's eyes. He starts to rise. The soldiers pick up their guns and that's when they see The Postman.</context>
      <utterance>Get on with it, you floppy-eared sonuvabitch!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="146" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... We were outnumbered, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A least a hundred. With guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With guns? Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIBBS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps away to get a better vantage point of the approaching army. He reaches out -- Getty hands him a pair of binoculars.</context>
      <utterance>Looks more like two hundred to me...</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem watches The Postman through the binoculars -- a hint of a smile on his face.</context>
      <utterance>Only thing worse than a coward is one who can't count. Lieutenant, do yourself a favor. Die well in this battle. In my army a deserter's life is a brief and unpleasant one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reckoning, gentlemen. This is the day I've dreamed of.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="147" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are they surrendering?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches for a moment as The Postman crosses the field - - moving well within range of Holnist fire. Then, he coaxes his horse forward.</context>
      <utterance>God, I hope not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="148" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM AND POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As they come face-to-face.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My little shipping clerk.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem sneers.</context>
      <utterance>We're both a couple of frauds. You know it; I know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great men are made by other great men. Patton had Rommel. Grant had Lee. But I get you.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE   POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're not even a good painter.</context>
      <utterance>You're no fucking general. You're a copying machine salesman.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you trying to goad me into a fight?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't it be great if wars could be fought just by the assholes who started them? We could settle this thing right here. You and me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately, it doesn't work that way.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman kicks his horse up into a gallop, and rides up the Holnist line. No one, least of all Bethlehem, is sure what's going on.</context>
      <utterance>It does in your army.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I invoke law seven of the Laws of Eight! Any man may challenge for leadership of the clan!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="149" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman wheels his horse around.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem is caught completely by surprise, but recovers.</context>
      <utterance>I challenge you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman rolls up his sleeve. He rides the Holnist lines displaying his brand for all to see. The Holnists murmur amongst themselves.</context>
      <utterance>You're not a Holnist. You're not a member of the clan. You don't have the right.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem can't believe his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I have every right. I invoke law seven!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The seed of doubt is planted. Is Bethlehem violating one of the Laws of Eight? The men look at one another. Gibbs looks to Getty. Bethlehem looks from The Postman's tattoo to his face.</context>
      <utterance>I challenge for leadership of the clan!</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do I know you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cry Havoc! And let slip the dogs of war.' Remember that?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shakespeare. The one who didn't want to fight.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should've found a way to kill you then. But you seemed so strong.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Law seven it is.  This war is settled here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="150" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman can't answer.</context>
      <utterance>I study people. I know your problem. Do you know why you can't fight?</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman grabs Bethlehem's knife-hand -- using all his remaining strength to keep him at bay.</context>
      <utterance>You have nothing to fight for. You don't care about anything. You don't value anything. You don't believe in anything. That's what makes me better.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I believe in the United States Postal Service.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="151" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem reels, stumbling back. The Postman pounces on top of him, begins to strangle him. Bethlehem tries to pry the fingers from his throat, but can't. He's going to die. The Postman is urged on. By both sides. Holnists. Carriers. Ford. Even Holnist Luke. He looks up at the faces -- and finally lets Bethlehem go. The General gasps for breath. As Ponytail and Chubby move forward to untie Ford, The Postman looks to both sides.</context>
      <utterance>Neither snow...  Nor rain...  Nor heat...  Nor gloom of night...  Will stay this courier from the swift completion of his appointed rounds...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford takes Chubby's pistol, sets it against the side of Bethlehem's head.</context>
      <utterance>It doesn't have to be this way. We don't have to kill each other. We can live together. We can --</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Law three. Mercy is for the weak.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bethlehem shakes his head -- doesn't want him to, either.</context>
      <utterance>Ford, don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford's going to shoot.</context>
      <utterance>Law eight. There is only one penalty and that penalty is death.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="152" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman looks at carriers and Holnists alike.</context>
      <utterance>He isn't worth it. I'm the head of the clan now! There are going to be new laws!  Law one! No more killing! There's going to be peace!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who else? Who else has a law?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone has to learn how to read.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's law two. Who else?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIER #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three. Liberty and justice for all!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four. No more tattoos.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Law five. Give peace a chance!</utterance>
   <speaker>HOLNIST SOLDIER #2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Law six. Mercy is, it's okay sometimes!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARRIER #3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman nods solemnly, looks to Ford.</context>
      <utterance>Seven! Bring back vacations!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford grits his teeth.</context>
      <utterance>How about it, Ford Lincoln Mercury? You give us law eight.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be a leader, Ford.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford FIRES! Bethlehem flinches, then sags as he realizes Ford has fired into the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Law eight...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="153" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Postman smiles in relief as Ford lowers the revolver and starts to hand the weapon over. Forgotten for an instant, Bethlehem makes a last, wild lunge, grabs Ford's gun. As Bethlehem aims at The Postman, a SHOT rings out. Hit in the chest, Bethlehem blinks in amazement before he falls to the ground, dying. Getty has shot him.</context>
      <utterance>... Live and let live.</utterance>
   <speaker>BETHLEHEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He dies.</context>
      <utterance>Would I had bestowed that time in the tongues that I have in fencing, dancing and bear-baiting. Oh, had I but followed the arts...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Getty throws his rifle on the ground. Other weapons are laid down. The war, at long last, is over.</context>
      <utterance>Grow like savages -- as soldiers will -- that nothing do but mediate on blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody take a letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHUBBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A letter...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="154" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE POSTMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Abby smiles down at the child in her arms.</context>
      <utterance>Mail's slow. I'll have to see about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ABBY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your daughter. Her name is Hope. The Postman takes the tiny child in his arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And so my father returned home after the Holnists were defeated...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="155" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>HOPE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She unveils the statue: we've seen this before. It's The Postman on his horse, low-slung in the saddle, leaning down to pluck the letter from the Little Boy's hand. There's an OLDER MAN in the audience who seems especially moved by the statue. There's a younger man beside him.</context>
      <utterance>But he never did see St. Rose. There was too much to be done. He'd made a promise and in keeping it -- he traded one dream for another. With no regrets. And so, in honor of my father...</utterance>
   <speaker>OLDER MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As St. Rose applauds...</context>
      <utterance>That was me.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
