<movie id="490" title="Shipping News The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you're shocked when someone aims kindness your way. That oughta tell you somethin' about yourself. Watches the little guy's undemanding smile. QUOYLE  Then again. If you're that kinda guy. It don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Quoyle gazes at his benefactor, the woman sneaks up, SNATCHES his Help Wanted ads. Races them over to her dryer. As the boys watch, she shoves them in, starts the machine with Quoyle's coins, and glares fiercely back at us. A mother bear protecting her cubs. Partridge chuckles. Holds out his hand...</context>
      <utterance>And put a cuppa bleach in, next time through.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle glances at the little man's cold fowl supper.</context>
      <utterance>Partridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh. No thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh.</context>
      <utterance>It's my name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the change SPILLS out of Quoyle's pockets, and CLATTERS onto the wood floor, ROLLING interminably, as Quoyle fidgets.</context>
      <utterance>I don't like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>REVERSE ANGLE now to see Quoyle's face. The neat moustache of powdered sugar.</context>
      <utterance>Partridge says you're not as dumb as you look.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>And takes a healthy bite from what's left of the doughnut.</context>
      <utterance>How could I be?</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle nods, dumbly. Knows this.</context>
      <utterance>Anyway, that's why I'm takin' a chance on you. Partridge said he'd re-write whatever of your stuff. Stay late...</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle nods bigger. Like he gets it. Punch shoves an antique tape recorder across the table.</context>
      <utterance>We're a family paper. Upbeat stories with a community slant. Self-help stuff: Are You a Break- fast Alcoholic?...Guide to Getting Dumped...like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD on Quoyle's eyes. Recalling...</context>
      <utterance>City Planning Board meeting at two- thirty. Three hunnerd words max. Sink or swim.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Quoyle's FATHER hauls him off the deck, and in a single motion, FLINGS him INTO the pool!</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it was my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Watches the THRASHING with mild contempt. Turns away before Quoyle simply SINKS beneath the surface.</context>
      <utterance>Sink or swim, pig-butt.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a water person.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, three hunnerd words would be, like, one page. This is...oh, fifteen, sixteen.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Partridge does glance up on that.</context>
      <utterance>So we should cut it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gonna have to.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or you could tie me in a sack, throw me in the river. Tell the police you thought it was oddly-wrapped lard.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nobody smiles. Nobody has to. Quoyle pulls a big glass jar from a paper sack. Sets it on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Might be quicker.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Partridge looks at the cornichons. They look expensive.</context>
      <utterance>Does your wife like special pickles? They're fine with cold cuts.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come by for supper, tomorrow. We'll</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DISSOLVE to...</context>
      <utterance>find out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mercalia takes out the package. Wrapped in tissue, a neat ribbon. She hands it to Quoyle, and leans up to kiss his cheek. Quoyle looks down at it, dumbfounded. A silence.</context>
      <utterance>We. Got you this.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle smiles. Sweet and slightly confused.</context>
      <utterance>It's...an anniversary present. Anniversary of our friendship.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to unwrap...</context>
      <utterance>Seven and a half month anniversary?</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...a wristwatch. A nice one. He is overwhelmed, but still uncomprehending.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Why wait?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERCALIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That stops Partridge's face. No more stalling...</context>
      <utterance>It's because we're happy. About something. And steals a glance at her husband. QUOYLE  You're havin' a baby!</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To California. Friday night.</context>
      <utterance>Mercalia and me are movin'.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle nodding slowly, smile still there. Yep. I guess y'can. Partridge sees that it's a death blow. Mercalia looks at her feet.</context>
      <utterance>You know she's been learnin' to drive a rig. She got the Oakland to New Orleans run. I'm gonna make her smoked duck sandwiches for the road. I can edit copy anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if parting advice. As if Quoyle should file that away. So Quoyle nods some more. As if he will.</context>
      <utterance>Love's all that counts. It's the engine of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>PARTRIDGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On this, Quoyle's smile deserts him. So Partridge reaches out his hand. Quoyle paralyzed, then takes it. CLOSE ON their handclasp, and DISSOLVE to...</context>
      <utterance>We'll just. Stay in touch.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>PAN up to see her. Tiny, twitchy, moist ringlets. A gray-eyed predator. She looks around at the milling suits and their name tags. As if they were alternatives.</context>
      <utterance>Petal Bear, Mr. Quoyle.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle transfixed by her slight form in its loose but clingy wrapping. The smile that sees him again and flickers...</context>
      <utterance>Do you hate this shit, or what?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Don't you? No answer. She laughs, as if at some off-color response. Runs hot fingers up his arm, leaning to his face...</context>
      <utterance>What do you think? You want to marry me, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buy me a drink somewhere, it's seven-thirty. I think I'm going to fuck you by ten. What do you think of that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Climbs on, the lithe move of a leopardess. Feeding time.</context>
      <utterance>Christ. I won the lottery.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Petal RIDING in silhouette, with great, violent swoops. CLOSE on his face, his eyes. Lovelight.</context>
      <utterance>It was pretty much like that for a month.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somewhere in there. We got married.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>...the back of Petal, talking to a big guy in a shiny suit.</context>
      <utterance>After that, I had to follow her to see her.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Closer. Close enough to hear...</context>
      <utterance>Which I know was wrong of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD on Quoyle's face. The lovelight has never left. It shines through the shock. As if in apology...</context>
      <utterance>What do you think? You want to marry me, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>DISSOLVE to...</context>
      <utterance>She didn't know she was pregnant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He takes a breath. Can hear the noise of a rowdy spot. Country juke box.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. How do you make an Alabama Slammer?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh. Where are y...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Bunny. Has stopped screaming.</context>
      <utterance>Alabama. Hence, the question.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come home. I'll make you one.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>What should he do? He sets Bunny carefully on the floor. She starts screaming again, and he LIFTS her quick, cuddles her. LOPES off, leaving the phone on the floor... ...RACES back in with the Mr. Boston, a bag of pork rinds, and a pacifier. Something for everyone. As he flips the pages, he murmurs into the phone...</context>
      <utterance>That's a swell idea. Now go look on top of the fridge, where I keep the Mr. Boston. I'll wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs, almost friendly. He smiles. Ever hopeful.</context>
      <utterance>You okay? Except for being thirsty?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm busy, I'll see y...</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>QUOYLE  Ounce Southern Comfort, ounce Sloe Gin. Ounce Triple Sec. Three ounces o.j....</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CLICK. The BUZZ of her disconnect. He glances down at Bunny, working the pacifier. Murmurs to the receiver...</context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hang up the phone. Kiss a baby. Eat a pork rind. Slow. As he gazes down on Bunny, we PUSH INTO her face, and MATCH DISSOLVE to...</context>
      <utterance>Me too. I'll tell Bunny you miss her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Really? She tears off her jacket, revealing that she has left her shirt somewhere and is down to her bra. She stalks toward him. Straight to the doorway. He flinches.</context>
      <utterance>There's. Cold chicken.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle swallows. Shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Find yourself. A girlfriend. With what you got down there, you'll do fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No. No. Tears of shock pool in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Only thing can work, here. Is divorce.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She shivers with disgust. Walks around in a frustrated circle. Back to his face. Are you sure? What does a girl have to do? And now... ...the tears are on his face. She flashes her hardest look. And yet... ...her slender fingers reach out. Wipe his face, not as roughly as she might have intended.</context>
      <utterance>I knew we had our problems. But I never thought I'd hear that word.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And CLOSES the door, quietly, but firmly. In his face. He stares at it. His lips part. But no sound comes. Instead, he walks the few steps to Bunny's room, to find her... ...wide awake. Sitting on the edge of her bed. No question, she heard it all. So Quoyle smiles. He reaches to the top of her battered armoire. His eyes damp but dancing for his daughter. Pulls down... ...a box of chocolates. Their stash. He sits on the floor. Opens the lid, like buried treasure. She comes to cuddle in his lap. He feeds her one. She feeds him one. They've done this before. As they chew...</context>
      <utterance>Your funeral, pussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew if I could take it. In the end. It would all work out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>LILA doesn't even bother to blush. A shrug is plenty.</context>
      <utterance>Lila, it's Daniel. Ten-thirty. Bring the. You know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quoyle, this is your father. Calling you. Dicky's machine is full. Your home one's broke. Well. It's time for your mother and I to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quoyle listening. Go?</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Oh. Go. Eyes are sneaking over now. Lots of them.</context>
      <utterance>Instructions about the undertaker. The cremation. On the dining room table.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Everybody just openly staring now. Quoyle's snack cake and coffee frozen in mid-air.</context>
      <utterance>You'll have to make your own way. I did. Nobody gave me nuthin'. Other men woulda give up, turned to bums. I sweated, wheeled barrows of sand, went without so you and yer brother could have advantages. Not that you did much with your chances.</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Her number's on the dining room ta...</context>
      <utterance>Hasn't been much of a life. Tell Dicky and my sister Agnis Hamm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MACHINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Quoyle nods. Sounded that way. Despite the hateful coarseness of this message, Quoyle is deeply moved. Lips pursed inward to stem tears. In the silence... FAT GUY (trying) Were they sick, or something? Quoyle stares into distance. Somewhere, feet shuffle.</context>
      <utterance>That was your final message.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, it is that. Wanders on over to his desk. They're still watching, but he doesn't seem to notice. Turns his ratty Rolodex with solemn slowness. Not to dishonor the moment. Finds the number, dials. Winces at the harshness of the voice he hears. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Brain tumor and liver cancer.  One apiece. FAT GAL  That's rough.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dicky. It's Mom and Poppa. They.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. For the funeral, I thou...</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Quoyle shakes his head once. That confused he isn't. QUOYLE (quietly) Well. Mom'll be there, too. Silence.</context>
      <utterance>You think I'd go pay that prick respects? You got me confused with you!</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Barfbag. They leave us anything, y'think?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I hadda send some grocery mon...</context>
      <utterance>Don't see how. Big mortgage. Spent their savings on the doctors.</utterance>
   <speaker>BROTHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>LONG ANGLE...they are watching him replace the receiver in its cradle. Think. Stumble slightly, as he makes his way toward...</context>
      <utterance>Well, see, that's why he did it. I mean, think how it felt. Taking from you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A full beat.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, Ed. I gotta drive down to my parents' place. I'll be back, Friday.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle's eyes sharpen.</context>
      <utterance>Take yer time. I gotta let you go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In what sense do you m...</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. Once again, life slips beneath even Quoyle's expectations. QUOYLE (a little dazed) Uh. Would next week be better? PUNCH (sighs) I got the summer interns comin' next week. They're free and they're smart. Gotta do somethin' to fight this slump. But don't worry... Don't?</context>
      <utterance>As in canned.</utterance>
   <speaker>PUNCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yer not the only one.  Eventually.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should I finish the sawmill piece?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MRS. MOOSUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uh-oh.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that may take awhile.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MOOSUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He knows the one.</context>
      <utterance>She came in at one, packed like crazy. Said she was movin' to Florida with the guy in the red Geo. You know the one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MRS. MOOSUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is heading toward the hall.</context>
      <utterance>She says you gotta pay my wages for the sittin'. Seven weeks, comes to $3080. 'Preciate a check right n...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MOOSUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That stops him. Cold. He turns...</context>
      <utterance>Don't bother. She took Bunny with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the last thing she'd ev...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MOOSUP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He TEARS out, DOWN the hall, INTO Bunny's room... ...closet open. Empty. No more tangled pile of Barbies. He surveys the wreckage of his life.</context>
      <utterance>She was real clear about my check. It's no fun workin' if you don't get paid.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least she took her toys. Wanted her to be happy. He staggers out of the room, down the hall...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. MOOSUP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>...into the kitchen. Lifts the receiver. Thinks. Dials. QUOYLE (quietly) Yes. I need to report a kidnapping. And straightens his spine. Just a little.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Quoyle? I ain't got all day, here!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's still holding the violets. He notices this. Sets them down, almost tenderly, in the sink.</context>
      <utterance>Quoyle. Q-U-O-Y-L-...no, Y, then L-E. Yeh, it's my kid.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this Mr. Guy Quoyle? QUOYLE  He's not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Lt. Amos Figg of the Mockingburg, New York Police. Could you have him call me when he ret...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's passed on. He's dead.  You said Mockingb...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Quoyle blinks. Not in the mood.</context>
      <utterance>We're a small town upstate. I'm actually trying to reach his son. He allegedly went down to his parents' place two days ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a detective, Lieutenant?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Well, as you've probably deduced, I am his son. Cause I'm at his place. As alleged.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ominous. Would be an understatement.</context>
      <utterance>Which is...? FIGG  You want the good news? Or the bad news.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The good. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Quoyle's heart. Has stopped.</context>
      <utterance>Your daughter Bunny was sold by your wife to a child pornographer. For $9000.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>INTERCUT...a dingy kitchen, scuzzier than we could even have guessed. Bunny in her underpants sliding merrily on a floor made slippery with dish detergent. PAN past the video camera on its tripod to the PORNOGRAPHER at the window, also in his underpants, screaming into a cordless phone. And... BACK to Quoyle. His heart must have started again, because he is able to say...</context>
      <utterance>But she's fine. We got her. And the doc says she wasn't touched. Yet. If you catch my drift.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's. The good n...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>INTERCUT...a riverbank somewhere high above swiftly-flowing water. Police and bystanders gathered. A winch reaching its chain into the depths.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Compared.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Here comes part of the Geo. Streaming water and mud.</context>
      <utterance>Your wife was in a red Geo which went through a guardrail over the Chesapeake Bay Bridge.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were doin' 97 in a fog. The</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BACK to the horrified husband. Waiting in silence.</context>
      <utterance>car was cut in half by the impact with the rail. Her male companion's body floated up downstream.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Petal...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>trousers for some reas...</context>
      <utterance>May never find the body. But she was mercifully killed on impact, without a doubt. They found her shoes under the dash and her...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That don't mean for sure she w...</utterance>
   <speaker>FIGG</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Oh. Tears finally force their way through the shock. As he realizes... QUOYLE (a murmur) Yeh. If she was alive. Don't guess she'd a left that.</context>
      <utterance>...and her purse. With the nine large.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We hadn't seen them, hidden beside his leg. A bunch of DAISIES. He gives them to her. Like her best beau.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, too. That for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's our candy?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then...</context>
      <utterance>In the store. That way, you've got the whole selection.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bunny doesn't understand.</context>
      <utterance>Give us a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL BACK to the cop, staring down on them from point-blank range. He doesn't move. Quoyle looks up, with an easy smile that says he'd just as soon tear all the arms and legs off, and sweat the consequences later. The cop backs well off. He can take a hint.</context>
      <utterance>I mean him.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks in her eyes. Shakes his head. No.</context>
      <utterance>Petal went to Florida. She'll be back soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She had an accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, I do. Tenderly pulls a strand of her hair aside.</context>
      <utterance>So do you.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was a car crash, sweetie. And they found...you know, the body. Of her friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's right. His big hand has wrapped around one of hers. She doesn't seem to mind. Their faces so close.</context>
      <utterance>Nestor.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You know dead. Like the turtle.</context>
      <utterance>Petal can't come back, she's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She drills his eyes. Calm as a moose.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>We found the turtle. And they found Nestor. Did you find Petal?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And leans her forehead. To rest against his.</context>
      <utterance>You never do. But she always comes back.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tall and rawboned and 60. A rugged, maybe even handsome face, set with ice-blue eyes. Calm, slightly scary eyes, that drift to his robe...</context>
      <utterance>Nephew, I'm your Aunt. Agnis Hamm.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is completely off-balance here.</context>
      <utterance>You sick? It's nine o'clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>uh, early to bed, earl...</context>
      <utterance>Uh. No, Bunny and I like to...</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not that she seems to approve. Not at all. His eyes now drift to the large, well-used SUITCASES dangling from her powerful hands.</context>
      <utterance>Losin' your wife, your folks, and your job'd depress anybody. It's a wonder you don't sleep all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And stops. The mouth doesn't smile. But the eyes crinkle slightly toward... ...Bunny. Who has crept out in her jammies. Hugging a sack of Pepperidge Farm cookies like it was a teddy.</context>
      <utterance>Thought I'd stay a day or two. Give you some relief with th...</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little girl nods. As if she certainly does.</context>
      <utterance>AGNIS  You like blue dogs named Warren?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got one in the car.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="27">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>See him now, sipping his tea. Wallowing in the detritus of his emotions.</context>
      <utterance>I never knew her, really.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agnis in the good chair. Teacup on her ample lap. Assessing a photo on the end table, Petal's arctic eyes, rigidly seductive pose. The snapshot enshrined by a neighboring votive rose in its jelly jar glass.</context>
      <utterance>But she was driven by terrible forces, no one could understand. She was a locked door. Even to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle's eyes cut instinctively toward his daughter, her innocence protected by distance and absorption with Warren's passivity.</context>
      <utterance>So she wasn't just a bitch in high heels?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't stress. She mighta heard worse from her momma. I'm only guessin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some people probably thought Petal was bad clear through.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People. Are a cynical lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agnis' unblinking eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I think she just couldn't get enough love.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think the evidence. Is on your side.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The eyes study him. Dissect him, even.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clucks her tongue.</context>
      <utterance>I'm headed north, Nephew, to where our family comes from, in Newfoundland. Thought I'd never go back. But the older y'get...</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Not a smile. But something. A softening of timbre, a flicker behind the eye.</context>
      <utterance>There's a pull. Becomes an ache. As if where your people started held a purpose for you. Like you're a piece in a puzzle...</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lifts her cup.</context>
      <utterance>...lookin' for where y'fit.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takes a sip. His eyes have narrowed in a burlesque of suspicion.</context>
      <utterance>You, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In what sense do you m...</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just like that.</context>
      <utterance>You need to come, Nephew.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hmmn?</context>
      <utterance>Nothin' here but hurt. You got to start fresh, everythin's gone!</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tilts her head. Who knows.</context>
      <utterance>The trip'll clear your head. Be educational for the squirt. Teach ya the world's still spinnin' outside this toxic slice o'Hades. And who knows...?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must have a newspaper up there. Somebody's gotta write it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He just stares. The blankest of the blank.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face softens. Hadn't thought of it that way. And seeing this...</context>
      <utterance>Tell the truth, I'd appreciate the company. You two are pretty much my family.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She waits. He rises. And when he does...</context>
      <utterance>A pot o'coffee would hit the spot. Drop o'whiskey would fit nice in it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He blinks. She looks at two URNS on the mantle.</context>
      <utterance>Which one's my brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The name of the funeral home tastefully stenciled. He clears his throat...</context>
      <utterance>Uh. There's Mom. And that's Poppa.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those are temporary.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle nods, glad to serve. Heads off to the kitchen. Agnis looks at Bunny and Warren.</context>
      <utterance>Coffee. And maybe a sweet.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She needs to go outside.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs out, the dog trotting after. Alone now... ...Agnis pulls something from her large carpetbag purse. It is an oversized ZIPLOC BAG. She stands. Crosses to... ...her brother's urn. She removes the lid. Turns the huge Ziploc upside down to COVER the urn. Then, in one deft movement... ...UPENDS the urn, a cascade of ash tumbling into the Ziploc. Seals it. Sets it to one side. Then, from her purse... ...another ziploc already filled with replacement ashes. She pours just enough into the urn. That should do it. Stashes the rest back in her purse. Turns now to lift...</context>
      <utterance>I know why.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Eyes flat and neutral.</context>
      <utterance>What say, Guy? The dumpster?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just a thought.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She stands at the rail. Smoking, despite the wind.</context>
      <utterance>They draft off our air currents, it's quite premeditated.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles a seasick smile. Lurches from his bolted-down chair to join her. She nods back toward... ...Bunny through the glass window, snuggled with Warren, feeding the dog french fries.</context>
      <utterance>They actually know the ferry schedule. Show up on time better'n the Newfies.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...image of m'sister, Feeny. She's married to a falconer in Arabia, now. Has to wear a black</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>thing over her face.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares in his eyes. Yes, like the falcon. They are growing on each other in a companionable way.</context>
      <utterance>Like the falcon.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles. It is nice.</context>
      <utterance>Nice. To be with family.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His smile changes color. A quiet pride in the modest...</context>
      <utterance>'Specially big shots. Who can land a job with one phone call.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When Quoyle looks back in at Bunny, he sees she is staring off at something with full attention. He follows her gaze to... ...a honey-haired MOTHER with her small BOY snuggled in her lap. She is feeding him an ice cream bar with evident tenderness. And though the child's face is blissfully vacant, she murmurs to him with serious intent.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that was my friend Partridge. Made the call. And it's just an interview.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cloud lifts further, and we see the house stands alone on a rocky point. The bay roils far below. Half the window panes are gone. Holes in the roof, paint flaking everywhere. Lonely and scary as any haunted house.</context>
      <utterance>The green makes me hurl.  Her, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle looks at her. Looks at the house. Looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Empty 44 years. And look at that roofline, straight as a ruler.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes Bunny's squirming hand and starts toward the house, as if crossing Jordan. AGNIS (calling back) The whole thing's lashed with cable, to iron rings set in the rock! He just stands there. Sees the cables now, the rings. QUOYLE (calling out) Uh. Why would they do th... AGNIS (calling back) Long story! Apparently a private one, too. Keeps walking.</context>
      <utterance>Take it easy. Floor mighta fallen into the cellar. AGNIS  Not likely. There is no cellar. No foundation, neither.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up those stairs, Aunt Pinkie slept. So fat she couldn't get down to her chamber pot. Wanna see if she's still there?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE...upstairs now. Agnis marching through like MacArthur reclaiming the Philippines. Room after rough-hewn spacious room, light spiking through a thousand roof holes in assorted shapes.</context>
      <utterance>Asked as a serious question. Bunny nods. Let's.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle looks down to his daughter. Who nods, as if that were a perfectly natural suggestion.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Too late to drive that road back 'round the bay. We'll camp in here tonight. Be right as rain.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one's Petal's room? I'll sleep there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer. That concerns him. The intensity of her focus. He notices now, the soda and beer cans with their tops popped. Lined up in a row. He lifts one, liquid sloshes out. They're full.</context>
      <utterance>Is that a belt or a crown?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sodas get flat withou...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She won't look up. He glances back to the doorway.</context>
      <utterance>This is important.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That why the Barbies are watching?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're being nice and patient.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must be chilly, tho. Should I get their clo...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks back. Well. Maybe so. Holds up one of the heavy boots he's carrying. It has a thick blue shoelace. The other. Has none. Sticks that one in front of her face. She looks up to him. Tugs on the shoelace, which she now wears as a necklace...</context>
      <utterance>They look better this way. They have great bodies.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...sees now what she has tugged from inside her shirt. The shoelace necklace holds a dull metal KEY as a pendant. He blinks.</context>
      <utterance>I need it. I look good in blue. QUOYLE  Well. I look good in shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was lookin' for that all over our old place. The landlady s...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes that in. The urgency of it. She is staring in his eyes. So he grins...</context>
      <utterance>I need it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't smile back. Returns to her work. He looks out by the cliff, to see Agnis staring across the bay, Warren sitting at her side. He pulls on his boots. Gets to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>You had quite the heavy morning. Take the rest of the day off.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be right back, and we'll start talking breakf... BUNNY  Watch out for the dog. He looks across the ground toward old Warren.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeh, her farts are pretty scary.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now their eyes meet. Matter-of-fact...</context>
      <utterance>I mean. The white one!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He draws a breath...</context>
      <utterance>The White Dog with the big teeth and the red eyes. The Skinny Ghost owns him. They came last night.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thinks this over.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't dream 'em, don't say I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And makes a funny gesture, like peeling his eyeballs. She goes back to work. His eyes linger. Then, he heads off toward the cliff. When he gets there... AGNIS (staring across the bay) I'll get us a carpenter. Fix the place up in no time. We'll find a rooming house til th...</context>
      <utterance>I was gonna say. I'll keep my eyes peeled.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she looks at him. Her flat, bottomless eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Be cheaper to build a new one. On the Riviera, even.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O-kay. That's settled. He nods, humbly, dumbly. She points off across the water. An actual TOWN.</context>
      <utterance>Only I weren't born. On the Riviera.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ten o'clock.</context>
      <utterance>Flour Sack Cove. What time's your interview at that paper? Ten o'clock?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tries a smile. Unavoidably lame.</context>
      <utterance>The drive's a bitch. We'll buy us a boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His grin hardens. Just enough to say that on this issue, maybe even she can't push him. He turns around. Starts back toward his daughter.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not. A water person. AGNIS  A boat. That's the ticket.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...not a water person.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Still staring in the mirror. The receding figures small against the rain.</context>
      <utterance>Someone found a pretty wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone always does.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More of a leering rictus than an actual smile. TERT CARD is aging, balding, potbellied over a once-rawboned frame. His face looks like cottage cheese clawed with a fork. He scratches his balls with a rough-hewn hand. He is never happy.</context>
      <utterance>As you can see, sometimes y'can't get away. I'm Tert X. Card, the bloody so-called managing editor, copyeditor, rewrite man, mechanicals, ad makeup department, mail and distribution chief, and snow shoveler.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you are either a big advertiser come to buy a four-page spread to push your warehouse of left-footed Japanese boots. Or. You. Are the breathlessly-awaited Quoyle.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Card rakes his privates once more, and offers the same hand in dubious greeting. Quoyle takes it.</context>
      <utterance>That'd be me. The second one.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Claps a mirthless hand on Quoyle's back, leading him into...</context>
      <utterance>Have to do without the Ultimate Cheese, y'will. Himself, Mr. Jack Buggit, is up at the house having charms said over his scrawny chest to clear out that impressive accumulation of phlegm he's been hawking all week.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy nods. That pretty much covers it.</context>
      <utterance>Billy does the Home News page. Poems, baby photos, household tips, and a gossip column, under the byline of Junior Sugg, that is pretty much straight libel.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Little salute from the Managing Editor. If Card likes anybody, he likes Billy. And he doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>In short. He writes the only stuff anybody actually reads.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>NUTBEEM is 50 and gangly. Buttery hair swept behind ample ears. A thin moustache, a bounteous bowtie, a ratty pullover. He opens a file folder. Gives Quoyle a piercing, meaningful glance.</context>
      <utterance>Now this miserable ugly Brit, is B. Beaufield Nutbeem. Imagines he's the foreign news chief. Steals every story off that foul shortwave radio and rewrites it in Limey prose. NUTBEEM  Which bloody Card rewrites in a mystical tongue most charitably referenced as an unacquireable taste.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mine: 'Burmese sawmill owners and the Rangoon Development Corporation met in Tokyo Tuesday to consider a joint approach to marketing tropical hardwoods.' Got it? Turns the page.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Card's rewrite: 'Burnoosed sawbill awnings and the Ranger Devotional Competition met Wednesday near Tokyo to mark up local hairwood.' A stunned. Silence.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's shorter, and I got Tokyo right.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If misspelled.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Card, who likes no one. Doesn't like Quoyle, too.</context>
      <utterance>Now what's funnier, Quoyle? My writing style, or the fantasy that any Newfie would read that moosepuckey in the first pIa... QUOYLE  How'd the meeting go? Did they agree on a joint marketing approach? The beginning. Of a beautiful friendship. NUTBEEM  Still in progress, old bean. One can only hope.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he turns away. Through the swinging door. SLAM. Quiet. Except for Nutbeem's chuckle.</context>
      <utterance>There's your miserable desk, Quoyle. We've got no idea what yer s'posed to do. But Mr. Jack Buggit will drop by someday and enlighten us all. Til then...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks into the truck. Sees all the stuff. She surveys his puzzlement.</context>
      <utterance>This is great stuff. 'A snowmobile mishap has taken the life of 78-year- old Rick Puff, who was on his way home from what the Widow Puff calls a 'screech-in and a carouse,' when his machine fell through the ice. A well- known accordion player, Mr. Puff had served four years in the 1970s for sexual assault on his daughters. Bet they aren't crying, either.' This Billy Pretty can really write! AGNIS  ...passes as colorful.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. Absorbs that.</context>
      <utterance>Nephew, we can't fix up the house proper on a journalist's wages. So I have un-retired.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From what?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle nods. Could be that. The sudden sound of footsteps above them, makes him look up sharply, to see... ...a fit young MAN in a toolbelt climbing down a ladder from the roof. The muscles of a stud, the shy smile of a boy, he waves a greeting and HOPS down the last six feet to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Upholstery. Been sought after for 33 years, wherever I've lived. This should be the real test, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>DENNIS offers a hand, and a smile that says he's expecting to like you. Makes the sentiment contagious.</context>
      <utterance>This is Dennis Buggit, master carpenter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A strong handshake. On both sides.</context>
      <utterance>Only til I get my lobster license. I'm a fisherman in my soul.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a Newfie thing, the compulsion to fish. Y'hear yesterday's tragedy</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle hasn't.</context>
      <utterance>'bout the Newfie who went ice fishin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle laughs good and honest. Dennis likes that.</context>
      <utterance>Brought home 200 pounds of ice. His wife fried it. They both drowned.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle nods, if a bit cautious. Dennis squints out across the bay.</context>
      <utterance>With me workin', we'll need day care for Bunny after school. Turns out Dennis and his wife send their little girl to this wonderful saintly woman. How's that for us livin' a charmed life?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sounds pretty sure of that. Punctures the amiable ambiance with a shard of silence.</context>
      <utterance>Agnis says yer buyin' a boat. Sooner's prob'ly better'n lat... QUOYLE  I'm not buyin'. No boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buggit, huh? Any kin to my boss on the Gammy Bird? The silence. Just got thunderous. A full beat. DENNIS (low) Oh, yeh. He's m'dad. Even the eyes glance down. What is that? In the wake of it... AGNIS (cheerful) Gonna chat up yer daughter, or just ignore her as usual? Quoyle nods. Better do that. Dennis sends a shy smile, as if apologizing for the awkwardness. Quoyle holds up a finger, be right back, and... ...heads on over to where Bunny is reading to Warren.</context>
      <utterance>Well, course we're buy... QUOYLE</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's got a stomach problem.</context>
      <utterance>Warren threw up in your sleeping bag.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Headline. Dog Fart Fells Freelance Reporter. Promising Career Nipped in Bud.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. Quoyle holds his face together, as Bunny strokes the limp Warren. Then, he crouches down... ...strokes Warren, too. Good dog.</context>
      <utterance>It's called cancer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holds out a brown fisherman's hand. Quoyle takes it.</context>
      <utterance>Based on my I.Q. test, huh. Where'd I rate? JACK  Advanced squirrel. This ties you with me, an' I own the place.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wink.</context>
      <utterance>Pleased t'meetcha, Billy says yer workin' out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>JACK (into bullhorn)</context>
      <utterance>Tert Card says he's keepin' an eye on ya. Since he's a self-servin' liar, helluva ad salesman tho, it means he's jealous. And Nutbeem... Lifts the bullhorn...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nutbeem's obsessed with actual news. Makes up for it by manning the sexual abuse desk. Can't keep up with the volume there, we're runnin' three, four a week. Leans forward. Like he's dishing the lowdown.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Card's in charge. Ya hear this and that 'bout his typos, but typos is part of Gammy Bird. Everyone gets a laugh, and gets to figger 'em out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stabs out his cigarette. Pulls a new one from a damp little box.</context>
      <utterance>Better'n a crossword.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Offers the box. Quoyle shakes him off.</context>
      <utterance>An' Billy. Well, Billy's a writer and a fisherman. Me, I'm just a fisherman.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>My pap the same. My boy.</context>
      <utterance>Fishin' and the sea is all I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah. Jack's smile doesn't actually fade. But the eyes flicker, and Quoyle is sorry he opened his yap.</context>
      <utterance>So he said. Waitin' for his license.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His glance goes to a photo. Jack and a strapping blond son. Not Dennis, that's for sure. Somehow, we are suddenly down to business...</context>
      <utterance>Naw, my boy's passed. Went to sea and there he rests. Bless his bones.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT...half a red Geo being fished out of the water. Petal's lifeless torso hanging backwards out the door, arms gracefully extended like a ballerina or Olympic diver. Over this...</context>
      <utterance>Want two things from ya, Quoyle. First. You cover every local car wreck, take pictures. Front-page photo every week, whether we have a wreck or not, an' we always do. When we don't, we dip into Card's file, he's got some beauties.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>BACK to Jack. Canny and keen. He knows this stuff.</context>
      <utterance>Knack to this. If there's a dark patch on the ground, it reads blood, whether it's motor oil or Diet Coke. Gloves, hat, lyin' in the road...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...somethin' that humanizes, makes ya feel. That's what a wreck is. It's always saying, 'There but for the grace of God...' Do ya follow? Quoyle follows.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Plus. We're starting a feature on the shipping news. What ships come in, what goes out. Whatever's of interest. Throwin' it to you, son. Chance to shine.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah. Jack takes this in. The smile returns.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Buggit. I'm not. Well, a water person.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If you catch my drift. Quoyle shuts up.</context>
      <utterance>Chance. To shine.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SMASH CUT to...</context>
      <utterance>One peculiarity. I'm no joke, son, and I don't tolerate jokes about Newfies. Or them that does.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His audience is Quoyle and Nutbeem. Each holds a squidburger of his own, tentacles dangling. Quoyle has his next one handy by his beer.</context>
      <utterance>So this Newfie comes to Toronto. Cabbie says, take ya to meet girls for a good time. Boy says, okay, but I only want a Newfie girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle takes a humongus BITE. Tentacles now dripping from his jaws. Rapt. Hypnotized.</context>
      <utterance>Right section of the party district, he finds a girl, they have sex, she says that's a hunnerd dollars. He says fine, tips her another hunnerd! She says, wow, can y'come back t'morrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Next two nights, same thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle hanging on the punch.</context>
      <utterance>Finally she says, I never met so sweet a guy, where ya from? He says, Misky Bay, Newfoundland. She says, really? Me, too!</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle SNORTS his laughter, dislodging a tentacled morsel or two. Nutbeem has to look away, as Quoyle retrieves the chunks, stuffs 'em back in his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>He says, I know. Yer ma asked me t'give ya six hunnerd dollars!</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drunken, devilish smile. Quoyle turns, innocent questioning eyes. You got a boat?</context>
      <utterance>Yer the model Newfie, Q, but fer th'boat. Why doncha buy Nutbeem's?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So casual and falsely modest, Quoyle's eyes are big.</context>
      <utterance>I built a Chinese junk. Sailed it up from Brazil. Missed Manhattan by a mile or so, got stranded here when I shipwrecked by Gaze Island.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Studies Quoyle's amazement. Confides...</context>
      <utterance>Almost finished my repairs. Be leaving soon. As paleontologists define the term.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dennis rises. Belches.</context>
      <utterance>She's ugly. And the only thing I've ever loved.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And off he lurches to correct the situation. Once he's gone...</context>
      <utterance>Yer story tugs at me bladder.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their eyes meet. The Brit sighs.</context>
      <utterance>Him and Jack. Tell it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack Buggit's psychic, start with that. He's got the gift. Specially about the sea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's right.</context>
      <utterance>Older brother Jesson, everyone's favorite, even Dennis'. Goes to sea like his dad. One day, rest of the family's sitting by the radio, and Jack goes white...</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sets down the burger. Runs a finger down the frost on his beer mug.</context>
      <utterance>Stands up. Says, Jesson's gone. Walks out of the house. Grief too big for walls to hold it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So Dennis is forbidden the sea. But being free, Newfie, and 21, he goes anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's enough t...?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A week.</context>
      <utterance>Death storm. Monster wave cracks her steel hull amidships, one inch crack from starboard to port. Men go in the water. Dennis lost. After a week...</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They come to Jack, call off the search. He stands like a stone. Then turns, sharp, the way he does. Says only, 'He's alive. And I know where.'</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man's a witch.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leans. Close.</context>
      <utterance>Went to sea, alone, in just a skiff. Finds him. Can you guess the odds? Finds him. Finds him. Both arms broke, 99% dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy comes to. Jack says if you ever</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle glances over. Dennis wobbling his way back through the tables.</context>
      <utterance>step in a boat again, I'll drown ya m'self. And you know what the kid said...?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say it fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They never spoke ag...</context>
      <utterance>Says fishin' licenses are all spoken for, I'd appreciate you givin' me yours. Jack looked in his eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's bein' blabbed here? NUTBEEM  Quoyle says you got a nice ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises his beer.</context>
      <utterance>Quoyle's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To my ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And, by God. They do.</context>
      <utterance>I'll drink to that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle freezes. She means, of course, the blankly-staring boy.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. HERRY smiles at Bunny. Suddenly, wonderfully. BUNNY (to Herry) Know how to be a dog? She DROPS to all fours and starts YAPPING like a terrier. Herry LAUGHS with delight. Tumbles down to the grass and does his impression of a Chihuahua on speed. BUNNY (to the woman) He looks fast to me. Maybe he's cured.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, how 'bout we ask what's wrong with you? There's nothing wr... WOMAN  Sure, there is. This is Herry, and he has Down's Syndrome. It means he learns things very slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids waddle off in their canine personas. Alone with the woman now, Quoyle is near-catatonic. Come on, brain!</context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman looks at him. Clear cornflower eyes. As comfortable in silence as he is agonized. Then, she squints out at the other women, desperately running ragged after the kids.</context>
      <utterance>Which one of those women is in charge here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh.</context>
      <utterance>Neither of 'em. They're just moms.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks back at him, blankly.</context>
      <utterance>Well, my lord, whoever runs the place should be giving this a little more attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The woman's eyes bottomless, unreadable. The silence excruciating for poor Quoyle. He clears his throat.</context>
      <utterance>I mean, children need structure. No one's even guarding that craft table, they could be running around with scissors and get hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she stands. The grace and quickness of a jungle cat.</context>
      <utterance>Um. I write for the newspa...</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Brushes off her skirt. He is in the dawning panic of beginning to realize...</context>
      <utterance>Well. I'd better get to work, I see. Providing structure and all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Heads off with a loose-limbed stride. Spins back around...</context>
      <utterance>I'm Wavey Prowse, and this is my place. Pardon our antiquated emphasis on individuality and the freedom to have fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Got it? He gawks like a stupid animal. Nods, got it. She's already gone.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeh. Running with sharp objects? We save for Tuesdays.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. Quoyle nods, blandly. As if it is a matter of no real concern</context>
      <utterance>Well, she don't wear a ring, cause she lost her husband at sea. Just after the boy was born.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I was just...</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...sharpenin' those observation skills. First tool of a quality reporter.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep walking.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She has wonderful. Posture. BILLY  Yer know, I never notic...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MELVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle looks to the sour-faced middle-aged lady, who glances disdainfully at us above her gimlet. SILVER MELVILLE used to be pretty and rich. She's still rich. QUOYLE (politely) No sir, your wife is very lovl...</context>
      <utterance>Ever seen anything like her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. Billy keeps a straight face. Silver ROLLS her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I mean. The ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was built for Hitler. You've heard of Hitler? Up here in Canada?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silver snorts a laugh. Melville wonders if that was irony. Looking at Quoyle, he doubts that's possible.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yessir. He was in all the papers. Way back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finest botterjacht ever built in Holland. Flat-bottomed, she can go right up on shore in a storm. Incredibly heavy, forty tons of oak. Not unlike the barges of Henry VIII and Elizabeth I. BILLY  We heard a them, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell them what happened. In</utterance>
   <speaker>SILVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at his wife. Clear in a glance they hate each other's guts. Go on, she nods. Tell it.</context>
      <utterance>Hurricane Bob.</utterance>
   <speaker>MELVILLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Expensive ones. To rubble.</context>
      <utterance>Pounded twelve beach houses.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SILVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Now tell them. Who let our insurance lapse.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She winks.</context>
      <utterance>Took six very expensive lawyers to weasel us out of it. An inch from bankruptcy.</utterance>
   <speaker>SILVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And holds out her glass. Billy looks out to sea. Like he hasn't heard this. QUOYLE (cheerful) So. What brings you folks up from Long Island? A beat. While husband and wife glare at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Moral of the story? When you marry a tour guide. Confine his authority to mixing the drinks. Same again, dear?</utterance>
   <speaker>SILVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to Quoyle. Who just gapes at her. Open-mouthed. QUOYLE (softly) Oh. My. God.</context>
      <utterance>My dining salon needs refitting. And the best custom yacht upholsterer in the Northern Hemisphere just moved here. I was forced. To follow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>You are a woman of mystery, Aunt. Mystery and surprise. AGNIS  Silver Melville says you was out there. Be nice in yer story, she's payin' for a piece of this house.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said upholstery. Never said yacht uphol...</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks up. Sees he's dazzled by how she moves right along.</context>
      <utterance>...never said not. Ask better questions, you got a chance fer better answers. Got my shop set up in Killick-Claw, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She winks.</context>
      <utterance>Two good workers. Mrs. Mavis Bangs is an old plow horse like m'self. But Dawn...</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He absorbs that. How fast can he change the subject?</context>
      <utterance>Dawn's young and on the sexy side. You oughta drop by and say hullo.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agnis looks at him. Reaches for the Bushmill's.</context>
      <utterance>Where's Bunny?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Upstairs, in what will soon become her room. She'll be all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pours some whiskey into her tea cup.</context>
      <utterance>What does that mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little early in the day f...</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drinks the whiskey. Stares straight in his eyes. Sees his sorrow. The honesty in...</context>
      <utterance>Warren died today. That's what that means.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agnis deciding. Whether to tell him...</context>
      <utterance>Poor old girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle shocked. What can he say? His empathy so naked, so real, even Agnis has to soften her voice...</context>
      <utterance>I used to live with someone named Warren. Died of cancer, after nine years together. Dearest soul on this earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Went from the funeral, and bought that dog. Named her Warren. Just so I could say the name a hunnerd times a day. Women are foolish, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A good moment for them. It holds a beat.</context>
      <utterance>I never thought so.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle nods. Rises slowly. He'd better go to her.</context>
      <utterance>Bunny wants to bury the dog with me. But I told her I'd rather do it alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another sip.</context>
      <utterance>Some advice about the child?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't get down on her level, the way you do. She'll never respect you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He knows what she means. Strokes her hair.</context>
      <utterance>That's the difference.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Another necklace, huh? Can I help?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Okay. He looks at the Barbies.</context>
      <utterance>You can watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up at him. Straight to his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Do I have to take my clothes off?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goes back to work. He watches her.</context>
      <utterance>You look better with 'em on.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know. You do look good in blue.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That extra beat before she says...</context>
      <utterance>Give you folks a lift?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doesn't smile. Doesn't look angry either. Just comfortable.</context>
      <utterance>We're enjoyin' the walk, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. My aunt can't bring Bunny to the daycare, she's got her shop now. But I worked it out with my boss. So I'll be bringin' her come next week.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No reaction.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If that's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now she smiles. One-tenth power. Still a dazzler.</context>
      <utterance>Love to have her. I'm sorry, Mr. Quoyle, about the other time. Women can be moody, you know. And temperamental.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Did she like that? Hard to tell. She looks around him...</context>
      <utterance>Only the best ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves, will do. She takes Herry's hand, starts off down the road. Quoyle sits and watches.</context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon, Dennis. Give our respects to Beety and Marty.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle looks over. His pal shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>Excellent posture.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can't help but snort out a chuckle of his own. Sneaks a look over at her, and she... ...laughs out loud. Healthy. Sexy, even. But from the delay, he guesses...</context>
      <utterance>The Newfie looks around. Still nobody. Hollers, WHO ARE YA? THE VOICE O' GOD? Voice comes back, NO! THE ARENA MANAGER!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks over at him. Her eyes dance a little.</context>
      <utterance>Heard it before, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he is lost in those eyes. Knows it's showing. Glances away to where... ...Bunny sits in a corner. Reading to a rapt Herry.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes, passion in performance. Beats the element of surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys hungry?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just like I did Warren.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh. I'm teaching Herry to read.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bunny looks over at him. He is so dumb.</context>
      <utterance>Is he learnin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Herry nods. Later. And out of the blue...</context>
      <utterance>First is the teaching part. The learning comes later.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle looks over to the woman. But instead of Wavey, he sees PETAL, staring at him with slow predatory heat.</context>
      <utterance>Wavey? Now are the berries ready to pick?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then, once more she is...</context>
      <utterance>Want to pick my berries, do you. Should I climb right up on this sink?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle. Takes note.</context>
      <utterance>Almost. Almost ready. You know, it's all about timing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's yer boat.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Said it was.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uh-oh. He looks from one face to another. Even Billy is irritated. Nutbeem gazes down, embarrassed for him.</context>
      <utterance>One question remains. Why. Is that. Yer boat?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. A boat's a boa...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle can't believe this. Hot shame burns.</context>
      <utterance>It's a shit boat. Best thing, get rid of it some dark night.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And standing in the doorway, the scariest sight of all. The boss. Just shaking his head. JACK (sadly)</context>
      <utterance>Go hire Alvin Yark to build ya a sweet little rodney. This thing's a wallowing cockeyed bastard that'll sink in a bathtub.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The word from Sinai on Quoyle's worth. A pity.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have the sense God gave a doughnut, do ya?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out the door with a SLAMM! Quoyle stares hopelessly after him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm goin' fishin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't jump off a bridge over it. Anyone can make a brainless, asinine, devastatingly revealing blunder. QUOYLE  Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Holds up some sheets of paper. Photos of the Melvilles' botterjacht. Reads...</context>
      <utterance>What in th' furry pit of Newfie hell. Is this!?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hitler's Barge...?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Profile of a vessel in port.</context>
      <utterance>That goes with the shipping news.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the car accident?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Card still reading.</context>
      <utterance>That's the one I didn't do. Mrs. Diddolate sprained her wrist. Period.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>So you didn't do the one Jack told yer to do, and you did one he don't know yer did!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pretty mu...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This copy. Is worse. Than yer boat. He looks up. Equal parts disgust and delight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Strides off for the door. Turns back...</context>
      <utterance>Run it.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out the door. SLAMM harder than Jack's.</context>
      <utterance>As for the part about you havin' half a mind? No comment.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nodding, in time to the hammer strokes.</context>
      <utterance>Jack, I completely understand, I would fire me, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hammers LOUDER, speaking in rhythm...</context>
      <utterance>In a heartbeat.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stops.</context>
      <utterance>You give me a chance, and what happens? I buy the wrong boat, I write the wrong story, I am the lowest form of alleged life. In fact, your comment...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sets them down. Stands UP on the steep pitch. QUOYLE (shocked stupid) Baby...</context>
      <utterance>Egg salad and Nehi grape.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the plate and bottle slip neatly OFF the roof and, after a noticeable beat, shatter softly far below. Bunny's turn to be shocked. She's contemplating going after them.</context>
      <utterance>They're mine but I'll share.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Closer, reaching toward her back...</context>
      <utterance>And if you don't move. Until I get there. Then...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...GRABS her arm, she STARTLES, violently LURCHING, but he YANKS her to him. Holds her to his heart. Holds her. He is breathing like a freight train.</context>
      <utterance>...then you win!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That. Was so easy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did ya see the Hitler's barge piece, Jocko?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle turns. Pretty much all his possessions are in a big cardboard box. Jack peers into it.</context>
      <utterance>I saw it. And heard from some who'd done the same.  Good. Neatness.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he's smiling. Like he's got the point.</context>
      <utterance>Reorganize. Start over. Good thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thing about the barge piece? I just thought it'd perk up th...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grasps Quoyle around the back of the neck.</context>
      <utterance>Got six phone calls 'bout that piece. Six. That'd be like half a million calls in Toronto.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle stares, slack-faced into the elfin eyes...</context>
      <utterance>People liked it, old son. Crowd went down to the dock t'see the thing, but it'd already pulled out.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just now, Card's jaw is scraping his boot tops.</context>
      <utterance>Course you don't know anything about boats, but that's entertaining, too. So go ahead with it. That's the kinda stuff I want, see?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From now on, you write a column every week. The Shipping News. Gonna order you a computer and everything. And y'know the beauty part...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quoyle doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have to tell Card all over again, cause he's already eavesdroppin'. So I'm free to take m'leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goin' fishin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wink. He heads toward the door. And never looking at him...</context>
      <utterance>Ah. You've an instinct for character and idiosyncrasy, old son.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Card looks down. He zips up, as the door slams. Billy Pretty sends Quoyle a thumbs-up, without turning. Nutbeem clasps his hands above his head, like a winning prizefighter. Quoyle slides a sheet of paper into his typewriter. Stares at it.</context>
      <utterance>Zip yer fly, Card.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thirty-eight years. First time anybody said you done it right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mavis holds out a hearty hand. Agnis is showing him the shop. A cutting table, two sewing stations. Billowing sailcloth hung over the windows. Racks of leathers and fabrics.</context>
      <utterance>Nephew, this is Mavis Bangs. A real professional.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dawn, once described by Agnis as young and on the sexy side, is that. Red lipstick and nails. Her eyes float up in a way that suggests reflexive sensuality. Agnis nods to her, and the girl reaches a slender pale hand...</context>
      <utterance>And this is Dawn Budgel. She's a vegetarian.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agnis is always saying such...things about you. It's nice to fit a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as she releases his hand, her eyes flick to Agnis. Some conspiracy there. Quoyle follows his aunt back to the big cutting table.</context>
      <utterance>With the name.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just, uh, came to see if you'd heard abou..</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shows him sheets of baby blue leather.</context>
      <utterance>Silver Melville? Snuck off in the night, they did. Not a penny paid for all we done.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Points to them. A neat row by the makeshift kitchenette.</context>
      <utterance>We'd installed the banquettes in her salon. Three of the chairs done and delivered, three to go...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Agnis is thinking...</context>
      <utterance>That's. That's just terrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as he glances off, he sees Dawn across the way. Her skirt hiked up, as if she were adjusting a stocking. She isn't wearing any.</context>
      <utterance>Strange. Leavin' the chairs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you understand that?</context>
      <utterance>In New York. They said she had a... personality disorder. WAVEY  And it was named Petal.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All these hallucin...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The necklaces, yeh. A thought that frightens him.</context>
      <utterance>The White Dog. Sometimes with the Skinny Ghost. Kids do things like that, it's called imagination. Like the necklaces.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She does.</context>
      <utterance>You know how many she makes?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her kind smile. No big deal.</context>
      <utterance>It's a skill, she's proud of it. And she brings her dolls along. And she looks good in blue. And she wears a key for a good luck charm.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wavey's slow nod.</context>
      <utterance>And she's saving her mother a room. Did she tell you that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how kids think. You have all those books.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That was naked. He swallows.</context>
      <utterance>The ones I read to teach Herry. They don't make me an exp... QUOYLE  Just. Is she okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Too serious a subject. Too good a woman. For an easy lie.</context>
      <utterance>I mean. If you had to guess..</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She swallows, too. Her eyes are damp.</context>
      <utterance>That child is the only friend my son ever had. So she's strange, you bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hold the look.</context>
      <utterance>I love that little girl. And I will see to it. That she's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I don't have to guess about it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods, dumbly. Of course. Okay.</context>
      <utterance>I want us. To be friends, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And friends. Need. To understand each other. QUOYLE  I understand. Believe m...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hard for her. He quiets.</context>
      <utterance>My husband drowned. Herry was...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you understand?</context>
      <utterance>He was two months old. And Herold took the boat out. Overnight. To fish for haddock.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence.</context>
      <utterance>Because I liked. Haddock.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>It's four years.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No smile.</context>
      <utterance>And it's yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Quoyle nods, sure. I'll be your friend. But what she sees is a lifetime of being Quoyle washing past his eyes. It makes her murmur...</context>
      <utterance>Now, did I blow it. Or can you still be my friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And from his heart...</context>
      <utterance>What? What are you thinking?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands up. HEAR him stumble off. HOLD on her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking I'm sorry. For everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How're you doin' with the Tall and Quiet Woman?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cindy Crawford and me is doin' fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh.</context>
      <utterance>I meant Wavey Prowse.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dad used to say there's four women in every man's life. The Stouthearted Woman...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the Maid in the Meadow... QUOYLE  Bunny I guess. Weavin' a daisy-chain necklace.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the Tall and Quiet Woman...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. She does have that posture goin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On this. Quoyle's smile fades. He looks away. They've reached a fence where blunt pickets enclose crosses and wooden markers, many fallen on the ground. BILLY (wistful) Me dad said that. Billy finds the right marker. Sets his satchel onto the grass. Kneels. His old fingers clear debris from painted words:</context>
      <utterance>...and the Demon Lover.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hears the thread of feeling in his simple words. And says no more. Withdraws two cans of paint from his bag. One white, one black. Two brushes. Lays them out carefully, for this task is sacred.</context>
      <utterance>That's me poor father. Thirteen I was when he died.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pries the lid off the tin of black. And when he sees Quoyle's eyes...</context>
      <utterance>Every time I wonder. Is this the last coat?</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An easy smile. Stating the obvious.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there's no one else to do it, y'see. QUOYLE  There is now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As if that were enough.</context>
      <utterance>Well, you said. There's no one else.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy stares at him. Stares at him. Clears his throat, gruffly.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. If you wanna rest next to him. I'll paint yours at the same time. No extra trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then better get Alvin Yark. T'build yer a real boat. So yer'll be around.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle thinks better of his answer. Chomps a bite instead.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know none a that impresses Jack Buggit. He's not one fer blatant ambition.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...takes his hand from his greasy burger. Scratches his crotch below the table.</context>
      <utterance>Even if you don't recognize 'Human Head Packed in Satchel' as the most compelling piece ever to appear in... CARD  Even if.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And winks at the silent hero.</context>
      <utterance>A triple increase in ad revenue. Does get. The man's attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weren't even double if yer figger it right.  Point is. A real reporter woulda</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>named the obvious suspect.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More obvious. Than the wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yer aunt, ya thick Statie lardface dumbass! Quoyle. And Nutbeem. Just look at each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She gets stiffed by the guy, after basin' her new shop on that revenue. And she ain't one ta fool with. Capable a anything, that woman! QUOYLE  Okay, where's the wife? Agnis kill her too?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle viciously BITES into his squidburger.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, where's this week's shipping news? Or you gonna rest on yer Crisco-coated laurels.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Card blinks. Looks at Quoyle with, dare we say, new respect.</context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh. The way he's chewin', he ain't a fat boy t'be trifled with! NUTBEEM  His piece. Is about oil tankers.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Scratches his crotch savagely. To honor civilization.</context>
      <utterance>Hope fer ya yet. Now that's news, the McGonigle oil field. Petrodollars, a golden flood a jobs. That's th'future a this god-forsaken ice rock. Civilization!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Puts his squidburger. Where his mouth is. Nutbeem clarifies for Quoyle...</context>
      <utterance>That's why those with half a brain already put our money where our mouths is!</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two shares. Of Mobil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL BACK to see Wavey now. Curled on the sofa, under a lap robe. She is knitting something in a heavy oxblood-colored wool. He watches her work. WAVEY (softly) That'd be old Nolan. He's actually your uncle, last of the crazy Quoyles. I should have realized. Keeps her eyes on her work.</context>
      <utterance>...so there they were, this goofy old codger and his dog, big as life.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sad, really. Lives like a hermit in a run-down shack. No one to look after h...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A silence. Which makes him uneasy.</context>
      <utterance>Here I was worried about Bunny night and day, and there's absolutely nothing wrong with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She meant to reassure him. Instead...</context>
      <utterance>Her only problem is her dad worries too mu... WAVEY  You are a loving and wonderful father. You're not the problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what is th...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks up with smoky eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Nice to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh.</context>
      <utterance>...after all this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle's smile tries to sell the innocence of his absence. WAVEY (very quiet) I thought you forgot. That I'm your friend, too. No smile from her. She wants him to know she was hurt. He shakes his head, serious now. No, I didn't forget.</context>
      <utterance>Well. I've been workin' longer hours. So Dennis and Beety were kind enough to bring Bunny to the daycare. Fed her a lotta meals, too. They're real friends.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up what's left of his four-decker. This is plenty. Takes a huge bite to show how much he likes it.</context>
      <utterance>You want another sandwich? There's roast pork.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He did, he nods. But just now he's scared to. And so she smiles. Which traps him. He pulls out a single sheet of paper. Clears his throat.</context>
      <utterance>You said. You'd read me your article.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. Likes that. He gestures, go back to your knitting. So she smiles, slyly. And commences to knit. QUOYLE (reads) There's a 1904 photo hung in the library. Eight schooners heading out to fishing grounds, sails spread it like white wings. Beautiful. Beyond compare. This means something to him. Hear it in his voice.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody Hangs a Picture of an Oil Tanker. That's the header.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More common today is the low black profile of oil tankers. Like the ruptured Golden Goose, which last week bled 14,000 tons of crude onto seabirds, fish and boats at Cape Despond. He stops. As if revisiting that little thought in his mind. QUOYLE (reads) There will be more and more tankers. They will grow old and corroded, and their tanks will split. They have already done to fishing. What their spill has done to fish. He sneaks a glance. She has never looked up. QUOYLE (reads) Nobody hangs a picture of an oil tanker. On their wall. Silence. A full one.</context>
      <utterance>QUOYLE</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She reflects.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Whatcha think?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think when Card sees it, he'll split a gut. I think he'll sit up nights thinking of cheap shots to pay you back. I think he'll never stop until you're fired. Quoyle keeps nodding at each point. Yep. Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle's heart explodes in his chest. And shines in his eyes. There is a long silence. WAVEY (softly) Maybe another sandwich. There's roast pork. He swallows. He just doesn't want to cry from happiness.</context>
      <utterance>I think I haven't been so proud. Of a friend. Since I don't know when.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hush. A frozen tableau in this room.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'll run it. Just easier t'copy edit. When yer can move th'pieces around.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Run it. Like I wrote it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slides the battered camera across the desk. They glare at each other a full beat. Card belches, softly. Quoyle takes the camera, heads for the door...</context>
      <utterance>How does this suit yer, Quoyle? I'll do my job. You do yers, which means a four-vehicle pile-up south a Killick-Claw. And don't ferget the camera.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle turns. Card doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>I fergot somethin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thinks.</context>
      <utterance>You pinko Greepeace sack a quivering pigfat.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>HOLD on him. Making a neat little pile of the torn pieces.</context>
      <utterance>Did I leave out moosebutt-ugly?  You may go.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>SLAMM! Across the room, Nutbeem stands. Takes his cigarettes. Passing Card's desk, on the way out...</context>
      <utterance>Like I wrote it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLAMM! Card shoots Billy a challenging look. You got something to say?</context>
      <utterance>Tough love. Impressive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you.</context>
      <utterance>I hope you get him fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just turns around. Flicks ON his computer. Back to work.</context>
      <utterance>So I can watch him beat yer to jelly.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He looks up. She is pushing the front door with one finger. It swings OPEN.</context>
      <utterance>Why'd you leave the house open?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...and lifts a long piece of TWINE. There are KNOTS neatly tied along its length. Quoyle stares. Stares. QUOYLE (calm) Sweetie. Come sit in the car.</context>
      <utterance>Can I keep the necklace?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A photo of the same tanker. That hangs on Card's wall. QUOYLE (reads) More than 3000 tankers proudly ride the world's seas. Even the biggest take advantage of Newfoundland's deep- water ports and refineries.</context>
      <utterance>Yer column's front page stuff. Only now, it's more like a caption, is all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Spelled everthin' perfect. So as not t'embarrass yer. QUOYLE  Oil and Newfoundland go together like ham and eggs, and like ham and eggs they'll nourish us in the coming years.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stares at the paper. In his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Even put yer name on it. QUOYLE  Let's all hang a picture of an oil tanker. On our wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle looks up. Card flinches back. But all that comes is...</context>
      <utterance>Man a yer principles. I unnerstan' resignation is th'only honorable course.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drops the paper on the floor. Steps on it, on his way toward the door.</context>
      <utterance>How can a man resign. To nobody?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle turns back.</context>
      <utterance>If yer off to see Jack Buggit, yer'll hafta swim some.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yer can whine an' beg t'him. But I</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A wink.</context>
      <utterance>runs his paper, every inch of it, every dirty time-eatin' job which he would have t'do without me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cackle of the guy holding the straight flush.</context>
      <utterance>An' if yer think he's gonna choose you over fishin'...yer not as smart as even you look!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle puts his hand on the door.</context>
      <utterance>Me an' Jack. Has a sym-bi-otic relationship. Yer can look that up.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out the door. It closes behind him. Card alone, crosses his arms in glee...</context>
      <utterance>I know the word, Card. It means you two deserve each other.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's looking straight in Quoyle's eyes. Defiant as ever.</context>
      <utterance>So. This is what Jack and I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We wanna run Quoyle's oil spill piece b'cause controversy sells papers and papers sells ads.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lives to needle this guy. Card keeps his laser gaze on Quoyle.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds reasonable to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And we're gonna let Quoyle have his head on these columns, up to 500 words. So he'll get his confidence up.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, let's not go overboard. He's rather green doncha thi...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we wanna expand his responsi- bilities to boat crashes. There's maybe four a week.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll need a raise. And need to be represented in the negotia...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nutbeem's eyes WIDEN. He mimes catching an arrow shot through his chest. Falls OFF the desk. CARD (to Quoyle) All that clear? Quoyle looks him in the eyes. Starts putting his things back in his desk.</context>
      <utterance>And. The oil tanker picture. Stays!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One more thing... Hear the SLAMM! QUOYLE  Jack's gone fishing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>No way in past the pounding surf, the savage rocks. So Quoyle turns sharply. Squints across the bay.</context>
      <utterance>Headline. Reporter Becomes Magnet For Dead Men.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CLIMBS into his boat, TURNS the engine over. KICKS it in overdrive toward the town across the bay.</context>
      <utterance>What was my panic? He was already dead. Maybe I thought, in some dim way...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>STREAKING out, toward the black sky. Racing to open sea where the chop INCREASES drastically. Closer. Closer...</context>
      <utterance>...if it wasn't too late for him. It wouldn't be for Petal.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>...clear of the point's protection, the wind ROCKS the tiny craft, swells coming BROADSIDE. The boat RISES, then DROPS with cruel speed. Quoyle tries to swing the boat around, the propeller RACES, the bow PITCHES violently, SLAMMING down, the stern SWAMPED, the hull filling, swerving broadside just as the oncoming sea HITS with all its force, and the little boat... ...rolls OVER, Quoyle suddenly FLYING under water, limbs flailing in all directions...</context>
      <utterance>Once I was past the shelter of the lee shore, and into the real wind. I realized my mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>INTERCUT...Quoyle's dad FLINGING him into the public pool, the youngster SINKING like an anvil in a profusion of bubbles, and</context>
      <utterance>Headline. Reporter Becomes Anchor Man.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Back to the surface, GASPING for air. And then, daintily rowing a small boat, unaffected by the waves, her filmy dress rippling in light breeze...</context>
      <utterance>Stupid. Stupid to drown with Bunny so young. No life jacket, no floating oar. No sense.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is the lilting smile cruel? Or only the irony that conveys intimacy, even affection.</context>
      <utterance>Look, it floats. Just like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And VANISHES. In her place, bobs a red BOX. A plastic beer cooler. He LUNGES for it, GRIPPING the handles, resting his chest on its top. The waves RISE, mountainous now, and he rises and falls with them. He has been swept a mile from the nearest shore. INTERCUT...a winch pulling part of the Geo, streaming mud, from swiftly flowing water. Police and bystanders gathered.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's filled with fat.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>BACK to the bay. A barely-conscious Quoyle still clings somehow to the plastic cooler. But hours have passed. Light is fading.</context>
      <utterance>And I wondered. Am I going where she's gone?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He turns. And there she is. Beaming at him from the bow of her little rowboat, a smile ambiguous in the growing dusk. It could be love. From behind her a light GLOWS, giving Petal the aspect of an angel. She drops a wink. FADES away. And the light becomes... ...the BEAM from a fishing boat. Quoyle squints his swollen eyes, as strong hands WRENCH him from his box. From the sea. A voice warbles, distorted by wind and Quoyle's diminished consciousness...</context>
      <utterance>...and will I see her?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle's teeth are chattering so hard, his body shivering so</context>
      <utterance>Jesus Cockadoodle Christ! I knowed somebody was out here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle burrows into the fish, like nestling in a down comforter. Jack covers him with a heavy tarp. Crouches down close...</context>
      <utterance>Thank god fer yer figure, me old son. A thin man woulda froze.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Yer lost th'boat.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now he sees the cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>Actually. It's just my bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now he sees the smile.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, it's not. I just wanted to see your eyes bug out like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice was a croak. So he CLEARS his throat with a massive and disgusting effort. It is gross and funny, and she smiles again.</context>
      <utterance>You don't smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rolls over, to see her better. They are very close.</context>
      <utterance>Only when I'm worried. I don't worry much.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'm in heaven.</context>
      <utterance>You don't have to, I'm all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. As he draws a breath to ask...</context>
      <utterance>I'm not worried. About you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Buggit called, knew Bunny was still with me. The kids are camped out in the parlor.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A longer one.</context>
      <utterance>Nice. You sittin' up with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. He will.</context>
      <utterance>S'okay. Someday you'll do somethin' nice for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who you worried ab...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ah. He nods. Well, that figures.</context>
      <utterance>You didn't find a second dead man. Just the rest of the first one.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On this, she stubs out her cigarette. Takes another from the pack.</context>
      <utterance>I asked. Who you worried about?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>You said Bunny talks to Petal at night. You ever listen?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really. Wouldn't be right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>STRIKES a match.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm not that nice a person.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She plays Petal. Talks to the Barbies, like Petal talking to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brings her cigarette. To the flame.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And.</context>
      <utterance>She says she's sorry she left them. It was just to see if they could be good girls. And they were...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes at once rapt and suffering. She watches that.</context>
      <utterance>...and she loves them.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Draws on her smoke.</context>
      <utterance>The Barbies look better naked, Bunny looks good in blue, guess who said that?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you understand?</context>
      <utterance>So we talked. Just before Petal left her with that...stranger? Bunny had snapped her mom's bead necklace. That's why she's making more.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tears are pooling in his eyes. Hers, too. She keeps going...</context>
      <utterance>When she's made enough. She'll be forgiven.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A thin stream of air escapes from his lips.</context>
      <utterance>She saves Petal a room at the house, but she's also got the key to the old place. In case her mom would rather go there.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And she talked about it. Just like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bitter smile.</context>
      <utterance>Sure, I lied. I said nice things about her mother.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Petal isn't gone.</context>
      <utterance>See, there's only one problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quoyle thinking. Madly. What can he do?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares back. Unease to match his own. Maybe time.</context>
      <utterance>So we're patient. And we wait, and we're good to her.  And. Maybe. Time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone smiles. Except the guru.</context>
      <utterance>Well, hurry up. Thirty, forty years I'll be rarin' to get back out on the water.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone looks. Except the guru.</context>
      <utterance>Gotta build her solid. Who knows, mebbe Jack Buggit'll give his fishin' license to his boy. So next time, won't be nobody to pull yer out. DENNIS  Jack Buggit's boy is drowned.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>ALVIN  Dennis. Y'hear the one about the Newfie who lived ferever?</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now he turns. A maritime Yoda, squinting to discern if his message is received.</context>
      <utterance>His kid never got a fishin' license.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs his hand along the backbone of the boat he's building.</context>
      <utterance>What we wait fer? She's like the main stem. Gives us our shape, doncha see.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crinkly old eyes, laser bright. Dennis isn't angry. Just resolved.</context>
      <utterance>Death's one shape. Fergiveness is another.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No smile, no spin. Just the truth.</context>
      <utterance>Thing 'bout waitin' on fergiveness? Mixes up who's waitin' on who.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the silence. A door opens.</context>
      <utterance>Death is simpler. An' a lot shorter wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. YARK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A sprightly bird-like woman. Wears apology and concern.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Quoyle...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. YARK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The school is callin'? It's about yer daughter?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...not only pushed Mrs. Lumball. Not</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Seated in a semi-circle around the desk of power. Quoyle, stricken, respectful. Wavey, already pissed off at the principal. And Bunny,her hat and coat on, arms folded, face crimson and set.</context>
      <utterance>only pushed her very hard...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Do you understand the severity of this, Mr. Quoyle?</context>
      <utterance>She knocked. Her down.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is that right, young lady?</context>
      <utterance>And. Refuses to explain her act. Or. Apologize.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bunny looks down. Glaring an evil spell of death at her own kneecaps. WAVEY (quietly) I think Bunny and I. Should take a walk. And stands.</context>
      <utterance>Under the circumstances. We have no choice but to suspend.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh. Wavey? If it's all the same to you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Apparently, that hasn't happened yet. More walking.</context>
      <utterance>When you gonna ask? QUOYLE  When you're in the mood.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Said like he means it. Which he does. And Bunny, squinting up, sees that. INTERCUT...the crime. Playground filled with kids. Bunny and girlfriends on the jungle gym. Bunny the best, a natural jock. MRS. LUMBULL large, sour, doughy, and betrayed by life, stands with her silver whistle in the midst of chaos. Her thoughts on a higher</context>
      <utterance>She musta done something. Really bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>plane.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Little Herry Prowse comes to tug at the teacher's wool coat. He is holding his crotch and jumping up and down. This does not require an advanced credential to interpret.</context>
      <utterance>She's the worst one of all!</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mrs. Lumbull looks down. From her face as she responds, she has already devoted, over time, more professional attention to this troublemaker than should be asked of any dedicated educator.</context>
      <utterance>Herry told her he had to pee. But the way he talks. He could just say 'eeee,' like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Herry, seemingly, disagrees. Still holding his crotch, he jumps up and down with greater agitation. She grabs him, rather roughly, by the arm. Marches him over to...</context>
      <utterance>She told him that recess was almost over, an' she wasn't gonna make a trip special, an' he could hold it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>...and walks off, pointedly ignoring him from ten feet away. He screams, pumping his fists in frustration. Grabs himself, suddenly. Whether or not we can see the dampness spread, we can see his humiliation all too clearly. As his tears come... ...a figure BOLTS into frame from behind Mrs. Lumbull. Hunched over like a linebacker, full speed ahead, LAUNCHING herself into the back of the large woman's knees. Her feet go UP, and the rest of her goes... ...DOWN like the proverbial amount of bricks. Herry's tears stop fast. Watching the woman shriek, and keep shrieking. Makes him laugh. CUT... BACK TO...the berry path. They are sitting on a fallen log.</context>
      <utterance>She made him stand against the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, a good dad would say hitting is always wrong. You coulda hurt her bad. I guess you know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle pulls out a single Snickers bar.</context>
      <utterance>She wasn't hurt for real. Just screamed like a baby.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wish I'd seen it. It really sounds funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her. Nods, probably will. Peels the candy bar free of its wrapper.</context>
      <utterance>Petal'll think so, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there won't be any trouble at school. I'II take care of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He breaks the candy bar in half. Tho not quite equally.</context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because the best thing about people. Is they can forgive each other. I heard that this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. Oh, yeh.</context>
      <utterance>That teacher. Is gonna forgive me?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh.</context>
      <utterance>That. And she won't want the story printed in the paper.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. I don't wanna forgive her.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out the two pieces of candy. She takes them both. the bigger one in his mouth. As he chews...</context>
      <utterance>Me neither.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nibbles at her own piece.</context>
      <utterance>I had to do it. 'Cept for Wavey, I'm the only family Herry's got.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hmmn?</context>
      <utterance>Like the ghost. Who's not a ghost.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The one who ties the knots? You're</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right? Her father doesn't react. He's even stopped chewing.</context>
      <utterance>the only family he's got.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And slowly. Quoyle nods. I said.</context>
      <utterance>You said.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nolan is listening. Sharp-eared, sharp-eyed. What trick is this? So Quoyle sets the carton down in the squalor. Takes out a loaf of fresh bread. One step forward. Lay it down. Good faith offering. And... ...Nolan scuttles to it. Like a wary crab. He tears off a chunk of bread. Nibbles. He likes it. And as he eats... QUOYLE (softly) You tied those knots, huh? At my house? ...crouches down to the old man's size. Almost close enough to touch.</context>
      <utterance>Uncle. My daughter Bunny and I. We got you some hot bread. And some meat. Some dried fish. Some squash and vegetables...a cake...some warm clothes...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's found the meat. Ripped off a chunk.</context>
      <utterance>Ain't yer house, it's th' Ouoyle house!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, I am Qu...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stuffs some into his face. Like this, even better.</context>
      <utterance>Old ones. Got run outta Omaloor Bay a hunnerd years ago. Dragged that house across th' ice. On spruce runners.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She.</context>
      <utterance>Hadda lash it to th' rock. She'll tell yer.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And as Quoyle draws a breath to ask...</context>
      <utterance>Course she never come t'see me. That's obvious why.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment. Of stone silence.</context>
      <utterance>Your Aunt Agnis Hamm, me son. That's cause she can't face me. I knows she killed 'im.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Him.</utterance>
   <speaker>NOLAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>INTERCUT...a tiny frozen pond. Long ago. A girl of 12, rawboned, husky, skating alone. We've seen her, in the photo at Quoyle's dad's house. And as she skates, she looks up to see... ...a boy of 15, stocky, sullen. He was in the same photo. Only now, he steps onto the ice. Unbuttons his pants. Begins to slide toward her on the soles of his fishing boots. She looks around. Snow banked on all sides of the pond. Nowhere to run on her skates.</context>
      <utterance>That baby she was carryin'. What was she t'do? She wuz only 12. An' it was her own brother what done 'er. Quoyle's wide-eyed shock. QUOYLE  Her own...</utterance>
   <speaker>NOLAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her brother, me son. She only had th' one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He was staring pretty intently. Realizes that.</context>
      <utterance>What? My hem crooked? As if I was wearin' a hem.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds his gaze with her own. Is she wondering?</context>
      <utterance>Naw, I just come from seein' your cousin Nolan. Guess I was thinkin' about him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody turns on that one. Mavis cuts her alter ego Agnis a look. Can you believe this slut?</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Quoyle? What do you think of my dress?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She actually looks pretty good in it. Wavey noticing that. Watching Quoyle say...</context>
      <utterance>I wore it just for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Polite banter? Or outright flirting? Hard to tell if it's Wavey or Agnis who disapproves more. Dawn ignores them.</context>
      <utterance>That was more consideration. Than I deserve.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did your aunt tell you about all</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agnis just blinks. Can scarcely believe she heard that.</context>
      <utterance>the money?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agnis told us it came from Macau. AGNIS  Hush yoursel...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...from Silver Melville. And it was more than she expected. And we shipped the chairs off to her. Y' know, the three remaining? A really frozen beat. QUOYLE  Uh. Why would she send you more tha... AGNIS  Do you have enough attention now, young lady?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agnis turns. Sizes him up.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Ma'am, I think so. Mavis echoes Agnis' glare. QUOYLE  Macau, huh? So. That where y'sent th' chairs?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Puts her fingers to her lips. Leans closer, to confide something he is obviously unaware of...</context>
      <utterance>It's flatterin' you showin' me how you've turned into such a competent reporter and all. But even if I remembered where I sent 'em. I couldn't tell ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Professional ethics.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only you. Could do this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And she's not pleased.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She scoops them expertly into a stack.</context>
      <utterance>You fed him. You gave him clothes. You're the first human ever was kind to him...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Serves them to...</context>
      <utterance>Accordingly. You're sick with guilt.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...Quoyle, who nods absently. About the one thing he is sure of. Just now, he's examining the prodigious status of her oxblood knitting. Still attached to the needles, it looks too broad for a muffler. QUOYLE (decides) Horse blanket. WAVEY (ah!) That's what that is! A beat. Another.</context>
      <utterance>You sure you're not a complex guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pushes the flapjacks closer to him, CLANKS down the fork, eat! She's exasperated. Thinks he's wasting his money.</context>
      <utterance>So if y'called around. Musta found somepla... WAVEY  One decent golden age home. It's in St. John's. You can maybe afford it, tho God knows why you should.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't put him there, til I go down to St. John's. See it's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great! Let's not be rash!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And everything. Sorta. Stops.</context>
      <utterance>Come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, the kids could stay with</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A meaningful beat.</context>
      <utterance>Dennis and Beety. Or Agnis, or...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks deep in his eyes. Hard to guess the answer she wants to hear. He clears his throat. Looks down.</context>
      <utterance>Why. Would I. Do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A witheringly sexy smile.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Remember when you said. Someday, I'd do something nice for you? And when he looks to her, she is... PETAL  And this is it.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He blinks. And sees...</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Overnight trip to St. John's. All expenses paid. Petal arches a delicate brow. PETAL  Overnight?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a playful smile. Of her own.</context>
      <utterance>What's wrong with a weekend?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His subtle smile. A guy could get used to this irony stuff.</context>
      <utterance>Now, listen to this for t'morrow. After I sign the papers at the home... She's already grinning. Feels so comfortable. QUOYLE  The answer to your annual outing! Rainbow trout fishing in four ponds. You pay for what you catch. Prizes in the ponds. If it drizzles or gets chilly, heated and lighted building available, right next to the ponds, with soft drinks, candy bars, ice cream and chips!</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or we could sleep in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Both so big.</context>
      <utterance>I just feel so guilty about all your expenses. Two separate rooms.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods. She did.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's my treat. You agreed.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even Quoyle. Has the message. He looks down at his beer, as he thinks about what he should say. Turns the glass in his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Still. Seems like we could figure out. Something.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up. Her eyes are waiting.</context>
      <utterance>A friend told me once. Love is the only thing that counts. He nods. Almost to himself. QUOYLE  It's the engine of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So when you told me how you think about your husband. I really understood, becau...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I wanted us to talk abou...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And everything. Stops.</context>
      <utterance>...because real love. Just comes once.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she's looking in his eyes. And so, she does. WAVEY (just above a whisper) ...is how much you love her. That's what it is.</context>
      <utterance>See, you know some of the stories about Petal. Some of the bad things. What you don't know...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Even tho. She never loved you.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs. The most miserable and the most honest he has ever been. All at once.</context>
      <utterance>Sorta. Because of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes are swimming. Can she possibly hear this?</context>
      <utterance>See, love. Isn't about what's good for you. Isn't about what you wish it was. Isn't about what...would make you happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. The piano plays something gay and stupid.</context>
      <utterance>Love. Is about want. What you really want. And you can't change that. Even if it's poison.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The last word was a tough one. It makes her nod. She stares in his eyes for the longest time. And when she speaks, he can scarely hear her voice...</context>
      <utterance>So that's why it's great. To have a real friend. When you're. Lonely.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But. One word. And even a stupid guy. Gets it all.</context>
      <utterance>I know you have to stay tomorrow. To sign the papers. But.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wow. He nods, dumbly. Watching his worst nightmare unfold before his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I should be heading back. Before Herry. Misses me. Too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets to her feet. She does seem a little unsteady.</context>
      <utterance>And I'm not feeling so well. What I get for mixing vodka and beer, huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So I'll grab a taxi. You stay and finish. Listen to the music. Is</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>that all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he stops. Because she's shaken her head once. Don't.</context>
      <utterance>I cou...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her voice chokes a little on that. She shakes her head, half- grinning at how foolish she feels. She smiles at him now. Like she means it. And leaves. Without another word.</context>
      <utterance>And don't worry. I'm still your friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He wants to cry. He wants to be sick. He doesn't know what he wants. Fumbles in his pocket for some wadded-up bills.</context>
      <utterance>She did stay my friend. In her way. Even tho, for awhile, we didn't see each other a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny. How one little talk. Can change everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Move?</context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it. Just get the aunt's house fixed perfect, and I gotta move.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three hours to drive from the Point, with all the ice. Alvin won't have my boat ready til New Years. Agnis can stay over her shop. Bunny and I have to find a room in town.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A good friend. Quoyle is touched.</context>
      <utterance>Stay with us. My kid follows yours around, they'll bunk t'gether. And we gotta fluffy couch that's more'n you deserve.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wouldn't want that. Very silent at this table. Against the din of the place. Is he serious? NUTBEEM (softly) I'm throwing myself a farewell party on Saturday. Departure to follow Sunday. Regrets, soon after, no doubt. And smiles. Serious as a heart attack. A long beat. QUOYLE (a murmur) Be careful. Careful?</context>
      <utterance>It's two years. My boat's ready. If I stay any longer, I'll begin to like it here.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So much feeling behind his eyes. Nutbeem can only say...</context>
      <utterance>Last friend left me. Turned into a truck driver.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And return the feeling. With his own.</context>
      <utterance>Well. With that warning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SEE it now. Half a sawed-off empty BARREL, with MOLASSES stenciled</context>
      <utterance>What's the barrel for?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>in orange, fills the shower stall.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle sends him a blank look.</context>
      <utterance>I'm British. I bathe.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gestures to thirty bags of potato chips, filling the kitchenette.</context>
      <utterance>Perfect for th' chips.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Soap. And mine.</context>
      <utterance>It's coated with two kinds of scum.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Works. We forgot to buy dip.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nutbeem hands him a beer.</context>
      <utterance>Feeling that and more. What's the situation?</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle looks sadly at the trailer. Realizing it was his place that got trashed. NUTBEEM (laughs) And the boat! Omigod!</context>
      <utterance>One. You're moving in with Dennis, no matter how fond you are of his wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm some disgusted. With the human race.</utterance>
   <speaker>NUTBEEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys look at each other. Humiliated by his generosity.</context>
      <utterance>I'da never made it, anyway. Storms would have blown me to bits. You boys saved my life. Yes, you did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And so, together, they begin to clean a small mountain of cod.</context>
      <utterance>Hands might as well be movin' while we chat. Always hated th' sight a grown men around a table workin' nuthin' but their jaws.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Editorial meetin', y'say. 'Bout what?</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doesn't look up.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Tert Card's gone, fer one thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle will.</context>
      <utterance>Yar, I know, he never said g'bye. Well, don't get all weepy-eyed about it, old son. Try t'be a man.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They called him from St. John's, he tells me. Wants him to help put out th' newsletter fer them oil rig suppliers.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup. Believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was sassy an' he was smug. Oh, there's a waitin' list, he assures me. They only skims th' cream.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, don't get all weepy-eyed abou...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No arguments arise.</context>
      <utterance>Truth t'tell. I was a wee help. B'hind the scenes, doncha know. Keeps working. JACK  Sometimes. Enough is enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Uh-oh. You don't mean...</context>
      <utterance>Well, Billy'll do a helluva job... JACK  ...right where he is. Too old a fish t'swim faster'n be wants. Gotta find someone a little dumber t'take on a shit job like this!</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle swallows. Arguably the proudest moment of his life.</context>
      <utterance>Spot I'm in, Christmas and all. Might have to offer th'mess. To you.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack looks at him for the first time. A real twinkle behind...</context>
      <utterance>Course. I'd need a raise.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Said with such sincerity, Jack can only nod. Good.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know. Yer do have the sense God gave a doughnut. QUOYLE  I'II try to live up to that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any other outrageous demands? Seein' as yer got me over a barrel. Here's your one chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And before he can stop his mouth...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mirth dies in his host's eyes. Like a 60-watt bulb in a brownout. Quoyle swallows the rest.</context>
      <utterance>Well, your son...</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle sucks it up.</context>
      <utterance>You were sayin'...?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jack's eyes. Flat and cold as the cod he's gutting.</context>
      <utterance>His whole life would be changed. If he could come upon. A fishing license.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, there's only one a those issued per family. So how exactly would he do that? This is not. Going well. A dangerous silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>JACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even doughnuts, y'know. Can push their luck.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh. I didn't. Most of these</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even better.</context>
      <utterance>are for Herry.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are on top. Personally wrapped in his slightly bulging, fine-motor-control-challenged, personal style. Be sets them on the counter.</context>
      <utterance>There's two. Are yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meaning, please don't. So she wipes her hands on her apron. Lets him see her eyes dance just a flicker.</context>
      <utterance>You prob'ly want to wait for Christmas.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Delicately unwraps the first. Lifts out a PORCELAIN TEAPOT, finely painted with an assortment of BERRIES. She holds it in her hands, at once admiring and wistful. Wondering if there's a message about their moment together while berry-picking.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm much too excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A simple pronouncement. She opens the second, flat and narrow. It is a TURQUOISE BRACELET. Actually, kind of stunning. She blinks, taken back by the beauty and perhaps the expense.</context>
      <utterance>It's from a museum catalogue. But it's not real. It's a copy. WAVEY  It is my favorite teapot.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't sayanything. Lets it dangle from her fingers, catch the light.</context>
      <utterance>It's nice for your eyes. I thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks to him. Her eyes are shining maybe more than she wants. Her voice perhaps softer than she even intends...</context>
      <utterance>It's for everyday. You don't have to save it for special.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Covers. With only a slightly more than friendly smile.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'll save this, all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I'll think of you. When I</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He can only nod. He'd like that. She holds up one finger, wait a second. And hurries off. So he waits. Looking at her kitchen. Feeling his feelings. She is back, with two boxes. Sets them down. Nods, go ahead... ...one is heavy and square. He opens it to find a LEATHER-BOUND CASE. He looks at her, smiles in his childlike way. Opens the case, which reveals... ...two leather-bound VOLUMES. One a dictionary. The other a thesaurus. He is obviously moved. QUOYLE (a murmur) You must have me mistaken. For a writer. And when he looks up.</context>
      <utterance>put lot on.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her long enough to make her nod toward the other package. Big and flat, but not heavy at all. He lifts the lid, and pulls out... ...a huge comfy SWEATER. In oxblood wool. He is completely stunned to realize... WAVEY (so pleased) Well, you can't be surprised. You've seen me knitting it for months.</context>
      <utterance>I don't make mistakes. About that kind of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Put it on, put it on! So he slips it over his head. Big enough and then some. This worries her. She plucks at it...</context>
      <utterance>It was so big, I thought it was a tea cozy for your car. But if it's for me, it has to be bigger, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. You'll grow into it.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's just beaming. Hugs himself to show how warm it is. The silence is companionable. Then...</context>
      <utterance>You kiddin'? After the holidays, we'll have to stretch it.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not used to a woman. Giving me presents.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She raises a brow. Can scarcely believe that.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds her friendly smile. But her eyes have changed. Slightly.</context>
      <utterance>One Christmas with Petal, I gave her eleven things. And I wrapped them. And watched her open them up.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't have anything for me. Like every year. But this one time, she said, 'Wait a minute.' Wait a minute.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Even his voice. Betrays the longing.</context>
      <utterance>She ran to the kitchen. I heard the fridge open. She came back. With her hands hidden behind her. Then, she held out...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, self-conscious.</context>
      <utterance>Two brown eggs. She gave them to me from her own hands. They were cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. A soft...</context>
      <utterance>Must sound really stupid. But they meant a lot to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. He's glad she understands.</context>
      <utterance>Well. It's the thought that counts.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I broke 'em, careful. Made her an omelette with 'em. And I saved the shells. In a little box. She can't help but show her surprise at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks worried now. Shouldn't have brought this up. And seeing this...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeh. They're on a shelf behind my desk. At the paper.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. But feels truly awkward now. So...</context>
      <utterance>I know how it is. To hold onto something good. In the middle of all the bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right. She nods. She understands this, too.</context>
      <utterance>Well. I gotta collect Bunny. Beety's gonna have supper waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takes her teapot and her bracelet. Holds them. A gentle barrier. Her hands now too full for a hug.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Thank you, very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a wonderful smile.</context>
      <utterance>Well. Merry Christmas!</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With one of her own.</context>
      <utterance>Merry Christmas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friends and neighbors, and most of all, your children. Have</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCIPAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THUNDEROUS applause, whistling, stamping. She is frustrated for a moment. Then, waves cheerily against the din, shouting...</context>
      <utterance>worked hard to bring you the best pageant ever.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She winks. They laugh. Billy laughing loudest.</context>
      <utterance>We all know Billy Pretty's ways. Never save fifty cents, if you can save a dollar.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Twirls the cane recklessly. In the third row, a goggle-eyed Quoyle couldn't blink if he tried.</context>
      <utterance>Well, last Feb'ry, Billy wants t'get his grandfather clock repaired. Calls old Leander Mesher. Local call. No charge.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's right.</context>
      <utterance>Well, says Leander, the big cost is pickup and delivery. Got t'charge fifty dollars, each way. Two strong boys. Gasoline. Air in the tires!</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WAGGLES her eyebrows, Groucho-style. They are busting their guts laughing. Connoisseurs of wit.</context>
      <utterance>There's no cost for air in yer tires!, says Bill. Get wi' th'times, he's told. Tis called inflation!</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She puts her toe out, SLIPS wildly, windmilling her arms, pantomiming as she bends double under the phantom clock.</context>
      <utterance>Billy lives at the top of the hill, Leander at the bot tom, doncha know. So Billy gets a rope, HOISTS the grandfather UP on his back. And muttering the words fifty bucks...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mite slick. Four feet thick a ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tears are streaming from a hundred eyes and more.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Bows to the old gal in the front row, who is scarlet-faced in hysterics, as all around her applaud. Wavey becomes her, inching along, casting fierce glances right and left to warn the world.</context>
      <utterance>Meanwhile, at the bottom, Auntie Fizzard, 91 years young, sets out in her non-slip galoshes and her cane with the rubber tip. Didn't yer, dearie?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is Billy once more, beneath his burden, her long legs stutter- stepping to one side, then the other, slipping, skidding, the howling all around her threatening to shatter walls, and...</context>
      <utterance>Meanwhile, at the top...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Miming the wild ride as they ROAR...</context>
      <utterance>...OVER he goes, clock-side down, and PICKIN' UP SPEED!</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>everything like a miracle, zeroing in on... She becomes Auntie Fizzard once more, shuffling, looking left, right, and suddenly up WILD-EYED!</context>
      <utterance>...eight blocks, NINE, missing</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nods sadly. Leaning on her cane. When at last they quiet.</context>
      <utterance>CLIPS 'er inta the snow bank!</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She says.</context>
      <utterance>Just two galoshes stickin' outta the snow. She digs 'er way out. Brushes herself off. Looks at him sprawled like a turtle on his back, tied to his massive burden. She says...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HEROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She can't even believe he said that. Never looking at him...</context>
      <utterance>I shoulda come last night. Seen the show.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Keep walking. His smile is gentle.</context>
      <utterance>Woulda been a thrill for the Christians among' em. They think you're dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, then we got good news for th...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>So does your son.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Breaking the words off. He's watching her profile.</context>
      <utterance>Even better news for him. WAVEY  You think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gauging the feeling behind the bitterness.</context>
      <utterance>HEROLD  I can't undo the hurt I've done. Unless you let me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is she even listening? He lets the silence hang.</context>
      <utterance>There's a million reasons to send me away. Good ones. And only two reasons not to.</utterance>
   <speaker>HEROLD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops walking. Flips her cigarette off into the snow. Turns now... Looks into his face. And sighs.</context>
      <utterance>I love you. And you love me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the folded print-out to her.</context>
      <utterance>We get so little mention in the wires. Thought you'd like to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks briefly at his eyes. Takes it. Starts to read.</context>
      <utterance>Head in the suitcase. The mystery's solved.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agnis keeps reading.</context>
      <utterance>Silver Melville was captured in Moored with a cruise steward. The boy was twenty, a looker, wearing Armani clothes. Driving a nice Lexus.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Says she did it all for love.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks in her eyes. And decides to say...</context>
      <utterance>She'd call me, time to time. Husband was a pig. More women should do what she done. Her situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The look holds. She sees the compassion in his eyes. Knows he's so on her side. She clears her throat. AGNIS (softly) Cousin Nolan. Hafta pay him a visit. They share a look. He glances at the sea. Beautiful spot.</context>
      <utterance>Some women. Shoulda done it to their brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares deep and unblinking into his eyes. She will tell him.</context>
      <utterance>Mavis said you buried Warren here. Called it an anniversary.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A held moment.</context>
      <utterance>Of a loss. But not the dog.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. And...</context>
      <utterance>What makes us do that, nephew? Give ourselves away to someone. So we can't eat or think or breathe without 'em? QUOYLE  I don't know. We just do.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And now she smiles. Something we have rarely seen.</context>
      <utterance>Wonderful, ain't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Irene Warren died. The mornin' after a Christmas. We get one true love in life, nephew. She was mine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't mean we can't give love again. And get some back.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Strong with that. Sure.</context>
      <utterance>For some, it does. AGNIS  Not for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His smile in return. Very real.</context>
      <utterance>And if that ruffles some small town feathers...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sounds pretty sure himself. Their look ho1ds.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know what the feathers around here need th' most? A good ruffling, I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>Y'know what I need th' most?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, one last time. Sounds like a plan.</context>
      <utterance>A really big breakfast!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hears it now, right enough. The anger, the Cuervo. She stalks on over to the coffee counter, only a bit wobbly. Plucks up two styrofoam cups.</context>
      <utterance>It was easy. I just kept thinkin'. How would Petal do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Back to his desk. Shrugs her coat off onto the floor. Pullover and jeans, she looks terrific. Hikes her butt up onto the edge of his desk.</context>
      <utterance>We're friends, right? Friends drink together.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her soft throaty laugh. He hasn't seen her this way. Can't decide if it's more scary or exciting.</context>
      <utterance>I asked a quest... QUOYLE  I'll drink with you. If you're not done yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Opens the bottle. About four fingers are gone.</context>
      <utterance>Not drunk enough yet to talk about Petal. Which we always seem to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pours herself another two. Thinks before she says...</context>
      <utterance>Let's talk about me. Which we don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pours two fingers for him. Stretches her body to slide the cup across the desk. The Cuervo sloshes.</context>
      <utterance>Growin' up, all I wanted from this place was out. Imagine. Give up all this.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's looking at her cup now. Not at him.</context>
      <utterance>I ran off to Toronto, went to school. Wanted to be a social worker. For kids.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Takes a swallow. Closes her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Came back one summer. Fell for Herold Prowse. That. Was that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Opens her eyes. Straight into his. Did you?</context>
      <utterance>Did you know I was a liar?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle blinks. A perfect stunned ox gape.</context>
      <utterance>Herold liked other women. But you know how that is. Sure you do. WAVEY  He didn't die. Not that he didn't deserve to.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Drains her cup.</context>
      <utterance>See, I'm a good liar.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ice-cold wink.</context>
      <utterance>He ran off to Seattle with some bitch. When his damaged son was two months old. And nobody knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pours herself another. Savors the memory.</context>
      <utterance>Like I said. It's four years ago. And it's yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shrugs a drunken, careless shrug.</context>
      <utterance>So I took his boat out. I sunk it. And told my little story. Grieving widow.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was leaving, of course. Why humiliate myself on the wayout? Yes? WAVEY  But a funny thing happened. On</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes are deeper now. And for a beat, the anger slips away.</context>
      <utterance>my way out.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence. A real one.</context>
      <utterance>All these funny, odd little folks? They put their hearts around me. So I wouldn't be alone. Having lost the man I loved.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I did.</context>
      <utterance>And since I knew, to my shame, that is exactly what I had lost. I let go of the will to leave. I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stares in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Decided to let my child grow up. Around folks better than his mom.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So she smiles. But the bitterness is there in it.</context>
      <utterance>You're quite the talker. QUOYLE  I take pride in that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the world. Ceases to spin. One man's world, at least. She watches that. Assesses it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, this morning. The man I loved. Came back.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sips at her second drink. Slides the rest of it down.</context>
      <utterance>Told me he knew. I loved him still.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes ask. Are you?</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Now I'm drunk enough. To talk about Petal.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shakes her head. Uh-uh.</context>
      <utterance>You're thinking we're kindred souls, you and me. In love with our nightmares.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Means those words as an opening blow. Jacks or better. Here comes the hole card...</context>
      <utterance>You don't love your Petal. You hate. Her cheating. Guts.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pure contempt. And honesty.</context>
      <utterance>You have to think it's love. Because if it's not, you're dead inside. So you keep that flame a flickering. Cos it's all you'll ever have.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lifts the cap. Screws it back on the bottle.</context>
      <utterance>You see. You're a good liar, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And from his prison of shock and shame. He points to a shelf. She is OFF his desk, like a panther... ...SNATCHES the tiny padded box with its treasure. RAISES it high to smash it, and... ...stops. To see the panic. In his eyes. It brings tears. Pooling in hers. And she sets the treasure down, with the tenderness that decency requires.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the damn eggshells? That's all I came to see.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cannot.</context>
      <utterance>Can you guess how I know about Petal?</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that. Is what she came to say.</context>
      <utterance>Because you and I. Are kindred souls. After all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She crosses the floor. Scoops up her coat. Walks, just a little wobbly, to the door. Sighs.</context>
      <utterance>So I told my husband. To fuck himself. And the ego he rode in on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nods. Means that.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for the mirror.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And leaves. The door closes quietly. Quoyle looks from it. To the eggshells. And back.</context>
      <utterance>If I don't see you. Happy New Year.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up. Sees him staring so fixedly at them. BUNNY (alerted) What's wrong?</context>
      <utterance>I think they're all here.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Oh. The kid doesn't smile. She decides whether to ask him...</context>
      <utterance>They're beautiful. I never saw 'em. All together.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks in her eyes. His heart breaks behind his smile.</context>
      <utterance>Will she be proud to wear 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well. Any woman would.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew Billy's dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle nods. Guess not.</context>
      <utterance>Ever'body knows ever'body. But Billy's pap didn't invent the Four Women in a Man's Life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Yoda is just staring at him. And quietly...</context>
      <utterance>Well. Which one is Bunny, I wonder? The Maid in the Meadow, mebbe.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His pupil blinks. Like a crystal bullet of clarity his brain.</context>
      <utterance>Doncha know? They're all the same woman. That's the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For some reason he could never name. Tears are pooling in eyes.</context>
      <utterance>The Maid in the Meadow, that's her innocence and play. The Stouthearted Woman, is when you need to lean on her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quoyle is nodding, now. It all seems so right.</context>
      <utterance>The Tall and Quiet Woman? That's the silent partner who always walks 'longside, so's yer never alone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A soft knocking at the door.</context>
      <utterance>And the Demon Lover. That's just the frostin' on th' cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The bird-like woman enters. The old man nods toward her.</context>
      <utterance>When y'find the woman who's all four? That's when y'got yer one true love.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she isn't alone. A man enters behind her. It is Dennis Buggit. And there are tears on his face. He brings a dreadful silence with him, because the face is an open grave.</context>
      <utterance>...like m'Gertie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sob escapes from this strong man's throat. He ignores it. No one knows what to say.</context>
      <utterance>My dad went over the side this mornin'. Tangled in th' sling- stone line.</utterance>
   <speaker>DENNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'd be real grateful.</context>
      <utterance>If you could write a memorial t' him. Fer t'morrow's Gammy Bird?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slightly startled, Quoyle can't help but smile, despite the solemn occasion. At the proud look on his aunt's face.</context>
      <utterance>Happy New Year, Mr. Quoyle. I'm sorry I missed you at the pageant.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Our girl, a course, is Agnis. Who nearly blushes at the compliment.</context>
      <utterance>I was in the wings, a course. Wasn't our girl somethin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well, who could argue with that. Dawn leans up, kisses Quoyle on the cheek. And with surprising softness...</context>
      <utterance>I say, y'have t'love a woman. Who's in touch with her inner chicken.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>AGNIS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nephew. You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her great aunt looks at this child. Bends to plant an unexpected kiss on the top of Bunny's head. The kid squirms, tugs her dad firmly off, as he sends a parting wave. Into the parlor now. Quieter here, as the new arrivals thread past Jack Buggit in his open coffin, resting on black-draped sawhorses. Dennis and his mom stand by Jack, a hand and a word for each. And moving into the line...</context>
      <utterance>He's okay. He's not sleeping in the box.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His words a murmur. Hers are bolder...</context>
      <utterance>Remember what I told you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he's not sleeping. Why do they call it a awake? He thinks. As if it is a worthwhile question.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nods to himself. Yes.</context>
      <utterance>We're the ones have to be awake. To how much we love him...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down. They are almost there.</context>
      <utterance>And how we should be good to each other. While we have the chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She is thinking. Keeping the thoughts to herself. At the coffin now, he lifts her up to see. Jack lies motionless, a wax figure of himself. Serene behind violet eyelids.</context>
      <utterance>You think?</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dennis looks over. His stolid, grim face releases a smile for his friend.</context>
      <utterance>He looks like he's sleeping.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sets her down. Clasps Mrs. Buggit's hand. And from his</context>
      <utterance>That's cos he's peaceful. No worries, anymore. No troubles.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>pocket...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An enameled wreath with the initial R, backed by a long, sharp pin She tears up again, just to see it.</context>
      <utterance>I found this in Jack's drawer at the paper. I don't know if it's somethin' special...</utterance>
   <speaker>MRS. BUGGIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles bravely as she takes it. Leans up to kiss his cheek. MRS. BUGGIT (a whisper) Dennis showed me what y'wrote fer th' paper. Did Jack proud. So they look at each other. Dennis clears his throat, looks away. And then, Quoyle is leading Bunny off.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, it's his lodge pin. We were lookin' all over.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hungry? There's sandwi...</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just a statement of fact. To no one in particular. Dad squeezes her hand. Manages...</context>
      <utterance>Petal's peaceful, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But she lets go. Scampers to a corner of the room. To Herry Prowse. And his mom. So Quoyle starts toward her, his heart in his throat. And when Wavey looks up. She is glad to see him. As he reaches her... She holds up her wrist. Dangling from it, her turquoise bracelet She wore her best for Jack. Quoyle stands very close. One last thing from his pocket...</context>
      <utterance>You bet. You can count on tha...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A small box. Wrapped as careful as he could. She looks to his eyes, really?</context>
      <utterance>New Year's present.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well, in that case. She takes it into her slender fingers. Undoes the ribbon, the paper. Lifts the lid to see, resting in tissue...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeh. It's a Quoyle tradition.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a funny thing to say. For the first thing he said.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Yeh. That.</context>
      <utterance>What? 'I'm keepin' m'damn lobster license'?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She keeps unpacking. Her face quiet and serious. Her thoughts her own.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe he just said it. To make your Uncle Dennis laugh so hard. You think?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And since he's said her thought aloud. She tells him...</context>
      <utterance>QUOYLE  It's not fair, is it. That Jack woke up. And Petal didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She's not looking up. But he knows she's listening.</context>
      <utterance>Well. The world's not fair. You said.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Eyes resolutely down, she nods. Remembers.</context>
      <utterance>That's something the world is always teaching us. And sometimes, the learning comes later. That gets through. Both adults can see it. QUOYLE  You taught me that.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her brow furrows. Doesn't understand that.</context>
      <utterance>You know. What we wait for? It's like the main stem of this boat. It gives us our shape.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On this. She looks up. Her dad is smiling from his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>See, I know why you saved a place for Petal. All this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And...</context>
      <utterance>Cos I'm the daddy. And you learn how to do. By watching me.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still holding Bunny's eyes. He beckons to the woman rowing. C'mere, a second. So Wavey sets down her oars. Slides over. And Quoyle whispers to his daughter...</context>
      <utterance>You just watched. Better than I knew.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans his face. To Wavey's mouth. A kiss so tender, even a child can't turn away. The moment lingers. And when it ends...</context>
      <utterance>Watch this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thanking your daddy. For all my presents.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wavey looks at this girl.</context>
      <utterance>There was only two.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Except. She gathers all the courage it takes to say...</context>
      <utterance>More than two. Everything I need. Except...</utterance>
   <speaker>WAVEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And waits. We can feel her heart pounding in her throat. Bunny stares back with eyes no one could read. And then...</context>
      <utterance>Except a necklace.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hush over this bay. A woman stunned and grateful.</context>
      <utterance>I got a box of 'em. You could pick one.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Well, that seems true. So, the woman nods. Her eyes flutter down. In the silence, she unwraps a sandwich... WAVEY (a murmur) You want the cheese?</context>
      <utterance>Then you'd have everything you need.</utterance>
   <speaker>BUNNY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Okay, then. She hands that one to Quoyle. And as she and Bunny look for another, we PULL... ...UP and AWAY, an AERIAL ANGLE swirling above the shimmering bay. The boat so far below us. The people tiny specks. They could be anyone. Anyone at all.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
