<movie id="276" title="Hitchhiker s Guide to the Galaxy The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A small square image appears on screen. Home video. The dolphin stadium at Sea World.</context>
      <utterance>It is an important and popular fact that things are not always what they seem.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The dolphins perform; leaping through hoops, etc.</context>
      <utterance>For instance, on the planet Earth, man had always assumed that he was the most intelligent species occupying the planet, instead of the third most intelligent which was, in fact, entirely accurate.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They leap madly, desperately. Higher and higher...</context>
      <utterance>The second most intelligent creatures were, of course, dolphins who curiously enough had long known of the impending destruction of the planet Earth. They had made many attempts to alert mankind to the danger, but most of their communications were misinterpreted as amusing attempts to punch footballs or whistle for tidbits, so they eventually decided they would leave Earth by their own means.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Dolphins leap over and interact with the opening titles. Breathtaking somersaults, back flips, choreographed to a Buzby Berkley-style song called, "SO LONG AND THANKS FOR ALL THE FISH." We end with a wide shot of all the dolphins jumping out of the top of frame, but they never come back down. TILT UP to a starry night sky - the dolphins have vanished.</context>
      <utterance>The last ever dolphin message was misinterpreted as a surprisingly sophisticated attempt to do a double- backward somersault through a hoop while whistling the "Star-Spangled Banner" but in fact the message was this... "So long and thanks for all the fish." TITLES ROLL -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MR. PROSSER, a bureaucrat, leans over him.</context>
      <utterance>What do you mean he's gone out to lunch? You just said he was still at breakfast!</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come off it, Mr. Dent. You can't lie in front of the bulldozers forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm game. We'll see who rusts first.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This bypass has got to be built and it's going to be built. You should have made your protest months ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The first I heard of it was when a workman came yesterday. I asked if he'd come to clean the windows, and he said he'd come to demolish the house. He didn't tell me right away of course. First he wiped a couple of windows and charged me twenty quid. Then he told me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>PROSSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. These plans have been on display at the planning office now for a year.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On display? I had to go down to a cellar!</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the display department.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I eventually found them in the bottom of a locked filing cabinet in a disused lavatory with a sign on the door saying 'beware of the leopard'.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Dent, have you any idea how much damage that bulldozer would suffer if I just let it roll straight over you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROSSER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Arthur and Prosser turn to see a man cresting a hill, pushing a shopping cart which is filled with beer and bags of peanuts. This is FORD PREFECT. Wiry, intense. As he heads downhill, he leaps up and rides the cart down towards Arthur's house -- like a kid in a supermarket. He rolls right past Arthur and the bulldozers.</context>
      <utterance>Arthur!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaps off, drags the cart to a full stop.</context>
      <utterance>Ford?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arthur! There you are. Here drink and eat with me. We need to talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Er, um...now's not the best time, Ford They're going to demolish my home,</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur simply motions to the bulldozer.</context>
      <utterance>Whoa. You already know? How?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. When you say "they" you mean they. Got it. Listen, I gotta tell you something important, and I gotta tell you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford looks to Prosser who is conferring with the bulldozer driver. He pushes the cart over to him. ARTHUR - watches as Ford gestures to Prosser who waves his hand and the all the 'dozer engines die. The bulldozer drivers step down, start drinking the beer and eating the peanuts. Ford returns to Arthur.</context>
      <utterance>But what about my house?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon. Let's go to the pub. He said they won't destroy your house until they've finished the beers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we trust him?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd trust him to the end of the Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how far's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About twelve minutes away.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six pints of bitter. And quickly. The world's about to end.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to pull pints. Ford shoves bar peanuts into his pockets while Arthur shouts into his phone...</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, sir? Nice weather for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shuts the phone, sits, looking forlorn.</context>
      <utterance>Well, when does he get back from lunch? Or is he going straight out for tea?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is shaping up to be a crap day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's about to get a lot crappier.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford slaps down a 50 note. The barman's impressed.</context>
      <utterance>There you are, six pints.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep the change. You've got ten minutes to spend it. Ford pushes three pints in front of Arthur.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three? At lunchtime?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time is an illusion. Lunchtime doubly so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very deep. You should send that in to the Reader's Digest. They've got a page for people like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drink up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why three pints?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Muscle relaxant.  And eat these. You'll need the salt.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on. Ford?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would you say if I told you I wasn't really from Guilford but from a small planet somewhere in the vicinity of Eetelgeuse?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, is it the sort of thing you're likely to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember when we met? That car was racing toward me, I was trying to greet it, you pushed me out of the way?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't you find it a little strange that I was trying to shake hands with a car?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I assumed you were drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought cars were the dominant life form. I was trying to introduce myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's why you're named after a discontinued car from the seventies?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur just stares at him, then turns to his beer.</context>
      <utterance>You saved my life that day. Now I'm saving yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This must be Thursday. I never could get the hang of Thursdays.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, if it's about your house...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shows Ford the photo of he and Tricia on his phone.</context>
      <utterance>No, it's not that. It's....</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found her. Ford. The perfect girl. I found her, and then I let her get away. You remember that fancy dress party I told you about?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur shakes his head. Ford checks his watch.</context>
      <utterance>This isn't a long story, is it? We've only got six minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Talk and drink. Fancy dress party.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At that flat in Islington. I told you about it. Last week, remember?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Arthur, dressed in safari attire complete with pith helmet, sits off to the side, observing, looking miserable.</context>
      <utterance>I can't bear those sort of parties, didn't want to go, would have much rather stayed home and, I don't know, brush the dog. Anything. But there I was -- and then, there she was...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRICIA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Arthur looks up. TRICIA MCMILLAN is dressed in a mid 19th century mens suit with mutton chop sideburns and is holding a taxidermy beagle -- and she still looks beautiful. Arthur, ever the gentleman, stands.</context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Arthur. Arthur Dent.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, the costume. Right. Er, um...  Livingston, I presume.  Granted. Not as clever as Darwin, but the best I could do on short notice.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the first person who's got it right. Everyone keeps calling me Sherlock.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? I thought the beagle made it rather obvious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THE BALCONY -- Arthur has just taken a digital photo of he and Tricia on his cell phone. They look at the screen image and laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Really? I thought the beagle made it rather obvious. He pets the dog. She smiles. He smiles back. 9 A CAMERA FLASH FLASHES. JUMP CUT to... 9</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was amazing, Ford. Witty, and beautiful, and brilliant. Four or five degrees. One in math, one in astrophysics, another in biology...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They clink their wine glasses, take sips, continue to chat.</context>
      <utterance>I've got so many degrees I am officially unemployable. Let's drink to that!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And just as I was asking myself, "Why is this stunning and intelligent woman even giving me the time of day, out of nowhere she says...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. It is a bit noisy. There's a lovely little cafe around the corner...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was thinking Madagascar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a new club on Dean Street?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's a country. Off the coast of Africa.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that Madagascar. Right, off we go then.  Good God, you're serious.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well...that's...an extraordinary proposition. But...I can't just up and go. What about my job?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quit. Get a new one when we return.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't just...what about my house? Who would feed my dog?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRICIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bring him with.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a Welsh Collie. He'd feel all out of place in Madagascar. Trillian forces a smile, clearly disappointed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They both turn to face ZAPHOD BEEBLEBROX - very charming, extremely handsome - whose attire seems very "other worldly." Knee high boots, a yellow sash...</context>
      <utterance>You don't want to go to Madagascar.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi. I'm Zaphod Beeblebrox, President of the Galaxy -- of course, you probably already know that. I'm headed for a lost and distant planet. Would you like to see my spaceship?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went to refresh our drinks. When I came back, she was gone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Would you like to see my spaceship?" Really, what sort of chat up line is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More popular than you'd think.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've left messages, sent letters... It's like she's vanished off the face of the earth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There's a ROAR OF ENGINES and a LOUD CRASH outside. Arthur and everyone else in the pub look up.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, it happens. Speaking of...  We've got two minutes. So drink up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He runs out. Ford rises, grabs two handfuls of peanuts from the bowl, tosses the barman all the money in his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>My house!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A round for everyone, on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really think the world's going to end?  Shouldn't we lie down or put a bag over our heads or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will it help?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives everyone in the bar a friendly salute, exits.</context>
      <utterance>Not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last orders, then?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shows Arthur his blinking Sens-0-Matic device.</context>
      <utterance>Ships from a Vogon Constructor Fleet. I picked up their signal this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD {CONT'D}</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He tosses Arthur the towel. Then, he removes a short black rod, his ELECTRONIC THUMB. He sticks it out.</context>
      <utterance>Here. You'll need this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VOGON CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean you've never been to Alpha Centauri? Oh, for heaven's sake mankind, it's only four light years away you know. I'm sorry, but if you can't be bothered to take an interest in local affairs that's your own lookout. PULL BACK FARTHER - people lay on the ground with PAPER BAGS on their heads.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of his walrusy FIRST OFFICERS pushes a yellow button.</context>
      <utterance>Apathetic bloody planet, I've no sympathy at all. Energize the demolition beams.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The title draws nearer. We see that it sits on an electronic book with lots of buttons.</context>
      <utterance>The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy is a wholly remarkable book...</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The book opens revealing TWO SCREENS. Images appear. A star map, layers of data, captions, video, animations...</context>
      <utterance>...Perhaps the most remarkable, certainly the most successful book ever to come out of the great publishing corporations of Ursa Minor.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More popular than the CELESTIAL HOME CARE OMNIBUS, better selling than 53 MORE THINGS TO DO IN ZERO GRAVITY, and more controversial than Oolon Colluphid's trilogy of philosophical blockbusters,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're not from Guilford, which would explain the accent -- which I've always wondered about...and you're not an out of work actor -- but rather a writer for this...this...book thing. Ford nods. Arthur rubs his weary brow.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ford hands him a fistful of peanuts.</context>
      <utterance>I don't feel well. I need a cup of tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur eats some peanuts, sits up, squints. Ford feels his way around the room, looking for something.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Eat these. If you've never been through a transmat beam before you've probably lost some salt and protein.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I asked where we were would I regret</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're safe. For now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're in a storage hold in one of the ships of the Vogon constructor fleet ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obviously some strange usage of the word safe I wasn't previously aware of.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me you're joking.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I'm joking.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford does a reassuring little laugh.</context>
      <utterance>And do a reassuring little laugh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now tell me where we really are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford continues his search. Arthur's breathing quickens.</context>
      <utterance>In the storage hold of a Vogon constructor ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me home. Ford.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Home? Arthur...your home... is...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls out his cell phone. Desperately punches numbers. Ford flips on a light switch, revealing a messy chamber full of alien junk and old mattresses.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God - it was demolished! I've got to reach my lawyer! He must be back from lunch by now...</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't remember, do you?  Okay. I've got something to tell you. It ain't gonna be easy, but you're gonna have to just deal, okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good god. Is this really the interior of a flying saucer?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Why?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, it's a bit squalid isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey man, you're in denial.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blown up? BLOWN UP?! Couldn't you have done something?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did. I saved you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there's six billion other people.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And all those ants.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but ants aren't exactly people!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford throws Arthur a towel. Arthur looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>And now you're thinking like a Vogon.  I saved your life, okay? Which makes us even. Next thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Arthur joins Ford near a rusty ventilation pipe.</context>
      <utterance>It's a tough galaxy. You want to survive out here, you really gotta know where your towel is. Now gimme a hand over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He slides the towel behind the pipe, holding each end of it, Arthur does the same.</context>
      <utterance>Careful, it's hot.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>shoots out. Ford holds the black Thumb under the pipe.</context>
      <utterance>We've got to get off this ship before the Vogons find us. Vogons hate hitchhikers. Which is why they make ships with walls that won't allow the Sub-Etna signal to pass through. So we've got to send the signal up and out if we wanna catch a ride. Pull. They both pull. A section of pipe snaps off. Steam</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's a Vogon?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford continues turning dials. Arthur lifts the Guide.</context>
      <utterance>Ask the guide. Say "Vogons."</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The word "VOGONS" floats up into his field of vision.</context>
      <utterance>"Vogons."</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vogons.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Arthur touches 'HOW TO HAVE FUN WITH.'</context>
      <utterance>Vogons are one of the most unpleasant races in the Galaxy - not evil, but bad- tempered, bureaucratic, officious and callous. They wouldn't even lift a finger to save their own grandmothers from the Ravenous Bugblatter Beast of Traal without orders signed in triplicate, sent in, sent back, queried, lost, found, subjected to public inquiry, lost again, and finally buried in soft peat for three months and recycled as fire-lighters.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The best way to get a drink out of a Vogon is to stick your finger down his throat. Arthur touches 'WHAT TO AVOID'.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On no account should you allow a Vogon to read poetry to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They can't think, they can't imagine, most of them can't even spell. They just run things.  And if we don't get a ride soon, you won't b need the guide to illustrate just how unpleasant the Vogons can be. They've destroyed a planet today, that always makes them a little feisty.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shhh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An image of the Earth appears on the Guide's screen.</context>
      <utterance>Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Arthur waits...and waits. The Earth image fades away.</context>
      <utterance>Harmless.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it? That's all this idiotic book has to say about my home? "Harmless?"</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, there are a hundred billion stars in the Galaxy and only a limited amount of space in the book's microprocessors. No one knew much about Earth. That's why I was there. To expand the entry. I fired off a new one to the editor before I got stranded.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it say now?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Arthur can react, a speaker HUMS to life with screeching HOWLS and GARGLES. Arthur cups his ears.</context>
      <utterance>Mostly harmless.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhh, what the hell is that?!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford removes a small yellow fish from his pouch. He moves to put it in Arthur's ear. Arthur struggles.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Put this in your ear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As he succeeds, the noise mutates to the Vogon Captain's voice. Arthur looks incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>Argh! What's happening...?</utterance>
   <speaker>JELTZ</speaker>
      <mode>ON SPEAKER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is your captain speaking, so stop whatever you're doing and pay attention!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The fish. It's translating for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELTZ</speaker>
      <mode>ON SPEAKER</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to our instruments we have unwittingly picked up a couple of hitchhikers who must be apprehended and...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JELTZ</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The door BURSTS open. A VOGON GUARD enters. Grabs Ford and Arthur. They struggle.</context>
      <utterance>...and this is not a taxi service for degenerate freeloaders.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The struggle continues. As they're dragged out the door, Arthur continues to try to yank the fish out of his ear. Ford wrestles with him, trying to keep it in.</context>
      <utterance>Resistance is useless!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Babelfish is small, yellow, leechlike, and probably the oddest thing in the Universe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur continues to struggle, until he passes a portal window. He backs up to look out.</context>
      <utterance>It feeds on brainwave energy, absorbing unconscious frequencies and excreting a matrix of conscious frequencies to the speech centres of the brain, the practical upshot of which is that if you stick one in your ear, you instantly understand anything said to you in any language.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>26a ARTHUR'S POV -- of space through the window, beautiful 26a purple-orange clouds of swirling stars and gasses.</context>
      <utterance>Now, it is such a bizarrely improbable thing that anything so mind-bogglingly useful could have evolved in the Universe purely by chance that many thinkers have chosen to see this as a final clinching proof of the NON-existence of God.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The argument goes something like this... "I refuse to prove that I exist," says God, "for proof denies faith, and without faith I am nothing."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The guard yanks Arthur away, pushes him forward with Ford.</context>
      <utterance>"But," says Man, "the Babelfish is a dead give-away. It proves you exist, and so therefore you don't. QED." "Oh dear," says God, "I hadn't thought of that," and promptly vanishes in a puff of logic.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Most leading theologians claim that this argument is a load of dingo's kidneys but that didn't stop Oolon Colluphid from making a small fortune when he used it as the central theme of his best-selling book,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VOGON GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Resistance is useless!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ford...</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't panic. If we're lucky, they'll throw us out into space.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Ford's apprehensive look we CUT TO...</context>
      <utterance>And if we're unlucky?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford VIBRATES like he's having an epileptic seizure. Arthur just looks like he has a migraine.</context>
      <utterance>Vogon poetry is widely accepted as the third worst in the universe.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Spasms wrack Ford's body. He SCREAMS. Arthur squints.</context>
      <utterance>The second worst is that of the Azgoths of Kria. During a recitation by their Poet Master Grunthos the Flatulent of his poem "Ode to a Small Lump of Green Putty I Found in My Armpit One Midsummer Morning," four of his audience died of internal hemorrhaging, and the President of the Mid- Galactic Arts Nobbling Council survived by gnawing one of his own legs off.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford's entire body tenses, arches, then goes limp. Arthur lets out an audible sigh as the poem ends.</context>
      <utterance>Or I shall rend thee In the gobberwarts with my blurglecruncheaon, see if I don't!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The absolute worst poetry was written by Paula Nancy Millstone Jennings of Sussix. It involved decaying swans. Luckily, it was destroyed when the Earth was.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford is spent, can't say a word. Arthur looks up.</context>
      <utterance>So, Earthlings, I present you with a simple choice. Either die in the vacuum of space, or -- tell what you thought of my poem.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeltz looks surprised. Ford notices, whispers to Arthur.</context>
      <utterance>Actually...I rather liked it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good tact. Run with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um...some of the words I didn't understand, but I found the imagery quite effective.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Continue. . .</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, um, interesting rhythmic devices which seemed to counterpoint the surrealism of the underlying metaphor of the humanity...</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vogonity!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Vogonity, sorry. Vogonity of the poet's soul, which contrives through the medium of the verse structure to sublimate, er...</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... whatever it was ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeltz rubs one of his chins, then smiles and claps slowly.</context>
      <utterance>... the poem was about.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you just saved my life again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JELTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guard grabs them, drags them out of the bridge.</context>
      <utterance>An astute analysis. Very impressive.  Throw them off the ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Resistance is useless!</utterance>
   <speaker>JELTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jeltz picks up his fishing rod, goes for another crab.</context>
      <utterance>Hmph. "Counterpoint the surrealism of the underlying metaphor..." Death's too good for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this is it? We're going to die?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur sits for a moment, then oddly chuckles to himself.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. No, wait! What's this switch?  No, it's nothing. We are going to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, it's at times like this, when I'm trapped in a Vogon airlock with a man from Betelgeuse and about to die of asphyxiation in deep space that I really wish I'd listened to what my mother told me when I was young.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? What did you she tell you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford folds his towel into a tiny square, holds it up toward Arthur. He raises an eyebrow. Will this help?</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I didn't listen.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford dabs Arthur's brow. They stare forward at the airlock door. Long pause. Nothing happens. They look to each other. Shrug. They might be okay. Then -- PSSH. The bottom drops out. They're sucked down and out.</context>
      <utterance>You're sweating.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The weightless guide twirls away. Arthur reaches for it. The words "DON'T PANIC" alight.</context>
      <utterance>"Space..." says the introduction to the Hitchhikers Guide, "...is big. Really big. You just won't believe how vastly, hugely mind-bogglingly big it is. I mean, you may think it's a long way down the road to the market, but that's just peanuts compared to space..." and so on.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It also says that if you hold a lung full of air you can survive in the total vacuum of space for about thirty seconds -- but with space being really big and all, the chances of being picked up within that time are 2 to the power of 2076775949 to 1 against...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He reaches for the phone, it's just beyond his fingertips. His eyes widen with fret as the phone tumbles away. 30a Then -- WOOMPH -- space seems to stretch and bend. A tiny 30a hole appears, then opens wide. Paper hats and party balloons fall out, then drift away. The hole flips inside out. Arthur and Ford are enveloped, then replaced by a stunning, sleek starship, the HEART OF GOLD.</context>
      <utterance>...which, by a staggering coincidence, is also the telephone number of the Islington flat where Arthur once went to a fancy dress party and met a very nice girl whom he totally failed to connect with.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>TRILLIAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two to the power of one hundred thousand to one against and falling...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FEMALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>TRILLIAN</mode>
      <context>The sofas shake a little.</context>
      <utterance>Two to the power of ten thousand to one against and falling.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ford...</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'm a sofa.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long pause. Both sofas begin to thrash in panic.</context>
      <utterance>I think I know how you feel.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>TRILLIAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five to one against and falling... A pair of arms and legs pop out of each sofa.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Four to one against and falling...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>ON TV</mode>
      <context>PULL BACK to reveal ZAPHOD BEEBLEBROX, leaning toward the TV, watching with a very satisfied grin...</context>
      <utterance>So, in the name of the people and freedom and, I dunno, democracy and stuff like that, I hereby declare this ship officially stolen!</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Annoyed, he turns. There's a woman with red hair (TRILLIAN), her back to him, reading numbers off a console display and speaking into a microphone.</context>
      <utterance>Three to one...two to one...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You will be sent for soon.</context>
      <utterance>Probability factor of one to one...we have normality, I repeat we have normality. Anything you still can't cope with is therefore your own problem. Please relax.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRILLIAN turns -- and we now recognize her as Tricia from the fancy dress party. Her hair is shorter and bright red. She looks amazing.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. Do you mind? I can't hear.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we put your ego aside for one moment? Something important has happened.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If there's anything more important than my ego on this ship, I want it caught and shot now. He turns back to the TV and turns it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode>OK TV</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...the question everyone seems to be asking is, has the Big Z finally flipped? We asked his private brain care Specialist, Gag Halfrunt...</utterance>
   <speaker>GAG HALFRRUNT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vell, Zaphod's just zis guy, you know --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His head jerks upwards. He quickly grabs it with his hands and shoves it back down.</context>
      <utterance>We have a couple of hitchhikers in our receiving bay.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't pick them up. The ship did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you engaged the Improbability Drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't engage the drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We picked them up in sector ZZ9 Plural Z Alpha -- where you picked me up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Just very, very improbable.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He reaches for a hi-tech gun on the wall. She stops him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have time for this! We've got the police of half the Galaxy after us and we stop to pick up hitchhikers?! Okay, so ten out of ten for style, but minus several million for good thinking, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod rolls his eyes as a humanoid robot rises from its seat behind them. This is MARVIN. He trudges slump- shouldered toward Zaphod.</context>
      <utterance>Don't. I'll send Marvin.  Marvin!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you ought to know I'm feeling very depressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have something to take your mind off things.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't work, I have an exceptionally large mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Go down to the number two entry bay and bring the two aliens up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't enjoy it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not asking you to enjoy it. Just do it will you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marvin turns and trudges away. Then he turns again.</context>
      <utterance>All right. I'll do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not getting you down at all am I?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, Marvin, it's fine really. It's just part of life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marvin trudges away. A door slides open for him and makes an audible, satisfied SIGH as it does.</context>
      <utterance>Life. Don't talk to me about life.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmmmyaaahhhhhh!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Approximately 15 Vogons sit around the table murmuring sporadically. A VOGON MESSENGER runs up, holding papers. Kwaltz takes them, signs, signs the next page -- and the next. He hands them back to the messengers (who has been jogging in place the whole time). He runs off. The VOGON CAPTAIN appears on the large screen before him.</context>
      <utterance>Get me the vice-president.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hyperspace permission granted, Captain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now this is more like my idea of a spaceship. Look at all these buttons...</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They listen. Hear footsteps.</context>
      <utterance>Shhh.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He pushes a button. The door slides open with a satisfied sigh -- "Hhhmmyaaaahhh". As they walk through... 37a INT- HOG- CORRIDOR NIGHT 37a</context>
      <utterance>This way.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They leap through to the other side as the door closes.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you for using this door. I've enjoyed opening for you. Hhmmyaahh...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>They whip around to find Marvin standing before them.</context>
      <utterance>Ghastly, isn't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Marvin turns and walks away. They shrug to each other and follow. Marvin passes through another door that opens with the same sigh -- "Hhmmaaaahhh"</context>
      <utterance>I've been ordered to take you up to the bridge. Here I am, brain the size of a planet, and they ask me to take you up to the bridge. Call that job satisfaction? - 'cause I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door closes.</context>
      <utterance>What a pleasure it is to open for you. I will gladly close for you now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door repeats its whole closing and opening routine again.</context>
      <utterance>"All the doors in this spacecraft have a cheerful and sunny disposition. It is their pleasure to open for you, and their satisfaction to close again with the knowledge of a job well done.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hateful, isn't it? You can thank the Marketing Division of the Sirius Cybernetics Corporation for building robots with GPP.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Genuine People Personalities." I'm a personality prototype. You can tell can't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Er. . .</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, did I say something wrong? Pardon me for breathing, which I never do anyway, so I don't know why I even bother to say it. Oh god, I'm so depressed. They round a corner...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then I've got this terrible pain in all the diodes down my left side. I've asked for them to be replaced but no one ever listens.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really? Wonder why?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably because he's so negative.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They continue on.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know. I was being...never mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod spins around in his chair, holding a gun but sporting that same politically correct smile.</context>
      <utterance>I've brought the aliens. Don't thank me or anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur and Ford throw their hands up. Marvin doesn't.</context>
      <utterance>Freeze!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you mean sit in a corner and rust or just fall apart where I'm standing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wasn't talking to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zaphod?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod gives Ford a big bear hug. He pulls away, then playfully punches Ford in the arm.</context>
      <utterance>Ixxie? It is you! IXXIE!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Praxibetel Ix, you zarking hoopy! What the hell are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know! Just stuck out the thumb and here I am.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is so you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And look at you! President? Last time I saw you, you were a beach bum.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it a great galaxy or what?  I still can't believe this. Ixxie! Here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, it's Ford now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name. It's Ford Prefect. Picked it up on Earth. Sorta grew on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace, tussle, punch arms. They bump into Arthur.</context>
      <utterance>Okay "Ford" -- you zarking frood.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, this is Arthur. Arthur, this is Zaphod Beeblebrox. My cousin? Semi-half brother?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He shares three of the same mothers as me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've met.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Arthur can explain, Trillian enters.</context>
      <utterance>Have we? Sorry. I've got a terrible memory for species.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, hon. Come here. You won't believe this. Ix...um, sorry..."Ford"...this is...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a closer look at him.</context>
      <utterance>Tricia McMillan?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arthur?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe this...I've been looking...and you're here? I went to get wine and...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur smiles, then realizes with some regret...</context>
      <utterance>I know. And it was rude to just leave, but I told you I wanted to get away, and he had a spaceship parked outside, well, honestly -- I assumed you were a sort of stay-at-home-and-read-a book type.  But you're here...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod stops in between them, puts his arm around Arthur.</context>
      <utterance>Actually -- I am that type. But...well you do know what happened, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--Ford picked him up, they hitched a ride, and here we all are. Now, enough small talk, Trill. We're on the run, remember? I stole a ship?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur SHOVES Zaphod's hand off his shoulder. Oddly, Zaphod reacts with a smile. And then -- his head shoots all the up way revealing a second head that lives somewhere under his chin.</context>
      <utterance>We're having a bit of a chat if you don't mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You blew it with her, Earthman, so shut up or I'll kick you in the gones!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur recoils in horror, instinctively raises his fists. Zaphod wrestles with Head 2 while A THIRD ARM springs out of Zaphod's chest and PUNCHES ARTHUR in the jaw. Arthur buckles and hits the floor.</context>
      <utterance>There's the Zaphod I remember.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should teach your pal a lesson, Ford. He's a guest on my ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you said you stole it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A KLAXON sounds. Red lights FLASH. Zaphod (Head 2) hurries to the console. Ford follows. Trillian hurries to Arthur who nurses his jaw.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. Get technical.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel like a bloody idiot. I've spent all week looking for Tricia McMillan and that isn't even your name.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is my name. I shortened it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trillian...!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'm still Arthur. Just plain average one-headed doesn't-own-a-space ship Arthur. Sorry to disappoint.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Trillian leaves Arthur, joins Zaphod</context>
      <utterance>A little help over here?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dull gray rectangular Vogon BATTLE CRUISER is easing up behind the Heart of Gold. Behind the cruiser is about ONE HUNDRED OTHER BATTLE SHIPS, flying in formation. (38 Cont) BACK ON THE BRIDGE-- (38 cont)</context>
      <utterance>They're after us! Fire a gun! Launch a missile! DO SOME DAMAGE! Zaphod's arms struggle with his head again. 38a QUICK SHOT. DEEP SPACE 38a</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A very eager male COMPUTER VOICE (EDDIE) sounds.</context>
      <utterance>Computer?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, guys, this is Eddie your shipboard computer and I just know I'm gonna get a bundle of kicks out of any program you want to run through me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you identify our pursuers?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd be happy to! Stand by, please.  Hey, guys, I'm just pleased as punch to report that it's a fleet of a hundred Vogon Battle Destroyers. You must be super important to warrant such an effort, and gee am I impressed. They're sending a message. I'd be super happy to play it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This people personality thing is gonna drive me nuts! Can't you change it? An IMAGE APPEARS on the ship's monitor - Vice President, QUESTULAR RONTOK, flanked by Vogon Commander KWALTZ {at H.Q.). He looks reluctant. He has to say this...</context>
      <utterance>Fine! Play it!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leap to hyperspace!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure thing, fella, but I should tell you we need proper authorization before entering a hyperspace expressway.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Trillian buckle up. Ford turns to Arthur.</context>
      <utterance>Or else what? They'll send a hundred and one ships? DO it!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brace yourself. This is a bit like being drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so bad about being drunk?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They are stretched and squeezed by extraordinary forces.</context>
      <utterance>Ask a glass of water.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did they have proper hyperspace authorization?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON WORKER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Commander.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Add that to their list of offences!  Blatant disregard for protocol.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do realize he did what he did because he knew this is what you would do.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Questular looks up to the screen at all the Vogon ships.</context>
      <utterance>Rules are rules, Mr. Vice President. And they are made to be followed.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you think this many ships is a bit, oh I don't know -- excessive?</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The provisions are clear. Under subsection 37a these are the forces we deploy to protect the president in the case of an attempted or actual kidnapping- He holds up one fat official book with one hand.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- and these are the forces we deploy to apprehend any intentional or actual kidnapper. He holds up another fat book with the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are aware, Commander, that the President kidnapped himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts the two books together, slams them down.</context>
      <utterance>Hence...</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any idea how ridiculous this is?</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A VOGON MESSENGER runs up holding papers. Kwaltz takes them, signs one in two places, initials others, lifts the top sheet, removes the pink copy. Folds it.</context>
      <utterance>I don't have ideas Mr. Vice President. I just do what I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hands slam Head 2 down. Zaphod (Head 1) turns to Ford.</context>
      <utterance>Damn, I'm good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So -- you along for the ride or am I dropping you somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends. Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WITH TRILLIAN -- who notices Arthur looking ill.</context>
      <utterance>Into the pages of history, cousin. And when you see what I'm about to show you, you'll beg me to take you with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Normally I would say "I'll live," but given the circumstances...  Is there any tea on this spaceship?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She exits. Arthur follows. Zaphod steps back, blocking his way.</context>
      <utterance>This way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, apeman. Earthman. I'm sorry, what was your name again?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arthur.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles broader. Then Head 2 pops up and finishes...</context>
      <utterance>Right. No hard feelings, okay? And sorry to hear about your planet, but don't mention it to the girl because if you do I'll...I'll...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod slams Head 2 back into place..then smiles again. Arthur furrows his brow and Zaphod and follows Trillian.</context>
      <utterance>I'll pull your spleen out through your ass!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two heads. Interesting choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apparently you can't be President with a whole brain.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you carved it up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the COBALT BLUE CUBE on his gold necklace.</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- I think. And I think I did it in such a way that it wouldn't be detected by the Government screening tests -- or by me. So, what's so secret that I can't let anybody know I know it, not the Galactic Government, not even myself? And the answer is--  --I don't know. Obviously. But I put a few things together and that's when I realized I had this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose I should have said it resembles tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So two heads is what does it for a girl, then? I mean, if I'd had two heads. Or three?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or your own space ship.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything else he's got two of?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on, Arthur, don't be like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Green? Bleeping? What?</context>
      <utterance>Well, what am I supposed to be like?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just be yourself. Have some fun. Does it hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I suppose it wouldn't..</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She points to his jaw, he nods, she picks up her BACKPACK.</context>
      <utterance>I mean...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She unzips it. TWO MICE scurry out and scamper off, a hair-clip is clipped to one of the mice's tail.</context>
      <utterance>I might have an aspirin.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Before she can catch them, they scurry under the door.</context>
      <utterance>Hey. What are they doing in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN {CONT'D)</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were from my lab at university. Odd...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So all that's left is me and you, "mostly harmless," and two lab rats. She furrows her brow. What does he mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, there's something I should tell you...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Showtime, Trill!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur nods. She leaves. He looks at his "tea", throws it in the trash bin.</context>
      <utterance>Can it keep? You might want to see this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this great task for which I, Deep Thought, the second greatest computer of all time have been called into existence?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUNKWILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your task, O computer...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang on. Did you say second greatest?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Second greatest. Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we designed you to be the greatest computer so you could...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUNKWILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're not talking about the Milliard Gargantubrain which can count all the atoms in a star in a millisecond?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Milliard Gargantubrain? A mere abacus, mention it not.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Omnicognate Neutron Wrangler then?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Omnicognate Neutron Wrangler could argue all four legs off an Arcturan Megadonkey, but only I could persuade it to go for a walk afterwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am the greatest computer you are able to design without my help. Which, one day, you are going to need.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUNKWILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just ask the question.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Long pause. Deep Thought bleeps and bloops.</context>
      <utterance>Oh Deep Thought, your task is this. We want you to tell us -- the Answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Answer...to what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LUNKWILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know. The answer. To Life...the Universe...Everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'd really like an answer. Something simple. Can you do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lunkwill glances at his time piece, Fook at the expectant throng behind them. They wait.</context>
      <utterance>The Ultimate Question of Life, the Universe and Everything. Yes. There is an answer. But I'll have to think about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Return to this place in exactly... seven and a half million years.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUNKWILL &amp; FOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PSSSH. The screen goes to snow.</context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no. There's more. They go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod nods, hits play. We PUSH BACK IN ON THE SCREEN.</context>
      <utterance>Seven and a half million years later?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deep Thought. Do you have...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An answer for you? Yes. I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There really is an answer?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. There really is one.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>LUNKWILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you tell us what it is?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Though I don't think you're going to like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't matter! We must know it!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're really not going to like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell us!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright. The answer to the ultimate question ...</utterance>
   <speaker>LUNKWILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... of Life, the Universe, and Everything ...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... is ...</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes ...!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The surrounding crowd is stunned. More MUTTERING.</context>
      <utterance>Forty two.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I checked it thoroughly. It would have been simpler, of course, to have known what the actual question was.</utterance>
   <speaker>LUNKWILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But it was the Question. The Ultimate Question!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but what actually is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOOK</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything! You know ... just EVERYTHING!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LUNKWILL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give us the Ultimate Question then!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The picture distorts and whites out. PSSSSHHHHHH.</context>
      <utterance>I can't.  But there is one who can. A computer that is to come after me, one that I will design. A computer to calculate the Ultimate Question, one of such infinite complexity that life itself will form part of its operational matrix. And you yourselves shall take on new more primitive forms and go down into the computer to navigate its ten million year program. I shall design this computer for you. And it shall be called...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're looking for the Ultimate Question?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to a different rack of instruments, consults a check list, starts flipping some switches.</context>
      <utterance>No, I tried that. "Why?" "Forty-two." Doesn't work.  Let's get her ready, babe.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, why do you want to know the Ultimate Question?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He continues preparing the ship. Trillian consults the huge MANUAL, turning dials, flipping switches...</context>
      <utterance>Oh. Well -- partly the curiosity, partly a sense of adventure, but mostly I think it's for the fame and the money.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But -- you're President of the Galaxy, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Arman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arthur.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whatever. Presidential fame is temporary, I find the Question, that's permanent. It sticks. Plus everyone thinks you're deep. Win-win.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you don't know the name of the computer that other computer was talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is why I'm going there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There. To find Deep Thought. On Magrathea.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Magrathea!? Magrathea is a myth, a legend...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it isn't. It's real, cousin. And this is the only ship in the universe that can get you there.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean to tell me you carved up your brain so you could become President so you would get invited to the launching ceremony of this ship...so you could steal it... so you could go to Magrathea -- which, according to most sane people, doesn't even exist?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yep.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beautiful.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod thinks again -- hard.</context>
      <utterance>Why this ship? What's so special about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't seem to be letting myself in on any of my secrets.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They turn to see Trillian flipping open a glass lid revealing a BIG RED BUTTON. Ford reads the glowing letters above the button...</context>
      <utterance>Because of this, obviously.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Infinite Improbability Drive? So they finally built one that works. And that's how we got picked up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly. And I'm guessing if we hit that button -- we go to Magrathea.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're guessing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, anyone who's not up for that, there's the door. Now who's in?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes out the Guide. Zaphod looks to Trillian.</context>
      <utterance>For a trip to a place that doesn't exist? I'm in. My editor will think I'm crazy, but what the hell -- he already thinks I'm dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're all standing together. They turn to Arthur. Arthur looks to Trillian. She stares back -- waiting.</context>
      <utterance>Definitely. I'm in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod smiles, all bright and cheery.</context>
      <utterance>Do I even have a choice?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur looks at the button.</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, Zaphod's Head 2 shoots up!</context>
      <utterance>What exactly does an Infinite Improbability Drive do?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Such generators were often used to break the ice at parties by making all the molecules in the hostess's undergarments leap simultaneously one foot to the left, in accordance with the Theory of Indeterminacy. Kwaltz and Questular appear on the monitor.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Controllers turn more dials, trying to find the ship.</context>
      <utterance>Well, Captain...?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Many respectable physicists said they weren't going to stand for that sort of thing partly because it was a debasement of science, but mostly because they didn't get invited to those sort of parties.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had them sir. These are the coordinates. But -- they're not here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The captain shrugs. Kwaltz heaves a walrusy sigh.</context>
      <utterance>I can see that. WHERE ARE THEY?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KNITTED ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this going to happen every time we hit that button?</utterance>
   <speaker>KNITTED TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>53 The air ripples. The 'knitted' crew flip back to their 53 former selves. Arthur pukes into a trash bin and with a sick expression, looks up to the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Very probably, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now Zaphod looks -- and he's elated.</context>
      <utterance>Did it work? Are we there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes!...I think. Computer?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Head 2 suddenly springs up.</context>
      <utterance>Hi, fella!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you please change that zarking annoying voice!!?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Computer? What planet is that, please?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PUSH IN ON ZAPHOD -- who's 2nd Head suddenly shoots up.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for waiting, everyone. I'm just tickled pink to tell you we are currently in orbit around the planet Viltvodle 6.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Humma Kavula!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VOGON CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, the Heart of Gold has just requested permission to land on Viltvodle 6. Should I pursue?</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode>ON MONITOR</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is not a request to which I can respond, captain. Should I pursue what? Are you requesting hyperspace clearance so that you may pursue the fugitive?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, commander.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode>ON MONITOR</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you must say that, captain -- in request form.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Requesting hyperspace clearance to pursue the fugitive, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode>ON MONITOR</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you. Request acknowledged. Await response.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is ridiculous! What do you need, an executive order? Fine. I order you. Stop doing this! Go and get him!</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to Subsection 94b, paragraph 2, you're not authorized to make such an order.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I'm acting president!</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kwaltz continues to fill out the forms. Questular grabs a clump of his hair -- and pulls it out.</context>
      <utterance>Then act like a president, and do nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why does he keep saying that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I'm not used to seeing him this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops, fires him a look.</context>
      <utterance>You mean fully clothed?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They squint through the fog at Zaphod, Head 2 out. His hands keep trying to get it down but the 3rd arm keeps whacking them away. He disappears into the fog.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, but I can't for the life of me figure out why you, the most brilliant woman I have ever met, have ended up with that half-witted, self-obsessed, vapid politician! I mean, look at him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clearly unlike any guy I've ever met.  Look, if you're going to pout your way around space, then maybe you should just go home.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't. That's the whole point -- and I've been trying to tell you...</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the guide to Trillian. She keeps walking.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, look what I found in the guide.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't tell her if I were you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She deserves to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if you tell her and she ends up with you because you're literally the last guy on Earth -- you'll always doubt her intentions. Arthur considers this. Nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got your towel?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do I need it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford puts his towel to his mouth as they follow Trillian down the mist covered street. She's reading the guide.</context>
      <utterance>Only always.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the beginning, the universe was created. This made a lot of people very angry and has been widely regarded as a bad move. Zaphod continues several steps ahead of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Many races believe that it was created by some sort of God, though the Jatravartid people of Viltvodle 6 firmly believe that the entire Universe was in fact sneezed out of the nose of a being called the Great Green Arkleseizure. The Jatravartids, who live in perpetual fear</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>of the time they call "The Coming of Great White Handkerchief" are small blue creatures with more than fifty arms each. ...who are therefore unique in being the only race in history to have invented the aerosol deodorant before the wheel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SLAM. Zaphod's two arms shove his chin back down.</context>
      <utterance>Humma Kavula!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>56a EXT. SEEDY STREET-VILTVODLE 56a The others approach, watching Zaphod as he stops a passing an eight-armed alien creature, asks him something, oozing charm. The creature points down the street with 3 arms, then with 2 others hands him a pen and paper. Zaphod signs an autograph and moves on. The alien beams, then squirts three cans of aerosol under several arms. More mist rises. FOLLOW IT UP revealing: 57 A LARGE BUILDING -- a temple with two giant arches. 57 The others follow. CAMERA TILTS UP and we see this building looks like a nose lying horizontally, the "giant arches" are the nostrils.</context>
      <utterance>I'll handle this.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Instead of bowing, they all point their noses heavenward. Zaphod marches down the center aisle while Humma prays.</context>
      <utterance>The handkerchief is coming, beloveds. Are you ready? Let us pray that the almighty will exhale a breath of compassion on us.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Zaphod stops a few feet away from Humma's chair.</context>
      <utterance>Almighty Arkleseizure, we lift our noses, clogged and unblown in reverence to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Humma.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's Humma Kavula? I thought he was just using a swear word.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Humma Kavula was his opponent in the election. Something happened during the campaign. Zaphod never forgave him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford shrugs. HUMMA looks up, sees Zaphod, smiles.</context>
      <utterance>What was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Send the handkerchief, lord, so that it may wipe us clean. We ask this in your precious holy name...</utterance>
   <speaker>CONGREGATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And they all sneeze. Akin to crossing himself, Humma raises a hand to his nose, then down again.</context>
      <utterance>Achoo.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zaphod Beeblebrox, our famous President. The Arkleseizure has exhaled many blessings upon you. What brings you to our humble planet?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you know why I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I think you think you don't, but we both know -- you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Elequent as always, Zaphod. Your ability to communicate a clear thought never ceases to amaze.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You called me stupid!</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMKA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Interesting. And I don't know what you're talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD HEAD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>During the campaign, Humma -- you said I was stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This Humma you speak of no longer exists. He came here in his consolation position as Ambassador to Gamma Z10 to squelch an ideological threat to the system and repented from his wicked ways. He now goes by the holy name Tazelo the Unceasingly Righteous, given to him by his devoted followers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do I get the feeling he's going to get us all killed?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Humma lays his palms on the table and lifts himself as if to stand - but there is nothing of him below the table line except for thirty, one inch metal legs, attached to the base of his torso. He glides towards Zaphod, the little legs extending to reach the floor as he reaches the end of the table.</context>
      <utterance>Probably because it's very possible. Just don't save me, okay? We're even.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A guard drapes a white robes over Humma's shoulders - which he ties with a belt - hiding his peculiar undercarriage.</context>
      <utterance>The election is ancient history, Zaphod, but if memory serves -- you won, proving that good looks and charm win over brilliance and ability to govern.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>His head jerks up. Zaphod stops it, paints on a smile.</context>
      <utterance>And incidently -- you are stupid.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's really not the point.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod doesn't answer. Humma motions to a guard who grabs his arm, twists it -- hard.</context>
      <utterance>You haven't come halfway across the galaxy to settle a campaign grudge. Why are you here, Zaphod?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls the nose off his body guard, turns a key. A secret safe door slides open from the mans' chest.</context>
      <utterance>How very, very...  ...improbable.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Another, smaller box rises from the chest cabinet. Inside we see glowing jewels, a skeleton hand, etc. Humma removes a PINK CUBE (like Zaphod's blue cube.)</context>
      <utterance>I kept a few souvenirs from my former life. Ah, the heady days of space piracy... so young, so foolish..,</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>COORDINATE NUMBERS on each side. Zaphod reaches for it. Humma takes it back...</context>
      <utterance>I'll gladly give you the coordinates to Magrathea... He holds up the pink cube revealing A SERIES OF</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...provided you bring me something in return.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A very special gun. Designed by the greatest computer ever invented, now buried in the bowels of Magrathea.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod reaches out. Humma pulls it back.</context>
      <utterance>Fine. I'll get your gun. Just give me the coordinates.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what will you give me to insure your return?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My word as President.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ha! I'd be better off with the dung of a Bethusian Mega Donkey.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, then I'll get you that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HUMMA KAVULA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ON ZAPHOD'S SECOND HEAD -- peeping out of the collar looking terrified. Humma smiles. Bingo. He signals the guards. They grab Zaphod who looks back to Trillian, offers a weak smile.</context>
      <utterance>I need a hostage, something you hold dear. Only what does Zaphod Beeblebrox treasure?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we sure this is the right way?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! I think. I don't know. Maybe not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford looks puzzled at Arthur. Did I clear it up? A crowd has gathered. When they see Zaphod, they scream...</context>
      <utterance>Yes, thank you for clearing that up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CROWD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod, still feeling the effects of whatever drugs he was given, dons a presidential smile and waves.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. President!...Zaphod, over here!...I want to have your baby!, etc...</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FIFTY VOGON POLICE -- emerge from the mist.</context>
      <utterance>Back to the ship. Quickly. They quicken their pace when suddenly...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON POLICE #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod, Ford, Trillian and Arthur freeze in their tracks.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. President! We are here for your protection!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The police fire. F, T, &amp; A run for it, but Z stays put.</context>
      <utterance>Fire upon the kidnapper!  EXT. MAIN STREET -</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zarquon! Friendly fire! Well, if that's what they want-- He pulls out his gun up and fires back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>With each line he fires. Ford grabs him. Shots hit a stack of aerosol cans. They EXPLODE. More mist rises. (63 cont) INT. VOGON HEADQUARTERS - (63 cont)</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Let's do lunch! Nice haircut, fella! Hey! Your kids are the same age as mine-- We should get them together some time!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commander! The President is the kidnapper!</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(62 cont) BEHIND THE KIOSK-- (62 cont} The gang run down an alley and hide behind a kiosk. Zaphod sports a goofy smile. Arthur is scared to death.</context>
      <utterance>Cease fire!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, I really hate Thursdays.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zaphod, what do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up two peace signs, a la Nixon.</context>
      <utterance>Build bridges between the stars!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian finds a deodorant can, grabs it, gets an idea.</context>
      <utterance>I think that was his campaign slogan.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She aims the can at Zaphod's ear- Arthur's face registers the madness of the moment.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, follow me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(62 cont) ON SCREEN -- Trillian, with aerosol can to Zaphod's ear (62 cont) moves down the street. The crowd GASPS. The quartet continues anxiously forward, eyeing the police whose guns track their every move.</context>
      <utterance>There they are!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back off or I'll kill him, I swear I will! KWALTZ -- looks confused.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(62 cont) The police step backwards -- but the crowd takes a step (62 cont) forward. A huddle of female ADMIRERS rush them, waving pens and paper as if the Beatles have arrived.</context>
      <utterance>Could that actually kill him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADMIRERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod paints on a smile, breaks away from the others to go sign a few autographs.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. President, Mr. President!...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE ADMIRER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I totally voted for you!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reveal that the female fans are actually a multi-headed, two legged GROUPIE. (63 cont) ON QUESTULAR AND KWALTZ-- (63 cont)</context>
      <utterance>Thank you!</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(62 cont) CHAOS! The walrusy Vogon police swarm in like maggots, (62 cont) surrounding Trillian and edging Ford and Arthur away.</context>
      <utterance>Get her!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON POLICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shots are fired. The crowd SCREAMS and SCATTERS. Arthur reaches for Trillian but she is engulfed by Vogons who move, en masse, and pull her away into the mist.</context>
      <utterance>Resistance is useless!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford, with Zaphod in tow, shoves Arthur forward, using his towel to clear a path through the mist. They see the Heart of Gold ramp descending from the belly of the ship.</context>
      <utterance>Tricia!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This way!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The captain nods. The screen goes black.</context>
      <utterance>Bring her to Vogsphere for processing, Captain.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're coming here!? But they've only accomplished half the mission. What about Zaphod? HE MUST FACE JUSTICE!!</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From a slot in his chair, he pulls his instructions -- signed in triplicate of course. He reads...</context>
      <utterance>My instructions were clear...</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Questular pulls out another small clump of hair.</context>
      <utterance>"Apprehend the kidnapper, rescue the president." We do them in that order. And until the kidnapper is properly processed, she isn't officially apprehended, now is she, Mr. Vice- President?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to go! Let's GO!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking strangely happy, he slides the PINK COORDINATE CUBE Humma gave him into a slot on the console.</context>
      <utterance>Right!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Computer! Take us to Magrathea!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? No! Follow those ships!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey -- my third arm. I had one, didn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The computer fires to life, BLEEPS and BLIPS. Only now it has an effete, effeminate, almost matriarchal voice.</context>
      <utterance>We have to go after her!</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look at the source of the voice, confused.</context>
      <utterance>Boys, please! Not so rough. You're damaging my joystick.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ghastly, isn't it? I was asked to change the personality type, this was the emergency back-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How, if you want me to take you somewhere, we're going to have to start using our magic words, "please" and "thank you."</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you change it back?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can -- but I won't enjoy it.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur sees the Vogon ships getting away. Desperate, he shoves_Zaphod out of_the_driver's seat. Zaphod hits the floor, considers protesting, lies down on the floor to sleep instead -- with a contented smile. Arthur sits. He looks very out of place in a seat normally reserved for the likes of Han Solo. He scans the console. Ford sits in the seat beside him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm wait-ing...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ford?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marvin?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't look at me. I'm too depressed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Computer?! Isn't there some kind of manual override switch thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeeessss...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Magic words?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show me the override switch or I'll reprogram you with a very large axe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford pushes a big button. AN ALARM SOUNDS!</context>
      <utterance>I think I should push this button.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that? What happened?!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur grabs the control, does his best to steer.</context>
      <utterance>A sign lit up saying "Please do not push this button again."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Dreadful, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry about the landing. Where are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Magrathea!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wrong. This is the Vogon planet. This is Vogsphere.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford reaches in his satchel, pulls out a sort of ELECTRONIC BERET, pulls it snugly onto Zaphod's head.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's Magrathea! I know it!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Little something I learned about on an Altairian star cruiser. Captains use them when they really need to concentrate.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod squints hard to think as he looks around.</context>
      <utterance>A Thinking Cap.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marvin moves out, a few paces behind.</context>
      <utterance>This will all end in tears, I just know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I checked the guide for ways to rescue a prisoner from Vogsphere. It said "Don't." I'm assuming your plan is better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A TELESCOPIC ROD WITH A PADDLE AT THE TOP shoots out of the ground, SMACKS Arthur on the face, then retracts. Arthur is stunned. None of the others have noticed.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I sort of had this idea we could...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did anyone see that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look at Arthur. It suddenly seems ridiculous.</context>
      <utterance>See what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all walk along - Arthur at the back, perplexed.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another paddle springs up, double smack in the face. Arthur leaps back. Looks down. Nothing. Nothing at all.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Just my imagination.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>They watch. Arthur walks. And walks.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, stop. Everyone stop and watch me. Something's happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A paddle springs up and smacks Ford's face.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. I think we...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur lifts his feet very carefully.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He stops himself and looks round.</context>
      <utterance>I th...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Zaphod pulls his thinking cap down, thinks hard.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think, Zaphod?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A paddle shoots up, smacks Zaphod's face. They all saw.</context>
      <utterance>I think we should keep going.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the blazes is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A paddle shoots up. Ford ducks. It misses. He grabs its telescopic stalk. It thrashes in his hands. He breaks it.</context>
      <utterance>I have... an idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A beat. They all strain to think of nothing. Several paddles shoot up. Smacking them.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, don't think of anything. Don't have ideas or theories -- nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't, help it! Trillian is in there somewhere and we need an idea to save her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have an idea.  Run!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They take off running. A forest of paddle stalks erupts out of the ground around them, smacking violently. They come to rest at the side of a Vogon building.</context>
      <utterance>Ever the politician.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, so...  ...not thinking, not thinking, no ideas coming...  ...this is by no means an idea that has any merit, but Marvin -- can you give me a hand?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alright, where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON BEHIND COUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur looks at the arm -- then slowly lowers it.</context>
      <utterance>Who? The Director of Robot Arm repair? Next building, out the door to the left.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, we're looking for...  ...someone you're detaining, perhaps in some form of incarceration...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON BEHIND COUNTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Prisoner Release Department. Six buildings down, out the door, right, left, then two rights. Big gray building, can't miss it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>VOGON OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Name?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He types into his ancient looking computer.</context>
      <utterance>Trillian.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not registered.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try Tricia McMillan.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tricia Yggarstuk McMillanus of Blaard?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Officer types, checks his screen, shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>No. Tricia Imogene McMillan of Earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. No record of "Earth."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOGON OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PUSH IN ON TRILLIAN -- gutted by the news.</context>
      <utterance>Right. Here it is. "Earth. Destroyed." Do you have a second home planet?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Destroyed? No -- that's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Says here it was destroyed to make way for a hyperspace expressway. The order was given...three weeks ago.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>THEIR P.O.V. -- all the buildings are gray. Arthur sees 2 VOGON POLICE escorting someone in handcuffs into one of the buildings.</context>
      <utterance>He said the gray building, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There. That's it. This way. He raises Marvin's arm, pointing the fingers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kwaltz now steps forward and extends a piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>I don't believe you. This is some sort of trick. Zaphod wouldn't blow up a planet, especially mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian takes the paper, runs her finger down to the signature line where it reads "Love and kisses, Zaphod!"</context>
      <utterance>These are the orders.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love and kisses...? She hands the paper back, swallowing emotion.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(74 cont) INT. PRISONER PROCESSING BUILDING/MAIN ROOM - CONTINUOUS (74 cont) Zaphod is in line with Arthur and Ford. He looks up to: A PRESIDENTIAL PHOTOGRAPH -- of himself, in suit and tie, smiling broadly. He lowers his thinking cap.</context>
      <utterance>Now -- according to Section 8, sub-section 34 dash A, the punishment for kidnapping is a recitation of the classic poem, "Ode to the Removal of Your Left Kidney." Unless -- said kidnapping is of the President, in which case you are to be fed to the Ravenous Bugblatter Beast of Traal. We thank you for your cooperation. A door is opened revealing a room with a large steel box. A huge, angry eye stares out of a tiny barred window. The box shakes like crazy. Trillian gulps.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE VOGON PROCESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur steps up, followed by Ford and Zaphod who keeps his head low and bowed.</context>
      <utterance>Next!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Hi. We're here about getting a prisoner released?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE VOGON PROCESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds out her hand. Arthur doesn't have a form. Annoyed, she points across the room to a wall that is nothing but shelves holding forms.</context>
      <utterance>Prisoner release form?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>69.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>HHGG 3rd Revised Draft 8/8/03 CONTINUED:</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Once I've filled it out can I return to the front of the line, seeing as I've already waited...</utterance>
   <speaker>FEMALE VOGON PROCESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur sighs, frustrated. All three of them walk to the shelves holding the forms. Arthur turns to Zaphod.</context>
      <utterance>No. Next!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you do something?! You're President, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur angrily fills out the form.</context>
      <utterance>You want me to make a speech, shake a hand? That's what I do -- I think. It's all a little fuzzy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FEMALE VOGON PROCESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur's breathing quickens. He can't take this.</context>
      <utterance>This Prisoner is being detained for...  Kidnapping the president. Not eligible for release at this time. You can make an appointment for a later date or take a number and wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at Zaphod, then back to the large portrait of Zaphod, then back to Zaphod. She nods. Okay...</context>
      <utterance>Alright, look.  This is the President.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FEMALE VOGON PROCESSOR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She reviews the form, stamps it, pulls off the carbon copy underneath, hands that to Zaphod.</context>
      <utterance>Okay...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOGON PROCESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a couple of VOGON GUARDS enter and hand Kwaltz a blue piece of paper. He reviews it, then signs it.</context>
      <utterance>Go to the Prisoner Release Lobby, out the door, right, left, 2nd door on the right.  BACK WITH TRILLIAN --  As she braces herself to be eaten by the monster.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Vogon Guard pulls Trillian up and out of the box on a cable. The Bugblatter beast goes berserk.</context>
      <utterance>You're free to go. Release her.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What!?  He's here?! Zaphod is here!? Let's go get him! But the Guard is already escorting Trillian out of the room. Kwaltz is completing paperwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Kwaltz holds up a walrusy hand, one finger raised, silencing Questular while he continues. Questular sighs. We hear the Bugblatter beast weeping as the doors are closed on him.</context>
      <utterance>Commander?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bastard. You signed the order to destroy Earth?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Love and kisses, Zaphod?" I saw the form. You didn't even read it, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honey, I'm President of the Galaxy. I don't get a lot of time for reading.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She SLAPS him again, storms away, bursting out the door.</context>
      <utterance>An entire planet, Zaphod. My home. Gone. All because you thought someone wanted your autograph!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They framed me! It's routine for controlling Presidents!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trillian...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew. Why didn't you tell me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I tried. He threatened me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She storms ahead of him. He stops.</context>
      <utterance>Get a backbone, Arthur.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(77 cont) EXT. PRISONER PROCESSING BLDG. - MOMENTS LATER (77 cont) Kwaltz and Questular, flanked by the Vogon police force, step out of the building just in time to see... 78 ...THE GLASS HEART OF GOLD POD soaring overhead. 78 They all watch as it disappears from sight.</context>
      <utterance>What about coming here to rescue you?! That was my brilliant idea! A paddle shoots up and slaps him in the face.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The President tests my patience. This time, I shall pursue him myself. Ready my ship!</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! This is more like it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, fellas. Hold on to your hats!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ship suddenly BLASTS forward. Their heads are slammed back into the seats as they VIBRATE VIOLENTLY.</context>
      <utterance>Eddie! Welcome back!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, that's it...I think. Computer? Is that...where are we headed again?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Magrathea?</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang on, fella, and I'll check.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and stares, wipes the tears away. Can't speak.</context>
      <utterance>Look, you're right. You deserved to know and I should've told you. I don't blame you if you're angry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Anyway...I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Hearing this news, Arthur, Trillian and Ford turn.</context>
      <utterance>Guys, it just tickles me pink to tell you we are currently in orbit at an altitude of three hundred miles around the legendary planet of Magrathea. Goll-ee.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>83a EXT. NIGHT DEEP SPACE - MAGRATHEA 83a They all stare in awe as they move toward a planet which gets closer and closer. Suddenly, their faces are awash with light. Two suns rise behind the planet. It's breathtaking.</context>
      <utterance>Take us in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marvin (both arms in tact) rises in the back, peers out.</context>
      <utterance>The twin suns of Soulianis and Rahm...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>83b Suddenly,a ghostly white swirl of light, vaguely in the 83b shape of a man, appears on the screen before them.</context>
      <utterance>It's rubbish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Closed? How can a planet be closed?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For once, Aldus, I agree with you. Okay, computer. Keep going. Take us down.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ship eases forward. The image appears again.</context>
      <utterance>Happy to!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>83c The screens show two huge rockets thundering at us, 83c Zaphod just smiles. Ford steps up.</context>
      <utterance>Guys, I'm delighted to tell you there are two thermonuclear missiles headed right for us. Should I take evasive action?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Massive acceleration! An illuminated dome lowers from the ceiling over the crew seats - creating a safety pod.</context>
      <utterance>Um...yes, computer. Evade!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(84 cont) EXT. SKY OVER MAGRATHEA - CONTINUOUS (84 cont) The H.O.G. streaks forward. The missiles are gaining.</context>
      <utterance>There seems to be something jamming my guidance systems. Impact minus 45 seconds. Call me Eddie if it'll help you relax.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Computer! DO SOMETHING!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big swell of Muzak. The ship drops like a stone. THE MISSILES -- miss, then turn in a screeching curve. (85 cont) INT. THE SAFETY POD - (85 cont) Zaphod tries to wrestle with three controls.</context>
      <utterance>Sure thing, fellah. Handing over manual control. Good luck!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(84 cont) THE H.O.G. -- spirals wildly, missiles narrowly missing. (84 cont) (85 cont) IN THE SAFETY POD - everyone is thrown. (85 cont) (84 cont) IN THE SKY -- the missiles are dead ahead, shooting (84 cont) straight for us. (85 cont) IN THE SAFETY POD-- (85 cont)</context>
      <utterance>I can't do this without my other arm!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did we lose them?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks down, sees the IMPROBABILITY DRIVE BUTTON.</context>
      <utterance>No. They're right behind us.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, why don't I just hit this thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The missiles turn and accelerate high into the sky. A second set of boosters kick in on the missiles as they soar back toward the H.O.G. --- much, much faster. (85 cont) ON THE BRIDGE-- (85 cont) They all stare at the approaching missiles. Arthur looks at the drive button. Screw it. He flips open the glass lid.</context>
      <utterance>NO! We're here! No telling where it will send us!  IN THE SKY--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um...where are we?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly where we were, I think.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the missiles?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the screen. The whale and petunias float by.</context>
      <utterance>Have apparently turned into a bowl of petunias and a very surprised looking whale.</utterance>
   <speaker>EDDIE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look to Arthur who shrugs. Zaphod nods his approval. Ford counts on his fingers -- are they even? He waves it off, gives Arthur a little salute and moves on. Trillian looks to Arthur and musters a smile.</context>
      <utterance>At an improbability factor of eight million, seven hundred and sixty-seven thousand, one hundred and twenty-eight to one against.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could really use a cup of tea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WHALE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>ANGLE: From below. The whale is wriggling a bit.</context>
      <utterance>Ahhhh!!!! What's happening? Excuse me! Who am I? Hello? Why am I here? What's my purpose in life? What do I mean by who am I? What is this 'I' that I want to know what it is? Calm down, get a grip now ... ooh! This is an interesting sensation...</utterance>
   <speaker>WHALE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The whale thrashes its tail. Between the camera and the whale drops the bowl of petunias. It falls from sight.</context>
      <utterance>Oh! This is an interesting sensation, what is it? It's a sort of... yawning, tingling sensation in ... well I suppose I'd better start finding names for things if I want to make any headway in what for the sake of what I shall call an argument I shall call the world, so let's call it my stomach! Good. Ooooh! It's getting quite strong now. And hey,what's this whistling roaring sound going past what I'm suddenly going to call my head? Perhaps I can call that ... wind! Is that a good name? It'll do. Perhaps I can give it a better name later when I've found out what it's for! It must be very important because there certainly seems to be an awful lot of it. Hey! What's this thing ... this ... let's call it a tail - yeah! Tail!</utterance>
   <speaker>WHALE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>It's eye tries to look down. Camera pulls back from the whale, abandoning it ...</context>
      <utterance>Hey! I can really thrash it about pretty good, can't I? Wow! Wow! Doesn't seem to achieve much but I'll probably find out what it's for later on. How. Have I built up a coherent picture of things yet? No. Never mind. Hey, this is really exciting, so much to find out about, ao much to look forward to, I'm quite dizzy with anticipation ... Or is it the wind? There really is an awful lot of that now, isn't there?</utterance>
   <speaker>WHALE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>suddenly coming towards me very fast, so big and flat and round it needs a big wide-sounding name like ... ow ... ound...round ... ground! That's it, ground! I wonder if it'll be friends with me? We hear a sickening thud o.s.</context>
      <utterance>And hey! What's this thing coming</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Curiously, the only thing that went through the mind of the bowl of petunias as it fell was "Oh no, not again." We hear the petunia vase SHATTERING.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Many have speculated that if we knew why the bowl of petunias had thought that we would know a lot more about the nature of the Universe than we do now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FORD (CONT'D}</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be portal doors.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the middle of the circle sits a stone receptionist desk with a sign on it that says "OUT TO LUNCH." Zaphod heads for the "To Design Department" stone. Trillian and Ford follow. Zaphod feels around it, looking for a switch, a knob, anything. He must've hit something because the front of the stone suddenly slides open revealing a SWIRLING</context>
      <utterance>You mean -- the hippies were right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?! Are you out of what's left of your mind? We can't step into that...that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta pick one, right? If it's not the right one, we come back and pick another. No biggie.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trillian, who hasn't said a word since leaving Vogsphere, covers her ears - trying to block them out</context>
      <utterance>Yes -- big biggie. What if that's the last door we ever step through? What if it rips us into tiny little atomic particle...thingies.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the right one. I have a hunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ford..?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got good hunches. I say we go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go with the hunch of a narcissist with half a brain who's wearing a ridiculous thinking cap!? Are you insane?!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I think I resent that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all start arguing over each other. We focus on Trillian -- Anger and frustration building, she covers her ears -- then screams....</context>
      <utterance>I don't care what you think you think...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He runs after Ford, stops at the door, turns like he's about to board Air Force one, gives a salute, jumps in. Arthur finally gets his legs to move, steps up -- but hesitates at the threshold, paralyzed with fear, unable to take a step. Then -- FFSSSSH - the door seals shut.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, wait for me!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He bangs on the stone, slides his hand around like Zaphod did, desperately looking for a way to open it. He collapses and buries his head in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>No. No! NOOO!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you this would all end in tears.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life is full of paradoxes, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk to me about life.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here I am, God knows how far from home...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't talk to me about God.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and this is where I see the most spectacular sunset I've ever laid eyes on. We only had the one sun at home. Planet called Earth.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. You keep going on about it. It sounds awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh no, it's beautiful. Or at least, it was...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did it have oceans?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Great wide rolling blue oceans.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur looks up at Marvin.</context>
      <utterance>Can't bear oceans.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So this is how it will all end, then? Me, on a dead planet -- with a manically depressed robot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think you've got problems? What are you supposed to do if you are a manically depressed robot? No, don't bother to answer that, I'm fifty thousand times more intelligent than you and even I don't know the answer. It gives me a headache just trying to think down to your level.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode>0.S.</mode>
      <context>Arthur spins to see AN OLD, BEARDED MAN IN LONG ROBES.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He jumps, crab walks backwards away from the man.</context>
      <utterance>Aah!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur continues to scramble away from the man.</context>
      <utterance>My name is not important.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must come with me. Terrible events are afoot. You must come or you'll be late.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Late? What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is your name, Earthman?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dent. Arthur Dent.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He motions to the stone that is marked "To Showroom."</context>
      <utterance>Late as in "the late Dentarthurdent." It's a sort of threat you see. Never been much good at them myself, but I'm told they can be terribly effective.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your friends are safe. You can trust me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust a man who won't tell me his name?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur reacts with a furrowed brow.</context>
      <utterance>My name? Very well...  My name is...Slartibartfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Slartibartfast motions to the door. He looks to Marvin.</context>
      <utterance>I said it wasn't important.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur rises, cautiously moves over to Slarti's side.</context>
      <utterance>I could calculate your chances of survival -- but you won't like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts his hand on a certain spot in the stone and presses. The stone dissolves revealing once again the jet engine swirling vortex. Slarti motions -- after you. Arthur takes a deep breath -- and steps in.</context>
      <utterance>I must warn you. We are about to pass through, well, a sort of gateway thing. It may disturb you. It scares the willies out of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is bent, twisted and sucked away. Slarti follows. Marvin stands for a moment, then looks up to... 92a THE SKY-- 92a where the fleet of Vogon ships has now arrived.</context>
      <utterance>Whaa!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funny how just when you think life can't possibly get any worse, it suddenly does.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you you might find it a bit disturbing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur realizes he has his towel with him. He wipes his mouth with it, dabs his brow. Then he notices... ...THE ROOM -- which is like a car dealer's showroom only instead of cars there are models of various planets.</context>
      <utterance>I have found this whole day a bit disturbing.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No. Arthur didn't know that. He looks perplexed.</context>
      <utterance>Did you know we built planets?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The best laid plans of mice, you know...</context>
      <utterance>Fascinating trade. Doing the coastlines was always my favorite. Used to have endless fun doing all the little fiddly bits round fjords. But the Galactic economy collapsed, and seeing that custom- built planets are something of a luxury commodity...  At any rate, there's been a terrible mix up with your planet. You must come with me or it's all going to blow up in our faces.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and men.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmm? What?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The best laid plans of mice and men.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He quickens his pace. Trillian and Ford follow. They round the corner to find... DEEP THOUGHT -- sitting there majestically. The TINNY MUSIC emanates from somewhere near him. Zaphod takes another step in and now sees the source of the TINNY MUSIC. Deep Thought is watching TV. A violent, stupid cartoon.</context>
      <utterance>This is it!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Deep Thought...!</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cartoon continues. Zaphod enters, removes his thinking cap and reverently approaches. He kneels...</context>
      <utterance>Shhh. This is a good bit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh great Deep Thought...we have traveled long...and far. Have you calculated... the Ultimate Question? Of Life, the Universe and Everything?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHQD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been watching TV.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod holds a smile but his world is slowly crumbling.</context>
      <utterance>Oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I designed another computer to perform that great task.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, right...I forgot.  Is it here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not here. Another world.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's on another world?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is another world. Or was.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod turns to Ford. Ford looks confused.</context>
      <utterance>Ask your companion.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Zaphod looks to Trillian. She looks equally confused. Zaphod puts the thinking cap back on. Strains hard.</context>
      <utterance>Not him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>0kay -- you're sure you don't have the Question? Or a way to you, you know -- access it or something. I think I've done like a lot to get here...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod looks up. Deep Thought is shushing him?</context>
      <utterance>Shhhhhh...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A robotic arm reaches out and turns up the volume. Zaphod stands, turns to Ford and Trillian, smiles that smile -- but it's starting to look a bit crazed.</context>
      <utterance>The show's back on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great. This is just great. Let's go find something else for my entire life to be about. He starts to march off. Ford grabs his arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zaphod. The gun? The one Humma sent us for? We have to get it. You gave the guy your head.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls his thinking cap down -- all the way over his eyes. Ford rolls his eyes, turns...</context>
      <utterance>I know. Why did I do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he finishes the sentence, a PANEL in the wall slides open revealing a LARGE, SCARY LOOKING GUN. A robotic arm pushes it forward. Ford goes over, takes it, carries it like it's nitroglycerin to Zaphod who's already walking away,</context>
      <utterance>Um...Deep Thought? We we're told you have a g...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORRIDOR LEADING AWAY FROM DEEP THOUGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ford hands Zaphod the gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Zaphod takes it with a smile...</context>
      <utterance>Here. Take it. I don't do guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...and instantly points it at his head. Ford lunges for it. There's a struggle. Ford's trying to get Zaphod's finger off the trigger when CLICK! The trigger is pulled. Ford winces. But apparently, nothing has happened.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great! This is a bust, too!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod isn't sure what just happened. But he smiles anyway. Trillian, however, is onto something.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, man, you must be really frustrated. To go through all you did only to come here and get no answer, which means no fame and money, and you deserve that, man. Because you're great -- you're just really, really great.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me that thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The galaxy was a bit of a shambles, you see. Everyone enjoying themselves being singers and comedians and really creative and interesting things like that. No one doing the boring jobs.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, you had that problem, too?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In spades. So a species was genetically engineered to do the boring jobs. Tax inspectors, traffic wardens, government officials. We were commissioned to build a special planet for them. Problem was, some cleverdick made it so any time one of the creatures had an interesting idea it would get a hefty smack around the face.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cart lowers down toward the surface of the planet.</context>
      <utterance>What? You did that? I've been there!</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I gather you've met some of the inhabitants.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Vogons?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relentless blighters.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>PULL BACK TO REVEAL -- Ford is hesitantly aiming the gun at Zaphod.</context>
      <utterance>...and you're right, I shouldn't be so upset 'cause life goes on and I should just go on with it, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford reluctantly pulls the trigger. CLICK.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hitchhiking is good. Towels are good, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brilliant.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She take the gun from him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I kinda like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She starts walking.</context>
      <utterance>A gun that makes people suddenly see things from your point of view. Useful tool for the deranged evangelist trying to convert the masses, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should get back. Arthur's waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who cares?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do -- especially since we're both somewhat of an endangered species now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course you're edgy, your planet's been blown up and you've been tooling around the Galaxy with the guy who signed the order CLICK. She shoots him again.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You actually wanted to know the Question because you always thought there was more to life, and now you're crushed because you find out there really isn't. She's getting angrier and more hurt. CLICK.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Hearing this puts a lump in her throat, causes her eyes to well with tears. She lowers the gun. Zaphod shakes his head -- the effect wearing off. But he realizes what he said and doesn't like it.</context>
      <utterance>You've got no home, no family, no one to be with -- and you're stuck with me, another in a long line of men who doesn't appreciate you because he's too busy appreciating himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He grabs the gun, points it at her.</context>
      <utterance>Give me that thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can react, A BRIGHT LIGHT SHINES BEHIND THEM. They turn, shielding their eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Won't affect me. I'm already a woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FLASH! KEEEOOOW! They are engulfed in WHITE LIGHT.</context>
      <utterance>Uh oh -- oh. It's okay, it's only a couple of...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So -- it wasn't destroyed?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earth Mark II.</context>
      <utterance>Actually, it was. This is a back-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're saying you ... made the Earth?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>101b Arthur nods. The cart pushes through the clouds, towards 101b Ayers Rock. A GUY ON A LADDER is painting it it's familiar red color. Some of it is still primer grey.</context>
      <utterance>Well, not me alone. It was a group effort. I did my part, though. Ever heard of a place, I think it's called Norway?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was one of mine. Won an award you know. Lovely crinkly edges. I was sorry to hear about it being blown up. Shocking cock up. The mice were furious.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mice? Who cares about bloody mice?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>101c ANOTHER MAN pushes a button causing mountains to spring 101c up noisily.</context>
      <utterance>Are you a fan of plate tectonics? Arthur looks up. Slartibartfast points down.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Arthur is working very hard to process all this. 101d JUMP CUT. They move through a forest where a man presses 101d a lever making several MUSHROOMS pop up on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Voila! Himalayas. Good, eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The transport cart flies out of forest toward the ocean.</context>
      <utterance>Earthman, you must realize that the planet you lived on was commissioned, paid for, and run by mice. It was destroyed shortly before the completion of the purpose for which it was built. Ten minutes later, we would have been free and clear. But we gave them our standard ten million year warranty and they have come here to retrieve this back-up copy. And they've brought you with them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They brought...I'm sorry, when you say "mice" do you mean the little white furry creatures with the cheese fixation?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These creatures you call "mice" are merely the protrusion into our dimension of hyper- intelligent pan-dimensional beings. The whole business with the cheese must've been a front. They were experimenting on you, you see. A vast computer program...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>101e Over the ocean, a "Perfect Storm" wave rolls toward them. 101e</context>
      <utterance>Ah. I see where you're confused. You see -- we were experimenting on them.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>101f They move toward the white cliffs of Dover. A man stands 101f on a cliff holding a giant hose, water spewing from it.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I gather they arranged for you to conduct some primitively staged experiments so they could prod your thinking here and there. But you were actually elements in the computer program. They really are very clever hyper- intelligent pan-dimensional beings.  Ah. They've nearly finished the oceans.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So -- you're trying to tell me that mice designed and built Deep Thought...and Deep Thought designed the Earth...which was a giant supercomputer...that you built...to calculate the Ultimate Question. Only, Vogons destroyed it ten minutes before the program was completed?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's bureaucracy for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, this explains a lot. All my life I've had this strange feeling that something was going on in the world, something big, something sinister ...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone in the universe has that.</context>
      <utterance>That's just perfectly normal paranoia.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know, perhaps I'm old and tired, but I always think that the chances of finding out what's really going on are so absurdly remote that the only thing to do is say hang the sense of it and keep yourself busy. I'd much rather be happy than right any day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>l03 The platform slows to a stop. Arthur steps out and is 103 stunned to see... HIS HOUSE. It's partially constructed. The chimney lies intact on the ground, waiting to be hoisted up. A row of hedges lies on it's side beside a trench. But it's his house alright.</context>
      <utterance>No. That's where it all falls down of course.  Here we are, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slartibartfast nods. Arthur, in a daze, stumbles toward the house. 103a INT. ARTHUR DENT'S HOUSE/MARK 2 - CONTINUOUS 103a Arthur enters his house. There is no furniture, no photographs or books or any evidence of his existence there. He feels the walls, the countertops. He's home?</context>
      <utterance>Is this...?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Arthur pokes his head around a wall to find... 104 FORD, ZAPHOD AND TRILLIAN -- sitting at an elegantly set 104 table -- stuffing their faces with a meal fit for a king. 103a INT. ARTHUR DENT'S HOUSE/MARK 2 - 103a</context>
      <utterance>Arthur!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They talk while continuing to stuff food in their mouths.</context>
      <utterance>What -- what are you doing? What happened to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Funniest thing.  Our hosts attacked us with Dismodulating Anti Phase Stun Mist  then brought us to this amazing meal as a way to make it up to us . Try the mutton. It's fantastic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They can't seem to stop eating, like they've been drugged.</context>
      <utterance>Zarking incredible.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur has spotted a TEA POT on the table. He hurries to it, feels it. Warm. He pours a cup, takes a sip, Closes his eyes, enjoying it.</context>
      <utterance>Hosts attack you --? And then you sit down for -- is that tea?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now that's a cup of tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He looks down and sees THE TWO WHITE MICE sitting on a silver platter.</context>
      <utterance>We're glad you like it, Earth creature.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur stares in shock...can't speak.</context>
      <utterance>After ten million years on Earth, and a rather large chunk of that time in England, it would be utterly humiliating if we didn't know how to make a decent pot of tea.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Arthur, these are our hosts. Benjy mouse and Franky mouse . They control a large sector of the Universe in our dimension . I'm sorry, I thought you were told about the mice...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steadies himself on the table.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Yes, I was. I just wasn't quite prepared for the full reality of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benjy pushes his hand through the air, the chair at the end slides backward.</context>
      <utterance>Sit, Earthman. Eat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a moment, perhaps. I can't seem to let go of this table. Slartibartfast steps forward.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon the interruption, but I'll just be getting back to work now.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That won't be necessary, Slartibartfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smarty fart blast?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY/FRANKY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eat!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It looks like we won't be needing the new Earth after all, now that we've found the only living native of the planet.</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But...they've nearly finished the oceans.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAHKY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slarti, slightly hurt, backs away out of sight.</context>
      <utterance>That will be all, Slartibartfast.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benjy holds up a strand of hairs, same color as Trillian's.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, when you say "the only living native" -- do you mean me? What about her?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We performed some rudimentary DNA tests on the ship. She's half-native. Her real father was a Blahardid, the hyper- intelligent yet carelessly nomadic race native to the planet Olbed, who apparently popped in to Earth for a one-nighter with a one Ms. Francis McMillan.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes back to eating. Arthur is taking this all in.</context>
      <utterance>Which explains a lot.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So -- mostly harmless and me. That's it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're sorry to have stage managed you so shamelessly, but once we learned you were the only full-blooded Earthling in the universe, it was important that we get you here by any means necessary.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANKY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've spent a considerable amount of time on your planet trying to find this wretched Ultimate Question, and the thought of doing it all over again on account of those idiotic Vogons sickens me to no end. Which is why you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit, Earthling. Sit. Arthur goes to pull out the chair beside him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benjy makes a motion. The chair he pushed out before slides over behind Arthur's knees, making him sit.</context>
      <utterance>This chair is much more -- comfortable.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He slides the cup of tea over. Arthur takes a sip.</context>
      <utterance>Drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmm. This really is delicious.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ford and Zaphod raise their glasses like drunken sailors.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Glad you like it. Now -- to business.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD/ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Benjy and Franky fire them a look.</context>
      <utterance>To business!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Thought you were proposing a toast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>FRANKY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But - and here's the point - we have to have product. Which means we still need an ultimate question.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or at least, one that sounds ultimate.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKY HOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Got to sound good.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An Ultimate Question that sounds good... From a couple of mice...for a chat show.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Franky tries to pour more tea. Arthur stops drinking, a little woozy. Did he hear them right?</context>
      <utterance>And as it turns out, the chances are astronomically high that the structure of the question is encoded in your brain. Which is why we need it. More tea?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry -- did you just say you need my brain?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. To extract the question.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't have my brain. I'm using it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Barely.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can replace it if you think it's important. An electronic brain maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A simple one should suffice. Who would know the difference?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur tries to get up. Clamps spring up from the chair and wrap around his arms. A dome flips over from the back and slams down on his head. Arthur struggles.</context>
      <utterance>No, you wouldn't. We could program you not to.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ford! Zaphod! TRILLIAN!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mice on the platter move ominously toward Arthur. Arthur, still attached to the chair, backs away. Scythes and rotating arms with circular saw blades shoot out -- ominous surgical equipment to remove his brain.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. You won't feel a thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait a minute, JUST WAIT A SODDING</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want the question that goes with the answer "42" How about "What's six times seven?" Or "How many Vogons does it take to screw in a lightbulb?" Or here's one, "How many roads must a man walk down?"</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Through the opposite window (in much the same way bulldozers arrived in the opening) we see more Vogons arriving.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, that's not bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine. Take it. There's plenty more where that came from because my head is filled, with questions, and I can assure you mate, no answer to any of them has ever brought me one iota of happiness. Confusion? Yes. Indecision? Loads. But happiness...? He shakes his head.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't want to be happy. We want to be rich.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take his brain.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BENJY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They try to lift the POV gun but it's way too heavy. Arthur, his butt still strapped in the chair, leaps over to the table and grabs the first thing he sees -- a leg of mutton. He raises it high. Benjy and Franky look up.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot him!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANKY MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur brings the mutton down, squashing them flat. The others instantly snap out of their food induced haze, Zaphod suddenly clutches his gut.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur looks up and now he sees the Vogons marching down the hill toward the house. He leans over the table, bumping his teacup. IT SHATTERS TO THE GROUND.</context>
      <utterance>Ohhhh, I think I'm gonna be sick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="140" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I must warn you, I'm feeling very depressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>KWALTZ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod appears at the front door and waves Presidentially.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. President! We are here for your protection!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>106 The Police open fire. Zaphod and the others flee as the 106 barrage of fire continues. Trillian drops the POV gun, goes back for it. Arthur stops her and pulls her behind the truck. Marvin catches a bullet in the back of his head - sparks fly and he is thrown forwards! Is he dead?</context>
      <utterance>Thank you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="141" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay -- that thing I said about not saving my life because we're even? Scratch that. Save at will.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need that gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need tighter gun control!</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up his towel.</context>
      <utterance>We need his other head.  Okay -- I'll create a distraction.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brilliant plan. I'm certain it will work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="142" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Duck!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks to the skies just as Ford fans out his towel and uses it to bring Z, A &amp; T to the ground just as...</context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="143" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zaphod takes the gun, fires it at Questular. He rises -- and paints on a big smile.</context>
      <utterance>Shoot me. Please Zaphod. Shoot me.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTULAR (CONT'D}</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Questular runs towards a lake/blow hole, takes off his clothes and jumps in.</context>
      <utterance>What am I so pissed off about? I'm great? I'm zarking incredible! Everyone loves me! WHOOO HOOO!!! Look at me...etc.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marvin. You saved our lives.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Wretched, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUESTULAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They share a laugh. Arthur approaches Slartibartfast.</context>
      <utterance>Oh man! I love being me!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="144" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Arthur thinks about it...looks around...slowly nods...</context>
      <utterance>I've just been informed by some of the lads that since we're so near completion, we're going to go ahead and finish Earth. We can put it back exactly the way it was when you left, you know -- unless there's anything you'd like to change. Something you think your planet could do without?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks to Trillian who raises an eyebrow. Really? She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRILLIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARTHUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, You name it. I'll go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZAPHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to Humma's. He has my head...I think. Doesn't he? I'm so confused.</utterance>
   <speaker>FORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>109 SLARTI'S FACTORY ELEVATOR -- where they all board. 109</context>
      <utterance>And I'm hungry. After we get your head let's grab a bite. I know this great restaurant at the end of the universe. As they walk away, we CUT TO...</utterance>
   <speaker>SLARTIBARTFAST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone grabs the rail, except for Trillian who holds on to Arthur. SSSSSSHHHHHHHHHVUMP! Up into the sky they go.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Hold tight.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>We hear KL-KLUNK. BZZZZZZZ... and watch nature burst into life - animals run - flowers bloom - waterfalls cascade - mountains rise in the mist - monkeys bathe in hot springs etc. Set to a wonderful, uplifting piece of music ("WHAT A WONDERFUL WORLD?"). Tilt up to the sky. The day turns to night. Stars appear. The Heart of Gold streaks through the stars.</context>
      <utterance>Stand-by for commencement of life cycle. All systems checked and cleared. Commencing.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
