<movie id="401" title="Mummy The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A gorgeous, olive-skinned goddess enters the outer foyer. It takes us a moment to realize that the skin-tight dress she's wearing isn't a dress at all, but rather her entire naked body has been PAINTED in the ancient Egyptian manner She's a stunning sight to behold. This is ANCK-SU-NAMUN.</context>
      <utterance>Home of Imhotep, High Priest of Osiris, Keeper of the Dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She makes her way through the ornate statuary. The CAMERA comes to a stop on a CRACKED STONE FACE. A BEAT. And then it's eyes suddenly POP OPEN. It's really a strange looking TATTOOED MAN. Several more of these hideous, bald MEN stand nearby. They are the PRIESTS of Osiris. Imhotep's guys. Their eyes watch Anck-su-namun vanish through the bedroom curtains. Anck-su-namun embraces Imhotep, they kiss passionately, feverishly. Imhotep's hands roam over her perfect body, smearing the paint. The Narrator's VOICE fills with lust:</context>
      <utterance>Birthplace of Anck-su-namun. Pharaoh's Mistress. No other man was allowed to touch her.</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And we realize that the Narrator is actually Imhotep himself on the other-side of the curtains, the bald Priests rush over and close the doors. But just as they do, the doors suddenly BURST OPEN. Pharaoh angrily strides in, looks at the Priests. The following DIALOGUE is in ANCIENT EGYPTIAN, --</context>
      <utterance>But for our love, we were willing to risk life itself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PHARAOH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Behind him, Anck-su-namun lifts a dagger and plunges it into his back. Pharaoh SCREAMS. Imhotep raises Pharaoh's sword. The hideous bald Priests SLAM the doors and bolt them tight. Through the curtains, they see the SHADOWS of Anck-su-namun and Imhotep stab away at Pharaoh. Suddenly, the doors are RAMMED from the other side, --WHAM! Imhotep and Anck-su-namun turn and look. --WHAM! The doors are RAMMED again. The two lovers share desperate looks. --WHAM! The bald Priests run up and grab Imhotep and try and pull him towards the balcony.</context>
      <utterance>Imhotep?... My priest.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIESTS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep tries to break free, but Anck-su-namun rips Pharaoh's sword out of his hand and pushes him towards the balcony.</context>
      <utterance>Pharaoh's bodyguards!</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCK-SU-NAMUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep's face fills with despair. The DOORS EXPLODE OPEN. MEN with BLUE-TINTED SKIN and strange PUZZLE-TATTOOS over their bodies stride in, armed to the teeth. These are the MUMIA. The Priests hustle Imhotep out onto the dark balcony just as the Mumia rip through the curtains. Anck-su-namun points at Pharaoh and hisses --</context>
      <utterance>You must go. Save yourself. Only you can resurrect me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANCK-SU-NAMUN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She PLUNGES the sword into her own heart. Out on the balcony, Imhotep's mouth opens into a horrible silent scream...</context>
      <utterance>My body is no longer his temple!</utterance>
   <speaker>NARRATOR/IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For murdering Pharaoh, Anck-su-namun's body was to be cursed. And it was I, the High Priest, whose duty it was to curse it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep, filled with dread, reads from a OBOOKO made out of pure GOLD. THIS IS THE BOOK OF THE LIVING.</context>
      <utterance>Her body was mummified, her vital organs removed and placed in sacred canopic jars.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Strange LIGHT suddenly FLASHES across the faces of the slaves and the EGYPTIAN SOLDIERS. Suddenly, everyone's fear-filled eyes all rise, as if watching Anck-su-namun's body rising. Then one last HUGE FLASH, accompanied by a BLAST OF WIND, and it's over. Anck-su-namun's body now lies twisted on the ground. Imhotep's Priests place the body into a stone sarcophagus. The Nubian slaves lower it into a hole and bury it with sand. Imhotep then signals to the Soldiers, who throw their spears at the Nubians. Killing them.</context>
      <utterance>The Book of The Living contained sacred incantations that would send the evil dead on a journey into the dark underworld.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep's knife-wielding Priests attack the now unarmed Soldiers, hacking at them in the flickering darkness as Imhotep and the Mumia solemnly watches.</context>
      <utterance>The slaves were killed...</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mumia walk off across the sand and then, one by one, the Priests stop their frenzied stabbing and stare off at the vanishing Mumia. As the last Mumia disappears over a distant dune, Imhotep nods, and the Priests leap onto Anck-su-namun's grave and begin digging it back up with their hands.</context>
      <utterance>...and the soldiers who killed them were also slain, so that no unholy person should ever know the exact location of the burial site.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The chariots arrive at a place marked on the map in hieratic. They race up the stone ramp and in through the city gates. SUPERIMPOSED across the SCREEN are the WORDS: HAMUNAPTRA - City of the Dead</context>
      <utterance>But there was another book, The Book Of The Dead, which was never to be opened, never to be read, for it contained the incantations that could bring a dead body back to life a most unholy thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was hidden at Hamunaptra, City of the Dead, inside the statue of Anubis, so that no such sacrilege might ever disgrace Egypt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Imhotep begins to read from The Book of The Dead, a large SWIRLING HOLE starts to open in the detritus bog. Several Priests look over at it, frightened, then quickly look back down and resume CHANTING. A strange MIST wafts up out of the swirling hole and over to the jars, it passes through them and into Anck-su-namun's body. One of the jars SHUDDERS, the heart inside begins to BEAT. The CHANTING PRIESTS, SWIRLING HOLE, WAFTING MIST, BEATING HEART and IMHOTEP'S READINGS are reaching a crescendo. Anck-su-namun's EYES suddenly FLY OPEN.</context>
      <utterance>Anck-su-namun's vital organs were still fresh, so a human sacrifice would not need be made.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep lifts a sacrificial knife above Anck-su-namun's breast, about to plunge it down. The CHANTING, SWIRLING and BEATING heart CLIMAX. And that's when the Mumia BURST IN and storm through the startled Priests. The HEAD MUMIA SMASHES the jar with the beating heart. The MIST instantly sucks back out of Anck-su-namun's body and IMPLODES back into the swirling hole. Anck-su-namun's eyes close. Dying once again. Imhotep SCREAMS in rage. The Mumia grab him and his Priests.</context>
      <utterance>Anck-su-namun soul had come back from the dead! Now all that was needed, was to return her organs to their rightful place within her body.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My Priests were condemned to be mummified alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Using a pair of tongs, an Embalmer slowly pulls Imhotep's TONGUE out of his mouth, then places a very sharp knife on top of it. WE GO TIGHT on IMHOTEP'S EYES as his tongue is apparently cut out. The Embalmer flings Imhotep's tongue onto the floor. The Mumia's dogs attack and quickly eat it. Imhotep is WRAPPED ALIVE. Only his mouth, nostrils and fearfilled eyes are left free of the slimy bandages. Detritus muck boils inside a black cauldron. Embalmers scoop out the fetid muck and apply it to Imhotep's wrappings as he squirms. He's then laid in a wooden COFFIN inside a stone SARCOPHAGUS. An Embalmer with a BUCKET steps up and looks into the coffin. Imhotep's wild eyes stare back. The Embalmer empties the bucket over Imhotep's chest: dozens of SCARABS, disgusting dung beetles. They scurry across Imhotep's SCREAMING face. Some vanish into his tongue-less mouth and up his nostrils.</context>
      <utterance>As for me, I was condemned to endure the HOM-DAI. The worst of all ancient curses. One so horrible, it had never before been bestowed.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lid to the coffin is SLAMMED SHUT. Then, using a strange four-sided KEY, the Head Mumia locks the coffin lid tight. The heavy sarcophagus lid is shoved into place and with a loud WHOOSH seals itself airtight. Once again, the Head Mumia uses the strange key, locking the sarcophagus lid tight.</context>
      <utterance>By eating the sacred scarabs, I would be cursed to stay alive forever. And by eating me, they were cursed just the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The blue-skinned, strangely tattooed man carefully collapses the sides of the key, -- turning it into a little puzzle</context>
      <utterance>I was to remain sealed inside my sarcophagus, the undead for all of eternity.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep's sarcophagus is dropped into a DETRITUS PIT. The disgusting muck SPLASHES up, drools down it-s sides, and then is mysteriously sucked into It's seams, vanishing clean.</context>
      <utterance>They would never allow me to be released. For I would arise a walking disease, a plague upon mankind, an unholy flesh-eater, with the strength of ages, power over the sands, and the glory of invincibility.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep's horrifying tongue-less SCREAMS can be heard coming from inside his sarcophagus as grave diggers shovel dirt onto it. THE MAIN TITLE IS SUPERIMPOSED ON THE SCREAM:</context>
      <utterance>And if I could raise my beloved Anck- su-namun from her place in hell, together, we would be an unstoppable infection upon this world. The Apocalypse. The End.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A doughy little Frenchman joins him as he makes his way across the top of the wall. This is BENI.</context>
      <utterance>I knew this was gonna be a lousy day.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Personally, I would like to surrender. Why can we not just surrender?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beni pulls off his cartridge belt. Hands it to O'Connell.</context>
      <utterance>Shut-up and gimme your bandolier.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell throws it on, crisscrossing his own bandolier.</context>
      <utterance>Then let's run away. Right now. While we can still make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beni pulls out his pistol and chucks it to O'Connell.</context>
      <utterance>Now gimme your revolver, you'll never use it anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell slides it into his belt, next to his own revolver</context>
      <utterance>Then let's play dead, huh? Nobody ever does that anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now go find me a big stick.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell turns and goes nose-to-nose with him.</context>
      <utterance>In the desert? What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The horde of warriors THUNDERS forward. Now a half mile out. Scimitars RATTLING. O'Connell and Beni run through the ruins.</context>
      <utterance>So I can tie it to your back, you appear to be without a spine.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd a guy like you end up in the Legion anyways?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got caught robbing a synagogue. Lots of good stuff in them holy places; churches, temples, mosques, and who's guarding them?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Altar boys?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beni trips and accidentally tackles O'Connell to the ground. O'Connell gives him a nasty look.</context>
      <utterance>Exactly! I speak seven languages, including Hebrew, so my specialty was synagogues. How about you? Kill somebody?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They get up and run out the gate and down the stone ramp</context>
      <utterance>No, but I'm considering it.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What then? Robbery? Extortion? Kidnapping!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None of the above, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both skid to a stop at the front line as they see the horde of warriors. The SOUND of CHARGING HORSES is deafening. O'Connell gives Beni a big cheesy smile.</context>
      <utterance>Then what the hell are you doing here!?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's when the cowardly Legionnaire Colonel suddenly panics, cuts and runs. O'Connell instantly stiffens.</context>
      <utterance>I was just looking for a good time.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gives the men around him courage. But onward comes the horde Hoofs pounding the sand. Several more Legionnaires take off.</context>
      <utterance>Oh shit. Steady!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and runs like hell, right through the front gate. Four Tuareg warriors on massive Arabians haul-ass after him. O'Connell hurdles a stone column, hits the ground running. He spots Beni inside the Temple doorway, trying to close the heavy sandstone door.</context>
      <utterance>Son-of-a-bitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beni has no intention of waiting up, he pushes harder.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! Beni! Wait up!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell runs faster. Beni pushes harder. The four Horsemen LEAP the big column and CHARGE after him. HOOFS POUNDING.</context>
      <utterance>What are ya doing?! Wait up!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you close that door! DON'T YOU</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Egyptian CURATOR storms in.</context>
      <utterance>Oops.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn quickly gets up and starts gathering books.</context>
      <utterance>Look at this! Sons of the Messiah! Give me frogs, flies, locusts, anything but this! Compared to you, the other plagues were a joy!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, it was an accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn turns to him, trying to contain herself.</context>
      <utterance>When Ramesses destroyed Syria, it was an accident. You are a catastrophe! Why do I put up with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You put up with me, because I can read and write ancient Egyptian, decipher hieroglyphs and hieratic, and I'm the only person within a thousand miles who knows how to properly code and catalogue this library.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Curator storms out. Evelyn just stands there, steaming. And then she hears a NOISE and quickly turns around. A BEAT.</context>
      <utterance>Who needs smart women? I put up with you because your mother and father were our finest patrons, Allah rest their souls. Now straighten up this mess!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quiet. Eerie. And then she hears it again, like feet, slowly shuffling across the floor, coming from a nearby gallery.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Abdul? Mohammed? Bob? Evelyn walks through the stacks and enters --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You...! YOU...!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meet JONATHAN CARNARVON. As he crawls out of the sarcophagus, Evelyn pulls a cigarette out of the mummy's mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Drunkard? Fool? Rat-bastard? Please call me something original.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you no respect for the dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grins drunkenly. Evelyn punches him hard in the chest.</context>
      <utterance>Right now, I only wish to join them.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I wish you'd do it sooner rather than later, before you ruin my career the way you've ruined yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He BELCHES, then falls back and sits on the edge of a tomb.</context>
      <utterance>My dear, sweet, baby sister, I'll have you know, that at this moment my career is on a high note.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan excitedly starts scrounging around in his jacket.</context>
      <utterance>High note? Ha! For five years you've been scrounging around Egypt, and what have you to show for it? Nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes I do! I have something right here!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan pulls out a small, ancient BOX; the collapsed KEY to Imhotep's sarcophagus and coffin. Evelyn is instantly curious, she grabs the box out of his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Oh no, not another worthless trinket, Jonathan, if I bring one more piece of junk to the Curator to try and sell for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan knows her weaknesses, gives her a mischievous smile.</context>
      <utterance>Where did you get this?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn rolls the box around in her hands, mumbling to herself as she translates the hieratics and hieroglyphs covering it. Jonathan licks his lips in anticipation.</context>
      <utterance>On a dig, down in Thebes.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn's fingers play with the various little slats on the box, shifting them this way and that way, it's like a puzzle box. Then suddenly, it UNFOLDS ITSELF, almost-mechanically, turning itself into the KEY. Sitting inside the open key/box is a folded piece of GOLDEN PAPYRUS. An ANCIENT MAP.</context>
      <utterance>My whole life I've never found anything, Evy. Tell me I've found something.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jonathan?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you found something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See the cartouche there, it's the official royal seal of Seti the First, I'm sure of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan leans in from across the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two questions. Who the hell is Seti the First? And was he rich?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was the last Pharaoh of the Old Kingdom, said to be the wealthiest Pharaoh of them all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Curator picks up the MAP. It's actually the exact same map that we established in the opening scenes of the movie.</context>
      <utterance>Alright, good, that's good. I like this fellow, like him very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Curator freezes, suddenly very nervous, then he recovers.</context>
      <utterance>I've already dated it, this map is almost four thousand years old. And the hieratics over here...  It's Hamunaptra.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My dear girl, don't be ridiculous, we are scholars, not treasure hunters. Hamunaptra is a myth.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we talking about the Hamunaptra?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. The City of The Dead. Where the early Pharaohs were said to have hidden the wealth of Egypt.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right, right, in a big underground treasure chamber. Everybody knows the story. The entire necropolis was rigged to sink into the sand. On Pharaoh's command, a flick of the switch! And the whole place could disappear beneath the dunes.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All we know is that the city mysteriously vanished around 2,134</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The map 'accidentally,' CATCHES ON FIRE. The Curator throws it to the floor. Jonathan drops to his knees and quickly puts it out. Lifts it up. The left third of the map is now missing.</context>
      <utterance>As the Americans would say: it's all fairy tales and hokum.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You burned it! You burned off the part with the lost city!</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's for the best, I'm sure. Many men have wasted their lives in the foolish pursuit of Hamunaptra, no one has ever found it, most have never returned.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You killed my map.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Curator reaches for the key/box. Evelyn quickly snatches it off the desk and gives him a very angry, suspicious look.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure it was a fake, anyway, I'm surprised at you, Miss Carnarvon, to be so fooled.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You told me you found it on a dig down in Thebes!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was mistaken.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lied to me!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lie to everybody, what makes you so special?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm your sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That just makes you more gullible.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You stole it from a drunk at the local Casbah?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Picked his pocket, actually.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="39">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what is he in prison for?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did not know, so when I heard you were coming, I asked him that myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The interior cell door BURSTS OPEN. O'Connell is in chains, dragged by FOUR GUARDS, they shove him up to the cell bars. From the looks of it, he's been here awhile; his face is half hidden by long hair, a scraggly beard and many new bruises. Evelyn looks at him, disgusted by his appearance.</context>
      <utterance>He said... he was just looking for a good time.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he's just a filthy criminal?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell gives Evelyn the once over, then looks at Jonathan.</context>
      <utterance>Way to go, Evy.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So who's the broad?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Broad?!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's my sister, actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn is stunned and furious. The Warden heads out the door.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Well,... I'm sure she's not a total loss.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be back in a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We uh,... found... your puzzle box, and we've come to ask you about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn and Jonathan quickly look around, hoping the guards didn't hear him. They step closer. Evelyn plays coy.</context>
      <utterance>No... You came to ask me about Hamunaptra.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know the box pertains to Hamunaptra?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn is dumbstruck. But Jonathan looks suspicious</context>
      <utterance>Because that's where I found it. I was there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell looks closer at Jonathan, a glint of recognition.</context>
      <utterance>How do we know that's not a load of pig swallow?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey,... don't I know you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell's FIST comes flying through the bars, hits Jonathan square in the jaw, DECKS HIM. He hits the floor. Out cold. A Guard CLUBS O'Connell. His head bounces off the bars again. He shows no pain, but gives the Guard another nasty look. Evelyn looks down at her brother, then back at O'Connell.</context>
      <utterance>Um, well, you see...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were actually at Hamunaptra?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just decked your brother</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell almost smiles. There's a bit of spark to this girl.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, well...  I know my brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I was there.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You swear?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every damn day.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I mean --</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- I know what you mean. I was there, alright. Seti's place. The City Of The Dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you find? What did you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The warden enters. Evelyn quickly leans closer to O'Connell.</context>
      <utterance>I found sand. I saw death.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you tell me how to get there? The exact location?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn leans in even closer.</context>
      <utterance>Want to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans her face right up to the bars, nervous and excited</context>
      <utterance>Really want to know?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell steps forward and KISSES her full on the lips.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn is stunned. A Guard CLUBS him, his face bounces off the bars again, but before he can react the Guards GRAB him, YANKS him away from the bars and DRAG him out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>Then get me the hell outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are they taking him?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn is shocked. The warden shows-off his green teeth.</context>
      <utterance>To be hanged.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apparently, he had a very good time.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No women allowed.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This seems to confuse the Warden, he shrugs and sits down. O'Connell looks up as Evelyn plops down beside the Warden.</context>
      <utterance>I am an English woman.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will give you one hundred pounds to spare his life.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would pay one hundred pounds just to see him hang.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two hundred pounds.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Proceed!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell can hear every word, he looks hopeful. Other than Evelyn, you could hear a pin drop. The HANGMAN turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>Three hundred pounds!</utterance>
   <speaker>HANGMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any last requests, pig?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Hangman grabs the lever to the trapdoor.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'd like ya to let me go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The prisoners go ape-shit, SCREAMING and SHOUTING in anger. The GUARDS look around, nervous. O'Connell struggles at the end of the rope, gagging. Evelyn is horrified, she quickly turns to the warden, leans forward and whispers in his ear.</context>
      <utterance>His neck did not break! Good! Now we watch him strangle to death.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The warden spins around and faces her.</context>
      <utterance>He knows the location to Hamunaptra.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the end of the rope, O'Connell is choking and gagging and turning several shades of red. The Warden stares at Evelyn.</context>
      <utterance>I would never!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you saying this filthy godless son of a pig knows where to find The City Of The Dead? Truly?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes and if you cut him down, we will give you ten percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fifty percent.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Twenty.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn hesitates, bites her lip. O'Connell's eyes bulge as he looks up at her, he can't believe this girl.</context>
      <utterance>Forty.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give... give him... give him GLAAAA--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The warden flashes a big green smile, then YELLS in Arabic. A scimitar SLASHES the air. The rope is CUT. O'Connell CRASHES to the ground. Half dead. Rolls over. GAGGING. All of the prisoners BURST INTO CHEERS. O'Connell looks up at Evelyn. She smiles broadly and waves down at him.</context>
      <utterance>Twenty-five percent, and not one single farthing more.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR'S OFFICE - NIGHT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>CANDLE LIGHT FLICKERS across the Curator's face.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Standing in the shadows across from his desk are THREE MUMIA: blue tinted skin, hideous facial tattoos, -- the works. One of the Mumia has a rusty metal HOOK for a hand. He shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>She must die.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She is like all the others. She will die in the desert.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Curator leans across his desk, fear in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No! She has seen too much. She knows too much.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spooks the hell out of the Mumia guys.</context>
      <utterance>Not only does she have a map, but she has the key.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The key!? She has the lost key!?</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. No one has ever had so much, been so close. We must stop her, or it will be the end of us all.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we will kill her, we will kill her and all those with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And burn the map and retrieve the key.</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will be done. But what of the American expedition? They leave tomorrow as well.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget the bumbling Americans, they will be like all the others. Without the map to guide them, how can they possibly find Hamunaptra?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE CRANE BACK: to reveal Beni standing on the bow of a PASSENGER BARGE. Surrounded by DANIELS, HENDERSON and BURNS.</context>
      <utterance>It is three days down the Nile, then two days by camel, sahibs.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE KEEP CRANING BACK: as Henderson slaps Daniels on the back.</context>
      <utterance>For all the money we're paying you, something better god-damned well be under that sand.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Now we see all of GIZA PORT: Team of explorers swarm the docks. Across the Nile, the PYRAMIDS spike the sky. Evelyn and Jonathan walk along the boardwalk besieged by HAWKERS selling everything from toy tombs to King Tut action figures.</context>
      <utterance>"Hamunaptra," Daniels, that's all ya gotta keep sayin, to yourself, "Hamunaptra."</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you really think he'll show up?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Undoubtedly, I know the breed, he may be a cowboy, but his word is his word.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Personally, I think he's filthy, rude and a complete scoundrel. I don't like him one bit.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They both turn. O'Connell walks up; shaved, showered, spit and polished, with a new haircut and clothes. He looks more dashing and handsome than ever. Evelyn is suitably impressed.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone I know?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan grabs O'Connell's arm and shakes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Oh... um,... hello.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell quickly checks his pockets.</context>
      <utterance>Smashing day for the start of an adventure, eh, O'Connell?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finds his wallet and relaxes. DIRECTLY ABOVE HIM: on the bow of the barge, Burns wipes his bifocals and turns to Beni.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure, smashing.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure Hamunaptra is out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's when Beni spots O'Connell. Beni shakes his head, as if seeing a mirage, then starts backing away from the men.</context>
      <utterance>Along with the scorched bones of my entire garrison, sahib.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beni quickly scurries off, vanishing down into the hold. BACK DOWN WITH: Evelyn, recovering, she clears her throat.</context>
      <utterance>A thousand pardons, my good sahibs but there is much work to be done.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell steps up close to Evelyn, invading her space looks her straight in the eye. Evelyn doesn't back away.</context>
      <utterance>Mister O'Connell, can you look me in the eye, and guarantee me this is not some sort of flimflam? Because if it is, I'm warning you --</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell takes her bags and heads up the gangplank and onto the same passenger barge that Beni and the Americans are on. Evelyn's eyes follow him, a bit wistfully. Jonathan sees it.</context>
      <utterance>All I can tell you, miss, is that my Colonel found that map in an ancient fortress, and the whole damn garrison believed in it so much, that without orders, we marched halfway across Libya and into Egypt to find that city. Like I told ya, all I saw was sand. Everybody else was wiped out by Tuareg warriors. I'll take your bags.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn gives him a look. Jonathan just grins. And that's when the warden suddenly brushes past, tipping his raggedy hat.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, yes, you're right, filthy, rude, a complete scoundrel, nothing to like there at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A bright good morning to all.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And up the plank he goes. Evelyn and Jonathan share a look. WE GO WIDE AGAIN: as the barge pulls out and heads down the Nile. WE TILT UP: to the SUN, which then DISSOLVES into --</context>
      <utterance>I have come to protect my investment, thank you very much.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sit down, O'Connell, sit down, we could use another good player.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I only gamble with my life, never my money.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell returns Daniel's cocky look.</context>
      <utterance>Never? What if I were to wager five hundred dollars says we get to Hamunaptra before you?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burns slips on his dirty bifocals.</context>
      <utterance>Yer on.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What makes you so confident, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henderson spits a wad of chew into a spittoon.</context>
      <utterance>What makes you?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell's poker face drops, perplexed. Same with Jonathan.</context>
      <utterance>We got us a man who's actually been there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell 'accidentally' hits him in the ribs with the gunnysack, shutting him up. Jonathan quickly covers.</context>
      <utterance>I say, what a coincidence, why --</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- whose deal is it? Is it my deal? I thought I just dealt?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="29">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry, didn't mean to scare ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only thing that scares me, Mister O'Connell, are your manners.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still angry that I kissed ya, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell reaches into the gunny-sack and starts pulling out revolvers, pistols, hunting knives, a massive elephant gun, and a half dozen carefully wrapped sticks of dynamite.</context>
      <utterance>If you call that a kiss.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did I miss something? Are we going into battle?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This takes the smile off Evelyn's face. O'Connell starts dismantling and cleaning the guns.</context>
      <utterance>The last time I was at that place everybody I was with died.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's something out there, you know, something under that sand.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell looks into Evelyn's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm hoping to find a certain artifact, a book, actually, my brother thinks there's treasure. What do you think is out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evil. The Tuaregs and the Bedouin believe that Hamunaptra is cursed, they call it, "the doorway to hell."</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a know-it-all grin.</context>
      <utterance>Ahmar is Ossirion. "Passageway to the underworld", actually.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe in fairy tales and hokum, Mister O'Connell, but I do believe that one of the most famous books in history is buried out there, The Book Of The Living. It's what first interested me in Egypt as a child. It's why I came here, sort of a life's pursuit.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn is surprised by his knowledge.</context>
      <utterance>And the fact that they say it's made out of pure gold, makes no nevermind to you, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know your history.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn gets up to go, then she hesitates, nervous, she turns back to O'Connell, and as matter-of-fact as possible says:</context>
      <utterance>I know my treasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell, cleaning his guns, just shrugs his shoulders.</context>
      <utterance>By the way,... why did you kiss me?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn's eyes widen, furious, she turns and storms off. O'Connell looks up, watching her leave, a bit perplexed.</context>
      <utterance>I was about to be hanged, seemed like a good idea at the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he hears someone SNICKERING under the table. He quickly reaches down, grabs that someone and lifts him up. It's Beni.</context>
      <utterance>What?... Wha'd I say?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My very good friend! What a surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell sticks a knife under Beni's throat. Beni swallows hard, then tries to weasel his way out with a big grin.</context>
      <utterance>Why if it ain't my little buddy, Beni. I oughta kill you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You never were any good with the ladies, O'Connell.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you're the one leading the Americans, I shoulda figured. So what's the scam? You get 'em out in the middle of the desert then leave 'em to rot?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell pulls the knife away. Beni relaxes, rubs his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately no, these Americans are smart, they pay me only half now, half when I get them back to Cairo, so I must go all the way.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They look as they hear Evelyn YELP. A single CAMEL in the HORSE PADDOCK takes another bite at her. She YELPS again and backs away. O'Connell grins as Evelyn flees down the deck.</context>
      <utterance>You never believed in Hamunaptra, O'Connell. Why are you going back? The devil himself lives out there.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The girl saved my life, figured it was the least I could do, keep her out of trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell's eyes narrow at the insult, he looks back at Beni.</context>
      <utterance>You always did have more balls than brains.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's make us even, shall we?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell grabs him and chucks him over the side of the barge. Beni SPLASHES into the river. O'Connell takes his gunny-sack and starts walking off down the deck.</context>
      <utterance>Even?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>O'Connell! I am going to kill you for this!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's when he spots THREE SETS OF WET FOOTPRINTS, coming up over the railing from the river and heading down the deck. O'Connell quickly looks around, immediately on the alert.</context>
      <utterance>Sounds familiar.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn's terrified eyes glance down. Hook looks over, sees the map lying next to a flickering candle on a nearby table.</context>
      <utterance>Where is the map?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn's eyes look confused. She shakes her head. Hook grins.</context>
      <utterance>And the key? Where is the key?</utterance>
   <speaker>HOOK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cocks his hook, about to kill her. And that's when the door is KICKED OPEN. O'Connell BURSTS IN, gun in each hand. Hook spins Evelyn around and holds her out in front of him. O'Connell looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Then I'll find it myself.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn's eyes widen. And that's when the candle on the table FLICKERS. Everything happens at once, READ FAST: O'Connell spins around just as a window BURSTS OPEN. A Mumia leans in. FIRES A GUN. Woodchips BLAST OFF the wall next to O'Connell's head. He returns FIRE. Kills the Mumia. The Mumia falls back. FIRING BLINDLY. A LANTERN in the room is BLASTED. Kerosene SPLASHES across the wall. BURSTS INTO FLAMES. Evelyn grabs the candle on the table and JAMS IT back over her shoulder, right into Hook's EYE. He SCREECHES in pain and lets her go. O'Connell grabs her and YANKS her out of the FLAMING ROOM.</context>
      <utterance>Friend of yours?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shoves her up against a wall.</context>
      <utterance>The map! We need the map!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax! I'm the map!  It's all up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell gives her a look, then pulls her forward.</context>
      <utterance>Oh that's comforting.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, there's still one more of those guys around here somewhere.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you swim?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well of course I can swim, if the occasion calls for it.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me. He picks her up and throws her over the side.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn SPLASHES into the water. O'Connell dives in after her.</context>
      <utterance>The occasion calls for it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hook suddenly stumbles up behind him, -- now a FLAMING TORCH. Jonathan turns around, Hook grabs him by the throat with his FLAMING ARM and pins him to the cabin wall. Jonathan's eyes widen as he sees a hook rising up inside the FLAMES about to strike him. The Americans pivot and OPEN FIRE. Blows Hook over the railing. Jonathan turns to the Americans and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Americans.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he points his thumb at himself</context>
      <utterance>I say! Good show!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts up his other hand, -- he has the key/box back.</context>
      <utterance>And did I panic?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's when the horses STAMPEDE onto the bow. Jonathan dives over one side, the three Americans dive over the other.</context>
      <utterance>I think not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey O'Connell! Looks to me like I got all the horses!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beni looks up at the stars, then angrily KICKS the sand CURSING. The FLAMING barge drifts off, slowly sinking...</context>
      <utterance>Hey Beni! Looks to me like your on the wrong side of the river!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe the price of these fleabags.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We coulda had 'em for free, all we had to do was give 'em your sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, awfully tempting, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's when Evelyn steps out of a trading tent. She's changed into a gorgeous, tightly fitted, Bedouin dress.</context>
      <utterance>Awfully.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then again...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The warden savagely attacks a chicken wing with his vile green teeth. Flies buzz around his head. He sucks at his gums, then spits out some gristle. O'Connell watches him.</context>
      <utterance>Never did like camels. Filthy buggers. They smell, they bite, they spit. Disgusting.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn is having the time of her life on top of her camel.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, disgusting.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE DO SEVERAL TIME DISSOLVES: showing the majesty of the desert, and our heroes getting deeper and deeper into it.</context>
      <utterance>Well I think they're cute.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you snore!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not snore!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All night you snored!</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up in front of them, O'Connell looks at Evelyn.</context>
      <utterance>I have never snored!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're almost there.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell looks down at the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Are you sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The others look down and see DOZENS OF SKELETONS sticking out of the ground. Bleached and eaten away. Some of the skeletons look like they're trying to crawl up out of the desert floor.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Warden shivers in fear.</context>
      <utterance>What in bloody hell is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The American Expedition rides out from behind the far end of the dune. The Americans are accompanied by TWO DOZEN NATIVE DIGGERS and an Arab EGYPTOLOGIST. Beni rides lead on a camel, the rest ride horses.</context>
      <utterance>Other seekers of Hamunaptra.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell just nods. The two parties come to a stop a hundred feet apart. O'Connell turns and stares out across the endless horizon. Beni does likewise. The Americans look puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Good morning, my friend!</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, what the hell we doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henderson looks over at O'Connell.</context>
      <utterance>Patience, my good sahib, patience.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell and Beni just stare out at the flat nothingness. Evelyn and Jonathan share a look. And then, the SUN starts to rise in the distance, breaking the flat horizon.</context>
      <utterance>First one to the city, O'Connell! Five hundred! Cash bucks!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn can feel the suspense and the majesty of the moment.</context>
      <utterance>Get ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Far off to the right, a HUGE SHAPE begins to rise with the sun. A VOLCANO. O'Connell and Beni watch it, expressionless. Daniels, Henderson and Burns share a look, and then --</context>
      <utterance>We're about to be shown the way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah, begging your pardon, but shouldn't we be going?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell doesn't say a word, staring hard. Beni watches the Americans and spits into the sand.</context>
      <utterance>After all, you rode us night and day to win that bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then suddenly, the volcano SHIFTS ACROSS THE HORIZON. Passing across the sun as it goes. It's a MIRAGE. The Americans crash their horses to a stop and race the other way, after the volcano. Evelyn and Jonathan smile, amazed. The volcano SHIFTS AGAIN, floating across the watery horizon. The Americans crash to a stop again and chase after the volcano. All three of them confused and CURSING. O'Connell and Beni just stare, waiting. The volcano SHIFTS AGAIN. And the Americans crash to a stop again. Burns is THROWN from his horse. Henderson angrily rips his hat off and chucks it to the ground. Daniels just curses as they give up the chase. The volcano comes to a stop on the far left of the horizon. The Americans are on the far right. Nothing moves. A BEAT. And then O'Connell grins. So does Beni. They share a look. And then SWAT their camels and RACE AWAY. Everybody else hauls-ass after them. O'Connell and Beni are neck-and-neck. And then Evelyn comes galloping up, hair flying in the wind. Beni takes out his camel whip and starts WHIPPING O'Connell. Trying to knock him off his camel. once. CRACK! Twice. CRACK! But on the third try O'Connell grabs the whip and JERKS Beni off his camel. Beni SLAMS to the ground and TUMBLES. Evelyn and O'Connell race across the desert. Evelyn has never felt so alive. She LAUGHS. O'Connell grins; he likes this girl. Beni stumbles to his feet, then quickly dances out of the way as Jonathan and all the other riders stampede past him. Evelyn beats O'Connell to the stone ramp, racing hard.</context>
      <utterance>Fools.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn ignores him as she races up the ramp towards the gate.</context>
      <utterance>Evelyn! Slow down!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Americans ride up and look in wonder at the ruins inside the volcano. O'Connell gives them a big, shit-eating grin.</context>
      <utterance>Never mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You boys owe me five hundred dollars.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd all these camels come from?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They belong to the dead. They will wait years for their masters to return before leaving.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That thing gives me the creeps.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn is positioning ancient MIRRORS along the crevice.</context>
      <utterance>Be nice. That thing saved my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That "thing" gets me excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The things that get you excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to Bembridge Scholars, inside the statue of Anubis was a secret compartment, perhaps containing The Book Of The Living.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are those mirrors for?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell shrugs, then rappels down into the crevice.</context>
      <utterance>Ancient Egyptian trick. You'll see.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you realize, we are standing inside a room that no one has entered in over four thousand years.</utterance>
   <speaker>WARDEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who cares? I don't see no treasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're welcome to my share of the spider webs.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn just rolls her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>And it stinks to high heaven in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan sniffs the foul air, then he looks at the warden and realizes where the smell is coming from. He stops sniffing. Evelyn brushes COBWEBS away from a METAL DISK on the wall, then repositions it on it's pedestal, aiming it at a RAY OF LIGHT shining in from the outer mirrors. -- THE RAY OF LIGHT</context>
      <utterance>Cretins.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is a neat trick.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god, It's a preparation room.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Preparation for what?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell quickly draws his gun. Jonathan gently nudges him.</context>
      <utterance>For entering the afterlife.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn heads down a narrow passageway. The others follow.</context>
      <utterance>Mummies, my good son, this is where they made the mummies.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya scared the bejeezus out of us, O'Connell.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But nobody lowers their guns. Daniels grins, the tough one.</context>
      <utterance>Likewise.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This here is our statue,... friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's when Beni, five Diggers and the Egyptologist step out of the shadows, -- all holding guns aimed at O'Connell.</context>
      <utterance>Don't see your name on it,... pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ten to one, O'Connell, your odds are no-so-good.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan clenches a tiny derringer.</context>
      <utterance>I've had worse.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell gives him a sideways glance. Beni cocks his gun, grinning, he wants it to happen. The tension thickens. Then Evelyn gently takes O'Connell's gun hand and pulls it down.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, me too.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn pulls O'Connell away. Jonathan and the Warden follow. Beni and the Americans slowly lower their guns, laughing. The Egyptologist excitedly begins translating the hieroglyphs.</context>
      <utterance>Let's be nice, children, if we're going to play together, we must learn to share.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to my calculations, we should be right under the statue. We'll come up right between his legs.  Oh my.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And when those dirty Yanks go to sleep --  No offense.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>None taken.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll sneak up and steal that book right out from under them.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you're sure you can find the secret compartment?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan looks around.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, if their Egyptologist hasn't already found it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I say, what's our smelly little friend got himself up to?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EGYPTOLOGIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henderson sees the intense look in the Egyptologist's eyes</context>
      <utterance>Seti was no fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks back at the native Diggers.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure...</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Egyptologist nods, then YELLS IN EGYPTIAN at the Diggers. The Diggers hesitate, filled with fear. Daniels pulls out his gun, aims it at three of the Diggers. The three Diggers hesitantly step forward with crowbars and stick them into the seams. The other Diggers back away, scared shitless. Beni and the Americans exchange looks, and then they back away as well.</context>
      <utterance>We'll let him open it.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lemme get this straight, they stuck a sharp, red hot poker up your nose, cut your brain into small pieces, then ripped it all out through your nostrils?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OWCH! That's really got to hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's called mummification. You're dead when they do this</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still...</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that'd bring you back to life.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's when a huge chunk of the roof suddenly GIVES OUT. O'Connell GRABS Evelyn and JERKS her clear. Jonathan DIVES for the far wall. A MASSIVE STONE CASEMENT DROPS OUT OF THE CEILING AND CRASHES to the floor. DUST FLIES. Fills the room.</context>
      <utterance>You two are worse than a couple of schoolboys.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god,... it looks like, it looks like a sarcophagus.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would they bury somebody in the ceiling?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They didn't, they buried him at the foot of Anubis. He was either someone of great importance. Or he did something very naughty.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn stares at the hieroglyph, confused and concerned.</context>
      <utterance>Well?... Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'He that shall not be named.' O'Connell dusts off the huge LOCK</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's some sort of lock here. You say these thing's are made of granite with a steel interior?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quarried granite with a cobalt lining.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoever's in here, sure wasn't getting out.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kiddin', without a key, it'll take us a month to crack this thing,</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A key! That's it! That's what he was talking about.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn starts rummaging through the pack on Jonathan's back.</context>
      <utterance>Who was talking about what?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn pulls out the key/box. Jonathan tries to take it back.</context>
      <utterance>The man on the barge. The one with the hook, he was looking for a key.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn slaps his hand and quickly unfolds the box, -- it's now shaped exactly like the LOCK'S KEYHOLE. Evelyn smiles. And that's when they hear the Warden's SCREAMS echoing through the labyrinth. All three of them turn and take-off running.</context>
      <utterance>Hey that's mine!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you suppose killed him?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell comes up over some rocks.</context>
      <utterance>Did you ever see him eat?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seems the Americans had a little misadventure of their own today, three of their diggers were killed.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Salt acid. Pressurized salt acid. Some sort of ancient booby-trap.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The campfire FLICKERS O'Connell and Jonathan share a nervous look. Evelyn laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe this place really is cursed. A GUST OF WIND blows through the camp.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You two!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't believe in curses, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell cocks his rifle, KA-CHANK! Gives her a big grin.</context>
      <utterance>No. I believe if I can see it and I can touch it, then it's real. That's what I believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan opens the Warden's POUCH, the one that held the scarabs. He reaches in, starts scrounging around. WE SLOWLY PUSH IN. Waiting for the attack. THE MUSIC BUILDS. And then, -- Jonathan SCREAMS in pain and RIPS his hand back out of the pouch. O'Connell and Evelyn both jump.</context>
      <utterance>I believe in being prepared.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan smiles at the bottle, then turns the pouch inside out and shakes it, nothing but SAND is inside it.</context>
      <utterance>Seagrams!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan takes a swig. O'Connell and Evelyn laugh, guiltily And then O'Connell suddenly kneels down and sticks his ear to the sand. Evelyn and Jonathan watch him. A BEAT. And then a BARAGE OF GUNFIRE IS HEARD coming from the American camp. O'Connell jumps up and throws the elephant gun to Evelyn.</context>
      <utterance>Well, he may have been a stinky fellow,... but he had good taste.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes off running through the ruins. Evelyn immediately gets up and runs after him. Jonathan grabs a gun, holds the bottle of Seagrams; tight and dashes after her.</context>
      <utterance>Stay here!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evy! Excuse me! But didn't the man just say -- !</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goin' somewhere?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell drags him back towards the American camp.</context>
      <utterance>Just looking for you, O'Connell! I wanted to be with my friend!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do you like to fight so much?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ardeth Ray gallops through the camp, cutting Diggers down with his scimitar. O'Connell runs up on top of some rocks, LEAPS OUT and TACKLES him off his horse. The two men SLAM to the ground. O'Connell spins up onto one knee and FIRES, point blank. Blows the scimitar out of Ardeth Ray's hand. O'Connell is about to shoot again when a horse rides up between them. A scimitar swoops down, almost takes O'Connell's head off, misses him by an inch. O'Connell leaps up and blows the Rider off his mount. The horse BOLTS. -- But Ardeth Ray is gone. Evelyn hides behind some rocks, watching the scene, suddenly, she hears something coming up behind her and spins around. A vicious tattooed Mumia Rider races at her. Evelyn quickly backpedals over the rocks, terrified. The Mumia Rider raises his scimitar, about to strike. Evelyn SCREAMS, trips over a rock and FIRES the elephant gun, -- BLAM! Blows the Rider off his mount and CATAPULTS him twenty feet back into some ruins. At the same time, the kick blows Evelyn off her feet and over a ridge. She FLAILS through the air and lands in a sand dune. Jonathan and some Diggers are holding their own near the temple door. Four Riders come CHARGING right at them. Jonathan takes a swig off the Seagrams.</context>
      <utterance>'Cause I look good doin, it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan and the Diggers OPEN FIRE. When the smoke clears, the Riders are either dead or gone. Jonathan grins.</context>
      <utterance>Let 'em have it, boys!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then several more Mumia leap off the temple and land behind them. Jonathan and the remaining Diggers spin around and suddenly find themselves in hand-to-hand combat. O'Connell is quickly loading his pistol. He hears something THUNDERING UP behind him. He spins around just as Ardeth Ray on a horse swings his scimitar. O'Connell instinctively raises his hands to protect his face, the scimitar STRIKES! Hits his gun, -- CHING! O'Connell's gun flips away. Disarmed, O'Connell dives and rolls and suddenly comes up with a stick of dynamite in his hand. He shoves the fuse into a fire. It IGNITES. He faces Ardeth Ray, towering above him. The two men lock eyes. The fuse continues to burn down. Ardeth Ray points his scimitar at O'Connell's head.</context>
      <utterance>I say, bloody good show.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn looks up into his strong eyes. It's the first time he's shown genuine concern for her. And she likes it. He's also holding her a little too close. And she likes that too.</context>
      <utterance>You alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beni crawls out from under some pillars as Henderson and Burns help Daniels to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>Yes,... fine,... thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See! That proves it! Old Seti's fortune's gotta be under this sand!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell looks up into the surrounding ridges, unsatisfied.</context>
      <utterance>For them to protect it like this, you just know there's got to be treasure down there.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn looks at O'Connell, suddenly very worried.</context>
      <utterance>These men are a desert people. They value water, not gold.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Jonathan?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell polishes off the bottle and chucks it away.</context>
      <utterance>Unlike my brother, sir, I know when to say no.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unlike your brother, Miss, you I don't get. You're a whole new brew.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know, you're wondering, what's a place like me doing in a girl like this?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Egypt is in my blood. My father was a famous explorer, he loved Egypt so much that he married an Egyptian. My mother! Who was quite an adventurer herself</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, I get your father, I get your mother and I get your brother, but what are you doing here? Evelyn is insulted, she staggers to her feet.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I may not be an explorer, or an adventurer, or a treasure hunter, or a gunfighter! Mister O'Connell But I'm proud of what I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn plops back down beside him, really drunk, she grins and proudly lifts her head high.</context>
      <utterance>And what is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans in, very close to his face, looks him in the eyes,</context>
      <utterance>...I am a librarian!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to kiss you, Mister O'Connell.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No you're not.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not unless you call me Rick.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would I do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him a goofy smile. He leans forward and KISSES HER. Evelyn's eyes slowly close. And then she passes out, slumping into his arms. O'Connell looks down at her, and just smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Because that's my name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe I allowed the two of you to get me drunk.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't blame me, I don't even remember being there.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell gives her a hurt look.</context>
      <utterance>Well neither do I, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn gives O'Connell a nervous look.</context>
      <utterance>You don't?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No... Why?... Should I?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell gives her a big cheesy smile. Evelyn's face drops, appalled and embarrassed. And that's when the lid FALLS OFF and LOUDLY CRASHES to the ground. All three of them instantly grab their sore heads and MOAN.</context>
      <utterance>Gee, yeah, you told me it was the best time you ever had.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>EGYPTOLOGIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is a curse upon this chest.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Curse my ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Egyptologist gives them the evil-eye</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, who cares.</utterance>
   <speaker>EGYPTOLOGIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In these hallowed grounds, that which was set forth in ancient times, is as strong today, as it was then.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Egyptologist slowly and carefully reads the inscription:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah, okay, what's it --</utterance>
   <speaker>EGYPTOLOGIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GUST OF WIND blows through the chamber. TORCHES FLICKER All the Diggers suddenly turn tail and run off SCREAMING. The Americans look at each other, suddenly very nervous.</context>
      <utterance>"Death will come on swift wings to whomever opens this chest".</utterance>
   <speaker>EGYPTOLOGIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says, there is one, the undead, who if brought back to life, is bound by sacred law to consummate this curse.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three Americans laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, let's just make sure we don't bring anybody back from the dead then, huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>EGYPTOLOGIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He will kill all who open this chest,... and assimilate their organs and fluids.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Assimilate their organs and fluids? Ya mean eat 'em?</utterance>
   <speaker>EGYPTOLOGIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WIND WHISTLES. Torches FLICKER. VERY SPOOKY. Beni and the Egyptologist share a fear-filled look. Henderson just shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>And in so doing he will regenerate. And no longer be the undead, but a plague upon this earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah hell, let's open it anyways.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my god, I've dreamed about this ever since I was a little girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn just gives him a look, then starts brushing dirt and cobwebs off the top of the coffin. Then she freezes.</context>
      <utterance>You dream about dead guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell and Jonathan are too excited to care.</context>
      <utterance>Look, all the sacred spells have been chiseled off. The hieratics and hieroglyphs that protect the deceased on his journey into the afterlife, they've been removed. This man was cursed,... doomed.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tough break.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn can't believe these guys. Jonathan inserts the key/box into the coffin's lock. Turns it. The lid cracks open with a HISS. They all react to the FOUL STENCH. Then O'Connell grabs the lid. It's stuck. He pulls with all his might. Jonathan helps him. It starts to give way. Slowly. Slowly. Slooooowly. And then it suddenly POPS OPEN and THE MOST HIDEOUS, MAGGOT</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I'm all tears, now let's see who's inside, shall we?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beni turns and bolts from the chamber. Daniels spits.</context>
      <utterance>The curse,... beware the curse!</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's when the seal breaks, -- A BLACK VAPOR BLASTS OUT OF THE CHEST. Everybody vanishes into the strange cloud.</context>
      <utterance>Stupid superstitious bastard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he supposed to look like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I've never seen a mummy look like this. He's, he's still...</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Juicy?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. He's more than four thousand years old and still decomposing.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell points at the inside of the COFFIN LID, where there are FINGERNAIL SCRATCHES and DRIED BLOOD all over the inside.</context>
      <utterance>And look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This sends a chill through everyone. Evelyn leans in closer.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my god, he was buried alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE PUSH IN on a grouping of hieratics WRITTEN IN BLOOD.</context>
      <utterance>And he left a message.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It says: 'Death is only the beginning.' Jonathan shivers. O'Connell looks around.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's my gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do? Shoot him?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he decides to wake up, hell yes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EGYPTOLOGIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Henderson kicks the sandy floor in anger.</context>
      <utterance>I have heard told of this book, but I never truly believed it existed. This, good gentlemen, is a most priceless treasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't trade ya for a brass spittoon!</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniels kicks the chest. It breaks open, unfolding to reveal a lower compartment. Inside, are Anck-su-namun's FIVE JEWEL ENCRUSTED CANOPIC JARS (one is shattered and without jewels)</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! It's supposed to be made outta pure gold!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell and Beni both grin. Jonathan looks horrified.</context>
      <utterance>What is this stuff? It smells like our late friend, the Warden.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did not!?... We're not!?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The gloating Americans sit down, fondling their jeweled jars.</context>
      <utterance>Rat gizzards. They smell bad and taste worse, but that's the best the desert has to offer.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say O'Connell, whadaya think these honey's'll fetch back home?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We hear you gentlemen found yerselves a nice gooey mummy. Congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Americans laugh. Evelyn walks up, sits down and drops a pile of big dusty BUG SKELETONS onto the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Ya know if ya dry him out, you can sell him for firewood.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shrugs, then looks at the roasting meat</context>
      <utterance>Scarabs, flesh eaters, I found them inside our friend's coffin. They can stay alive for years living off the flesh of a corpse, or in this case...</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell and Jonathan stare at the bug skeletons, disgusted.</context>
      <utterance>Famished.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you saying somebody threw these things in with our guy, and they slowly ate him alive?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very slowly.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He certainly was not a popular fellow when they planted him.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must of got a little too frisky with the Pharaoh's daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to my readings, our friend suffered the HOM-DAI, the worst of all ancient Egyptian curses, one reserved for only the most evil blasphemers. In all of my research, I've never read of this curse actually having been performed.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That bad huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, they never used it because they feared it so. It's written, that if a victim of the HOM-DAI should ever arise, he would bring with him the ten plagues of Egypt.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ten plagues?... You mean all ten plagues.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what that Moses guy did to that Pharaoh guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's one way of putting it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's see, there was frogs, flies, locusts...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hail and fire.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The sun turning black.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Water turning to blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the men share nervous looks, really spooked. Evelyn just laughs at them, then pulls a meat stick out of the fire.</context>
      <utterance>And my personal favorite: people covered in boils and sores.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fried gizzard anyone?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure you outta be playin, around with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn opens the cover. THE FIRE FLICKERS. She and O'Connell share a nervous look, then Evelyn shrugs and starts reading.</context>
      <utterance>It's just a book, no harm ever came from a book.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn continues READING THE BOOK ALOUD IN ANCIENT EGYPTIAN.</context>
      <utterance>Ahm kum Ra. Ahm kum Dei.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you see that!? Grasshoppers! Billions of grasshoppers!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's one of the plagues, right? The grasshopper plague!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn steps forward, something SQUISHES. O'Connell lowers his TORCH, -- the entire floor is FILLED WITH SLIMY FROGS.</context>
      <utterance>This is not a plague. It's generational. Every so many years the locusts of Egypt have a population explosion and they all take flight.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay,... and what about frogs?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>BURNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burns half-blindly staggers forward. The Figure doesn't move.</context>
      <utterance>Daniels?... is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BURNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burns TRIPS, stumbles forward, towards the Figure, his hands reach out and SINK INTO IMHOTEP'S PUTRID CHEST CAVITY. Burns jumps like a scalded cat, pulls his hands out and looks at them, -- HIS HANDS ARE COVERED IN MOLTEN FLESH ROT. He starts to SCREAM. A SKELETAL HAND clamps over his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Henderson?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as she reaches him he turns around. It's Burns. BOTH OF HIS EYES ARE MISSING. He stares at her with vacant sockets. Evelyn SCREAMS in horror and backs away, hyperventilating, she bumps into something. She SCREAMS again and spins around It's Imhotep. With two fresh EYEBALLS in his sockets. Evelyn SCREAMS again and backs away into a wall. Her hair is down, her face is dirty and sweaty, her blouse is ripped, her dress is torn, she's never looked sexier. Imhotep SQUINTS.</context>
      <utterance>Oh thank goodness, you're one of the Americans, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anck-su-namun?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burns opens his mouth, but can only GURGLE and MOAN because HIS TONGUE IS MISSING. Imhotep grabs him, throws him to the ground and sets his skeletal foot on Burns' chest, like a big game hunter standing on his kill. Imhotep then parts his fetid lips, -- A FRESH TONGUE FLAPS BETWEEN HIS ROTTED TEETH.</context>
      <utterance>Help me,... please,... help me.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn shivers in fear. Suddenly, O'Connell comes flying around the corner and runs right up to her.</context>
      <utterance>Kadeesh pharos Anck-su-namun!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell sees the look in her eyes and turns around, -- at the sight of Imhotep, O'Connell jumps back in fright.</context>
      <utterance>Would you quit playin, around! Let's get outta here already!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you to leave or die, you refused, and now you may have killed us all. For you have unleashed the creature that we have feared for more than four thousand years.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax, I got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No mortal weapons can kill this creature. He is not of this world.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we talkin, about the same creature? The walking corpse? Really big mouth? Really bad breath?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It has no effect on Imhotep, who continues forward. Beni quickly grabs at the other symbols and icons, holding them out towards Imhotep, one after the other, trying to slow his progress: an Islamic Sword and Crescent Moon necklace; a Hindu Brahma medallion; a small Buddhist Bodhisattva statue. All while blessing himself in Arabic, Hindi, Chinese and Latin. Nothing works. Imhotep's skeletal hand reaches for Beni's throat. Tears run down Beni's cheeks he's so freaked. And that's when he holds up THE STAR OF DAVID and blesses himself in HEBREW. Imhotep stops in his tracks. His hand lowers. His grotesque new eyeballs stare at Beni.</context>
      <utterance>May the good Lord protect and watch over me as a shepherd watches over his flock. And may Satan in all his forms be vanquished forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks at him quizzically. Imhotep takes a step back.</context>
      <utterance>The language of the slaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep reaches into his tattered robe, and then holds out his fetid hand, filled with squirming MAGGOTS. Beni cringes, about to throw up, but then the maggots part, -- revealing a tiny pile of little JEWELS. Beni's eyes widen. Imhotep raises his other hand, it holds Anck-su-namun's BROKEN CANOPIC JAR.</context>
      <utterance>I may have use for you. And the rewards will be great.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are the other sacred jars?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bastards!</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do to him!?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We saved him! Saved him before the creature could finish his work. Now leave, all of you, quickly, before he finishes you all.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn ELBOWS Jonathan in the ribs.</context>
      <utterance>You're not going to kill us?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ardeth Ray and the Mumia start heading down into the crevice. O'Connell yells at them, trying to convince himself.</context>
      <utterance>We must now hunt him down, and try and find a way to kill him, before he consumes the earth. Allah be with us.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ardeth Ray stops and looks back, deadly serious.</context>
      <utterance>I told ya, I already got him!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ardeth Ray turns and jumps down into the crevice,</context>
      <utterance>Know this, the creature will be coming for you. He must consummate the curse. And until he does, he will never eat, he will never sleep, and he will never stop.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell heads for the closet. Evelyn UNPACKS the dresses</context>
      <utterance>I thought you didn't believe in this stuff!?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Having an encounter with a four thousand year old walking-talking corpse tends to convert one.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it, we're out the door down the hall and gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell throws a handful of her underthings into the trunk.</context>
      <utterance>No, we are not.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell continues to PACK Evelyn's clothes as she continues to UNPACK them:</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes we are.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No we are not. We woke him up, and we must try and stop him.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We?! What we?! You didn't read that book. I told you not to play around with that thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell angrily stretches a bra between his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Alright then, Me, I,... I read the book, I woke him up and I intend to stop him.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn grabs the bra and throws it into a drawer.</context>
      <utterance>How!? You heard the man, no mortal weapons can kill this guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we'll have to find some immortal ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell stuffs a pile of Evelyn's shoes into the trunk. Evelyn KICKS the lid shut, slamming it on his fingers. O'Connell YELPS and angrily storms around the room sucking his fingers as Evelyn follows him.</context>
      <utterance>There goes that belief again. Not me, I am outta here!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>According to that Book, once this creature has been reborn, his curse will spread, and as he grows in strength, so will his curse grow, infecting the people until the whole of the earth is destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? So? Is that my problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's everybody's problem!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look lady, I appreciate you saving my life and all, but when I signed on, I agreed to take you out there and bring you back, and I did, now were even, end of job, end of story, contract terminated.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I am to you? A contract?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can either tag along with me, or you can stay here and play around with Mister Maggot.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm staying.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Beni ya little stinkweed, where did you slink off to?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You left me! You left me in the desert to rot.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah,... sorry bout that.  So who's this guy?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is Prince Imhotep, High Priest of Osiris.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell sticks out his hand, -- Imhotep instantly recoils O'Connell gives him the once-over. Beni quickly covers.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, hey, how ya doin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Prince does not like to be touched by other humans. A Silly eastern superstition, I'm afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, we all got our little problems today don't we?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He has come to help Mister Burns. Somehow I feel responsible.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't gimme that, you never had any scruples.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell fake-punches him. Beni flinches. O'Connell gives Imhotep a look as he strides off.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know where I can steal some?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep's grotesque new eyes glare out from behind the mask.</context>
      <utterance>See ya around, Padre.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tough customers shove him away. Winston staggers over to O'Connell and Jonathan at the bar, not missing a beat.</context>
      <utterance>I'm the last of the Royal Force still stationed here, you know? All the other laddies died in the air and were buried in the sand.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever since the end of the Great War, there hasn't been a single challenge worthy of a man like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell shoves him away. Winston staggers back to Jonathan.</context>
      <utterance>I've heard it before, Winston.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan shoves him towards another group of unlucky sods Henderson and Daniels sidle up to the bar next to them. Burns, now tongue-less, talks with a severe impediment.</context>
      <utterance>I just wish I would've chucked it with the other laddies, gone down in a flame of glory, instead of sitting around here, rotting from boredom and booze!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURNS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep opens the drawer and pulls out some bifocals. He puts the bifocals on over his death mask, -- and grins broadly, his rotted teeth showing through the mouth hole.</context>
      <utterance>The drawer there, spectacles.  As you see, I won't be needing them.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The expression on Burns' face starts to change, very puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Mister Burns, Prince Imhotep thanks you for your spectacles, -- and for your eyes,... and for your tongue.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look of pure fear registers on Burns, face. Beni quickly backs away and runs out of the room. Imhotep picks up the sacred canopic jar, then removes the death mask, revealing his hideous, shattered CORPSE-SKULL.</context>
      <utterance>But I am afraid more is needed, the Prince says he must finish the job, consummate the curse which you and your friends have brought down upon yourselves.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweet Jesus! That tasted just like,... like...</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all look at each other, even more nervous.</context>
      <utterance>Blood.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A look passes over O'Connell's face, a realization.</context>
      <utterance>"And the rivers and waters of Egypt went red and were as blood."</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He suddenly jumps away from the bar and runs for the door.</context>
      <utterance>He's here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's here!?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The guy! The Priest! THE MUMMY!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's when a barrage of HAIL AND FIRE slams into the courtyard. O'Connell and Evelyn jump back. A water fountain bursts into STEAM. A wooden trellis catches FIRE. O'Connell and Evelyn run under the eaves as SOLDIERS, SERVANTS and CAMELS run in every direction, trying to avoid the maelstrom.</context>
      <utterance>We got problems.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's here! I saw him! That thing is here!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell gives her an incredulous look and gestures at the HAIL and FIRE.</context>
      <utterance>The creature!? Are you sure!?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The HAIL and FIRE come to a stop. Everything goes dead quiet. O'Connell and Evelyn freeze. And then a BLOOD CURDLING SCREAM is heard coming from the living quarters directly above them. O'Connell and Evelyn race up the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Pretty sure!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep starts to move towards them, staring at Evelyn.</context>
      <utterance>We are in serious trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep keeps coming. O'Connell OPENS FIRE. BLASTING Imhotep Bullets RIP through his body. Imhotep doesn't seem to mind. Jonathan, Henderson and Daniels run into the room. They're all stunned at the sight of Imhotep. O'Connell steps forward, throws a RIGHT HOOK, punches Imhotep in the face, -- HIS FIST GOES THROUGH IMHOTEP'S SKULL AND GETS STUCK DEEP INSIDE HIS HEAD. O'Connell stares at it, shocked, then quickly YANKS his fist back out. The area of Imhotep's face that came into contact with O'Connell's fist quickly DEGENERATES and DECAYS, right down to the bone, as if O'Connell's hand instantly infected it. Imhotep angrily turns, grabs O'Connell, and with no effort, THROWS him across the room and into Jonathan and the others knocking them down. Imhotep looks at his hand, the one that just grabbed O'Connell, -- IT STARTS TO SHRIVEL and DECAY. He quickly turns to Evelyn. Evelyn backs away into a wall, terrorized. Imhotep steps up to her.</context>
      <utterance>Back off, creep.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans in, about to kiss her with his decayed face. And that's when a WHITE CAT jumps onto the piano, HISSING. Imhotep SHRIEKS. The balcony doors BLOW OPEN. Imhotep spins into a BLAST OF WIND AND SAND and SWIRLS out the doors. Gone. O'Connell, Evelyn, Jonathan and Daniels stand transfixed. Henderson kneels next to Burns, shriveled body, horrified.</context>
      <utterance>You saved me from the undead. For this, I shall make you immortal.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The curse. The curse.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miss Carnavon. Gentlemen.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is he doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everybody tenses, guns up. Then O'Connell uncocks his .38.</context>
      <utterance>Do you truly wish to know? Or would you prefer to just shoot us?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slides his gun back into his shoulder-holster.</context>
      <utterance>I just saw my fist vanish into some guy's head.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm willin, to go on a little faith, here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will not believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are part of an ancient secret society, the cult-of-the-Mumia, and we have a sacred mission, passed down through thirty-nine generations. For over four thousand years we have guarded The City Of The Dead. we are sworn at manhood to do any and all in our power to stop the High Priest Imhotep from being reborn into this world.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And because of you, we have failed.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you think this justifies killing innocent people!?</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To have stopped this creature? Yes!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, let's cut to the chase. He's afraid of cats, what's that about?</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniels is totally wigged-out, he looks at O'Connell.</context>
      <utterance>According to the ancients, cat's are the guardians at the gates of the underworld. Imhotep will fear them until he is fully regenerated, and then he will fear nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right! And ya know how he gets fully regenerated?! By killing everybody who opened that chest and sucking us dry! That's how!</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, the creature must first try and regenerate, and then he will attempt to resurrect the one he has loved for more than four thousand years.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Curator and Ardeth Ray look at Evelyn, thunderstruck.</context>
      <utterance>Anck-su-namun.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the necropolis, when I saw him, - alive,... walking, he called me Anck- su-namun. And then in Mister Burns' quarters he tried to kiss me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan scratches his ear with the barrel of his pistol.</context>
      <utterance>It is because it was you who read from the Book. He has chosen you to be the human sacrifice needed to regenerate the body of Anck-su-namun.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ardeth Ray has been staring out a wall of windows.</context>
      <utterance>This is not good. Not good at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone follows Ardeth Ray's eyes, through the windows we can see the SUN, -- which is now going into a FULL ECLIPSE.</context>
      <utterance>Tonight is the full moon. The moon of Osiris. It will begin tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"...and he stretched forth his hands towards the heavens, and there was darkness throughout the land of Egypt."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to Daniels and Henderson.</context>
      <utterance>We must stop him from regenerating.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who opened that chest?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell turns from the window.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there was me and Daniels here and then poor Burns of course, oh yeah, and that Egyptologist fella.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about my buddy, Beni?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Naw, he scrammed outta there,</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell looks at Evelyn, Daniels and Henderson.</context>
      <utterance>We must find the Egyptologist and bring him back here to the safety of the fort, before the creature can get to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All three of them pounce on him at once --</context>
      <utterance>Okay,... Evelyn, you wait here, you two come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell with that! I'm not goin' nowhere! We're safe here.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I'm not leavin, this fort for nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell just shakes his head and SIGHS. Totally put-upon. Then he takes Evelyn, shoves her into the bedroom, slams the door and locks it with a skeleton key. From inside her room we can hear Evelyn POUNDING on the door and YELLING. O'Connell throws the skeleton key to Daniels.</context>
      <utterance>Who put you in charge? You can't just leave me behind like some old suitcase. I'm the one responsible for this mess and I intend to be the one to clean it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep an eye on her. If you leave her door, I'll rip your spleen out. C'mon, Jonathan. Jonathan swallows hard and points to himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Beni spins around. O'Connell and Jonathan stand in the door.</context>
      <utterance>Well, well, well.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beni turns and runs for an open window. O'Connell grabs a chair, FLINGS IT into his path. Beni TRIPS and CRASHES into a wall. O'Connell strides over, grabs him and lifts him up the wall. Beni's feet dangle off the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme guess, spring cleaning?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your new friend?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell quickly slides his knife up under Beni's chin.</context>
      <utterance>What friend? You're my only friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then you got no excuse for living. What the hell you doin, being buddies with this creep, Beni? What's in it for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It is better to be the right hand of the Devil,... than in his path. As long as I serve him, I am immune.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Immune from what?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shall see.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell shoves the knife deeper into Beni's skin.</context>
      <utterance>What are you looking for? Lie, and I'll slit your throat.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The book! The black book they found at Hamunaptra! Imhotep wants it back. Said to me it would be worth it's weight in diamonds.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does he want the book for?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That looked rather painful.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ya know, ever since I met you, my luck has been for crap.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And that's when they hear a BLOOD CURDLING SCREAM coming from down in the bazaar. O'Connell and Jonathan scramble to the window and look out --</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know, I do that to people.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn-it! That's two down and only two to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They turn and race out of the office.</context>
      <utterance>And then he'll be coming after Evy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The hell with this. I'm goin, downstairs to get me a drink. You want somethin'?</utterance>
   <speaker>HENDERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>shot of bourbon and a bourbon chaser. Daniels nods and heads out. Henderson just sits there, alone, smoking. He reaches into his jacket pocket, pulls out his SACRED CANOPIC JAR and fondles it. A BREEZE suddenly comes in through the open window. The curtains flutter. Henderson gets up and goes over to shut it. He looks out the window. The CAMERA races over the compound, into the window and HITS Henderson square in the FACE just as he's about to scream. Henderson is lifted into the air by a mass of SWIRLING SAND. His body TWISTS and TURNS and slowly SHRIVELS as the life is SUCKED out of him. Then he COLLAPSES to the floor. On the wall above him, the SHADOW of the SWIRLING SAND condenses, forming a SHADOW of a human body. The SHADOW CONVULSES as the body REGENERATES. And then it's over. Imhotep steps into view. He's regenerated even further and looks almost normal now, his face no longer decayed. He steps over Henderson's shriveled body and up to Evelyn's door, rattles the knob. It's locked. Imhotep grins.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, get me a glass of bourbon, a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep's sadness turns to anger as he spins around and faces O'Connell. Imhotep licks his fetid lips. O'Connell smirks.</context>
      <utterance>Get your hands off my girl, pal.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep starts to move for O'Connell.</context>
      <utterance>Nice lips.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws the white cat at Imhotep. Imhotep instinctively catches it. He SHRIEKS, drops the cat and stumbles back towards the window, -- which suddenly BLOWS OPEN. Imhotep spins like a dervish and BURSTS INTO A WHIRLWIND OF SAND. Everybody covers their eyes. The Imhotep/sand-devil EXPLODES out the window and vanishes over the compound. Jonathan aims his gun at the window, his hand shaking badly. O'Connell hugs Evelyn as she wipes her mouth in disgust. Daniels walks in, looks at Henderson's shriveled body on the floor... and drops the martini glasses.</context>
      <utterance>I figured you might be here, so I brought a friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You called me your girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?... Oh yeah, that was just um, you know, figure a speech.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you were jealous</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Daniels leans forward from the back seat, filled with fear,</context>
      <utterance>Jealous? You kiddin' me? Did you see that guy's face?</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They race into the driveway of the museum of Antiquities.</context>
      <utterance>Shut-up! JUST SHUT-UP! We gotta do somethin'! we gotta do somethin, NOW! Before it's too late!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last month I came across an inscription that mentioned The Book Of The Dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>DANIELS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That book we found at Hamunaptra?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I dismissed it, because it talked about bringing people back from the dead. A notion I was unwilling to believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Believe it, sister. That's what brought our buddy back to life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And now he's going to use it to bring his girlfriend back</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Curator joins Evelyn at her side as she heads up the stairs, everyone else in hot pursuit.</context>
      <utterance>And if he succeeds, the two of them together will bring about the apocalypse.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach the display cases. Evelyn quickly opens them.</context>
      <utterance>The plagues we have seen so far, are merely Imhotep flexing his muscles. Only at the moment of Anck-su-namun's resurrection will he be truly invincible.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking that if the black Book Of The Dead can bring people back to life --</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- then perhaps, the golden Book Of The Living can return them to the underworld.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly --</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So your sayin', if we find the book made outta gold --</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- And read the sacred incantations contained inside it.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think it'll send this guy back to hell?</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LOUD CHANTING is heard coming from outside. They all rush over to the upper windows and look down -- OUTSIDE: A large, CRAZED MOB covered in hideous boils and sores comes CHANTING up the driveway: 'Anck-su-namun! Anck-su-namun!'</context>
      <utterance>Correct, And that's when --</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It has begun. The beginning of the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn dashes back to the display cases. Everyone follows.</context>
      <utterance>Not quite yet it hasn't. C'mon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The BANGING gets LOUDER. Multiple windows SHATTER. Evelyn talks while quickly translating the tablet:</context>
      <utterance>Got what?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn finds the translation in the tablet and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Since the black Book of The Dead was found inside the statue of Anubis, then according to this, the golden Book of The Living should be inside...</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The golden Book Of The Living, is inside the statue of Horus.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which would be located not far to the east of the Anubis statue.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me we gotta go back out there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TWO HIDEOUS BOIL &amp; SORE-COVERED MEN charge out of a doorway, SCREAMING. O'Connell and Ardeth Ray grab them and chuck them over the railing. The men fly through the air and CRASH into the lower display cases. The front doors suddenly BURST OPEN, The crazed mob pours into the museum. our heroes haul ass across the balcony and down the staircase.</context>
      <utterance>If we want to kill the creature, yes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crazed group runs past him and heads into the front doors of the museum. Jonathan leaps into the convertible, fires it up and 180's it back over to the bushes. O'Connell, Evelyn, Daniels, Ardeth Ray and the Curator jump inside the car. Beni steps out of the museum and sees them.</context>
      <utterance>Anck-su-namun! Anck-su-namun!</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep looks out of the museum from the shattered upper windows just as the convertible PEELS OUT. O'Connell points a finger at Beni as they race past him.</context>
      <utterance>Imhotep! IMHOTEP!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep UNHINGES his jaw, his mouth stretches to an inhuman size, he lets out one of his horrific, primordial SHRIEKS. His disease-ridden disciples immediately begin pouring out of the front doors of the museum and chasing after the car.</context>
      <utterance>You're gonna get yours, pal!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all leap out of the car. But the angry, festering mob quickly surrounds them. O'Connell quickly reaches into his gunny-sack, pulls out a stick of dynamite, then reaches into his pocket and pulls out a match. He looks around for a way to light it, then reaches over and strikes it across Ardeth Ray's stubbly face. Ardeth Ray YELPS. O'Connell holds the lit match near the fuse. The crazed, CHANTING mob gives O'Connell a wide berth, staring at him and the others with insane, bloodshot eyes. And then Imhotep steps through, -- having fully regenerated, he now looks as young and handsome and muscular as he did the day he was buried alive. Evelyn stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon! C'mon! Let's go! Let's go!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell gives her a look, the match burns his fingers. He YELPS and throws it down, grabs another match and strikes it across Ardeth Ray's face again. Ardeth Ray YELPS and gives O'Connell a look to kill. The Curator shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>He's gorgeous.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE CURATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep moves forward, heading right for them. O'Connell LIGHTS THE FUSE. Imhotep steps up to O'Connell and stops, watching the fuse burn down. it's a game of chicken. The tension mounts. The LIT FUSE is about to vanish inside the stick of dynamite, blowing it up, -- when Evelyn leans forward and blows it out. O'Connell exhales, but keeps his eyes on Imhotep, who extends his hand to Evelyn.</context>
      <utterance>He has consummated the curse, now all he need do is raise Anck-su-namun from the dead, then it will be the end of us, and the beginning for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beni steps through the swarming mass, translating.</context>
      <utterance>Koontash dai na.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn hesitates, looks around at the huge, bloodthirsty crowd surrounding them, holding axes, picks and scimitars, waiting to pounce, then she looks at Imhotep, confident, powerful, invincible. Then she looks at O'Connell.</context>
      <utterance>Take his hand and he will spare the others.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell talks through angry, grit teeth.</context>
      <utterance>Any bright ideas?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn looks back at Imhotep, then starts to reach out to take his hand. Both O'Connell and Jonathan move to stop her, -- but Ardeth Ray grabs them both and holds them tight.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, fresh out.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't do it, Evelyn.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn's trembling hand touches Imhotep's: His hand closes around hers. Nothing happens. Imhotep smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I have no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keetah mi pharos, aja nilo, isirlan.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn gives Beni a nasty look, correcting him --</context>
      <utterance>Come with me my princess. It is time to make you mine, forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she looks at O'Connell and puts on her best face.</context>
      <utterance>All eternity, idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell almost smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You better think of something, because if he turns me into a mummy, you're the first one I'm coming after.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got guts, lady.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep suddenly notices something. He reaches forward and --</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I know, and I'd like to keep them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ardeth Ray holds Jonathan back. Imhotep pulls Evelyn away. O'Connell can't take it anymore, he tries to break free of Ardeth Ray's grip.</context>
      <utterance>Hey that's mine -- !</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The huge, powerful man holds him tight.</context>
      <utterance>Evelyn!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crowd parts for Imhotep and Evelyn. And then Imhotep stops and looks back at O'Connell.</context>
      <utterance>Be calm. There is still time. We can stop him yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn SCREAMS.</context>
      <utterance>Pared oos.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We gotta get her back.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell looks at Ardeth Ray.</context>
      <utterance>I'm with you, old man. No one touches my sister like that and gets away with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know where he's taking her?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan looks worried.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. To Hamunaptra. To perform the ritual.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what ritual would that be?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ritual to bring the body of Anck- su-namun back to life.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And how does one do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By reading the Book Of The Dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then killing your sister.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ardeth Ray looks at O'Connell.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan taps him in the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Imhotep is now able to cross the desert with great haste.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ardeth Ray ignores him.</context>
      <utterance>Begging your pardon, but I wasn't quite clear on that last part.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he arrives before us, it will be too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Did you say 'kill' my sister?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And on that WE SMASH CUT TO -- THE ERFOUD DUNES - DAWN Jonathan's bashed-in convertible steams it's way up to a set of semi-abandoned Quonset huts. A single WWI BIPLANE with R.A.F. INSIGNIAS sits in the sand beside them. A SIGN READS:</context>
      <utterance>I know how to beat him to it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's your little problem got to do with His Majesty's Royal Air Corp?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winston looks intrigued.</context>
      <utterance>Not a god-damned thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it dangerous?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This really interests him.</context>
      <utterance>You probably won't live through it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By Jove, do you really think so?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Winston nods his head, he's hooked.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody else we've bumped into has died, why not you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's the challenge then?</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A slow grin spreads across Winston's face, then he gives them a snappy salute.</context>
      <utterance>To save the damsel in distress, kill the bad guy and steal his treasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Winston Havlock at your service, sir!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What just happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then they hear a plane in the sky and look up.</context>
      <utterance>All I remember is him turning into a blast of sand,... and then I remember nothing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>WE GO WIDE AS: The sandstorm chases the diving, twisting biplane. Getting closer and closer, about to engulf it. O'Connell looks back into the blinding sand and sees a GIANT FACE forming inside the sandstorm. It's Imhotep. Grinning. O'Connell grabs the Lewis machine-gun, cocks the bracket and FIRES, blasting away at Imhotep's giant face inside the sandstorm. Imhotep's face begins to laugh, then his jaw unhinges, his mouth opens wide, and he ENGULFS the plane. Winston blindly fights for control, elated.</context>
      <utterance>Hang on, men!</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The biplane SPINS inside the BLOWING SAND. Engines ROARING. Wind HOWLING. Jonathan and Ardeth Ray SCREAMING. Winston Havlock LAUGHING.</context>
      <utterance>We're going down!</utterance>
   <speaker>WINSTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell braces himself for impact,</context>
      <utterance>Here I come, laddies!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, now what the hell does this Horus guy look like?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a big fellow with pointy ears and a face like a falcon.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn gives him a look.</context>
      <utterance>Keep moving.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beni suddenly looks worried.</context>
      <utterance>You know, nasty little fellows such as yourself, always get their comeuppance.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beni looks even more worried, he nervously starts chewing on his lip. All three of them walk over the bridge crossing the disgusting DETRITUS MOAT. Evelyn looks down at it, horrified.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, always.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks over and tries to jiggle it free. It comes loose in his hand. He looks at the scarab in his palm. It starts to glow. And then something inside it starts to WIGGLE.</context>
      <utterance>I say, look at that.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wiggling continues; a long, agonizing BEAT, and then the scarab breaks out of it's cocoon and instantly BURROWS into Jonathan's palm. Jonathan starts to freak out and SCREAM. O'Connell runs up and rips the arm off Jonathan's shirt. The scarab is now BURROWING UP JONATHAN'S ARM. O'Connell whips out his butterfly-knife, snaps it open and grabs Jonathan's arm. Jonathan's eyes widen in terror as the knife passes in front of his face. Jonathan SCREAMS LOUDER, obviously being cut open. O'Connell's hand flicks something away. The scarab hits the floor and immediately starts scurrying back towards Jonathan, wanting to finish the job. O'Connell pulls out his gun and blows it away, -- BLAM!</context>
      <utterance>Say, gents! You should come have a look at this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn blushes, feeling complimented by the handsome prince.</context>
      <utterance>Prince Imhotep wants your heart.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep continues SPEAKING while laying the four jewel encrusted canopic jars next to the shattered one.</context>
      <utterance>Tell him, I'm truly flattered... but that it's already taken.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn's eyes widen.</context>
      <utterance>He wants your heart and your brain, your liver, your kidneys...</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and how do you say? Those slimy things, in your stomach?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Intestines.</utterance>
   <speaker>BENI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn can't believe it, she furiously turns to Imhotep.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! Them.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep looks at her and grins, then BACKHANDS her -- WAP! Evelyn goes down for the count. Imhotep stares at her, cold, malevolent, then he turns and walks off into the mausoleums. Beni nervously glances around, then quickly scurries away.</context>
      <utterance>You only want me for my organs?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell are these guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell pulls the elephant gun out of his gunny-sack.</context>
      <utterance>Priests. Imhotep's priests.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never killed a priest before.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are evil, cursed, they matter not.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell FIRES the elephant gun. SMOKE and FLAME shoot out. BLASTS one of the mummies. Blows it's upper torso clean off. O'Connell pumps the gun, the huge spent cartridge flips through the air. He FIRES again. BLASTS the other mummy, blows this one's torso clean off as well. The smoke clears. The two sets of LEGS keep walking forward, unaffected by the loss of their upper torsos. O'Connell can't believe it.</context>
      <utterance>Well, okay then.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then the disemboweled upper torsos start to move, turning over and crawling towards our heroes, who start to back away.</context>
      <utterance>Oh come on, gimme a break here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The men race around a corner. More mummies. They race around another corner. More mummies. Onward they come. Methodical. Relentless. Boxing in our heroes. O'Connell and Ardeth Ray FIRING as they go. Ardeth Ray goes empty.</context>
      <utterance>This whole place is comin, alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He throws the machine-gun down and they all race into --</context>
      <utterance>I'm out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They run up to the base of the statue,</context>
      <utterance>There he is!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell looks back at the mummies coming down the passageway. He reaches into his gunny-sack and pulls out a stick of dynamite. Ardeth Ray taps him on the shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Hello Horus old boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell hands him the dynamite and a match, then turns to look at the statue. Ardeth Ray reaches forward and strikes the match off O'Connell's stubbly face. O'Connell YELPS. Ardeth Ray lights the dynamite and throws it down the passageway. They all hit the deck. The dynamite EXPLODES. Ripping apart the creatures, causing a CAVE-IN and sealing the passageway with rock and dirt. Now there's only one way out, -- another dark, creepy passageway.</context>
      <utterance>Allow me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ardeth Ray grabs the elephant gun and a handful of shells and runs off towards the mummies.</context>
      <utterance>These guys just don't quit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell and Jonathan redouble their efforts, pulling harder on the seam. The compartment starts to loosen. About to give. The last time this happened, salt acid sprayed out, remember? Our heroes keep tugging. The tension mounts... And that's when a SKELETAL HAND BURSTS UP OUT OF THE GROUND and grabs O'Connell's ankle. Several more moldy hands BURST up out of the ground. O'Connell and Jonathan struggle with the mummies as they crawl up out of the dirt floor. One of the mummies violently shoves O'Connell away. Another grabs Jonathan by the throat and starts to strangle him. A third mummy grabs at the secret compartment and pulls hard.</context>
      <utterance>Keep digging!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARDETH RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mummies quickly overwhelm and start to tear him apart. O'Connell lights the last stick of dynamite and throws it against the far wall. He and Jonathan hit the deck.</context>
      <utterance>Save the girl! Kill the creature!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wall BLOWS. Debris COLLAPSES, -- but now here's a hole for them to get out. O'Connell and Jonathan race out through the hole just as the remaining mummies enter the chamber.</context>
      <utterance>That's the last one, we better get lucky.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>IMHOTEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He raises it up over Evelyn's chest, about to plunge it down. Evelyn's eyes widen in horror. And that's when O'Connell and Jonathan BURST IN. Imhotep spins around and faces them. Jonathan beams as he holds up the golden Book Of The Living.</context>
      <utterance>With your death, my love and I will be invincible!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I found it, Evy! I found it</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell grabs an ancient sword out of a statue's hand, jumps up onto a gravestone and leaps out over the Priests. The Priest-mummies stop chanting. The MIST vanishes. Imhotep steps forward. O'Connell STRIKES the sacrificial knife out of his hand. Imhotep BELLOWS a command. The Priests stand up, swords and knives in hand, they ATTACK O'Connell.</context>
      <utterance>Shut-up and get me off of here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="24">
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell RACKS and CHOPS at the attacking Priest-mummies, fighting his way to Evelyn. The skeletal creatures wildly SWING their swords, trying to STAB O'Connell. Jonathan fumbles with the book, struggling to open it, -- he can't.</context>
      <utterance>Open the book, Jonathan! Open the book! That's the only way to kill him!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell CUTS two of the mummies in half, then swings his sword down at Evelyn, -- CLANG! One chain breaks free. Jonathan spots a series of SOLID GOLD, FOUR-SIDED LOCKS along the binder. It hits him like lightning --</context>
      <utterance>I can't open it! It's locked or something!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep grins, then grabs the KEY/BOX hanging from a chain around his neck, rips it off and shoves it into his pocket He picks up the sacrificial sword and heads for Jonathan.</context>
      <utterance>We need the key!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I do, Evy!? What do I do!?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell swings his sword down again, -- CLANG! Evelyn now has one hand and one leg free. More mummies attack O'Connell force him back. Jonathan quickly starts translating the cover inscription, but his ancient Egyptian is clearly awful.</context>
      <utterance>Read the inscription on the cover!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan starts to backpedal through the cemetery, clutching the golden book; wide-eyed, as Imhotep moves in on him.</context>
      <utterance>Keetash-something, naraba-something.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jonathan trips and falls on his ass. Imhotep CHARGES FORWARD. O'Connell SLASHES another chain. Only one more left holding Evelyn. Jonathan sits up and quickly looks back at the cover.</context>
      <utterance>Ebarra im hatu Kashka ummmmm -- ?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep raises the sacrificial sword, about to kill Jonathan. And that's when the giant statue of Anubis suddenly CRASHES through the wall -- shades of Ray Harryhausen. Only better. The god of Deaths, horrible, decrepit STONE FACE stares angrily down. Jonathan stares back.</context>
      <utterance>Rasheem Aaaaa ANUBIS!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell DECAPITATES a mummy and looks up at Anubis.</context>
      <utterance>Oh boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep leaves Jonathan and heads for the giant statue. O'Connell leaps over and with one last swing of the sword, frees Evelyn from her chains. More Priest-mummies attack, forcing him away. Evelyn jumps off the altar and starts to head for O'Connell, -- a SKELETAL HAND grabs her! Spins her around. It's Anck-su-namun's rotted corpse. Evelyn reacts. Imhotep looks up at Anubis, points to O'Connell, and in ANCIENT EGYPTIAN commands him to attack. Anubis moves for O'Connell, STOMPING over mausoleums and through the detritus moat on his way. O'Connell quickly backs away.</context>
      <utterance>This just keeps gettin, better and better.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do something, Jonathan! Kill it!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn is backing away from Anck-su-namun.</context>
      <utterance>You have got to be joking?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finish the inscription, idiot!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anck-su-namun ATTACKS Evelyn. Evelyn fends her off as best she can. Jonathan quickly looks back at the hieroglyphs on the book cover, fumbling badly under the pressure --</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ummm, Hootash im... Hootash im now what is this last symbol here?</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Anck-su-namun grabs Evelyn by the throat. The statue of Anubis corners O'Connell, reaches down and GRABS him with it's MASSIVE TALONS. O'Connell HACKS away at it. Jonathan stares at the inscription, slightly oblivious.</context>
      <utterance>What's it look like!?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn is being STRANGLED by Anck-su-namun.</context>
      <utterance>It's an Anck symbol, with two little squiggly lines above it, and a bird, a stork! on either side.</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah! Ah! Ahmenophus!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The talons lift O'Connell up and start to CRUSH him.</context>
      <utterance>Yes,... I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The giant statue of Anubis instantly freezes in it's tracks and PETRIFIES. It's off balance. Starts to fall. O'Connell slides free of it's talons. Evelyn SHOVES Anck-su-namun away, Anck-su-namun looks up and opens her fetid mouth to scream just as Anubis CRASHES DOWN on top of her, SMASHING HER to powder and DRIVING her into the ground. Imhotep SHRIEKS in rage and horror, then turns and angrily heads for Jonathan. Jonathan, sitting on his ass, quickly backpedals on his hands and heels. O'Connell leaps to his feet, sword in hand and runs for Imhotep. Imhotep grabs Jonathan, lifts him up, rips the golden Book Of The Living out of his hand and pins him to a wall. O'Connell runs up and swings his sword at Imhotep, -- WAP! SLICES Imhotep's right arm off. It drops to the ground, still clutching The Book Of The Living. Imhotep drops Jonathan and spins around, facing O'Connell. O'Connell grins.</context>
      <utterance>Hootash im Ahmenophus!</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep grabs O'Connell with his left arm and THROWS him half way across the cemetery. O'Connell SLAMS into a gravestone, bounces off and crashes to the ground. He shakes it off.</context>
      <utterance>Okay pal, let's see how tough you are without your right arm.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Imhotep is already striding towards him. Jonathan lifts up his hand, -- HE HAS THE KEY/BOX BACK! He smiles at Evelyn.</context>
      <utterance>Alright,... so he's left handed.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn runs for Jonathan. O'Connell SWINGS his sword and CLEAVES a big chunk of molten flesh rot out of Imhotep's stomach. On the outside, Imhotep looks human, but on the inside he is still a rotten old mummy. Imhotep BACKHANDS O'Connell. Knocks him twenty feet back. O'Connell staggers to his feet. Imhotep is right there. CLUBS him hard with his left arm. O'Connell spins through the air, SLAMS into the side of a mausoleum. Imhotep approaches, rage in his eyes. O'Connell gets up, quickly pivots and HACKS into Imhotep's head. Imhotep grins and PUNCHES O'Connell in the face. O'Connell is thrown back, pulling his sword with him. He bounces hard off the mausoleum. Lands on his feet. Totally beat-to-shit. Knees buckling. He can barely stand. Jonathan lifts up the heavy gold book, -- Imhotep's severed hand still clings to it. Jonathan cringes in disgust. Evelyn yanks it off, throws it away, then start furiously working the key into the series of locks, unlocking each of them. Imhotep strides forward. O'Connell backs into the mausoleum, swings the sword, Imhotep tries to catch it, -- it CLEAVES through his palm and deeply imbeds itself into his forearm. No matter, Imhotep rips the sword away from O'Connell and casually flings it away. The golden Book Of The Living opens with a HISS. Jonathan holds it tight as Evelyn quickly turns the heavy gold pages looking for something. O'Connell turns to run, but Imhotep grabs him by the throat and lifts him off his feet. O'Connell hangs there, a dazed mess. Imhotep grins, says something in ANCIENT EGYPTIAN, then starts to strangle O'Connell. O'Connell chokes. About to die. Evelyn turns and faces Imhotep and reads an inscription:</context>
      <utterance>I got it!</utterance>
   <speaker>EVELYN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kadeesh mal! Kadeesh mal! Pared oos!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONATHAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>O'Connell looks at Evelyn.</context>
      <utterance>Well,... I guess we go home empty handed.</utterance>
   <speaker>O'CONNELL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Evelyn returns the look, A BEAT, and then she wraps-her arms around his neck and kisses him. O'Connell returns it. Jonathan just rolls his eyes, snorts in disgust and climbs up onto a camel. When the kiss is over, O'Connell and Evelyn share a smile, then O'Connell leaps up into the saddle, reaches down, grabs Evelyn's hand and pulls her up behind him. Evelyn wraps her arms around his waist. O'Connell and Jonathan slap the reins.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't say that.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
