<movie id="209" title="Fifth Element The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Professor points emphatically to the snake, the symbol of Evil, coming through the door between the three planets in eclipse. C.U. Billy's hand sketches the snake quickly. He is a natural artist.</context>
      <utterance>"..the black hole like a door is open... Evil comes ... sowing terror and chaos..." See? The snake, Billy. The Ultimate Evil ... make sure you get the snake!</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Professor's fingers touch the signs.</context>
      <utterance>And when is this door opening snake act supposed to occur?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..if this is the five..and this the thousand.. He calculates.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every five thousand years..</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: Omar. Standing at the entrance to the chamber with the water bag, entranced by the sight. A skeletal hand falls on his shoulder. Omar turns to an ancient PRIEST in a rough milled black cannock.</context>
      <utterance>So I have some time.. He reaches for the pad.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Startled but obedient, Omar gives the water bag to the Priest.</context>
      <utterance>I will take it to them my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Priest makes the sign of the Cross on the boy's forehead, dismissing him. As soon as he is gone, the Priest turns a worried eye to the Professor. ANGLE ON: The Professor is back to translating, Billy to sketching.</context>
      <utterance>Go with God.. be safe from Evil..</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"..then arrange the elements of life against the Terror just so.." His fingers run on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His fingers fall on the one element that has a human shape, surrounded by all the others. The Priest opens the water skin and begins to pour a vial of powder into the skin. ANGLE ON: Aziz falling asleep. The mirror falls, the light fails.</context>
      <utterance>"..Water..fire..earth..air..four elements around the fifth.."</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy struggles to stay awake. The mirror comes up.</context>
      <utterance>Aziz! Light!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lord forgive me.. they already know too, much..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Professor turns to the Priest who is pouring water into a tin cup from the skin.</context>
      <utterance>Amen..</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father.. it in the most extraordinary thing.. the greatest find in history..can you imagine the implications.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands the cup to the Professor. The Professor takes it, has it almost to his lips when..</context>
      <utterance>Only too well... here you must be parched..</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In his excitement he does not drink, much to the Priest's chagrin.</context>
      <utterance>I mean look.. it is like a battle plan..</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Priest looks up, Aziz the mirror boy, tips his mouth under the water skin, drinking the leakage.</context>
      <utterance>Here the Good.. Here the Evil..</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to the Five Elements.</context>
      <utterance>Here..</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A weapon against evil. Amazing! I am going to be famous.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then let us toast to your fame! Here Billy.. The Priest hands Billy a cup.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drink!</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Professor raises the cup to drink, and then...</context>
      <utterance>To fame.. salud..</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Priest watches, disconsolate, as the Professor tosses away his water. Billy finishes his cup before running off into the tunnel.</context>
      <utterance>We cannot toast with water.. Billy ! In my sack.. the Grappa!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"..this perfect person.. this perfect being.." I do not understand this.. perfect?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is that boy? Billy!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At that moment, the reflection from Aziz's mirror drops again. The light fails.</context>
      <utterance>And this divine Light they talk about.. what is Divine light?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room is flooded with light all of the sudden.</context>
      <utterance>Aziz light!</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Professor turns around, and is stunned speechless to find himself face to face with two MONDOSHAWANS. A dozen others fill the hall manning the source of the light, large luminous globes. Aziz is fast asleep.</context>
      <utterance>Better.. this is the most unbelievable thing I have ever seen..</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Professor is lifted up and carried off to the side by the aliens. The KOMMANDER stops in front of the Priest who is still on his knees, face to the ground.</context>
      <utterance>...Uh, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two MONDOSHAWAN GUARDS hold the professor three feet off the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Master... He was about to discover everything, but I had the situation under control.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you? Are you Germans? Sprechen Sie Deutsch?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>10	INT.  TEMPLE  ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The KOMMANDER holds out his hand to the Priest.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Priest jumps to his feet excitedly.</context>
      <utterance>What did I do wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kommander goes over to the wall and seems to be looking for a lock. He finds it and slides in his metallic finger which is more intricate than a key to a safe. He turns his hand, activating a mechanism that opens the wall.</context>
      <utterance>Servant, you and the thousand guards before you... You have done your work well, but we have to recover the elements. War will soon engulf your planet. We must keep them safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kommander turns around and crooks a finger. One of the MONDOSHAWANS waves his hand, puts the professor to sleep and heads down the hallway revealed by the opening. He is followed by his men. The Priest slips in behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Unbelievable!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Fifth Element...</utterance>
   <speaker>KOMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His men carry out his order.</context>
      <utterance>Take them and put them in a safe place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will the elements be gone now forever from this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>KOMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We will return.</context>
      <utterance>When mankind comes to its senses.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Knowing mankind as I do, that could take centuries!</utterance>
   <speaker>KOMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Angle on: Billy staggering forward, raising his pistol, blinking his eyes to focus.. A MONDOSHAWAN puts the fourth element in the case The Kommander shuts the case and looks at the Priest.</context>
      <utterance>Time is of no importance, only life is important. The Priest nods and lowers his eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When EVIL returns so shall we.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy suddenly staggers into the room, brandishing his gun.</context>
      <utterance>We will be ready, Lord.</utterance>
   <speaker>BILLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Billy trips, the gun goes off. He empties the clip. The Mondoshawan carrying the case crumples to the ground. The wall immediately begins to close. Billy fires wildly, unable to control the powerful kicking gun.</context>
      <utterance>Stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Priest rushes Billy. The weapon has such a kick to it that Billy starts shooting into the air, backs up, then stumbles and knocks himself out. The Priest is on the ground, seriously wounded. So is the Kommander. The WARRIORS are in a panic.</context>
      <utterance>No!!! Don't!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wall continues to close. Sand pours in from everywhere. The vast room fills up like an hourglass.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry, Kommander! The wall's closing!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>KOMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Kommander picks up the case and reaches the wall but can't get through it. His armor is too bulky, the opening too small. He manages to get his arm and the case through.</context>
      <utterance>A mission is a mission, Savoia. You'll learn that.</utterance>
   <speaker>KOMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wall closes, crushing his arm. The CLERK scoops up the case and runs through the huge piles of sand.</context>
      <utterance>My apologies to General Kroi -- and my wife..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you have anything? Not even a temperature?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Never seen anything like it.</context>
      <utterance>The thermo-analyzers have jammed. One of them reads over a million degrees, the other's at minus 5000...</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's taking shape.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell can it be?</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>General Staedert remains calm.</context>
      <utterance>Hook-up with the president in one minute, General.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Send out a probe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>General Staedert leans over his screen and seems surprised to see the room but not the president.</context>
      <utterance>President on line sir..</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Staedert, do you read me?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President grabs the mini-camera on his desk and yanks it around to face him. His face fills the screen.</context>
      <utterance>I can hear you, Mr. President, but I can't see you .</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that better?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfect, Mr. President.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just the facts, General.</context>
      <utterance>I have to address the Supreme Council in 10 minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are no results from the chemical and molecular analysis as of yet, all the calibers are overshot..we're hoping a thermo nucleatic imaging..</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Consternation reigns in the President's office.</context>
      <utterance>What you are saying is you don't know what this..thing..is.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet Sir..The only thing we know is it just keeps getting bigger!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Options.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait or act.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Recommendations.</utterance>
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My philosophy Mr. President is shoot first ask questions later. I don't like uninvited guests.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gentlemen?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The security of the Federated Territories is and remains number one priority.  I suppose General Staedert's "philosophy" is acceptable to you? All the Generals nod "yes"</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, then! Staedert?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The President scans the room. Staedert remote controls the camera toward the room.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. President?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera moves up the Priest and we finally discover his face. He is in his sixties, a shrewd look in his eyes. Around his neck hangs the Kommander's finger, the key to the temple.</context>
      <utterance>...Yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIEST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cornelius, Vito Cornelius. 50th level parish. I have a different theory to offer you, Mr. President.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>anything that can be identified because it prefers not to be, because it is the antithesis of all we are. Because it is evil.. TOTAL EVIL.</context>
      <utterance>Imagine for a moment that this. thing is not</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All the Generals nod in agreement.</context>
      <utterance>One more reason to shoot first eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Shooting would only make it stronger.</context>
      <utterance>Evil begets evil, Mr. President.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President looks puzzled.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. President, we're at crisis point.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your theory is interesting Father but I don't think we have time to go into it right now!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time is of no importance, Mr. President. Only life is important.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The most terrible intelligence imaginable, Mr. President. The President hesitates.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The missile is loaded, General.</context>
      <utterance>...The ship is in combat formation.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I have a doubt.</context>
      <utterance>Staedert? Give me a minute...</utterance>
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't, Mr. President.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Load a series of 740 missiles. Maximum shield protection.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President is growing ever more worried.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Staedert? What's going on? Did you destroy it?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm about to, Mr. President.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>SCIENTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The planet's diameter has greatly increased and it's moving toward the ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Staedert? Get out of there immediately! I don't want an incident, do you hear me, Staedert?</utterance>
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...What do we have that's bigger than 240?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing, General.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bead of sweat pearls Staedert's forehead. He is about to give an order when a gigantic flame emerges from the planet and literally swallows Staedert's spaceship.</context>
      <utterance>Staedert, get out of there! That's an order!</utterance>
   <speaker>STAEDERT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The flame fills the screen with a horrendous NOISE that....</context>
      <utterance>... Good God!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs the phone and crosses his tiny apartment (27 feet long by 6 feet wide) heading for the door, patting himself for a light. Behind him, the bed makes itself automatically.</context>
      <utterance>I'm coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He opens the door for the cat and starts to rummage through a drawer for a match. Out come a handful of war decorations, a hero's collection.</context>
      <utterance>Hey bud! Finger here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>...A Medal of Honor Certificate to Major Dallas</context>
      <utterance>Hi sweetie!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love you too Major, but you haven't called me that since basic training.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was talking to the cat.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>...A picture of Korben and his ex-wife on their wedding day.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, I forgot.You still prefer your cat to the real thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least, the cat comes back.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>There are a million women out there.</context>
      <utterance>You still pining for that two timing bitch. Forget her.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want a million - I just want one. A perfect one.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>...A picture of Korben and Finger in uniform next to a space fighter.</context>
      <utterance>Don't exist bud.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just found a picture of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I look?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben finds a box of matches with three matches. He strikes one. It does not light. Korben opens the fridge, bare, except for an empty can of GEMINI croquettes. On the packet is an ad:</context>
      <utterance>Like shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be an old picture.. Listen, you gotta bring me your hack for the 6 month overhaul. A.S.A.P. Korben heats up some brackish water.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't need one.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>I know how you drive.</context>
      <utterance>You forgetting who sat next to you for a thousand missions.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finger! I'm driving a cab now, not a space fighter!!</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many points you got left on your license?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... at least fifty.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Finger has hang up. Korben sighs and does the same. He gets the heated brackish water and sits down. The cat pounces on the table and meows for its food. Korben pours half the coffee in the cat's cup. The cat meows. Korben taps his cup to the cat's saucer.</context>
      <utterance>In your dreams! See you tonight!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cheers!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have forty-eight hours, the time it needs to adapt itself to our living conditions.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President appears upset himself by this image.</context>
      <utterance>And then it will be too late. The goal of evil is to wipe out life! All forms of life. For all eternity...Life upsets it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there anything that can stop it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes..thank God..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President points to the spot occupied by the 5th element.</context>
      <utterance>..will produce what the ancients called the light of creation, the light of total goodness which is the only thing that can defeat EVIL.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what happens if instead of this... Ultimate Warrior... it is EVIL who stands here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President's nerves quiver.</context>
      <utterance>White turns to black. Light to Dark. Life to Death. For all eternity.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, we have a Mondoshawan spaceship at the frontier requesting permission to enter our territory.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess I should make a decision..</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are the only ones who can help..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FIRST OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two non-identified ships approaching.</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Must be the welcoming committee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Blast after blast hits the defenseless ship.</context>
      <utterance>We've been hit! General alert!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The huge ship veers oft course and heads for a small red planet, taking hit after hit.</context>
      <utterance>We're losing control! We have to land fast!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The huge ship approaches the planet at blinding speed.</context>
      <utterance>Send out a distress signal!!! Activate the emergency landing procedure!</utterance>
   <speaker>FIRST OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The red planet looms ever closer.</context>
      <utterance>Impact in less than ten seconds!</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ship crashes in a gigantic explosion.</context>
      <utterance>Time is of no importance...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In response, the cat meows. Korben opens the door to..A huge gun, brandished by a nervous MUGGER, pointing right in his face.</context>
      <utterance>Don't watch it all day, it'll rot your mind. Bye sweetie..</utterance>
   <speaker>MUGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cash man!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been here long?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unperterbed, Korben looks at the mugger's fearsome weapon.</context>
      <utterance>Don't fuck with me man or I'll blow you into tomorrow!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neuro charged assault model?</context>
      <utterance>Isn't that a Z140? Alleviated titanium.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mugger is lost. He looks at his weapon.</context>
      <utterance>You know you could hurt someone with this puppy..good thing it's not loaded..</utterance>
   <speaker>MUGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben points to the button on the side of the gun. The mugger takes his advice.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta push the little yellow button...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And with lightning speed, Korben blasts the mugger with a straight right hand, sending him down for the count. Korben retrieves the gun.</context>
      <utterance>You're welcome..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the mugger clears his head, Korben opens a drawer next to him which is full of similar guns! The mugger's eyes pop out of his head. He scampers to his feet and runs off. Korben shrugs, exits his apartment, and closes the door. The cat watches a nuclear holocaust on T.V., uninterrupted.</context>
      <utterance>..you know these things are VERY illegal.. you could get in a shit load of trouble.. I better hang onto it for you..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben complies, and starts to push a series of buttons on the dash.</context>
      <utterance>Please enter your license..</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome on board Mr. Dallas..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben hits a button. The garage door starts to open.</context>
      <utterance>How you doing this morning? Sleep OK? I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuel level 6.03..Propulsion 2x4...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had the worst goddamn nightmare.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have nine points left on your license..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the garage door lifts, the Megalopolis that is New York City in the 23rd century comes into view. Startling in it's height, and breath.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks for reminding me..</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben lets the propulsion build.</context>
      <utterance>Have a nice day..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lets the gear slip. The taxi rockets off into the City.</context>
      <utterance>Right..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>49	INT.  PRESIDENT'S  OFFICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cornelius collapses in a chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We are lost!</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. President, the attack was launched by two unregistered warships.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close all borders and declare a state of general alert.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try to contact these Mondoshawans. We owe them an explanation.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President motions to his guards to come and get Cornelius.</context>
      <utterance>This is government business now. You ought to go home and get some rest, Father.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A weary Cornelius leaves the room with David's help.</context>
      <utterance>I promise to keep you informed.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Has the rescue team found any survivors?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is all that survived?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually only one cell survived..</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you identified it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not that easy..we've never encountered anything like it before..you see normal human beings have 40 DNA memo groums..which is more than enough for any species to perpetuate itself..This one has 200,000.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk English Doc.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This cell is like a huge library. It has infinite genetic knowledge stored inside. Almost like it was...engineered.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like a freak of nature to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They pass into the lab.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... I can't wait to meet him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His knowledge is probably limitless..</context>
      <utterance>The compositional elements of his DNA chain are the same as ours, there are simply more of them tightly packed.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there any danger? Some kind of virus?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Munro hesitates a moment. Then he sighs and uses his personal key to open the self-destruct box.</context>
      <utterance>We put it through the cellular hygiene detector. The cell is for lack of a better word... perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mactilburgh starts the operation rolling as Munro puts his hand on the sell-destruct button, ready to use it. Thousands of cells form in the heart of the generator, an assemblage of DNA elements. Then the cells move down a tube, like a fluid, and gather in an imprint of a HUMAN body. Step by step bones are reconstructed, then the nervous and muscular systems. Whole veins wrap around the muscles. An entire body is reconstructing before our very eyes.</context>
      <utterance>OK, go ahead! But Mr. Perfect better be polite... otherwise I turn him into cat food.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOCTOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shield comes over the reconstructing body and makes it invisible.</context>
      <utterance>Three seconds to ultra-violet protection.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The meter slows, drops to zero.</context>
      <utterance>Wonderful!</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A whoosh of air in the glass chamber. Captain Munro has his hand on the self-destruct button, ready to destroy the being that has barely been reborn.</context>
      <utterance>... End of reconstruction, beginning of reanimation .</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An electrical discharge fills the glass chamber causing the body inside to jerk. After a few moments of silence, the SOUND of a heartbeat fills the room over the loudspeaker.</context>
      <utterance>Activate life support system.</utterance>
   <speaker>ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Supreme Being is alive once again.</context>
      <utterance>Life support system activated.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ASSISTANT automatically removes the ultra-violet shield which slowly reveals... a woman... nude... young... and very beautiful. Munro stands there gaping. Not quite his vision of the Supreme Being. Mactilburgh glances at Munro and gently pushes his hand away from the self-destruct button.</context>
      <utterance>Remove the shield.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Munro is hypnotized by the GIRL's beauty.</context>
      <utterance>I told you ... perfect!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mactilburgh looks at him with a grin. A remote-control camera approaches the girl's face, a flash goes off. Blinded by the flash, the girl jumps and screams. She cowers in a corner, shaking from the cold, darting eyes everywhere looking for the case she was holding.</context>
      <utterance>...I'd, uh , like to get a few pictures for the archives before she wakes up.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Minoi ay Cheba! Givomana seno!</context>
      <utterance>Ouacra cocha o dayodomo binay ouacra mo cocha ferji akba ligounai makta keratapla. Tokemata tokemata! Seno santonoi-aypa!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's she saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl kicks the window repeatedly.</context>
      <utterance>Activate the phonic detector.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The ASSISTANT hits a button. A pile of clothes drops out of a trapdoor in the ceiling. She snatches up the clothes angrily and dresses quickly. Munro draws closer to the glass window. He watches her dress with undisguised pleasure.</context>
      <utterance>And give her a light sedative... and something to wear!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This thing solid?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Girl finishes dressing.</context>
      <utterance>An elephant couldn't crack it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Munro smiles safely behind his plate glass window.</context>
      <utterance>Teno akta chataman assin-omekta!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHIEF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The COPS stare into the gaping void.</context>
      <utterance>Go on follow her!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CHIEF angrily pulls out his gun and shoots at the girl who ducks around the corner of the building. Unfortunately the other side in full of cops as well. A flying police car zooms up in front of her, sirens blaring.</context>
      <utterance>...No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The girl feels trapped. She looks down into the endless 450 below and all the cars flying underneath her. Then she raises her arms... and dives off.</context>
      <utterance>This in the police. Your status is illegal. Please put up your hands and follow our instructions!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Korben manages to stop his cab, pulls over to the side.</context>
      <utterance>You have just had an accident. Seven points have been temporarily removed...</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE / KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben sighs and looks in the back seat to see what the damages are. The girl, a bit dazed (who wouldn't be), emerges from the debris and sits up. There's some blood on her face. Korben is stunned. The girl's still alive and... so beautiful. His heart heads for a meltdown.</context>
      <utterance>You have one point left on your license. Have a good day.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Akina delutan, nou-shan.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A police car with wailing sirens halts in front of Korben.</context>
      <utterance>...'Scuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thank you for your cooperation.</context>
      <utterance>You have an unauthorized passenger in your vehicle. We are going to arrest her. Please leave your hands on the wheel.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben can't resist her plea.</context>
      <utterance>Please... HELP...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But he cannot say no to her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Don't put me in this position... I can't... I'm late as it is...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben shuts oft the meter and floors it, sideswiping the police car as he roars away.</context>
      <utterance>Finger's gonna kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Korben whips out a gun and shatters the loudspeaker.</context>
      <utterance>Your license has been revoked. Would you please....</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The police car takes out after him, sirens screeching. An insane chase ensues.</context>
      <utterance>I hate when people cry... I got no defense...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daya deo dono Dato. Dalutan!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben turns his cab sideways and scrapes through a narrow passageway, ripping his taxi light from the roof. The police car smashes into the wall. The other one brakes just in time.</context>
      <utterance>It there's one thing I don't need advice on, it's how to drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The car makes a U-turn, looking for a wider passageway.</context>
      <utterance>Shit! Attention all-patrol cars!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl grabs his shirt collar and pulls him close, whispers in his ear.</context>
      <utterance>We'll wait till things quiet down a bit. You mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Priest...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl hands him the handle of the case, struck with the three Egyptian suns.</context>
      <utterance>You're not that bad... Come on we'll get you to a doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vito... Cor... Ni-lious... Priest...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl nods, then faints. Korben is somewhat lost faced with so much mystery.</context>
      <utterance>Vito Cornelius?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, I'm looking for a priest.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius closes the door. The doorbell RINGS again.</context>
      <utterance>Weddings are one floor down. Congratulations.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>According to the phone guide he lives here.</context>
      <utterance>She's not my bride, she's my fare. She's looking for this Vito Cornelius.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>where did you find her?</context>
      <utterance>That's me. But I don't know who she is...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben hands him the metal handle with the three Egyptian suns, stamped on it.</context>
      <utterance>She dropped in on me... holding this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He faints dead away. Korben, with the girl still in his arms looks around helpless.</context>
      <utterance>The fifth element.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finger's gonna kill me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I brought the girl remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornalius gets up. He looks at the handle.</context>
      <utterance>The girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>on my taxi... talking... this... this bizarre language... And then it dawns on Cornelius who the girl is.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah! She dropped in on me. I mean</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a she!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You noticed...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you do know her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius runs into the next room. Korben looks at the girl, goes to slap her, then changes his mind. Her beauty troubles him. He hesitates, then, gently caresses her cheek. Her skin seems so soft, so fragile.</context>
      <utterance>Uh yes, we're cousins..distant cousins..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfect...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a miracle!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eto Akta Gamat!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The girl hesitates, then snatches the card like a wild animal.</context>
      <utterance>You're right, I was wrong! I shouldn't have kissed you... especially since we haven't been introduced and...  Here, it's a bit late, but... my name is Korben, Korben Dallas. Keep it, you never know, maybe... you'll need a cab one day. I'll be happy to open the door this time!.</utterance>
   <speaker>65	INT.  SMALL  ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cornelius is lost in the closet.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, will you please explain what's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Supreme Being, the fifth element is here, in our parish!!! It's a miracle!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="21">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...What's your name?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leeloo Minai Lekarariba-Laminai-Tchai Ekbat De Sebat.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben is falling in love.</context>
      <utterance>...Leeloo.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius bursts into the room. She turns the gun on him. He bows before her.</context>
      <utterance>That's... really cute...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Appipulai Leeloo Minai..</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Corn-i-Lius?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>LEELOO lowers her guard starts to laugh. An irresistible childish laugh. Korben smiles.</context>
      <utterance>At your service.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father. You sure she's the Supreme Being?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David bows low, but his eyes glance up at Leeloo. Cornelius begins to lead Korben toward the door, hustling him out.</context>
      <utterance>Absolutely sure There's the triple suns on her gloves!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They all like this in your family, father?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's an exception..</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you so much for your help Mr...?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius takes his arm. Leeloo stops laughing when she sees Korben leaving.</context>
      <utterance>Dallas. Korben Dallas.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A thousand times over!</context>
      <utterance>Yes. That's fine! Thank you very much.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might call to check up on her, you know... to see if she's better?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>just needs some rest..she's had a very long trip.</context>
      <utterance>She's fine, really..don't you worry..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius is about to close the door. Korben's hand blocks it.</context>
      <utterance>I know. I was there when she arrived.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me! Just one thing! She said something to me a while ago and... I don't really get it... Akta Gamat?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It means, "Never without my permission".</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius slams the door in his face.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I thought.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evening...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben enters his-apartment.</context>
      <utterance>...Thanks... You, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh god. I forgot your food ... I'm really sorry! How about a nice Thai nosh to apologize? How does that sound, huh? The cat meows, appeased, just an the phone rings.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey bud...I'm waiting all day here.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finger..man..I'm sorry..listen..I was on the way over but I had a fare fall into my lap.. y'know one of those big fares you just can't resist..</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, just how big was this fare?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>5'7", green eyes... long legs... great skin... perfect.. Korben takes out a cigarette.</utterance>
   <speaker>FINGER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh huh..and I don't suppose you got the name of this..perfect fare..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leeloo..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's she doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo breaks into her childish laughter.</context>
      <utterance>Learning our history! The last 5000 years that she missed! She's been out of circulation a while, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you laughing about?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She laughs again and tosses some capsules into the microwave.</context>
      <utterance>Napoleon... small.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo takes her plate out of the microwave. A steaming plate heaped with chicken and exotic vegetables.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Of course..</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits back down in front of the screen and chomps away heavily on her second chicken. Cornelius sits opposite her. and holds up the case handle.</context>
      <utterance>Leeloo..I'm sorry to interrupt you but..</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where is it?</context>
      <utterance>The case..with the stones...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>San Agamat chay bet... envolet!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo nods her head, quite unperturbed and continues to devour the food in front of her.</context>
      <utterance>The case was stolen?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who in gods name would do such a thing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RIGHT ARM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They reach a door at the end of the corridor. Zorg enters a code.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me sir, the council is worried about the economy heating up. They wondered if it would be possible to fire 500...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fire 1000.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIGHT ARM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ZORG turns slowly. A small scar across run across his face, his eye stutters. This is not a man to cross, or contradict.</context>
      <utterance>But... 500 is all they need, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIGHT ARM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door opens...</context>
      <utterance>1000! Fine, sir! Sorry to have disturbed you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>dealer ... Asking all these questions about the Sacred Stones..at the time I didn't think anything of it.. What was his name? I'm so bad with names...</context>
      <utterance>There was this guy with a limp who came a month ago..said he was an art</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo is happy. She pulls off the towel and stands there nude. Cornelius and David turn away.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't know your size.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They really made her...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo finishes dressing. She is delighted.</context>
      <utterance>Perfect.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David smiles, dumb with admiration. Cornelius comes over.</context>
      <utterance>Domo danko!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo settles down, sits at the computer and turns it on.</context>
      <utterance>Leeloo? The Stones... We must get them back.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ikset-kiba. Me imanetaba oum dalat!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know exactly where they are!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LEADER nods. A disgusted look stamps Zorg's features.</context>
      <utterance>Aknot? Is that you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AKNOT's face burns away revealing the head of a monstrous MANGALORE.</context>
      <utterance>...What an ugly face! Doesn't suit you at all! Take it off...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AKNOT says nothing, but if his eyes could talk!</context>
      <utterance>That's better! Never be ashamed of who you are... You're warriors... be proud...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes out a weapon from one a crate and goes into a sales pitch.</context>
      <utterance>So what if the Federal Army crushed your entire race and scattered your people to the wind... Your time for revenge is at hand... Voila... the ZF1.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Breaks down into four parts, undetectable by X-rays.. It's the ideal weapon for quick, discreet interventions. A word on fire power: Titanium recharger. 3000 round clip with bursts of 3 to 300. With the replay button, another Zorg innovation, it's even easier... one shot. He fires at the mannequin.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zorg spins around, the rounds all hit the mannequin.</context>
      <utterance>... and replay sends every following shot to the same location...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mannequin has been blasted into a pile of ashes covered by a net,. stuck with arrows, the whole mess frozen solid. He tosses the weapon into AKNOT's hands.</context>
      <utterance>...Rocket launcher. The always efficient flame thrower... My favorite. Our famous net launcher, the arrow launcher, with exploding or poisonous gas heads - very practical. And for the grand finale, the all-new ice-cube system!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AKNOT sets the case on a crate. Zorg gloats while stroking the case.</context>
      <utterance>...Four full crates, delivered right on time! What about you, my dear Aknot, did you bring me what I asked you for?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zorg smiles, takes a deep breath, opens the case. It's empty</context>
      <utterance>...Magnificent.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you mean empty?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>anyone care to explain?</context>
      <utterance>Alright..I've got an open mind here..</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little group comes over to look.</context>
      <utterance>Dot!</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Planet Fhloston, in the Angel constellation Cornelius plops down into his armchair.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...We're saved!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zorg calmly closes the case and gives Aknot a blood-chilling stare.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fucked!</utterance>
   <speaker>AKNOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We brought you a case.</context>
      <utterance>You asked for a case.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>AKNOT's men grow edgy.</context>
      <utterance>A case with four stones in it. Not one! Not two or three! But four!!! Four stones!!! What the fuck am I supposed to do with an EMPTY case?!!</utterance>
   <speaker>AKNOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...We are warriors, not merchants!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up four fingers.</context>
      <utterance>But you can still count. Look... my fingers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Four stones, four crates... Zero stones...</utterance>
   <speaker>AKNOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We risked our lives. I believe a little compensation is in order.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zorg's men leave a crate and exit with the other three.</context>
      <utterance>So, you are a merchant, after all.  Leave them one crate. For the cause!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cat meows just as a red light blinks, announcing the arrival of a message in a glass tube. Korben ignores it.</context>
      <utterance>So you forgive me?</utterance>
   <speaker>THAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not going to open?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've never gotten a message that wasn't bad news.</utterance>
   <speaker>THAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How someone strong like you scared from a message? Is good news I sure!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The last two messages I got? The first one was from my wife telling me she was leaving! And the second was from my lawyer telling me he was leaving too... with my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>THAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben hesitates, then gives the envelope to the Thai, who opens it with a big smile that fades as reads the contents aloud.</context>
      <utterance>You right that is bad.. but mathematically luck must change! Grandfather say: "It never rain every day." This is good news guarantee.. I bet you lunch!</utterance>
   <speaker>THAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>...You're fired. Oh!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At least I won lunch.</utterance>
   <speaker>THAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cat meows.</context>
      <utterance>Good philosophy..see good in bad.. I like..I prepare number one dessert.. special for you and pussy..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>and a detailed blueprint of the entire hotel!</context>
      <utterance>I got it! Everything here we need to know about Fhloston Paradise Hotel...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The doorbell rings.</context>
      <utterance>Good work, my son. Now all we need is a way to get there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius opens to Right Arm with armed escort.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get it. Finish your work my son.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIGHT ARM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father Cornelius?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My son?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIGHT ARM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Zorg would like a word with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Who?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>83	INT.  ZORG'S  OFFICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zorg turns to Cornelius.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>nice to see you again</context>
      <utterance>Zorg. Jean-Baptiste Emmanuel Zorg...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I remember you now..the so called art dealer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm glad you got your memory back, Father... Because you're going to need it... Where are the stones?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Why on earth do the stones interest you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>I'd rather sell weapons..but I have a customer... so tell me...</context>
      <utterance>Personally, they are of no interest to me,</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even it I did know where the stones were I would never tell somebody like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? What's wrong with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...I'm a priest! I'm here to serve life, All you want to do is destroy it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zorg leads Cornelius into his inner office.</context>
      <utterance>Ah, Father... You are so wrong. Let me explain...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...would you like a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Follow me.. Life, which you so nobly serve, comes from destruction. Look at this empty glass. Zorg pushes the glass with his finger.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zorg pushes the glass off the table. It shatters on the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Here it is... peaceful... serene... but if it is...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Small individual robots, both free-wheeling and integrated, come zipping out to clean up the mess.</context>
      <utterance>Destroyed...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Look at all these little things... so busy all of a sudden. Notice how each one is useful. What a lovely ballet, so full of form and color. So full of..life!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SERVANT comes in pours water in another glass. Zorg tosses a cherry into it.</context>
      <utterance>They are robots!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes but... by that simple gesture of destruction. I gave work to at least fifty people today. The engineers, the technicians, the mechanics. Fifty people who will be able to feed their children so they can grow up big and strong. Children who will have children of their own, adding to the great cycle of life! Cornelius sits in silence.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father, by creating a little destruction, I am, in fact, encouraging life! So, in reality, you and I are in the same business!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Destroying a glass is one thing..killing people with the weapons you produce is quite another.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Unfortunately, he chokes on the cherry. Unable to breathe, Zorg starts to panic.</context>
      <utterance>Let me reassure you Father..I will never kill more people in my entire life than religion has killed in the last 2000 years. Zorg smiles, holds up the glass and takes a drink.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius whacks him on the back. The cherry comes flying out. Zorg regains control of himself. GUARDS come running in.</context>
      <utterance>Can I give you a hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GUARDS throw Cornelius out.</context>
      <utterance>You saved my life... So, I'm going to spare yours.  Throw him out!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are a monster, Zorg!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GUARDS drag Cornelius out of the office.</context>
      <utterance>I know...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right Arm salutes and hurries out of the office.</context>
      <utterance>...Torture whoever you want, the president if you have to but I want those Stones. You have an hour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why the hell is it eating up all those satellites like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD SCIENTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We're working on it.</context>
      <utterance>...We're working on it, Mr. President.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MUNRO enters the office just as a cockroach crawls onto the desk. There's a small antenna on its back.</context>
      <utterance>It should only choke on them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I managed to contact the Mondoshawan. They deplore the incident, but accept our apologies.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the Stones? Did you find them in the wreckage?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The-Stones weren't aboard the ship.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So is Zorg's Right Arm.</context>
      <utterance>...What do you mean? The President is all ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>human race..they felt we're too unpredictable.. so they gave up the Stones to somebody they do trust. Her name is Plavalaguna. She's a Diva and she's going to sing at the charity ball on Fhloston Paradise in a few hours. She has the Stones with her. The President breathes easier. Zorg's Right Arm is delighted.</context>
      <utterance>The Mondoshawan never fully trusted the</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President crushes the cockroach with his shoe. Right Arm's earphones fly off his head. Good-bye eardrums.</context>
      <utterance>Excellent!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want your best man on this!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, Sir. I have the perfect one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="38">
   <speaker>THAI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben forces a weak, polite smile as the Thai looks on expectantly. The phone rings.</context>
      <utterance>Stewed jellyfish cake.. my speciality..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben rises to get his cigarettes, and answer the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Saved by the bell.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the nastiest dirtbag I know in this stinking City!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi Ma...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Korben goes to light his cigarette. There are only two matches left in the match box. Korben strikes one and it fizzles.</context>
      <utterance>I've been playing twice a week for 20 years, 20 years I've been eating those shitty croquettes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Thai starts to clean up. Just as Korben goes to strike the second match..</context>
      <utterance>You wouldn't even eat one to help your poor mother, and you win the big prize? Know something? The whole thing makes me sick!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you listening to me, you ingrate!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben sighs and puts the match back in the box. Korben enters his code on the keypad the Thai is holding.</context>
      <utterance>Yes ma..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Thai casts oft. Korben closes the window.</context>
      <utterance>Go on... This is gonna take a while!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Other than that... You all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The Thai flies off. In the hall, the cat meows-for more food.</context>
      <utterance>...And now you're making fun of me? I'm warning you! If you don't take me after all these years of sacrifice, I'll never forgive you!!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm coming!. Ma, what're you talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I get it! You want to make me beg, is that it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A message drops in his tube. The red light goes on.</context>
      <utterance>All I want is an explanation! I just got in, I lost my job. I smashed my cab. I got mugged, but other than that everything's peachy, Ma, thanks for asking!! Now settle down and explain to me calmly..</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Ten days in Fhloston Paradise for two!</context>
      <utterance>You just won a trip, you dolt!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone would have notified me.</context>
      <utterance>Ma. If I'd won, I'd know about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He eyeballs the message still in the tube. The doorbell rings.-</context>
      <utterance>They've been blaring out your name on the radio for the last hour, blockhead!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben hangs up before his mother can say anything and heads for the door. Before he gets there it opens, General Munro enters followed by a Captain and a Major. MAJOR ICEBORG is a woman. All she needs to become a man is a mustache. Munro opens a file.</context>
      <utterance>Ma.. it's the door. I'll call you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What mission?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To save the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where have I heard this song before?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're to leave immediately for Fhloston Paradise. Retrieve four Stones from the Diva Plavalaguna. And bring them back with the utmost discretion as possible. Any questions'?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just one... why me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three reasons... One: As part of The Elite Special Forces Unit of the Federated Army you are an expert in the use of all weapons and spacecraft needed for this mission. Munro pulls out a long list of documents.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two: Of all the members of your unit you were the most highly decorated.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the third one?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Munro removes the message Korben hasn't bothered to look at.</context>
      <utterance>You're the only one left alive...</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you open your messages?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've had enough good news for today</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Korben the tickets. Korben gets it.</context>
      <utterance>You have won the annual Gemini contest and a trip to Fhloston Paradise. For two. Congratulations. Here are your tickets.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Munro nods.</context>
      <utterance>You rigged the contest?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The idea of taking a trip with Iceborg makes him sick.</context>
      <utterance>Major Iceborg will accompany you... as your wife...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You couldn't come up with something a little more discreet?</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old tricks are the best tricks eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not going.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One reason... I want to stay the only one left alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>110B	INT.  KORBEN'S  APARTMENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The doorbell rings.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben goes to the door and looks out the peephole: the beautiful Leeloo. Korben panics, overcome with happiness.</context>
      <utterance>...Scuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben has two seconds to make up something to get rid of Munro.</context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's my wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were divorced.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He puts them in the fridge, shoving the jellyfish cake in Iceborg's hands.</context>
      <utterance>I mean my future.. my ex.. My future ex.. if she sees you here I'm finished. She hates you guys. It's what killed us in the first place. Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Sorry, General, but we've got no choice! It'll only take a minute! Let me set up another meeting and I'll be back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three of us will never fit in there!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben slams the fridge door. The doorbell RINGS again.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes you will...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He whips through his place in ten seconds, gathers up things laying about, shuts drawers, rolls up his laundry in the folding bed. He brushes his hair back and opens the door with a big smile only to discover a gun stuck between his eyes held by Cornelius.</context>
      <utterance>...Coming!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apipoulai!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose that means "Hi" ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry to have to resort to such methods, but we heard about your good luck on he radio and we need the tickets to Fhloston.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that the usual way priests go on vacation?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not going on vacation..we're on a mission..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of mission?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to save the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck..</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius is disappointed. Leeloo looks crestfallen.</context>
      <utterance>Father, I was in the Army for awhile and every time they told us we were on a mission to save the world the only thing that changed was I lost a lot of friends. So thanks for the offer.. but no thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry..</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone freezes as the whole building resounds with the electronic voice.</context>
      <utterance>This is a police control action..</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius starts to panic. Korben takes charge.</context>
      <utterance>This is not an exercise. This is a police control.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben pushes a button sending the fridge to the next floor. A shower takes it's place.</context>
      <utterance>Oh my god oh my god..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo hops in. Korben tosses Cornelius on the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Leeloo, hide in here and don't move!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>..and hits a button on the wall. The bed disappears into the wall. Korben grabs his tickets and slides them in his belt.</context>
      <utterance>Trying to save your ass so you can save the world.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A COP slaps a viewer device on Korben's door which makes part of it transparent.</context>
      <utterance>...Spread your legs and place your hands in the yellow circles, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben takes his time hiding his face. The Cop looks at his sheet. He's looking for a... KORBEN DALLAS. He has his picture, but it is Korben with long hair and beard.</context>
      <utterance>Put your hands in the yellow circles, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir? Are you a human?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I'm a meat popsicle.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 3</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>C.U. Korben's calling card is clumsily stuck to the door of the neighbor's apartment. COP 3 slaps the viewer on the nasty neighbor's door. The neighbor is at his sink shaving instead of against the wall, COP 1 arrives with Korben's picture.</context>
      <utterance>I found him!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The neighbor steps right up to the viewer, shaving cream on his face. He could pass for Korben.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, this is a control. Please put your hands in the yellow circles.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!!</utterance>
   <speaker>113	INT.  KORBEN'S  APARTMENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Korben still has his hands to the wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SHOT O.S. EXPLOSION. Scuffle.</context>
      <utterance>Wrong answer.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, we got the guy under wraps.</utterance>
   <speaker>115	INT.  ZORG'S  OFFICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right Arm is on the phone, facing Zorg.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Thanks for the tip!</context>
      <utterance>It was not easy, but we bagged him!.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIGHT ARM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Glad to help.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIGHT ARM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shows him a plane ticket, and a passport with his picture and Korben's name.</context>
      <utterance>They just arrested the guy for Uranium smuggling. Everything's going as planned.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIGHT ARM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zorg sits there quietly for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>All I have to do now is to go to the airport and take his place. I should be in Fhloston in less than four hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't come back without the Stones.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes fall on an old blanket.</context>
      <utterance>I'm really sorry.. there wasn't time.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben wraps her in an blanket and vigoroualy rubs her back. Leeloo warms gradually and snuggles closer to that warm comfortable shoulder. Korben's rubbing slows, looking more like caresses.</context>
      <utterance>Here let me wrap you up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo suddenly realizes that she has maybe gone a bit too far. She recovers, looking embarrassed too.</context>
      <utterance>..It's funny. I've met you twice today and you've ended up in my arms both times.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valo massa... Chacha hamas.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The intimacy makes him nervous. He looks for a diversion.</context>
      <utterance>Uh..you're welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes a button on the coffee machine.</context>
      <utterance>Coffee! That's what you need! A nice, hot cup of coffee!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben rummages through the drawer. Leeloo, innocent, doesn't seem to quite understand everything that is going on.</context>
      <utterance>With some honey! You'll see, honey's great!...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He rummages through the cupboard, exceedingly nervous. Leeloo smiles and begins to look around. She opens a drawer and comes upon..</context>
      <utterance>A hot cup of coffee... with honey...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>..pictures of Major Korben Dallas War Hero.</context>
      <utterance>I've got this great honey somewhere. You know about honey? There used to be these little animals who made it with antenna...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..and these other animals who ate it.. one were bees the other were bears.. She looks back to the man fumbling for honey.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And she smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I forget which ate it and which made it but..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben holds up the jar of honey.</context>
      <utterance>Here it is!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo innocently sticks his finger in the jar then puts it in her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Taste this...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She savors the honey, slowly; sensually. Her lips shine with honey. Her eyes narrow with pleasure. Korben is hypnotized by her lips, like a moth attracted to a flame. He begins to lose control, which makes him nervous. An indistinct sound comes from the wall. But Korben is so entranced with the sight of Leeloo licking her honied fingers, he doesn't hear it until it becomes quite a racket.</context>
      <utterance>It... melts in your mouth, doesn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cornelius..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben pushes the button on the wall. The bed pops out, fully made, with Cornelius tucked in it, struggling to get out.</context>
      <utterance>Oh god!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben begins to pull at the covers when..</context>
      <utterance>I'm really sorry.. let me help you..</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben turns..</context>
      <utterance>Achta ge lumitai de matala..</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to Leeloo struggling out of her wet clothes. His breath is taken away by the sight of her perfect body. Cornelius whacks him heavily on the head with a lamp. Korben drops to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Soun domo kala chon hammas!</context>
      <utterance>Vano da, mechteba?!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But we don't have the luxury of choice.</context>
      <utterance>No, I'm not proud of myself...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AKANIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Korben Dallas! We got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>AKNOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perfect... Take command, Akanit. Go to Fhloston and get the Stones... If Zorg really wants them... He'll have to negotiate. Revenge is at hand.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings, he manages to answer.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus!... Some priest!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you pulled yourself together?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben opens the fridge door. The three officers are frozen solid. Korben grabs some ice, presses it to his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>...Not yet. He hangs up.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the door.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take the mission.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A hand taps Leeloo from behind. She whips around catching David in the face.</context>
      <utterance>Illegal gathering in Zone 4.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to David who in holding his bloody nose.</context>
      <utterance>Leeloo, be careful.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David hands Cornelius two passports.</context>
      <utterance>Did you get them?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excellent... Leeloo Dallas. He hands it to her. The name makes her smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She frowns.</context>
      <utterance>And Korben David Dallas.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Akta dedero ansila do mektet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at David holding his bloody nose.</context>
      <utterance>I can't pretend to be your husband... David's in great shape.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ANGLE ON: Korben comes rushing into the airport. Walking quickly, he scopes the hall looking for Leeloo. A POLICE PATROL bearing down on the STRIKERS jostles him. The cops open fire. The strikers dive into the garbage and disappear.</context>
      <utterance>He'll protect you. Go on... See the Diva... get the Stones... See you at the temple... God be with you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHECK-IN ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>David gives her a bleak smile. Leeloo rolls her eyes. Back a ways, Korben has spotted Leeloo and... David. He heads right for them. Leeloo's seen him. She is both delighted and panicked. David's seen nothing. Korben presses one of his fingers like a gun to David's back.</context>
      <utterance>Congratulations on winning the contest.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey! I really thought I was going to miss my flight!  Thanks, kid! You put the luggage on the conveyor belt?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh... yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Paralyzed, David leaves. Korben turns to the attendant.</context>
      <utterance>Great! Now beat it!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at David's fake ID.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me. I was so afraid I'd miss the flight that I sent the kid here to pick up my boarding card.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo is unable to hold back a smile.</context>
      <utterance>...My cousin David...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHECK-IN ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben grabs the ID and reads it.</context>
      <utterance>Your wife?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You know how it is... Love at first sight. You meet, something goes tilt,. you get married, you hardly know each other. Right, darling? Leeloo rips her boarding card out of the attendant's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, yes... Newlyweds.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dinoine chagantakat!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He winks at the stewardess.</context>
      <utterance>Took the words right out of my mouth. Go on... I'll be right with you.  It's our honeymoon. We're going to use the trip to get to know each other better.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CHECK-IN ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dallas... Korben...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The check-in attendant triggers a transparent blue light that shines on their faces, revealing two other faces: Mangalores.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, that's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHECK-IN ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hits a silent alarm, but the Mangalores feel something is wrong.</context>
      <utterance>Just a minute, please.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They spin around and hurry away.</context>
      <utterance>We'll be right back ... we're gonna check out the duty free...</utterance>
   <speaker>ROBOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The same?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Cornelius turns to David.</context>
      <utterance>Make that two...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Leeloo?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>the real one.</context>
      <utterance>On the plane... with Mr. Dallas...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands David the Temple Key from around his neck.</context>
      <utterance>It's all my fault. I'm the servant... It's my mission! Here!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius tosses David's drink into his own, downs it all in one shot, and takes off, passing the Mangalore couple headed for the exit. They are very nervous. A police patrol is coming. This time, it seems to be for them.</context>
      <utterance>Here's the key to the Temple.. Prepare for our arrival!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEIGHBOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The tawdry girl nods and peels off. The neighbor takes out a gun and blasts away at the cops. The cops fire back. A firefight rages in the hall. The tawdry girl dives into a pile of garbage and disappears.</context>
      <utterance>Tell Aknot plan A flopped. Tell him to go to plan B.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Send in a back-up unit, Zone 7!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>123	INT.  HALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Korben is led down the hall by a STEWARDESS.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are so lucky... Loc Rhod is the coolest DJ in the universe.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen... I don't want to be interviewed. I'd prefer to remain anonymous. The stewardess stops in the corridor.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget anonymous. You'll be doing Loc Rhod's live show every day from 5 to 7!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stewardess smiles and shakes her head. The door next to him suddenly swings open and smashes him in the face. In walks LOC RHOD amidst a tornado of music and security guards. He is young, good-looking, eccentric, charming as an elf or sly as a fox. A bundle of energy. He is the 24th century's most popular DJ.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta be kidding!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loc Rhod grabs Korben's arm and leads him down the hallway, as fast as the music.</context>
      <utterance>Does it get any better or what!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Quiver ladies, he's gonna set the world on fire right here from 5 to 7! You'll know everything there is to know about the D-man. His dreams, his desires, his most intimate of intimates. And from what I'm looking at intimate is the stud muffin's middle name. So tell me my main man... you nervous in the service?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loc Rhod lets go of Korben's arm and grabs the Stewardess.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Freeze those knees, my chickadees, 'cause Korben is on the case with a major face... Loc Rhod rubs up against the stewardess.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They come to an intersection. The airline company has prepared drinks for them. Loc Rhod pushes on, grabs a glass of champagne, scribbles his autograph.</context>
      <utterance>...Start drooling, ladies! My man here is a sharp-tongued Sire who's gonna stroke your every desire.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yesterday's unknown will be tomorrow's Prince of Fhloston Paradise, the hotel of a thousand and one follies, home of luxury and beauty. A magic fountain flowing with non-stop wine, women and Bootchie Koochie Koo... He tosses away his champagne glass.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Howling, Loc Rhod grabs another stewardess by the arm.</context>
      <utterance>Beware out there puppy dogs my man is on the prowl. Owwww!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...And start licking your stamps little girls, this guy's gonna have you writing home to Momma! Tomorrow from 5 to 7, I'll be your voice, your tongue and I'll be hot on the tail of the sexiest man of the year... D-man... Your man... My man. The stewardess shivers. A BEEP is heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOCODER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The MUSIC suddenly stops. Several assistants come and compliment Loc Rhod who sighs, lights up a cigarette, and drops his pretense.</context>
      <utterance>End of transmission.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Korben sweetheart do me a favor I know this is probably the biggest thing that ever happened to you in your inconsequential life. But I've got a show to do here and it's got to pop. So tomorrow, when we're on air, give me a hand... Try to make believe you have more than a one word vocabulary. OK pal? That does it. Korben grabs him by the collar and drags him into a corner. Loc Rhod's feet don't touch the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Crystal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHECK-IN ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zorg's Right Arm gives her a big smile.</context>
      <utterance>...Mr. Dallas... Korben Dallas?</utterance>
   <speaker>RIGHT ARM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The attendant scans the ID with a yellow beam, it checks out, and the blue light reveals no other face but his.</context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHECK-IN ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The problem is I only have one Korben Dallas on my list... and he's already checked in. Right Arm's smile shatters.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIGHT ARM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's impossible! He's in j... I mean, there must be some mistake. I have my ticket! I'm the real Korben Dallas! A shrill BELL rings out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIGHT ARM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pounds on the counter with both fists. A steel curtain comes down. Red sighting beams target spots on his body, ten gun barrels protrude from the wall, all aimed at him.</context>
      <utterance>I want to see your boss! Get rid of this fucking window! Somebody's made a mistake, goddamnit!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Put your hands in the nearest yellow circles...</context>
      <utterance>This is not an exercise. This is a police control.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apipoulai!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo smiles, as if complimented.</context>
      <utterance>Not hard to find you...just follow the Chaos...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leeloo, listen to me... these tickets... they're not mine... I mean they are, but not for vacation like everyone thinks... I'm on an operation... and if I didn't come get you, you'd be in a shitload of trouble... I'd love to be on vacation with you... but now.... now I've got to work... And Leeloo... I would love to work in peace. Leeloo types in "LOVE" on the keyboard.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Love...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! But "love" isn't the operative word here, PEACE is! Leeloo types in this new word.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She brings up a picture of a 60's style Hippie flashing a peace sign. Korben sighs and switches off the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Peace... and love...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes you can't learn everything from a screen..sometimes it's better to ask someone who has experience..</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben just stares at her for a few minutes.</context>
      <utterance>What is... Make Love?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns the computer back on.</context>
      <utterance>Know what? On that subject maybe you'd be better off asking the screen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK! Finished!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finished what?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Learning language.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which one?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben doesn't know if he should laugh or not.</context>
      <utterance>All 900.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You learned 900 languages in five minutes?!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! Now it's your turn! I learned your language, you have to learn mine!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know how to say "Hello". Teach me how to say "Good-bye", that's all I need.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apipoussan!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apipoussan?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good! Do you know how we say "make love"?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben literally melts.</context>
      <utterance>...Hoppi-hoppa.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Luckily, a stewardess smiles at him through the box window.</context>
      <utterance>Help...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The stewardess sets the timing sleeper. Korben and Leeloo immediately fall asleep. A STEWARDESS at the other end of the shuttle has a problem.</context>
      <utterance>Sweet dreams, Mr. Dallas!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Loc Rhod you have to assume your individual position.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want an individual position, I want all positions!</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to take off soon, Mr. Rhod!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now you're talking!</utterance>
   <speaker>COPILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stewardess 1 enters the cockpit.</context>
      <utterance>Molecular axis authorization. Vector 130. Destination Fhloston.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zone 1. 217 locked. The sleep regulator is OK.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Stewardess leaves with a smile. A red light flashes on the vast control panel.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Miss.</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell the ground crew we've got parasites in the landing gear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RIGHT ARM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is already sweating.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, it's me... Put Zorg on.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm listening.</utterance>
   <speaker>RIGHT ARM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He took my place.</context>
      <utterance>The real Korben Dallas is on the plane!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is a joke, right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COPILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anti static pressure?</utterance>
   <speaker>MECHANIC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mechanic presses a series of buttons.</context>
      <utterance>Primed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COPILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>10 seconds...</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- The stewardess undergoes a power surge from Loc Rhod that's about to lift her of. - Zorg finishes gleefully typing in the number.</context>
      <utterance>Power increase.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>3... 2... 1...</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- The stewardess in close to screaming.</context>
      <utterance>- The engines at full blast.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>- In the hall, Right Arm literally explodes along with the phone and everything else within 60 feet.</context>
      <utterance>Liftoff. - The copilot pushes a button. - So does Zorg. - The engines release their full power. - The stewardess screams in ecstasy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>141	INT.  COCKPIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In the cockpit, the atmosphere loosens up.</utterance>
   <speaker>COPILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Landing gear secure. Let's light one up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HEAD SCIENTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The thing is sending out radio wavelengths!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell does it want with radio waves?</utterance>
   <speaker>HEAD SCIENTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President and his Generals look at him in astonishment.</context>
      <utterance>...Probably wants to make a call!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Zorg shoots to his feet. Picasso tumbles to the floor. Zorg picks up the phone, both excited and uneasy. He stands there, almost coming to attention.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Shadow on the line.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The voice is feeble. It comes from the far reaches of time, from the bowels of the universe.</context>
      <utterance>Yes... Zorg here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I disturbing you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SHADOW'S breathing is awesome.</context>
      <utterance>No... not at all. Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Not far, now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the middle of an electronic snowstorm, a blackish, vaguely human, quiverinq form appears. Two eyes, like lava, give an idea where the head is. Zorg feels sick.</context>
      <utterance>Really? Maybe I can get you on my screen and see you at last! Zorg brings up a huge screen and pushes a few buttons.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have the picture now Mr. Zorg?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's our deal coming along?</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The black liquid oozes all over the screen which starts to melt. Zorg sweats profusely, his legs tremble.</context>
      <utterance>Money is of no importance... I want the Stones!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Stones will be here. I'll see to it personally!</utterance>
   <speaker>SHADOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zorg sighs and sits down totally freaked.</context>
      <utterance>...I can't wait to be among you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stewardesses walk down the aisles waking the passengers one by one. They press a button on the door of each box. In the corner, Loc Rhod and the stewardess awake with a start and straighten their clothes quickly. The stewardess is embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>Ladies and gentlemen, we have begun our descent toward Fhloston Paradise...</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARDESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loc Rhod puts on his sunglasses and presses a finger to her lips. He disappears behind the curtain leaving the sighing stewardess on her own.</context>
      <utterance>I wanted to tell you that...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>151	INT.  COCKPIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A blinking light goes on.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The 1st Mate heads off.</context>
      <utterance>Shit! Parasites in Zone 1. Take a look.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My main man! Please don't leave me here alone. My head's killing me and my adoring fans are gonna tear me apart! Get me outta here!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll take you to the bar, after that, you're on your own.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yes! Do that! You treat me right, man. Tell me all about yourself, your roots, your personal life, your childhood dreams...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't think this is a good time...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Big, I suppose?</context>
      <utterance>...You got brothers and sisters? What about your dad? Tell me about your dad! What was he like? Physically?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, very big, a giant.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't have a dad... never saw him... never even heard him. 50 billion people listen to me every day... and he doesn't hear me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The hostess pulls back the closet door. Twenty tuxedos in a row.</context>
      <utterance>For the concert it says formal attire... I didn't bring...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You little sleaze bag!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Ma???</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Korben drops into an armchair and sighs. His eyes go to the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you ever ask me for another thing in my life again, you've killed your poor mother with your own hands!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Ma!!!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Diva's ship is coming in.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF OF POLICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want maximum security.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF OF POLICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>OK, let's hear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where was I?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHIEF OF POLICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bomb go off in your face?</context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAT-UP COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius perks up.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... A 5 foot 7 inch bomb... with green eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all turn to look at him.</context>
      <utterance>And the smile of an angel?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May I speak to you alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DIVA'S ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Diva's assistant turns the painting right side up.</context>
      <utterance>Please forgive this little incident. She wants you to know that she senses great powers in you... in the service of a noble cause... She will give you what you have come to get, but she wants to sing first... One last time...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIVA'S ASSISTANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo looks at the painting, seems to understand it better.</context>
      <utterance>Miss.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Diva enters her suite without letting him finish.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, I'm head of security. Everything is in order. You can...</utterance>
   <speaker>FOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>If you need anything...give it a knock!</context>
      <utterance>...make yourselves at home safely.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, Ma! I've only got a few days vacation and I'll be damned if I'm gonna spend them on the phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben opens the door. It's not the champagne. Even better. It's Leeloo.</context>
      <utterance>...Hang on, it's the door. No! I told you I didn't bring anybody! I'm all alone... as usual!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo heads right for her suitcase and starts to undress. Korben has to turn away once more.</context>
      <utterance>...I'll call you back.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here we go again...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know women normally change five times more than men.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get that off the screen?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... you know there's a lot of differences between men women.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You noticed..</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben turns around. Leeloo has put on a very simple dress which is sexy to the max. He is smitten. So much so that Leeloo wonders if something isn't quite right.</context>
      <utterance>OK, you can turn around!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to see the Diva sing. What's the matter?... Do I look bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo smiles at him, his compliment pleases her. She turns, revealing her unzippered back. Korben cannot help but stare at her bare flesh. Her perfect bottom.</context>
      <utterance>No, not at all! I mean, just the opposite, you're... you're beautiful!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben's blood boils. She wriggles, pressing her hands together close to the zipper.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know how this works?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But instead of pulling on the zipper he slips a bracelet on her wrist. A flourescent beam bursts out of the bracelet and forms a vertical bar going from the floor to the ceiling. Stunned, Leeloo is held captive.</context>
      <utterance>I have an idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Remember? I need to concentrate.</context>
      <utterance>I told you I need to work in peace.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you can't concentrate with me around?.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tries to breakout.</context>
      <utterance>It's difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo tries desperately to get out of the handcuffs. Impossible. Korben sets the radio down in front of her and turns it on. Leeloo looks like she'd like to break his head.</context>
      <utterance>Army issue. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're nothing but a... a...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The door flies open. Loc Rhod barges in.</context>
      <utterance>The words you're looking for weren't in the dictionary you studied. I won't be long.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then he sees the scene, Leeloo cuffed, in a low cut dress. His mind goes to the obvious.</context>
      <utterance>Hey Stud we gotta...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben grabs him by the collar..</context>
      <utterance>Korben my man what's happening here? Who's the chick? What's the gig? We free forming here? Getting funky with the monkey? Can I get in on this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And yanks Loc Rhod out of the room. Leaving Leeloo looking extremely unhappy.</context>
      <utterance>No..to all of the above.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AKANIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's showtime!</utterance>
   <speaker>178	INT.  CONCERT  HALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The lights dim slowly in the concert hall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah!?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Flowers for the Diva.</utterance>
   <speaker>MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's allergic to flowers!!!</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The manager takes one look at the stubborn bottle and opens the door. And finds himself staring down the barrel of a gun. A dozen Mangalores rush in. One of them, with a human face, closes the door and waits out in the hall.</context>
      <utterance>There's champagne as well...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...My God!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Commander, I have a ship with a main malfunction. He requests permission to dock for repairs.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you check out his registration number?</utterance>
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everything's in order.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put him in the docking garage and inform the police.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAPTAIN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Zorg sits at the controls.</context>
      <utterance>Permission granted. Dock 575. You have an hour. Will that be enough time'?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More than enough.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MANGALORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Mangalore is about to open the case when... Leeloo descends quietly and gracefully from the ceiling. Time stands still.</context>
      <utterance>I have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apipoulai!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MANGALORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were waiting for us! It was an ambush!</utterance>
   <speaker>AKANIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it's war they want it's war they'll get! Enact the Final Plan! All the Mangalores cock their weapons.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo smiles and hands him the case. Zorg arms the ZF1 and gets ready to kill her.</context>
      <utterance>My compliments, little lady! ...And thanks for doing all the dirty work! I couldn't have done it any better myself!  ...Now hand over the Stones!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo catches on quickly. She kicks the scotch bottle on the floor into the gun which throws Zorg's shot off. She jumps to the ceiling and disappears in an air vent. Furious, Zorg fires at the ceiling.</context>
      <utterance>Nice knowing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>198	INT.	AIRSHAFT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leeloo dodges the bullets as best as she can.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AKANIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Chief of Police is goggle-eyed. Cornelius leans toward him.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody move! We're taking over this ship!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Mangalores!</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Send a battalion out immediately!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was sent by the government to help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben is a little surprised, but... the Diva is an artist.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. This is my fate... How was the concert?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Mangalore jumps on them from the stage. Korben makes short work of him and grabs his gun.</context>
      <utterance>I've never heard anything so beautiful in my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She was right to have chosen you...</context>
      <utterance>You're a good man...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben is floored.</context>
      <utterance>The Fifth Element... The Supreme Being... Your wife...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leeloo... is... she's...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, and more than that... You must give her the Stones, she's the only one who knows how to use them.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...So Cornelius was telling the truth!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course I was telling you the truth!... If you had listened to me in the first place, we wouldn't be in this predicament now!</utterance>
   <speaker>210	INT.  CONCERT  HALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Korben wastes two more Mangalores.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>your love. She's more fragile than she seems... Korben looks around, ready for another attack.</context>
      <utterance>She needs you. She needs your help and</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Diva takes his hand.</context>
      <utterance>...Yeah, so am I.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was taught to love the life of others... but not her own. You have to teach her to love if you want her to truly live!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll help her, I promise, but I think you should tell me where the Stones are!</utterance>
   <speaker>DIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you love her?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I... I don't know! We hardly know each other... it takes time!</utterance>
   <speaker>DIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have time... I need to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Listen, the last time I admitted to a woman I loved her ... I never saw her again.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Diva's eyes close.</context>
      <utterance>I would like to have died in peace...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes her, gently slapping her cheeks.</context>
      <utterance>You tell me to save the world then you go off and leave me in the shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on! You're not gonna die in peace! You're not going to die at all! You hear me? Where are the Stones?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, but... the Stones...</utterance>
   <speaker>DIVA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Diva dies. Blue blood streams from her mouth. Korben frisks the Diva but doesn't find anything. The shooting slowly stops in the theatre. The Mangalores are now in total control.</context>
      <utterance>They are... with me...</utterance>
   <speaker>MANGALORE 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The guests comply</context>
      <utterance>Stay calm and nobody will get hurt! Hands on your head and into the hall!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>and then it occurs to him.</context>
      <utterance>...The Stones are with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches the Diva's stomach and senses something hard. Girding himself, he sticks his hand in the wound and pulls out a Sacred Stone. Then another. And another. Korben pulls out all four Stones, covered in blue blood. Everyone has left the theater. The Mangalores check the aisles one by one. Loc Rhod peeks out from under a seat.</context>
      <utterance>...In me?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A Mangalore spots Korben kneeling alongside the Diva. He grabs Korben by the shoulder and pokes him with his gun.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you think we'd better be going?</utterance>
   <speaker>MANGALORE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben spins and, in one swift motion, breaks his arm. Just for starters. Another WARRIOR rushes over. Korben punches him into oblivion and snatches the gun.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, you! With the others!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's it... I've had... all day people have been sticking guns in my face... Korben wraps up the four Stones in his shirt.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Korben man... These dudes are going to waste us if we don't do what they say. Korben gives him the package and grabs his mike.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't do what I say... I'll waste you myself. Got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MUGGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Three Mangalores are suddenly blasted through the glass door leading to the theater. Korben bursts into the hall, two huge guns in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>There's no more resistance. Everything's under control.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben takes out two more WARRIORS coming towards him, rolls behind a column. Laser bullets stinging all around his head.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody down!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>contest just killed three warriors like he was swatting flies... Panic everywhere! Heavy firing fills the hall.</context>
      <utterance>This is amazing! Korben, Korben Dallas, the winner of the Gemini Croquette</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone taps Loc Rhod on the shoulder. He jumps with fright.</context>
      <utterance>It's Roy von Bacon, the Lions center forward joining in the battle...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCESS AACHEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loc Rhod covers his mike.</context>
      <utterance>All this is terribly exciting, hmmm?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toss me the balls!</utterance>
   <speaker>BABY RAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another piece of the bar explodes.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben apes playing pool, but Baby Ray really is stone-deaf.</context>
      <utterance>The balls for Christ's sake!</utterance>
   <speaker>EMPEROR JAPHET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The EMPEROR rolls the balls over to Korben. The Mangalore loads more missiles and shatters another part of the bar. Korben hides behind the last bit left.</context>
      <utterance>He wants the balls! You deaf or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The EMPEROR glances at the Mangalore, who in reloading.</context>
      <utterance>How far is he from here?</utterance>
   <speaker>EMPEROR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben hefts the ball, jumps up and hurls it with blinding speed. The Mangalore catches it right in the head. He drops, firing in the air. The missile strikes the ceiling which collapses on him. The emperor gives Korben a thumb's up.</context>
      <utterance>I'd say about thirty yards to the left.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The COPS on the floor rise, scoop up weapons from dead Mangalores and lay down a line of fire at the last of the fleeing rebels . Roy whirls his arm in victory.</context>
      <utterance>...And our man Korben has literally knocked out the opposition with an amazing 90 foot pitch.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Forget it. Korben grabs Loc Rhod and takes him with him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben goes to the door and peeks around the corner. Loc Rhod arrives.</context>
      <utterance>The winner of the Gemini Croquette contest.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Seven to the left. Five to the right.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben leans around the corner and fires rapidly.</context>
      <utterance>What's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Six to the left. One to the right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's on vacation.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got to find the leader. Mangalores don't fight without a leader.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Found him...</utterance>
   <speaker>AKANIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Send someone to negotiate!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mind if I go? I'm an excellent negotiator.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben gets ready.</context>
      <utterance>Uh... Sure, go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're sending someone in who's authorized to negotiate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone else want to negotiate?</utterance>
   <speaker>COP 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where'd he learn to negotiate like that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're probably very angry with me and I quite understand. But I want you to know I'm fighting for a noble cause.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I know... to save the world... but right now all I want to do is save Leeloo.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leeloo's in trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When is she not in trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben realizes that Cornelius in probably right.</context>
      <utterance>Uh.. Have you tried the Diva's suite?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>POLICEMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He brings up the ZF1 and wipes out the garage.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing I can't fix myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Up in the airshaft, Leeloo has heard him.</context>
      <utterance>Leeloo?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Korben... Her voice is too weak, Korben can't hear her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben gives the bomb a prefunctory glance.</context>
      <utterance>Korben man... what the hell is this?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Three minutes left on the timer.</context>
      <utterance>A molecular bomb.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And, uh, what're these numbers clicking by?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius smiles and continues his search.</context>
      <utterance>Probably the time remaining before it explodes.</utterance>
   <speaker>232	INT.  MAIN  HALL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The lights flicker.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A wave of panic engulfs the hall. The cops are unable to hold back the crowd as it stampedes to the exits.</context>
      <utterance>This is a Type A alert. For security reasons the hotel must be evacuated. Please proceed calmly to the lifeboats located in the main hallways.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe we oughta be going, what do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loc Rhod cannot take his eyes off the bomb.</context>
      <utterance>Not without Leeloo.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben breathes out, bothered. He turns his attention to the bomb.</context>
      <utterance>Like D-Man, I hate to bother you but uh, like, we're down to 2 minutes here...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's the latest model.. I've never seen one before... it works off a magnetic coded card... Let's see if I can rig it up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben drags the desk over, jumps on it and pokes his head in the torn up airshaft He spots Leeloo who gives him a weak smile.</context>
      <utterance>Hey! What are you doing? The bomb!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls her toward him, helps her out of the shaft and stretches her out on the desk.</context>
      <utterance>Don't worry, I'm here now!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>30 seconds left on the timer.</context>
      <utterance>Just relax. I've got the Stones. Everything's going to be fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like Korben, can I have 30 seconds of your time here?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben dashes over to the bomb. He is stopped by the barrel of the ZF1. Zorg, in person, holding a magnetic card.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be right back.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zorg slips a small magnetic card in the bomb, it starts to count down from 5 minutes.</context>
      <utterance>Allow me...</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loc Rhod faints.</context>
      <utterance>Just for the fun of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben doesn't reply.</context>
      <utterance>Well, what do we have here? Is this Korben Dallas? The famous winner of the Gemini Croquette contest? Or is this Korben Dallas from Special Section sent by old Lindberg himself.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Zorg fires at Korben who figures he is dead. Nothing. Zorg tries again. Nada. The clip is empty. Zorg starts to panic.</context>
      <utterance>...In any event, whoever you are, I was glad to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...A 3000 round clip! I didn't fire off 3000 rounds... did I?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben punches him square in the face, shows him his index.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you know how to count. It's not all that hard. Watch!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Second Punch.</context>
      <utterance>One! That's for trying to kill me!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben pummels him mercilessly.</context>
      <utterance>Two! That's for firing me! Three! That's for pushing around a priest! And the rest is for what you did to my wife!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cornelius grabs Loc Rhod and gives him a resounding slap.</context>
      <utterance>We're outta here! He picks Leeloo up in his arms.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you nuts, Father? That hurts! I can't feel my teeth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doesn't matter all you need are your legs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Korben bursts the lock on the first ship he finds and enters followed by Cornelius and Loc Rhod. The ZFX200.</context>
      <utterance>Two minutes to complete evacuation...</utterance>
   <speaker>240	INT.  DIVA'S  SUITE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zorg starts to come around.</utterance>
   <speaker>241	INT.  ZFX200</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Korben sets Leeloo down.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One minute to total evacuation...</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know how to fly this thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's like a cab isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>30 seconds...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone know how to release the lines on this crate?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loc Rhod searches frantically.</context>
      <utterance>Found it?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even know what I'm looking for!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben slams the throttle into full forward. The ship roars away ripping the lines to shreds. Loc Rhod is thrown to the rear of the ship.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck it! Hold tight!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Solid little jobs, aren't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOCODER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Loc Rhod lets out a huge sigh.</context>
      <utterance>Beep. End of transmission.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The best show I ever did!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's that? Can you hear me better now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>So, how was the concert?</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. Zorg, I hear you perfectly!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The batteries on my phone are almost gone.</context>
      <utterance>Who gives a shit! I didn't come here to listen to music! Listen up instead of running off at the mouth!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Sir!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Someone stole mine.</context>
      <utterance>Dispatch me another ZFX200 immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECRETARY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right away, Sir. I'll send you a new one to the hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not at the hotel!</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?...</utterance>
   <speaker>BEEPER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Zorg is all alone, lost, in the middle of the glacier.</context>
      <utterance>Battery dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>ZORG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay calm.... stay calm...</utterance>
   <speaker>250	INT.  PRESIDENT'S  OFFICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General Munro enters the office with a smile.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>President Lindberg closes his eyes in relief.</context>
      <utterance>Major Dallas has the Five Elements on board. The priest is guiding them directly to the temple.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A SCIENTIST rushes in.</context>
      <utterance>Thank God! We've been saved!</utterance>
   <speaker>SCIENTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. President.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes? Now, what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo smiles, weakly, feverish.</context>
      <utterance>Apipoulai..</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so very sad.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? We did pretty well, wouldn't you say?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everything you create is used to destroy...</context>
      <utterance>Five hundred wars... Arms... Drugs... Money...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you not to read all that crap!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her eyes close and she falls back asleep. Korben is worried. She seems so depressed. Cornelius enters.</context>
      <utterance>Protect life... Until death.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His name's Mambo, I think.</context>
      <utterance>There's a General on the phone...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President clears his throat and takes the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Munro here. President Lindberg wants to talk to you. Hold the line.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Major, first off, I want to thank you, in my name and in the name of the Federation...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For the praiseworthy courage you have shown us! I'd like to congratulate General Munro for his choice. He found the ideal man for such a...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President drops into his armchair and sighs.</context>
      <utterance>So now what's the problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben thinks fast. The Priest is with him. The Five Elements are on board.</context>
      <utterance>There's a ball of fire 1,200 miles in diameter heading straight for the earth. And we have no idea how to stop it! ...That's the problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President queries the scientist with a nod of the head.</context>
      <utterance>How much time before the collision?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCIENTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If its speed remains constant... in an hour and 57 minutes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DAVID</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're all safe. Thanks be to God!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The small group enters the chapel.</context>
      <utterance>Later, David! Later! There's not a minute to lose!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They just landed in the desert.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much time is left?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's obvious he doesn't know where to put it.</context>
      <utterance>Uh, this one... must be water!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't tell me you don't know how all this works?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben can't believe his ears. He tears the Stone out of Cornelius' hand and studies the inscriptions. He goes over to one of the four bases the stones rest on and tries to figure it out. The symbol of air is on the Stone, the same as on the base.</context>
      <utterance>Theoretically, yes! The four Stones form the beam and the Fifth Element is supposed to stand in the middle there, but... I don't have the reference book. I've never seen the Stones work!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben places the first Stone and picks up another one. Cornelius has found the symbol for water. Loc Rhod sits down. He is very tired.</context>
      <utterance>Match the symbols!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben pulls him to his feet and sticks a Stone in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>What is this some kinda game? Like chess?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loc Rhod's got it and runs over to put in his Stone. The four Stones are all in place but nothing happens.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's much simpler. If we don't figure out where these Stones go in five minutes, we're all dead! Think you got it?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no light! You told me there were supposed to be four beams of light.</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They have to be open for it to work.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, of course, but... The Stones are shut!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you don't know how they open, is that what you are saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>266	EXT.  SPACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Dark Planet closes in on Earth rapidly.</utterance>
   <speaker>267	INT.  CHAPEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Korben leans over Leeloo.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Leeloo? The Stones! We have to open them! How does it work?</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The wind blows... the fire burns...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know all that, Leeloo! I'm talking about the Stones.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben is desperate. Leeloo's too weak, he won't get anything more out of her. He darts over to a Stone and turns it over and over.</context>
      <utterance>...The rain falls...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loc Rhod stands in front of his Stone looking at Korben.</context>
      <utterance>The rain falls... the wind blows?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try and figure out how this fucking thing opens, instead of staring at me like that! Loc Rhod starts feeling the Stone all around.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm looking, I'm looking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SCIENTIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Three minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've lost contact with them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sighs. Three hooks pop off the Stone. Loc Rhod can't believe his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>...we'll never make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben rushes over, looks at the Stone. Hooks are undone.</context>
      <utterance>It... it moved! Korben! Korben!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you say? What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing! Swear to God, I didn't do nothing!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loc Rhod tries to duplicate the same movement.</context>
      <utterance>Look, you did something that set it off. Try to remember. Concentrate. Tell me exactly what you did!!</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was like this... With my hands here and... I said, "We'll never make it!" That's all! Nothing happens.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that all?</utterance>
   <speaker>LOC RHOD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loc Rhod sighs, really depressed this time. The Stone opens even more. Korben's got it.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... then I sighed... like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben blows on the Stone which immediately opens revealing a patch of blue sky with some miniature clouds floating around inside. A yellow beam pops up like a ray of sunlight, like Korben's smile.</context>
      <utterance>The wind! The wind blows...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The two men move fast. Korben on the 4th Stone: Earth. He grabs a fistful of earth and throws it on the Stone. A miniature patch of green appears and immediately forms a green beam. Cornelius wipes his forehead with a scarf and wrings it out over the Stone. It opens revealing a patch of miniature raging sea. A blue beam appears. Loc Rhod has a problem.</context>
      <utterance>Quickly, everyone on a Stone! Water for water! Fire for fire! Earth for earth!</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Loc Rhod and Cornelius hold their breath. Korben strikes the match. A small flame appears on the tip. A breeze goes through the room. Korben feels like he's got TNT in his hands. He approaches the flame to the Stone. The flame twists, dims, flickers ...but holds on. The Stone opens. A patch of miniature fire appears. Korben sighs, snuffs out the match. The fourth beam, a red one, immediately forms.</context>
      <utterance>Don't breathe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's up to you now, Angel!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so tired...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can sleep tomorrow... come on...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to sleep... forever...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Korben slowly releases Leeloo and steps back from the altar. Leeloo can barely stand in the center of the four beams. An indistinct white beam begins to form around her, starts to rise.</context>
      <utterance>Leeloo! Listen to me! I'll take you on a vacation afterwards! A real vacation, this time, for as long as you want. Come on! You can do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The beam loses its intensity. Leeloo crumples to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Come on Leeloo! Come on!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo wraps her arms around Korben's neck.</context>
      <utterance>Leeloo! If you don't get on with the program we're all gonna die! And that's not on my agenda for today.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>when you see what you do with them!</context>
      <utterance>What's the use of saving lives...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're right but there are lots of good things... beautiful things...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Like love...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I don't know love... I'm like a machine programmed to save other people's lives but never to have one of my own.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have thousands of memories but none of them are mine... There is no need for me other than this. I'm immortal but I have no life.</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, you do! I need you. More than you can imagine! Stand up straight!</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?... Why would you need me?</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because...</utterance>
   <speaker>CORNELIUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A bit of the black acid falls on Loc Rhod's shirt setting it on fire. He rips if off.</context>
      <utterance>Tell her, for God's sake!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leeloo has tears in her eyes. The heat is overpowering. Black acid is everywhere.</context>
      <utterance>Because...</utterance>
   <speaker>LEELOO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me...</utterance>
   <speaker>KORBEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despite her fatigue, Leeloo smiles broadly.</context>
      <utterance>I love you...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>MUNRO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. President, let me introduce you to Professor Mactilburgh, who runs the center.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's an honor to receive you. Mr. President.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.. Well? Where are our two heroes?</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were so tired from their ordeal that we put them in the reactor this morning..</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have 19 more meetings after this one Professor..</utterance>
   <speaker>PROFESSOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course.. Let me see if they're revived.</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mactilburgh goes to the reactor and opens a small slot which allows him to see what is going on under the blue shield. Leeloo and Korben are naked, arms wrapped around each other, kissing and probably engaged in hoppi hoppa. Mactilburgh looks troubled.</context>
      <utterance>We go live in one minute, Mr. President.</utterance>
   <speaker>MACTILBURGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President, pressed for time, looks over to his aide who in struggling with a phone call.</context>
      <utterance>I.. uh.. they need five more minutes, Mr. President.</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No ma'am... I tried... No ma'am...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>AIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some woman... claims she's Korben's mother...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The President takes the phone and goes to the window.</context>
      <utterance>Give it here...</utterance>
   <speaker>PRESIDENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Dallas, this in the President. On behalf of the entire Federation, I would like to thank...</utterance>
   <speaker>MOTHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't pull that crap with me, Finger... I'd recognize that trash can voice of yours in a dark alley during a rain storm. You tell that worthless no account son of mine he should plotz for the way he's ignored his mother... when I think of all I sacrificed for him...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
