<movie id="569" title="Tourist The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's waiting for someone.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNGER WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably waiting for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A MESSENGER clad in leather, wearing a motorcycle helmet, enters the cafe and looks around. He consults a photograph. His eyes land on Cara. He walks over and holds out a document-sized envelope.</context>
      <utterance>The door's waiting for you if you don't get back to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MESSENGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'est vous, Mademoiselle?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the messenger walks away she opens the folder and shakes out the contents. There is a ticket for the Orient Express and a handwritten letter... She spreads it out on the table like a precious treasure map. Her beautiful forehead creases with concentration as she reads...</context>
      <utterance>Oui.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She looks up. Takes out a small makeup mirror and holds it in front of her face to glance around behind her...</context>
      <utterance>They are following you Cara.</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>CAMERA glides down to see the signature at the bottom: "Love, Alexander." We barely have time to read this before Cara's perfectly manicured hand crumples the letter, places it in a saucer and sets fire to it. The YOUNG WAITER hurries over, alarmed.</context>
      <utterance>They think you'll lead them to me. But if you follow my instructions closely, there is a way for us to get away... Cara scans the rest of the letter.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNGER WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cara is already gathering her things and walking away.</context>
      <utterance>Mademoiselle! Je vous en prie--</utterance>
   <speaker>ALEXANDER'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Her eyes scan the platform.</context>
      <utterance>Take the 4:25 Orient Express to Venice. En route select a man my approximate height and weight...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WIFE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With a regretful backward glance at Cara, he allows himself to be dragged away. Frustrated, Cara turns and casts about for another possibility. She spots a TOUSLE HAIRED MAN seated on a bench.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing Vincent? Our train car is over here!</utterance>
   <speaker>CONDUCTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tousle Hair gathers his bags to get on the train. Encouraged, Cara moves to cut him off. As Tousle Hair stands up REVEAL... he's six foot seven. Cara stops short, irritated. The MAN behind her boarding the train is fumbling with his suitcase and doesn't notice. BAM he walks straight into her.</context>
      <utterance>All aboard! All aboard the 4:25 is departing!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ow!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FRANK TAYLOR (30's, amiable) is a cheerful American tourist. Open face, completely lacking in guile. Frank continues to mutter apologies as he walks gingerly around Cara and boards the train. Cara watches him with thinly veiled contempt. Frank is a man of average size, average build... she peers over her glasses at him. And her expression slowly changes. She follows him onto the train.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry! Excuse me. Pardone moi.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank is barely able to respond.</context>
      <utterance>I think I'm going to need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank finally moves into action. He sets his book down and leans closer. Awkwardly he reaches towards Cara's beautiful neck. He attempts to unwind the trapped thread of fabric. But the zipper resists.</context>
      <utterance>My zipper...  It's stuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slides forward on her seat, to get even closer.</context>
      <utterance>I'm afraid of hurting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The train car sways slightly and throws Frank off balance. He tugs sharply and the zipper suddenly gives-- with a tearing sound. Frank freezes, looking down at the zipper still in his fingers.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be afraid.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cara's eyes flash fury for a brief moment.</context>
      <utterance>I'm... sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I should let you do this--</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reluctantly, Frank continues with the zipper. The tearing sound continues as he lowers the zipper, inch by inch. First her neck, then her throat, then her cleavage are gradually uncovered. The zipper keeps going downward. No sign of anything underneath. Frank is practically sweating. Finally he uncovers fabric. He finishes unzipping the sweater and sits back into his seat. Cara slides it off her shoulders, sensuous as ever.</context>
      <utterance>Don't give up so quickly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>And settles back into her seat, cat-like. He stares at her for several moments, at a loss for words.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A white-jacketed STEWARD arrives.</context>
      <utterance>Cara.</utterance>
   <speaker>STEWARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Will you and your wife take dinner here or in the dining car this evening, monsieur?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me? Oh, no. We're not actually--</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The steward nods and disappears. Frank just stares.</context>
      <utterance>The dining car would be lovely, thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you ill?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at all the pills spread out beside his plate.</context>
      <utterance>What? No.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just nervous. I don't like travelling.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates.</context>
      <utterance>So you decided to take a holiday on the Orient Express?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on my honeymoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cara is annoyed at this revelation.</context>
      <utterance>Your honeymoon?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Should we ask the waiter to set another place?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off her questioning look...</context>
      <utterance>She's in Pennsylvania.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure you want to hear this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you'd like to tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two weeks ago she left me. For the owner of a pizza parlor.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank nods, matter-of-fact.</context>
      <utterance>That's awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No travel insurance. No refund on the tickets. So... here I am. On my honeymoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I really loved that pizza too. "Bala Pizza" if you're ever in Rosemont.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A waiter delivers their drinks.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't touch it. I'm loyal to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Cointreau for Mademoiselle. And for Monsieur... a "Miller Light."</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The waiter rolls his eyes and leaves them. Cara seems amused by Frank's obliviousness.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She nods toward his well-thumbed paperback.</context>
      <utterance>What takes you to Venice?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(playful)</context>
      <utterance>You read spy novels.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>You tell me what my story is.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a mysterious woman on a train.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... you'd be a diplomatic attach or... let's see... a girl from East Germany whose father's been kidnapped by Soviet agents. They're blackmailing you into stealing... probably a microchip. There's usually a microchip involved.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What awaits me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trouble, certainly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Danger?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No doubt. You'll probably be shot at in less than two chapters.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>Is there a man in my life?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He gazes at her with a glimmer of hope. She's insanely out of his league. But she's the one flirting with him.</context>
      <utterance>Or a candidate for the job?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're putting a lot resources into this investigation, John. Tell me you're going to get him this time.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>GOYAL, (Ackerman's Deputy) closes his cell phone.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to get him this time, Ms. Jones.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's on the train. They'll be in Venice in the morning.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman clicks a slide projected on a large screen behind him: a fuzzy photo of a British schoolboy with a shy grin.</context>
      <utterance>Our target's name is Alexander Pearce. British citizen, born in London into an ordinary middle class family. The only thing remarkable about his childhood was a preternatural gift for numbers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>JEAN LUC (French Interpol liaison) looks up skeptically.</context>
      <utterance>Which he used to hack into a computer and fix the test results his final year at school.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JEAN LUC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your mastermind couldn't pass his exams on his own?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A ripple of laughter through the group.</context>
      <utterance>He didn't fix his test scores; he fixed the scores for all the girls in the class. It made him very popular.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What started as school pranks eventually became something much more serious. After a year in the training program at Goldman Sachs, he decided that gambling suited him better than working for a living. That, in turn, involved him with some rather unsavory people and ultimately led him to put his financial genius to work in his true calling: money laundering. QUINN is the Swiss Interpol liaison. He speaks with the crisp accent of a man who is fluent in several languages.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've assembled quite a task force to catch a common money launderer, Mr. Ackerman.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He clicks through a series of flashy Powerpoint slides illustrating Pearce's financial dealings.</context>
      <utterance>There is nothing common about Alexander Pearce. Quiet simply, he has turned money laundering into an art form. His greatest innovation: The False Lawsuit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pearce sets up two companies: one is a Casino in Arizona for example and the other is a shell company in the Cayman Islands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Cayman Islands company files a lawsuit against the casino, claiming copyright infringement or some other complaint. They "succeed" in winning the case and the casino pays the shell company an enormous settlement.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The money travels from America to the Cayman Islands...</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, but now the money is legal.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean Luc leans toward his colleague.</context>
      <utterance>Not quite legal. The I.R.S. has been cheated out of the revenue.  We calculate that Mr. Pearce's tax bill currently stands at $743.7 million dollars.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN LUC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ms. Jones gives him a glacial stare.</context>
      <utterance>That explains what the American harridan is doing here.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean Luc reddens. Oops. Apparently not every American fits the stereotype.</context>
      <utterance>Exactement, monsieur.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Click: A PHOTO of a balding RUSSIAN OLIGARCH emerging from a limo.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Pearce has some other debts as well. Most of you will recognize Ivan Demidov...</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...Pearce laundered over a billion dollars for Demidov. At some point Pearce decided he'd rather steal from Demidov than help him steal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Given Demidov's ties to organized crime, I'd say that was a mistake.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman smiles coolly at her.</context>
      <utterance>The U.S. Government is not participating in an investigation of a member of the Russian parliament; our target is Alexander Pearce.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An INTERPOL OFFICER from Germany raises his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>GERMAN INTERPOL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman looks down for a moment, as if it pains him to answer.</context>
      <utterance>Has Mr. Pearce ever been in custody?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Finally. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>14.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They follow the team.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cara sits on the bed, drying her hair. On a night table beside her are keys, a wallet and an expensive MAN'S</context>
      <utterance>I'll be ready in fifteen minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WATCH.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks across the tiled floor to the balcony overlooking the elevator entrance. She freezes; six tactics OFFICERS face her with guns drawn. ACKERMAN steps up the stairs, pistol in hand. He gestures at Cara to be quiet and come towards him... Cara stands stock still for a long instant. Then...</context>
      <utterance>Cara pauses; she's heard something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cara looks at him for a moment, then lowers her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>You have nothing to say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Tall Commander shepherds the handcuffed Cara down the stairs and into the elevator. She wears Alexander's WATCH....</context>
      <utterance>Get her out of my sight.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does this Alexander Pearce look like?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nobody knows. He disappeared after his escape. He's had extensive plastic surgery to alter his appearance since then. Drug lord Amado Carillo did the same thing in the 90s to successfully elude authorities.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know about it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pearce worked with no more than a few accomplices at one time. He treated them so well that they're virtually all completely loyal. None of them would cooperate. We've questioned the ones we could find, and the only thing we learned is that Pearce apparently arranged it so even his own people have never seen him after the surgery.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN LUC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So nobody knows what he looks like?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Correct.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN LUC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman regards him with aplomb.</context>
      <utterance>Forgive me for saying so Mr. Ackerman, but he slipped away from you when you knew his whereabouts and his appearance... What makes you think you can catch him now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His girlfriend was recently released from custody. He'll come for her. We'll be waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cara's face fills the screen behind him. A murmur runs through the room. Every man stares.</context>
      <utterance>What makes you so certain? Ackerman clicks on a slide.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman himself glances up at her face with a look of longing. HOLD ON CARA'S IMAGE for a moment before we...</context>
      <utterance>He'll come for her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was afraid I'd missed you. I wanted to ask where you're staying in Venice... I'm supposed to catch a shuttle to my hotel but I thought maybe--</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes it hesitantly. She peers at him over the rims of her sunglasses with a very slight smile...</context>
      <utterance>I've got a better idea. She holds out her valise for him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a booking in the name of Mason.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Si, Signorina.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods at Frank. For a second, the receptionist cannot keep the surprise out of his eyes. This glamorous, superbly dressed creature is married to a dull, American tourist in a T-shirt? He recovers his composure and alters his manner at once.</context>
      <utterance>Signora. That's my husband.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very good, Senora Mason. Welcome to the Danieli. You are in the Doge's-- our premiere suite.  Is there anything special you require?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have a copy of today's Herald Tribune sent up to the room please.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He gives her a large gold key and nods to a porter to take the luggage. Frank hurries to catch up with her. THE RECEPTIONIST he watches them go.</context>
      <utterance>My pleasure, Signora.</utterance>
   <speaker>RECEPTIONIST</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mother of God, what a waste.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances at Cara; she doesn't look like a woman who spends a lot of time in the kitchen.</context>
      <utterance>The bedroom is through here. You have two bathrooms, here and here. There is a small kitchen which...</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The porter throws open a pair of French windows. He lets the view speak for itself. They step forward. The whole of St. Mark's Basin and the Venetian lagoon are laid out below them.</context>
      <utterance>...you may not need. There are two televisions, video, DVD, radio, hi fi sound system. And...</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is everything satisfactory?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>PORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Porter looks expectantly to the "husband" for a tip. Frank doesn't get it. An awkward beat. Cara takes a few Euros from her purse and tips him. The Porter exits.</context>
      <utterance>Then I will leave you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You like it? Frank opens his mouth to answer. Then laughs.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's not to like?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd have been bored here on my own. There's more than enough room for two.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can see that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looks at her for a beat, barely able to breathe.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't ask for an extra bed...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>His face falls. He tries to cover up his reaction.</context>
      <utterance>Are you all right with the sofa? If you like, I can have them bring one up?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before he can say more, the buzzer sounds.</context>
      <utterance>No, no, no. The sofa's fine. Perfect in fact.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The luggage.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes back inside to answer the door. Cara remains alone on the balcony, immobile, as if holding her breath. She's waiting... listening.</context>
      <utterance>I'll get it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to face him.</context>
      <utterance>I've put my things in the other bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Have you ever been to Venice before?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we need to go out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>she's not alone.</context>
      <utterance>She's checked into the Danieli...</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.  Maintain surveillance but keep your distance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's a '97...</context>
      <utterance>Take a seat, Mr. Quinn. Can I offer you a glass of Brunello?</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Demidov swirls his glass.</context>
      <utterance>No thank you, Mr. Demidov.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I'd never admit this at home, but Vodka is for peasants. There's much we could learn from the Italians.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Quinn takes out an envelope and passes it over.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me I'm not going to be disappointed.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flips it open and examines the contents. WE GLIMPSE a photo of CARA and some text.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>QUINN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Demidov looks at Quinn thoughtfully.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Demidov... if I may ask you a question... Why do you care so much about Alexander Pearce? I mean, you've come here yourself... as if it were personal.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quinn smiles tightly. He's ready to get out of there.</context>
      <utterance>It may be difficult for you to understand, Mr. Quinn; you Swiss are mercenary by nature. But for some of us, there are things more important than money. I put my trust in Alexander Pearce. He betrayed that trust.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And it's bad business to let somebody make a fool of you. If Pearce gets away with it, what does that say about me?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So... when you're not on a Grand European Tour, what do you do in Rosemont, Pennsylvania?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances at him slyly over her movie star shades.</context>
      <utterance>I'm a teacher. High school math. And you? What do you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is what I do, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sound of voices and laughter drift toward them. Up ahead on the beach they see a group of Italians in formal clothes. A woman wears a white bridal dress.</context>
      <utterance>You're good at it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh look... a wedding. How lovely.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not really into weddings at this particular moment in my life...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes his arm and steers him toward a bistro with sidewalk tables.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes. I forgot.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think it's really over?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe she'll change her mind. Women do. She might give you a second chance.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose that's a possibility.  That's what I tell my statistics class anyway; life is a game of chance. Endless possibilities and permutations. You just have to calculate the odds.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't answered the question.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cara looks at him curiously.</context>
      <utterance>Well...  I'd like to think that love is a question of destiny, not chance...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head and takes a sip of wine.</context>
      <utterance>For a moment there you just reminded me of somebody.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He had a way of dancing around a question so eloquently that you never noticed until later that he'd completely avoided the truth. His entire life was wrapped up in deception.  He told so many lies, I wouldn't believe him even if he finally did tell the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't sound like much of a friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank glances at her wrist.</context>
      <utterance>He wasn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks up at him.</context>
      <utterance>So why are you wearing his watch?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs her fingertip over the face of the watch. Then, impulsively unclasps it and reaches for Frank's hand.</context>
      <utterance>You're smarter than you look, Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She puts it on Frank's wrist, over his protests.</context>
      <utterance>And you're right. Here, take it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? No, I can't. This thing must be worth a fortune--</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hesitates. She means it. He closes the clasp.</context>
      <utterance>I insist. You're doing me a favor.  Take it or I'll toss it in the ocean.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He feels the heft of it on his wrist. Admires it for a moment. It really is a beautiful watch. She settles back in her chair, pleased with herself. He looks up and sees her smiling at him.</context>
      <utterance>I'll wear it until you regain your senses.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It suits you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank stares after her in stunned disappointment.</context>
      <utterance>You should leave Venice tomorrow.  It's a city for lovers Frank; no place to recover from a failed engagement. She turns and walks toward her bedroom...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses at the door. Her expression softens slightly.</context>
      <utterance>What... what did I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then she disappears into her bedroom. The door closes behind her and we hear the click of the lock. Frank remains standing alone, immobile. After several moments he sits on the sofa. There are two folded blankets and a pillow. From within Cara's bedroom we can hear her voice, muffled but still audible...</context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...that's exactly what I'm doing, but now I want him to go...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank stares in surprise at the food spread out before him.</context>
      <utterance>Pardone Signore. Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>La Signora ordered this for you when she left.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around the suite. He is alone. He nods.</context>
      <utterance>When she...?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The waiter has finished. He hovers for a moment... Finally Frank takes the hint and gives the man a one Euro tip. He takes it with disdain and leaves. Frank throws off his blanket and sits up.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another round of shots ring out. They don't seem to care. Frank goes over the railing with another awkward HEAVE. His pursuers scale the adjoining stone work and step onto the Pallid Woman's balcony. This time Frank lands in the lap of a BURLY WELSHMAN.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn it! I'm a fucking tourist!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURLY WELSHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Burly Welshman PUNCHES Frank in the stomach, which drops him out of the way of...</context>
      <utterance>Are ya bloody mad?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank stands.</context>
      <utterance>You can't let them stay over, man. You start cuddling and then she wants to borrow your car. Stop cuddling, Tomaso!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, what are you doing in here?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dominico glances over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>The officers told me to wait here. I've been sitting here for over two hours...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank sits back down heavily. Domenico sits on the edge of a desk.</context>
      <utterance>I think they forgot about you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to you, anyway?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Domenico picks up Frank's statement and glances at it.</context>
      <utterance>Somebody tried to kill me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Domenico looks at mild-mannered Frank sitting there in his boxers. The story seems unlikely.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Taylor, wow, you had quite a day. Eh? We got chasing, we got shooting.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm crazy but it's all true.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you crazy AND it's true, my friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, so who are these guys? Why they mad at you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have absolutely no idea.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They followed you from the Danieli?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They came to the room. They pretended to be room service.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't scopata one of their girlfriends or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't "scopata" anybody!</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He consults a piece of paper.</context>
      <utterance>Who is...</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank is quiet. Domenico playfully points at him.</context>
      <utterance>Cara Mason?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I catch you, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In America the cops catch the crooks, not the victim.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Domenico considers for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Ha ha, we do that sometimes here, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is no domestic, then?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long you know Cara Mason?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I met her yesterday.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you take her to the Danieli? That must have been good meeting, yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The infectious grin again lights up Domenico's face.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't take her. She took me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Taylor.</context>
      <utterance>You lead an exciting life, Mr.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Domenico picks up the phone and dials a number. He talks in brisk Italian, listens again and replaces the receiver.</context>
      <utterance>Not usually.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Signora Mason was staying with "her husband" last night. You marry her, Mr. Taylor?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>I think maybe Signora Mason might know why these guys behave badly. What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think that's possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a phone number, mobile?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't give me one.</utterance>
   <speaker>41.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Domenico looks him over.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank stands and half-heartedly follows him to the doorway. He spots something in the adjoining room; a computer that has been left on. He wanders over and looks at the screen. An idea comes into Frank's head... he looks around. Nobody is watching him. He glances at the inscription on the</context>
      <utterance>You need some clothes. I'll be right back. He leaves Frank alone again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank looks at the clothes.</context>
      <utterance>Here. Put these on. Time to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... thanks. Where are we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm taking you to the hospital, Mr. Taylor. A doctor should take a look at you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd really rather just go--</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I put you in Padua, away from Venice. You'll be safe.  Any worry, you call me. I give you my home number.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately we've already re-let the room.  We'd rather the guests didn't know about the incident.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I'll be discreet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Clerk knocks. The door is opened by Ivan Demidov.</context>
      <utterance>Grazie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CLERK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I beg your pardon, Signore, but this is a police officer. He needs to briefly examine the room.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Demidov steps back, holding the door open.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened, officer?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Domenico gets down on his hands and knees and looks around. He spots something under the sofa and fishes it out with his penknife... a spent bullet casing. He puts it in a plastic bag, pleased with himself. Demidov catches his eye. He smiles at him.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I'm trying to find out, Signore.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are a good detective.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Domenico stands and takes his leave.</context>
      <utterance>I do my best.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>As he and the clerk exit, Scarface steps out from the other room. Off Demidov's look, he leaves the suite to follow...</context>
      <utterance>Sorry for the inconvenience. Enjoy your stay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did we find on the American?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Has bad luck.</context>
      <utterance>He's a tourist. Member of the teacher's union. Pays his taxes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Evidently. He had a pair of Russian hit men after him. Are you still going to tell me Demidov is clean?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never said he is clean. I just said he isn't our target.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just wondering how they tracked them down at the hotel...</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at Goyal.</context>
      <utterance>Just so long as they don't beat us to Pearce when the real one arrives.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's the teacher now?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The local police picked him up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then he's safely out of the way.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You're not mad.</context>
      <utterance>Well it's official Mr. Taylor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a relief.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank glances around uncomfortably.</context>
      <utterance>I went to the hotel. Somebody shot at somebody. I found a shell casing. I'll have it analyzed in the morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd like to be on a flight home tomorrow morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Relax, you're perfectly safe where you are.  You have any visits from your Signora Mason?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOMENICO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the restful silence he hears a DISTANT BANG. A gunshot? A door slam? Nervous, he gets up and goes to the door...</context>
      <utterance>Never let them cuddle, Mr. Taylor. One cuddle and it all turns to merda. Good night. If you need anything, you have my number. Frank hangs up, shaking his head.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you miss me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He glances anxiously over her shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>A little.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Um... you may not believe this but there are some people trying to kill me--</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Cara drives toward the ramp. He looks at her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know why?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops the car and waits for the metal gate at the top of the ramp to open. It rises with a loud creaking to</context>
      <utterance>It's because I kissed you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That guy has nothing to do with this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks her straight in the eye. She relents.</context>
      <utterance>Neither do you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She turns over the ignition.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. If you want to play hero...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cara revs the car and pulls out fast, cutting off the Nurse's car. He leans on the horn. At the top of the exit ramp, the metal parking gate is slowly being lowered. She weaves around the black car, deliberately heading for the gunman. He opens fire. BRRRRRAAAP!! Bullets spray wildly, ricocheting off the walls, shattering windshields... Frank covers his face as a side-window pops, showering him with glass. The GUNMAN is forced to jump out of the way as Cara scrapes the side of her car along the wall. Sparks fly. The black car burns rubber as it U-turns to follow her. She guns it up the ramp towards the closing door.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's not enough room!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's enough room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We won't make it!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the last second he ducks instinctively and closes his eyes. The gate clips the top of Cara's car with a tremendous CLANG! Traps it. Cara presses her foot all the way down on the accelerator. Smoke pours from the tires.</context>
      <utterance>I thought Americans were optimists.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank holds up his wrist.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know--?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hesitates. A pause.</context>
      <utterance>The watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. You're about his size. That's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know what your own boyfriend looks like?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Alexander crossed a very dangerous man. He changed his appearance in order to vanish.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't worry. I'm taking you somewhere you'll be safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should go to the police.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank doesn't respond.</context>
      <utterance>Because they did such a good job protecting you before?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank looks at her. Then relents, leaning his head back against the support and closing his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Trust me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank steps over a greenish puddle.</context>
      <utterance>And I thought I wouldn't get to do any sight-seeing.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses before a run-down palazzo.</context>
      <utterance>Here we are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She quickly directs the gun away from him. Frank leans over, catching his breath. Cara starts to giggle. Frank starts to laugh too.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls out, a flashlight in her mouth.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank watches her walk over to the FUSE BOXES.</context>
      <utterance>Making sure no one sabotaged the gas lines.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cara has poured herself a glass of wine.</context>
      <utterance>He goes Barracuda fishing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He goes Marlin fishing. You catch the Barracudas by accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>55.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank looks at the steak...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank smiles and pours himself a glass of wine. Cara takes a bite.</context>
      <utterance>And she left you for a cook?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmmmm! That's decadent.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank savors a bite of his meal.</context>
      <utterance>With these ingredients, it's not hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Cara laughs. She clinks his glass.</context>
      <utterance>You know something? Food tastes better after you've been shot at.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They watch one another eat for several moments.</context>
      <utterance>I'm glad I decided to come back for you, Frank Taylor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sets down her fork. Leans back.</context>
      <utterance>Can I ask you a question.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it like? Being a criminal?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not a criminal.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You carry a gun, you consort with people being chased by killers... I hate to break it to you, but--</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a big gulp of wine. Moves over to the sofa.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, I'm a criminal.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She lapses into silence. Frank comes and sits beside her.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't mean for things to turn out like this. I always lived by a certain code. But then... I broke it.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She doesn't answer. Which is an answer.</context>
      <utterance>For Alexander Pearce?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>What's he like?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shifts deeper into the leather cushions as if reliving a memory of sensual pleasure.</context>
      <utterance>He's the most interesting man I've ever known. When I first met him, I wasn't expecting that. He took me by surprise.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She frowns into her empty wine glass. Frank slides a little closer.</context>
      <utterance>If I'd been prepared, I might not have loved him. But I wasn't. So I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't regret it, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Regret what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks into her eyes. They are sitting very close on the sofa. The lights are low. The mood is romantic... Frank puts an arm over her shoulders and leans in for a kiss-- Cara stands abruptly.</context>
      <utterance>Kissing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at her, questioningly.</context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank doesn't respond.</context>
      <utterance>You thought what? That I saw you on the train and my heart stopped? That all my life I've been waiting for a math teacher from the Midwest to sweep me off my feet?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He does. His humiliation complete, he rises with as much dignity as he can muster and carries the plates into the kitchen. Cara looks after him... exasperated yet already sorry for being so blunt. She is about to say something when... Her CELL PHONE RINGS. A special ring. She answers right away.</context>
      <utterance>I picked you because of your height. Do you understand?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... there was nothing there today. Is... is it you? Alexa--</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No names. Not on the phone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been a busier weekend than I expected.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A HORN-RIMMED AIDE zeroes in on a MAP screen. The screen gives him a map of VENICE. Then zooms into a map of the SAN MARCO district...</context>
      <utterance>Place him. Place him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a recipe in a Tuscan cookbook there I need. Would you look it up for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do we really need another "recipe?"</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to make sure our guests are surprised.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goyal is already out the door and Ackerman grabs his Kevlar vest and follows, racing down the steps...</context>
      <utterance>Go! Go! Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pouts, only partially joking.</context>
      <utterance>That's because you leave everything up to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fine by the way, in case you were concerned about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My only concern is for those who cross you, my love.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Englishman is at the Ponte del Suspiri-- the "Bridge of Sighs."</context>
      <utterance>You may not believe it, but every step of this miserable game is taken in the hope of earning your trust and ever-lasting regard. I mean that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a talent for saying the right thing.  You always did.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should check for prints. Maybe he forgot to wipe it down...</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman looks around.</context>
      <utterance>I doubt it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens his eyes and looks at her.</context>
      <utterance>Frank... I have to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't go out. All you need is here. In four or five days everything will be resolved...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Resolved?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It will all be over. I'll give you the all clear and you can go back to your life. This will be a great adventure you can look back on.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When will I see you again?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him evenly; one last glance between two people from two completely different worlds.</context>
      <utterance>Never.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She leaves.</context>
      <utterance>Good-bye, Frank.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he worth it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She has stopped mid-flight.</context>
      <utterance>Get back inside.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to risk everything for him. Would he do the same for you? She is quite straightforward in her response.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter. I love him.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>He doesn't deserve it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as she raises her voice a door opens below them in the hall, and an old man comes out. He looks up at Cara.</context>
      <utterance>None of this is your business anymore. Now get back inside Frank!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is exactly what she did not want. But she controls her annoyance, nods in greeting and continues towards the front door.</context>
      <utterance>Signorina.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Neighbor nods as Cara walks out the door. He admires Cara's shapely form as she crosses the cobblestone streets and disappears into the alley. He glances back up at Frank and whistles appreciatively. Frank turns and goes back inside.</context>
      <utterance>Mi dispiace, Signor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean Luc can't tell if she's serious.</context>
      <utterance>Don't look at me. I married my personal trainer.  She's twenty-six.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did Pearce seduce that beautiful woman? Was it his charm? His looks?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman sips from his ten thousandth cup of espresso.</context>
      <utterance>Looks change.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks around to see if the others like this theory.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe it's because if he adores himself and spends every moment gratifying his desires, so then can she.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>There is a bitterness in Ackerman's tone that reveals he is personally hurt by this. Goyal's Blackberry makes a beep.</context>
      <utterance>She can become a child again. Who wouldn't want that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman pushes himself wearily to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>She's on the move. Time to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By all means. Let's follow the children.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pats talcum powder on himself. The men remain stone- faced.</context>
      <utterance>When I was a young man, times were very hard. When an opportunity presented itself, you took it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He points at his platinum cufflinks on a bedside table and snaps his fingers. Scarface hands them to him.</context>
      <utterance>I was twelve years old when Gregor asked me if I was ready for a man's job. He was the top chelovek in our housing block. So I said yes. He gave me a crowbar and told me to go bash in the skull of another boy who had stolen something from him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He carefully knots his tie in the mirror.</context>
      <utterance>Now it just so happened this boy was a friend of mine. I did not want to do this terrible thing. But when you come from the streets, you have no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He turns and smiles at his THICK-NECKED bodyguard. He gestures toward the man's holstered pistol --</context>
      <utterance>I worked very hard for years to get past that life. So I would not have to do these terrible things. So I would have a choice...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He holds out his hand; THICK NECK hands him the pistol.</context>
      <utterance>I have people like you to do these things for me...</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Suddenly Demidov pistol whips the man across the face! Blood explodes from THICK NECK's nose. He falls down to one knee, clutching his face in pain.</context>
      <utterance>Except that you don't!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AGENTE DI POLIZIA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eh, we do not know any further...characteristics?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what we know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is that fool doing in the middle of my operation?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time for Alexander and me to meet face to face.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank sits at the table with Cara and eats a CASHEW.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you're talking about. Please go, I'd like to have a quiet coffee.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The UNDERCOVER WAITER quickly moves away from Cara's table. Ackerman stares at the monitor which captures Cara's angry expression.</context>
      <utterance>Move off. Move off.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get rid of him!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank turns back to Cara, who calls out--</context>
      <utterance>Caffe, per favore?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cameriere! No caffe for signor!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>With milk!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to be dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank pulls out a Gitane cigarette. He lights it, smoking while he talks.</context>
      <utterance>Not particularly, but I'm tired of being afraid. I've been running around like a frightened mouse long enough and I've decided I'm finished.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank frowns at the cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>When I first saw the name I got scared: "Alexander Pearce." He even sounds like some super cool master criminal with Russian enemies and the beautiful girlfriend... he probably works out. He might own a pizza shop on the side for all I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are disgusting.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman peers directly out the window, as if he's going to see something different.</context>
      <utterance>He's not going anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put Lipetti in. Tell him to play it like he's dealing with a rowdy guest-- escort him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank, you have no idea what you're sticking your nose into.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably not. But I'm doing it anyway. Alexander Pearce nearly got me killed. It was his idea, right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank works himself up, drawing courage from his anger.</context>
      <utterance>He told you to pick out some random sap on the train to take a bullet for him, didn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well I'm not playing the role anymore. I'm going to confront him. He's supposed to meet you here, isn't he? I'm going to tell him exactly what I think of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank leans in.</context>
      <utterance>Wonderful. Another macho idiot.  Conto, per favore!</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the lure, Cara? Obviously not his character. Is it the money? The luxury? What's any of that worth if you're getting shot at and you could go to jail?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm leaving Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's smooth, right? He probably has mistresses in every European city, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's really a shame you've scared him off-- She tosses some Euros on the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The THIN WAITER arrives with a PLATTER. He sets it down in front of Cara. The UNDERCOVER WAITER now moves toward the table with a grim expression... The THIN WAITER removes the platter. Cara looks down.</context>
      <utterance>The two of you make a nice couple.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Englishman has already turned away, but the Undercover Waiter is moving quickly toward Cara's table. The Undercover Waiter picks up speed, changing course slightly. WE SEE he's after The Englishman who is about to enter the restaurant kitchen... Then FRANK steps in front of The Undercover Waiter, mistaking him for Pearce.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell? As Frank looks up.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is this him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Frank!</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Abort! Abort, goddammit!</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POOLSIDE RESTAURANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Undercover Waiter tries to move past Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank SHOVES him back.</context>
      <utterance>You hide out poolside and send your girlfriend and a total stranger to face the murderers who are after you? Not much of a tough guy, are you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman rubs his face and squats down, frustrated beyond measure.</context>
      <utterance>That goddamn fool.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do we do with him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Throw him in the lagoon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks Frank up and down.</context>
      <utterance>Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice suit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's borrowed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a good fit.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman reaches into his breast pocket and takes out his INTERPOL credentials. Tosses them on the table for Frank to see.</context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ackerman smiles. Frank remains defiant. He jerks his head toward the mirror confidently.</context>
      <utterance>Police... better than the alternative I suppose.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ackerman looks over at the mirror, taken off guard by the question. He stands and goes to the mirror -- lifts it off its hooks and sets it on the floor. Nothing but plain wall underneath. Ackerman sits back down. Frank is a little bit chastened.</context>
      <utterance>Who's watching from behind there?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have a vivid imagination.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I haven't needed it lately.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>I'm not Alexander Pearce.</context>
      <utterance>You're in for a disappointment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looks up.</context>
      <utterance>I know that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank stares at him blankly...</context>
      <utterance>Since the beginning.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How...?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come. I want to show you something Frank.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank peers at the screen. He spots the instructor-- Ackerman seven years younger.</context>
      <utterance>Take a good look.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank examines the second row. One of the young women is... CARA MASON. Her hair is pulled back. She looks more the determined police cadet than the sexy siren... but it's definitely her.</context>
      <utterance>Take a look at the second row. INSERT CLOSE UP on the screen.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is dumbfounded.</context>
      <utterance>Cara...</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been watching you this entire time.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saw those men try to kill me and you didn't intervene?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank grows angry.</context>
      <utterance>I'm trying to apprehend a major criminal. I'm not a babysitter.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones clears her throat from a chair across the room.</context>
      <utterance>I want to speak with somebody at the American Embassy. I'm going to tell them that you and your undercover officer knowingly and recklessly endangered the life of an American citizen! Let's see what my government has to say about that!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank is incredulous.</context>
      <utterance>We're aware of the situation, Mr. Taylor. But we take a long view of these things... fortunately you are unhurt...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then I'll go to the press. I'll tell the entire story to the New York Times.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I don't think you'll do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank falls silent. Ackerman puts an arm around his shoulder and leads him away from the others.</context>
      <utterance>Because I don't think you want to see Cara's entire career destroyed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Espresso?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Women like Cara don't come along very often.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In my case, they don't come along at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's the worst combination: stunning looks and a brilliant mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If she's so smart, how did she get caught up with Pearce?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It started out as a straightforward placement...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman finishes his espresso.</context>
      <utterance>She was no longer with us. She was with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She explains it now as the confusion of her new life outside the academy. That I misread her capacity for this kind of work.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then why are you still using her?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>She's all I have, Mr. Taylor.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think she'll turn him in this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goyal walks up behind Ackerman waiting patiently for a moment to interrupt him.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank looks back at him evenly.</context>
      <utterance>I do know however, that you are very smitten with her.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman acknowledges the point with the barest of nods. Goyal signals that Ackerman has a phone call.</context>
      <utterance>It's not just me, is it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cara? Where have you been?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERCUT WITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>ACKERMAN on the phone at his office.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you got him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You mean the idiot who ruined our operation?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman glances out the window at Frank.</context>
      <utterance>Have you got him?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cara is relieved.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's your own fault. We never should have endangered a civilian. You should have put an agent into place.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was no time. Besides Pearce is too smart for that; he would have spotted the agent a mile away.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman smiles bitterly.</context>
      <utterance>He didn't spot me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cara doesn't answer. Ackerman regrets the jibe. He steps into a HALLWAY where it's quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Apparently he didn't have to.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ON HER FACE as she listens to him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Cara. That was uncalled for.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm on edge because of our failure today. If only the American hadn't messed everything up... I felt sure Pearce would show up today.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ackerman's face lights up...</context>
      <utterance>What makes you think he didn't?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones, Quinn, Jean Luc and the rest of the team assemble. Goyal has Frank with him, dragging him around like a lost puppy dog...</context>
      <utterance>Okay everybody, listen up.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have a location and time for the next meet. Pearce's villa. Eight o'clock. We have to move fast--</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pearce's own villa? Why would he risk going back there? He must know we'd be watching.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN LUC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps he's nostalgic.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He left in a hurry after all.</context>
      <utterance>I doubt that. Maybe there's something of value still there.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call in a search team.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up his coat.</context>
      <utterance>We searched the place after the raid last year. If there's anything hidden there, only Pearce knows where it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Frank speaks up unexpectedly.</context>
      <utterance>We need to get agents in place all around the villa.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A dozen heads turn to look at him.</context>
      <utterance>If you're all around his house, will he show up?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Ackerman turns back to the rest of the room.</context>
      <utterance>If I needed your advice Mr. Taylor, I'd ask. Frank shrinks down in his chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The meeting breaks up. Everybody jumps into action. ON QUINN as he slips out a side door.</context>
      <utterance>Establish a wide perimeter. We'll keep our distance and wire the entire villa for video surveillance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank enters the room. Sees her half-dressed--</context>
      <utterance>Come in.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In an echo of their first meeting on the train (but without the false flirtation) she turns to him and hands him a piece of tape. Their eyes meet. A flicker of a smile passes between them. Frank's fingers are perfectly steady this time as he helps her secure the microphone and do up her shirt.</context>
      <utterance>It's okay. Come over here. I need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>Ackerman told me everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps back from her. She smooths her blouse. Turns to him.</context>
      <utterance>There's no apology necessary.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do I look?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The complete honesty and directness of his compliment takes her by surprise. She's strangely moved by it. She brushes her hand affectionately over his cheek.</context>
      <utterance>Like the most beautiful woman on earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When will you go home?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something occurs to Frank.</context>
      <utterance>Ackerman asked me to stay with the surveillance team in case the thugs who came after me at the Danieli show up. I'm the only one who can identify them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you tell him to keep an eye on me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods. A little pleased at her concern.</context>
      <utterance>I told him to make sure you were safe until this was over.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What about you?</context>
      <utterance>You shouldn't worry about me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about me?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you going to do? She takes a beat, then puts her game face on.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all read the same newspaper.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank nods. Ackerman sits down next to Frank as if he were an old pal instead of a quasi-captive.</context>
      <utterance>It's a good paper. And sold throughout the world. Makes the classified ads especially useful...</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since the internet came about, hardly anybody uses old school methods like that to communicate anymore. Except Alexander Pearce. No lines to tap. No signals to intercept.  He's a very clever man, your double.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I look forward to meeting him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So do I.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They all turn to look. A male figure, his face masked, approaches the lens of the surveillance camera... BLINK! The FEED shuts off. Ackerman barks at a technician.</context>
      <utterance>Who's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The surveillance techs begin madly punching buttons, etc.</context>
      <utterance>What happened? Get it back on line!</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was that Pearce?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BLINK! Another monitor goes dark. Then another.</context>
      <utterance>How did he know there would be a camera?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's taking out the entire surveillance system--</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TECHNICIAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank looks anxiously at Cara on the monitor climbing the stairs... Blink! She disappears from view as well. Everybody starts talking.</context>
      <utterance>I can't! He's cutting the feed at the source.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JEAN LUC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can one man move through the house that fast?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They quiet down. Ackerman turns to the tech.</context>
      <utterance>Shut up! Everyone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The tech nods.</context>
      <utterance>Do we still have audio?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Everybody in the Church stands stock still. Staring at the dark monitors. Listening. Cara's footsteps click up the stairs and then slow... They move tentatively across the floor. WE HEAR A THUMP. A door or a heavy footstep? Cara's breathing gets louder. There's somebody else in the building.</context>
      <utterance>Turn it up.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>No response. Click, clack, click... She takes a few steps. ON FRANK -- concerned. ON ACKERMAN -- calm.</context>
      <utterance>Alexander?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cara pales.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry to disappoint you, my dear. He steps toward her.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who is that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you this evening?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fine, thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN LUC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The accent is Russ--</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Shh!  It's Ivan Demidov.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not possible.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cara doesn't reply.</context>
      <utterance>You're waiting for someone, Ms. Mason?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't seen Alexander Pearce in a long time, yes? I'm sure it will be a touching reunion.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you don't mind, we'll keep you company while you wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we going to do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to wait for Alexander Pearce. Just like them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SNIPER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's brought them to the window...</utterance>
   <speaker>SNIPER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>ON FRANK'S FACE - he looks around at the cops desperately hoping somebody will do something. They all look to Ackerman.</context>
      <utterance>...there are three of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not very polite of your boyfriend to keep you waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He loses track of time easily.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a hard time believing that.  Perhaps he's already here somewhere... hiding... even watching us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A long silence. The tension grows. Then we hear...</context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>A LOUD SLAP.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone in the room flinches.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode>V.O. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ANOTHER SLAP - MORE VICIOUS THAN THE FIRST. This time Cara cries out in pain. Goyal turns to Ackerman.</context>
      <utterance>You know... I have a feeling he is around here somewhere. And if he cares about you... if he wants to see your lovely face again... he should show up before it's too late.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jean Luc looks to his colleagues-- Jones, Quinn... then turns to Ackerman. Every one of them is about to burst.</context>
      <utterance>Demidov's right. He's here somewhere... Another SLAP. Another scream.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN LUC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to do something--</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to wait.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN LUC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes but--</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A muffled THUD. Cara groans and WE HEAR her body hit the floor. That wasn't a slap.</context>
      <utterance>She's my agent. She's my responsibility.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The lack of sound in the church is even more disturbing than before. Suddenly Goyal notices...</context>
      <utterance>What if he doesn't come? Ackerman doesn't respond.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Taylor?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Demidov ignores her and walks up to Frank.</context>
      <utterance>That's not Alexander Pearce.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds out his hand and one of his THUGS gives him a PISTOL and a SILENCER.</context>
      <utterance>You know, Mr. Pearce, I thought I was finished with this sort of thing. But in your case, I've been forced to make an exception.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Demidov begins screwing the silencer onto the barrel. The thugs push Frank to his knees. But he's barely paying attention to them. His eyes are locked on Cara. She meets his gaze. For a moment, it's as if nothing else in the world exists but the two of them. He may only be a hapless tourist, but he loves her. He's the one here, willing to give up his life to save hers.</context>
      <utterance>He is NOT Alexander Pearce!</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh Frank... I'm so sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Demidov finishes attaching the silencer. He points the gun at the back of Frank's head.</context>
      <utterance>Nothing to be sorry for.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMIDOV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At this moment, Cara fills her lungs and screams:</context>
      <utterance>Good bye Mr. Pearce.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ackerman!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cara nods. She looks at him for a long moment, then breaks out into a smile.</context>
      <utterance>Are you all right?</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank's turn to smile. He looks around the room at the carnage.</context>
      <utterance>I did well to choose you on the train...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You didn't get to arrest Alexander Pearce...</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frank slides closer to her. Gently, carefully, he slips his hands into Cara's cleavage. Surprised, Cara starts to pull back-- but he puts a finger to her lips. She hesitates... looks at him questioningly. But she doesn't protest as his fingers move toward her bra...</context>
      <utterance>He never showed up.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She straightens up. Her heart skips a beat.</context>
      <utterance>You're wrong. I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She covers her mouth. Her eyes mist over with tears. She runs her fingers over his face with loving amazement. Like a blind person trying to recognize a familiar face. Her mind reels... Then their lips meet. They kiss. And kiss. Like drinking from a fresh spring in the desert. Finally she pulls away and looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>It's me. I'm here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares into his eyes for a beat. Finally looking at her without a trace of deception. She believes. They hear voices on the stairs below. Frank holds up a finger to her-- wait. Frank crawls across the room and presses a hidden latch on a built-in bookshelf. It swings out of the way to reveal a hidden safe built into the floor. Frank removes the fitted floor boards. There is a sophisticated BIO-METRIC LOCK -- just like the one at the gate in the beginning of the movie.</context>
      <utterance>You said I'd told so many lies, you wouldn't believe me even if I did tell the truth... This was the only way to convince you.  The truth is that I love you. All that matters is that you believe me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She blows right past him. Ackerman calls out after her.</context>
      <utterance>Cara... I want the paramedics to make sure you're all right--</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ackerman looks down for a moment, ashamed.</context>
      <utterance>Cara... She pauses. Turns to face him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry... I... we'll talk about this later.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks past him. For a moment Ackerman and Frank look at one another.</context>
      <utterance>No we won't. There's nothing to talk about. I don't work for you anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at Frank with a measure of begrudging respect.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Taylor... you're free to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems I underestimated you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It seems you did, Mr. Ackerman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jones looks on eagerly as numbers fill the screen.</context>
      <utterance>He was here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Account numbers... access codes... unless I'm mistaken... he left the money behind.</utterance>
   <speaker>JEAN LUC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A mistake perhaps?</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Goyal scans down to a total...</context>
      <utterance>How much is there?</utterance>
   <speaker>GOYAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like 744 million.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds out her hand to the TECH who has just removed the FLASH DRIVE.</context>
      <utterance>That's no mistake...  That's his tax bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She slips it into her pocket, then turns to Ackerman.</context>
      <utterance>I'll take that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ackerman's shoulders are slumped, staring at Demidov's dead body on the ground. Jones puts a hand on his back, consoling him.</context>
      <utterance>Well John... with the funds recovered, I don't think there's going to be any appetite from our side to continue this investigation.</utterance>
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Then Ackerman turns... a big smile on his face.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry you didn't get your man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh but I did get my man, Ms. Jones. She realizes; he was after Demidov all along. Ackerman nods to Goyal, a twinkle in his eye.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Quinn is taken completely off guard. Before he can move, Goyal and another agent have placed him in handcuffs.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Goyal, you may place Mr. Quinn under arrest now.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He turns to Jones with a smile.</context>
      <utterance>What? You thought I didn't know? You were unwittingly quite helpful; without you Mr. Demidov might have escaped justice.</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Ackerman walks over to the window as Quinn is led away. ACKERMAN'S POV - Cara and Frank walk toward the canal in the street below. A WATER TAXI approaches.</context>
      <utterance>After all, Demidov wasn't a target of this investigation, was he?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>understand... how did Pearce manage to get here and open that safe without anybody noticing? And where did he go? Ackerman stands at the window with his hands behind his back. For the briefest of moments, Frank looks back up at him and their eyes connect. Frank gives him a little smile. Cara takes his arm to climb onto the boat. CLOSE ON ACKERMAN: his eyes narrow. He knows. For a moment he doesn't move. Then, in spite of himself, a small smile creeps over his face too.</context>
      <utterance>There's something I don't</utterance>
   <speaker>ACKERMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because Pearce was cleverer than all of us.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>THE ENGLISHMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>$20 million dollars worth of surgery and that's the face you chose?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They embrace warmly. Cara is in disbelief, realizing just how completely Frank/Alexander has planned things out. She casts one last glance backwards.</context>
      <utterance>It's good to see you too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really think they'll just give up?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Americans have their money. I left it all for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>CARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Demidov's money?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You have to save something for your pension. The Englishman opens the door to the cabin for them. A bottle of Crystal Champagne and two glasses are set out for them. Frank leads Cara in and offers her a glass. Instead, she slips into his arms and presses against him. They begin to kiss... CAMERA STAYS discreetly behind as they pull away from us, the water taxi swinging out into the Grand Canal. As it recedes from view, the vaporetto's tail lamps shimmer and blend into the beautiful lights of Venice... a city for lovers.</context>
      <utterance>Well...</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
