<movie id="574" title="Truman Show The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truman! Truman!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing's there. It's the same as this.  Come down,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gimme a copy of "The Sydney Morning Herald".</utterance>
   <speaker>VENDOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We ran out.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Truman hurries away, the Vendor picks up the copy of Cosmo and instantly turns to the torn page. It is a Lancome advertisement with ISABELLA ROSSELLINI's nose missing. Truman is still in view but the Vendor makes no effort to confront him, almost as if he were expecting it. Passing one of the tall, black mirrored buildings that grow out of the pavement, Truman glimpses himself in the reflective glass. He doesn't like what he sees and attempts to suck in his gut, but quickly concedes defeat. The image triggers another childhood memory.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks anyway.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DOUGLAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna be a chiropractor like my dad.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell the class what a chiropractor does, Douglas.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOUGLAS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He helps people by fixing their backs, Sister Olivia.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CLASS titters. Douglas sits down, pleased with himself, throwing a smirk to Truman.</context>
      <utterance>That's right, Douglas.  Perhaps I'll be your first patient.</utterance>
   <speaker>SISTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman rises to his feet.</context>
      <utterance>What about you, Truman?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want to be an explorer  ...like</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...okay, okay, let's call it what it is... I'm not gonna lie to you...life insurance is</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The person on the other end has hung up. With an apathetic shrug, Truman replaces the receiver. He looks over his shoulder and places another call.</context>
      <utterance>...just think about what I've been saying and lemme...hello?...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you connect me with directory inquiries in Sydney, Australia?  ...er, yes. Do you have a listing for a Lauren Powers...  ...nothing listed?...what about a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TYRONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it goin', Truman?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad. I just won the State Lottery.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TYRONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrone holds up a front page of the New York Post that features a photograph of a scaled-down replica of Columbus' Santa Maria, moored in front of the Manhattan skyline. Truman's eyes widen at the photograph.</context>
      <utterance>Hold on, Truman. I got somethin' to show ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The flagship of Christoforo...our Genoese navigator, huh? I know you love this like me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tyrone tries not to let his disappointment show as Truman pays the Cashier and exits.</context>
      <utterance>Not me. You got the wrong man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TYRONE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See ya tomorrow, Truman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up. After a moment the phone rings again.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?...I'm sorry, I got more than enough insurance.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman turns pale.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Burbank, I got a bridge-buyer in Stapleton I need you to cloes by four.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stapleton on Staten Island?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know another one?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't do it.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A half hour across the bay. Sea air. Do you good.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I...  ...I got an appointment uptown.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're upping our quota. You need this. Lawrence exits the cubicle. Truman's head drops. He picks up the framed picture of his wife from his desk. MERYL, early thirties, a petite woman easy to mistake for frail. He deposits the photo in his briefcase and departs.</context>
      <utterance>This is a sure thing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go further, daddy! Let's go further!</utterance>
   <speaker>FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's getting late, Truman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COMMUTER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe he's taking the long way.</utterance>
   <speaker>COMMUTER 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'll never make it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here to see a Mr Hamilton.</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCIERGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You from the insurance company? You missed him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When will he be back?</utterance>
   <speaker>CONCIERGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Vacation. Two months. He waited as long as he could. You was supposed to be here by four. A clock on the wall reads 4.l2pm.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>YOUTH 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His companion smirks.</context>
      <utterance>You wanna read to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy returns the book to the woman, but before doing so rips out the last page from the novel and stuffs it in his shirt pocket.</context>
      <utterance>Please...</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUTH 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The train pulls into a deserted station. Feeling vulnerable, the woman jumps up from her seat and exits. The youths, sensing a chase, also exit. Scanning the empty platform, the woman realizes she has made a serious error. Truman watches through the train's open door as the boys corner the frightened woman but still he remains in his seat.</context>
      <utterance>Now you're gonna have to ask me how it ends.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUTH 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One of the youths produces a knife from his pocket and waves it in the woman's face.</context>
      <utterance>We're gonna tell you how it ends, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUTH 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boys pin the woman to the station wall with the weight of their bodies. The woman looks again in Truman's direction. Again she makes eye contact, eyes pleading.</context>
      <utterance>Don't you wanna know how it ends?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The threesome walk along the platform together, as if lifelong friends.</context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He did nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUTH 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Physical violence paralyzes him. Always has.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking over Truman's shoulder, she notices a small uncut patch of grass, missed by Truman in one of his passes.</context>
      <utterance>I got it free with the tune-up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meryl enters the house. Truman restarts the lawnmower and obediantly pushes it towards the offending patch of lawn. As the mower brushes up against the unconforming blades of grass, Truman pulls back abruptly. He checks the kitchen window for Meryl and wheels the mower away, leaving the patch uncut.</context>
      <utterance>You missed a section.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do they hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman picks up Meryl's newspaper and skims idly through it. He notes an article headlined, "SLAYING TRIAL ENTERS SIXTH WEEK".</context>
      <utterance>I was afraid I'd seize up during cross. One of the keys kept sticking.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he gonna take the stand?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No point. Two eye witnesses saw him near the dumpster where they found the legs. She flexes her arthritic wrists.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna eat before you leave?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get something out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman turns to her too sharply, his guilt showing.</context>
      <utterance>Did something happen today?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What could happen?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ouch. Whose nuts were those?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlon tees up a ball of his own. initialed with the letter "M".</context>
      <utterance>Mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta get out, Marlon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah? Outta what?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Outta my job, outta Queens...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't mean anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman gulps his beer as he prepares his answer.</context>
      <utterance>Sure and go where?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See here, this is Queens.  All the way round here, Australia. You can't get any further away before you start coming back.  Y'know, there're still places in Australia where no human being has ever set foot.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So when are you leaving?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlon nods even though the concept of taking flight is beyond his imagination.</context>
      <utterance>It's not that simple. Takes money, planning. You can't just up and go.  Oh, I'm gonna do it, don't worry about that. I just gotta move slow. Pick a moment. Bonus time's just around the corner. Soon as I get a retaining wall built on the back of the house I can start thinking about selling up...and I'll be gone. Up and away on that big steel bird.  I'm going, don't you worry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An awkward moment. Truman, once again, not so sure of himself. He masks his doubt by teeing up another ball.</context>
      <utterance>I never knew anybody who got out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlon looks sideways at Truman. It sounds to him like the beer talking.</context>
      <utterance>Tick-fucking-tock. That's the fucking problem, Marlon. I'm thirty-four. I'm older than Jesus Christ.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do the dreams go, Marlon?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You win.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really think it could've dropped off an airliner?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. It's halogen. You oughta report it.  You coming for a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't tonight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing? Come to bed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I figure we could scrape together eight thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh. God, everytime you and Marlon--</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--We could bum around the world for a year on that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then what, Truman? We'd be back to where we were five years ago. You're talking like a teenager.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe I</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We said we'd try for a baby. Isn't that enough of an adventure?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meryl gives a derisive laugh.</context>
      <utterance>That can wait. I want to get away. See some of the world. Explore.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to be an explorer? You mean like all the other great explorers from Queens? You don't even have a passport, Truman. I bet you don't even know how to get one. The words sting. Truman turns away. Seeing the pain she's caused, she changes tack.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This'll pass. Everybody thinks like this now and then.  Come to bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GUARD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How can they have a child?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not gonna be his, you idiot.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUARD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think she'd go through with it?  Guess I always thought they'd adopt.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It left him with more than his obvious fear of the water. It's as if he felt his father had gone beyond his limitations and he vowed never to repeat the mistake. He was never the same curious little boy again.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're all born with a pound of cocaine up our nose. By the time we're eleven it runs out.</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD WOMAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Half the people I knew named their babies after him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly a distinguished OLD WOMAN walking a small dog and a YOUNG MALE BUSINESS EXECUTIVE carrying a briefcase, walking in opposite directions along the sidewalk, grab the Homeless Man, one taking each arm. A bus suddenly screeches to a halt beside the struggling group, doors already open, and before Truman can react, the Old Woman and the Young Executive force the Homeless Man onto the bus. Truman lurches after them, but he is met by the bus doors, closing sharply in his face.</context>
      <utterance>Daddy...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman thumps against the doors, but the BUS DRIVER ignores his cries and the bus roars away from the curb. He starts to run after the bus, colliding with several PEDESTRIANS who make no attempt to avoid him. Stepping blindly into the street, he tries to hail a taxi. A vacant cab suddenly switches off its "FOR HIRE" light as he reaches it. Truman pleads with the TAXI DRIVER through the closed windows and locked doors of the cab but the driver is apparently oblivious to Truman's shouts. Frantic, Truman, dashes into a nearby parking structure and grabs a bunch of car keys from the key rack of the unsupervised parking attendant's kiosk. Running along the rows of parked cars, Truman desperately presses the car security buttons attached to the key rings A car alarm chirps and Truman turns in time to see the car's winking sidelights. He jumps inside a brand new BMW and guns the car. The PARKING ATTENDANT, alerted by the squealing tires, appears from the Men's Room and attempts to wave Truman down.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, stop! Stop!!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman ignores the attendant and accelerates into the street without looking, causing a taxi and a postal van to take evasive action. Catching sight of the bus in the distance, Truman leans on the car's horn as he recklessly weaves past other motorists. He is only a couple of car-lengths from the bus.</context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the taxis and cars directly in front of him start to slow for no apparent reason. Truman looks for a way around but the cars crab across the street, blocking any passage, working together almost as if they are running interference.</context>
      <utterance>Two, four, oh, six.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman suddenly jumps the sidewalk in the car, scattering</context>
      <utterance>Outta the way! Outta the way! The bus is escaping.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck are you trying to pull?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No harm done!</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry! I'm sorry! No harm done!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Attendant looks into Truman's terrified eyes. They get the better of him.</context>
      <utterance>I oughta fuck you up!</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Attendant shoves Truman's briefcase into his arms and brushes him aside. As he departs, Truman notices that the traffic jam in the street and the mysterious crowd of pedestrians has dissolved.</context>
      <utterance>Get the fuck outta here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing?  The man told you there's no such bus.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlon stops walking. Truman continues his inspection. Seeing there is no reasoning with him, Marlon hurries to catch him up.</context>
      <utterance>He's lying. Two, four, oh, six was definitely the number.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never believed he was dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C'mon, Truman, a lotta times they don't find a body. You know what the currents are like in that water.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You had to see his face when that wave hit. He wasn't scared Marion. It was like he was expecting it, waiting for it. He knew it was coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would he fake it?  He's not Elvis Presley.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I imagined it, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman is surprised Marlon remembered. Marlon nods to the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>I think you're missing your dad.  The anniversary was yesterday, wasn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman looks down at his feet. A small, tell-tale pile of sand has poured out of his tight trouser cuff.</context>
      <utterance>You got sand in your cuffs.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see a flashback in Truman's head of the earlier scene in the Lower Manhattan street. It confirms that the old woman's DOG was abandoned on the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe you're right. If only the old woman hadn't left her dog behind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RAQUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you dare go in. Truman. I just got her off to sleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raquel fixes Truman with a contemptuous stare.</context>
      <utterance>It was Dad. I swear.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAQUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, the next time he shows up. bring him over. Until then, I'm not saying a word about this to Mom and neither are you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it wasn't him, it was his twin. Can you think of a reason he'd want to hide from us?</utterance>
   <speaker>RACQUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know a reason he'd want to hide from</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm telling you he's alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You did well.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof nods indifferently, knowing the damage is already done.</context>
      <utterance>We've tightened security.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would he do this to us?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Old age. Sentiment. You play someone's father all those years, you</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YOUNG CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>To simulate the wave, one of the divers puts his full weight on the side of the dinghy to capsize it. Kirk and the boy are tossed into the water. While the boy immediately bobs to the surface in his life jacket, Kirk fails to surface. After a long moment, he reappears with the second diver some distance away. now wearing a spare aqualung.</context>
      <utterance>The freak wave will strike from the starboard side. Remember, you don't go to the diver. The diver goes to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>YOUNG CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kirk is staring at Truman's stand-in, clinging to the upturned boat. Kirk's expression suggests he is not a totally willing participant in the masquerade. The present-day Christof freezes the monitor on Kirk's uncertain face.</context>
      <utterance>...Good! Good!...of course, on the day you only surface once you're safely beyond the cove...Try it one more time...You okay?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're you doing out here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meryl doesn't look like she buys it.</context>
      <utterance>Fixing the mower.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw my father on State Street dressed as a homeless man.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I made macaroni.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meryl nods, not at all convinced. After an uncomfortable pause, she turns and heads back to the house.</context>
      <utterance>I gotta go out. About a replacement...  ...mower blade.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman passes her the brown paper bag without reply. Veronica removes a bottle of perfume and proceeds to liberally apply it.</context>
      <utterance>Bout time you got this thing cleaned.  Don't tell me you bin makin' your old lady wear it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's the Sell-By Date?</context>
      <utterance>God, do they still make this stuff?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A SEVENTEEN-YEAR-OLD TRUMAN, carrying a stack of books, spies LAUREN, sixteen going on thirty-five, wearing the lavender, beaded cardigan at her open locker. She is entertaining two GIRLFRIENDS with what appears to be a lewd tale.</context>
      <utterance>He's re-created the event on and off for a number of years. We've never understood what prompts him to indulge the fantasy, or for that matter what inspired such a painfully shy boy to approach her in the first place...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Truman, obviously terrified, musters the nerve to approach the lockers. The three girls look up, surprised by the interruption.</context>
      <utterance>We'd noticed them making eyes at each other for some weeks but never thought he'd say anything. She was a year older, wrote poetry, way out of his league...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIRLFRIEND 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lauren is unsure whether or not to follow her friends.</context>
      <utterance>See you in class.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her name is carefully written in blue ink on the covers of her text books.</context>
      <utterance>Lauren, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look. I was wonder--</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--I can't go out with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I haven't asked you yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well when you do, that's my answer.  I'm sorry. It's not up to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lauren smiles despite herself.</context>
      <utterance>Why, you married?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not asking you to have my children, just a pizza. How about Saturday?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lauren looks around the deserted school corridor.</context>
      <utterance>Friday?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Truman and Lauren run up to the ledge of the pool surrounding the steel sculpture.</context>
      <utterance>We knew we were taking a risk. She hadn't been properly coached, but we were torn... He'd summoned the courage to make the approach...We wanted to reward that. Of course she took full advantage...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They both stare down at the inviting water. Lauren suddenly throws off her cardigan and jumps into the pool without another thought. She comes splashing to the surface. Truman stares down, transfixed hy the shimmering water.</context>
      <utterance>I never knew this place existed.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on! Come on! It's wonderful!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lauren suddenly stops splashing.</context>
      <utterance>I...I can't.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She quickly climbs out of the pool, dripping wet.</context>
      <utterance>That's right. Oh, God, I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lauren wrings out her dress.</context>
      <utterance>Why? You've got nothing to be sorry about. Has someone been talking to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Lauren starts walking away.</context>
      <utterance>Get me out of here. I don't want to be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAUREN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name's not Lauren! It's</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="17">
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a minute someone's going to come and stop me talking to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who? There's no one around.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And you sat down.</context>
      <utterance>You remember when you were a little boy, you stood up in class and said you wanted to be an explorer like Magellan. And your teacher, Sister Olivia said, "You're too late, Truman. There's nothing left to explore." And all the other kids laughed.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know about that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter. You've forgotten about that boy, Truman. You got scared. Just because something happens, doesn't mean you can't take another chance in your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There isn't much time. Just listen. Everybody's pretending Truman. Everybody but</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everywhere,</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey!</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman jumps up.</context>
      <utterance>Get in the car, Lauren!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Does he look anything like me?!</context>
      <utterance>No he's not! He's just saying that!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man backhands Sylvia roughly across the face and bundles her into his car. Truman rushes at the man.</context>
      <utterance>Shut your mouth!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The man easily fends Truman off, knocking him to the ground. He slams shut the passenger door of the Plymouth.</context>
      <utterance>Leave her alone!</utterance>
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't listen to him, Truman. Make yourself deaf. Come find me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Plymouth roars away. Truman stares after it and then turns back to the cardigan left on the ground.</context>
      <utterance>Don't bother! We're moving to Australia. New York's done something to her head.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did he say Australia? Why couldn't he have said New Jersey?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want me to do it again? I think I could do it better.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman picks up the cardigan. They return to the car.</context>
      <utterance>No...thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Veronica, what do you know for sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(taking a long drag on her cigarette as she gives the question due consideration) The nuns at my school, they used to say, "The whole of life is faith." Truman regards his companion in a new light. He comes to a stop at the corner where he picked her up.</context>
      <utterance>For sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>VERONICA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When he decided to go after Sylvia, we were forced to intervene once again...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got something to tell you, Sis.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAQUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've got something to tell you too.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to Australia.</utterance>
   <speaker>RAQUEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman's face falls. As he enters the bedroom where his ill MOTHER lies gazing at the ceiling, we focus on his EXCHANGE STUDENT APPLICATION that he has inadvertently crushed in his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Mom's real sick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I help?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have an appointment at, er...Diamond Enterprises.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The second Security Guard is rising from his seat to block Truman's path to the elevators but Truman reads his mind and makes a dash for it. He slips into an elevator just as the doors are closing, defeating the flailing arm of the pursuing guard. A WOMAN EXECUTIVE in the elevator looks in horror at Truman. The cause of her concern becomes all too apparent. Looking beyond the woman, Truman discovers that there is no back to the elevator car. The elevator is simply an opening into the body of the building. Truman pushes past the Woman to be confronted with the fact that the entire office block is nothing but a giant, empty shell with no floors above the ground floor. The PEOPLE Truman has just witnessed entering the other elevators are milling around a refreshment table, sitting on folding chairs, changing their clothes behind temporary curtained cubicles or lining up to re-enter the bogus elevator cars. Gradually, they all turn to gape at Truman, who in turn stares back, appalled. The Security Guards suddenly appear at Truman's side and take him by the arm.</context>
      <utterance>They went bust.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gotta leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're they doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guards frog-march Truman out of the huge facade towards an Emergency Exit.</context>
      <utterance>You gotta leave.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just tell me what the hell's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're re-modelling.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like fuck! What're they doing?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't tell me, I'll get you investigated!</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD 2</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman sees there is no point in arguing further. His shouts are attracting the interest of PASSERS-BY. A thought occurs to him. He starts to run along the street, suddenly entering another building at random. An office block with a bank on the ground floor. As he skirts the bank, he feels the eyes of the BANK STAFF and CUSTOMERS on him. Is he so suspicious-looking or were they expecting him? Truman rushes to the elevators. The lights above the doors show all the elevators on upper floors. Frantic pressing of the elevator button gets no response. Truman heads for the stairs but is intercepted by a BANK OFFICIAL who bars his way.</context>
      <utterance>Investigate what? You're trespassing!</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICIAL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't--</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman backs away out of the office and continues to run down the streets of Lower Manhattan's financial district. Every building he encounters seems to have a SECURITY GUARD anticipating his arrival or a building OFFICIAL hanging a CLOSED FOR BUSINESS sign on the front door. He feels the eyes of PEDESTRIANS. Is he simply drawing attention to himself by his behavior? Truman wheels around, trying to make eye contact with passers-by. They shy away. Truman stops still, his head reeling.</context>
      <utterance>--I know.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever been into the AMT Building?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not since they begun reconstruction.  What're you doing with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to visit a site.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What for?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I never do.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why we got adjusters.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got a problem with me going?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a problem with you not doing your job, Burbank. You already screwed up once this week.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman exits with the report. After waiting only a matter of seconds for an elevator, he impatiently enters the stairwell. As soon as he disappears from sight, a grim CHRISTOF emerges from a nearby office, shadowed as always by CHLOE. They approach Lawrence with the familiarity of business associates.</context>
      <utterance>Let me worry about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof nods. Chloe opens a flip-phone to make a call.</context>
      <utterance>680 West 89th.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When was the fire?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Week ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How come it's still smoking?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Started up again.  Kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Says here it burnt to the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy is wise well beyond his years. Truman fixes him with a glare.</context>
      <utterance>Wishful thinking maybe?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Someone send you to tell me all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The boy casually rides away.</context>
      <utterance>You the one askin' questions.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Small world.</utterance>
   <speaker>JOGGER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman blocks the man a second time.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An almost subliminal flashback appears in Truman's head confirming that the JOGGER and the HOMELESS MAN in the wheelchair two days earlier are one and the same.</context>
      <utterance>You don't remember? Two days ago I gave you my meatball sandwich in the park. You were in a wheelchair. Same sneakers.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Marlon. I've gotta talk to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truman! Sorry, I'm up against it today.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Something to do with my Dad. I think.</context>
      <utterance>I've fallen over something, Marlon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you okay? You look like shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's big, Marlon. You wouldn't believe who's in on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In on</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something's definitely in the air. My last delivery, a kid got crushed to death. tilting a vending machine. They won't even let me take the rest of the day off.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlon scoffs at the suggestion then realizes Truman isn't joking.</context>
      <utterance>Do it, anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm deadly serious. Marlon. We can't talk here. I'm being followed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>some friends here, they owe me. We can lean back. (pointing out a taxi parked outside the yard) Is he one of them?</context>
      <utterance>Is someone leanin' on you, Tru? Cos I got</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Could be. One thing's certain. The key is spontoneity. Be unpredictable. They can't stand that. That's why we've got to get outta here. Can you come with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where're we going?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The beach.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You remember, Moses, it used to end right there, before the expansion.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christof, the cracks are starting to show.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll paper over them.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truman's had bouts of paranoia before and recovered.</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Becoming</context>
      <utterance>No, not like this. It's compromised.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know why they're so nervous. The birth of Truman's child is going to double revenue. For God's sake don't let him upstage you.  You've been grooming a successor.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's not ready.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What're we doing here, Truman?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is where it started.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There were a hundred people on the beach that day. Everybody knew what was going on except me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to put you down but why would anybody go to all this trouble over you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A couple of years ago, I tried to get hold of a copy of Time Magazine. The week before an ad said, "Next Week: Truman Burbank and the Lost Generation". Marlon shrugs, unimpressed.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I've been mistaken for somebody else.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlon remains unconvinced.</context>
      <utterance>A guy with the same name as me in Time Magazine. It ain't a common name so I looked out for it. But the day it came out, every newstand was sold out. No library had it. I even wrote off for a back-issue. Never seen a copy to this day.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlon looks skeptically at Truman. He hasn't had that feeling.</context>
      <utterance>Maybe I'm being set up for something. You ever feel like that, Marlon? Like your whole life has been building to something?</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A coincidence. Haven't you ever heard of a coincidence?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a walking coincidence. I can't count 'em. No something's happening, Marlon. I've got to get to the bottom of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All I got on me is the takings from the machines. Why do you need it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going away for a while.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The program cuts to a commercial break. The commercial is for "Global Travel".</context>
      <utterance>We could do it right here, like we used to.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lemme go to the bathroom.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman exits the living room. However, on his way to the bathroom he hesitates at the kitchen table. He surreptitiously lifts the platic-coated plaid tablecloth to reveal numerous bills laid out flat beneath it to keep the stash hidden.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be too long.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened overnight?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He couldn't do it, even on the sofa.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, that thing of his must be psychic.  He didn't masturbate?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chloe exits and Christof climbs out of bed.</context>
      <utterance>Not for the last two inonths.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you gonna be late?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a call in the area.  What's the case? Anything interesting?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman's eyes widen. We see a quick flashback in Truman's head of the two YOUTHS assaulting the WOMAN on his train.</context>
      <utterance>Rape on the subway.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meryl gives him an affectionate kiss and exits the back door. Truman waits for the sound of Meryl's car to disappear down the road and exits himself.</context>
      <utterance>They're guilty as hell but they'll walk. No witnesses. Her word against theirs.  Maybe we could meet for lunch today.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You a witness?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Er, yes...  No, no I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>SECURITY GUARD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before the guard can move him on. Truman sneaks a look at proceedings through the courtroom door window. He recognizes the two YOUTHS sitting at the defendent's table. A PROSECUTOR is on his feet, addressing the JURY. MERYL is working attentively at her stenotype machine, her fingers rapidly pressing the keys. However, Truman notices a glaring omission. There is no paper emerging from Meryl's machine. The roll of paper tape sits on the floor beside her chair leg.</context>
      <utterance>Closed session.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wanna book a flight to Australia.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where exactly?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You are a</context>
      <utterance>You sure you're not trying to keep me here?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why wouldn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you were in a hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman pulls out a wad of money from his pocket and several rolls of quarters from Marlon's vending machines. The agent looks askance at the pile of cash.</context>
      <utterance>You want to book the flight?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The travel agent ignores the question and prints the ticket.</context>
      <utterance>You were expecting me, weren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's non-refundable.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>PROD. MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof gives a grudgingly complimentary nod.</context>
      <utterance>Happy?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we contain him long enough?</utterance>
   <speaker>PROD. MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof looks skyward at the cottonwool clouds above the harbor.</context>
      <utterance>I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>PROD. MANAGER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof gives another grudging nod of approval. The Production Manager is beckoned by a group of CONSTRUCTION WORKERS who are putting the finishing touches to a corner of the Opera House. CHLOE drifts to Christof's side, a Watchman TV in her hand.</context>
      <utterance>He flies at night. Thick cloud cover to disorient him. Hopefully we'll knock him out with complimentary cocktails, pull the shades down during the movies. He'll never know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof glances at the TV screen in her hand, showing TRUMAN sitting in his office gazing at his composite picture of SYLVIA.</context>
      <utterance>Why go to all the trouble?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He believes she has the answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not just tell him she's dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>him. He's going to have to find out for himself. See it with his own eyes. Right now he needs something genuine. (rueful, all too aware of the contradiction) Even if we have to fake it.</context>
      <utterance>It's too late for that. That won't satisfy</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Noting two colleagues exchanging a look, he pulls the computer off the desk to get their attention. It lands on the floor with an expensive crash.</context>
      <utterance>Why're you all pretending? Huh?  What is this a front for? Why aren't I in on the joke? Was I away that day?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm talking to you! Who am I?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see Truman's manic face from the sprinkler head's POV. Truman stomps off down the corridor, other Insurance Agents giving him a wide berth. He shoves computers, desk lamps and pot holders off desks as he goes.</context>
      <utterance>You don't believe a single word you're saying!  None of you do!  You hear me?!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CHLOE's attention is focused on a subsidiary monitor displaying a freeze frame of TRUMAN reading the dictionary a few minutes earlier.</context>
      <utterance>...and back to the close-up...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think he sees the entry?</utterance>
   <speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hard to tell.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't we ask him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof turns his back on the screen and stares out the window. We focus on an enhanced picture of the dictionary's text. genuinely, etc. 2. in fact; really.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know how it got there!  Enhance.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The young mother, frozen with fright, does not reply.</context>
      <utterance>Say my name or I'll smash its head open.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say my</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Say my name! You</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What's my</context>
      <utterance>I mean it! I'm ready to do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...is...my...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meryl doesn't wish to participate in the game and makes for the house. Truman holds her arm, forcing her to watch. He turns to check his prediction. A convoy of cars approaches.</context>
      <utterance>I predict the next four cars will be a white Honda Civic, a blue and white Dodge Dart with the front hubcap missing, a Volkswagon Beetle with a dented fender and a motorcycle.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meryl's attention wavers. Truman tightens his grip.</context>
      <utterance>There's the Honda...the Dodge...here comes the dented Beetle...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Following the VW is a school bus.</context>
      <utterance>Look, damn you!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman is momentarily disappointed. Meryl seizes her chance and heads for the house. Truman follows her inside.</context>
      <utterance>Where's the motorcycle?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maybe you</context>
      <utterance>Don't you want to know how I did that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where have you been? I've been calling you all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been concerned, Meryl? Nice name. "Meryl". I always liked it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nice of you to say so after eight years.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actress's name, isn't it? What's your</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a break. Meryl  I</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drop it, I said. It's over.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...we need more charcoal.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shut up!</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna take a shower.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. We're going for a drive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Despite her protests, Truman drags Meryl out the back door and towards his car.</context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For years I've been saying I want to go some place, well now I'm ready to go. Let's just jump in the car and go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought maybe, Atlantic City.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hate gambling.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right. I do, don't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why do you wanna go?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cos I never have. That's why you go places, isn't it? Cos you're curious. I haven't been curious since I was seven years old, y'know that? Back then you'd have to nail me to the floor to keep me in one place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long to take Atlantic City out of mothballs?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We could be up and running...three hours maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a number five gridlock on the Jersey Turnpike.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the side of the road, TWO MOTORISTS, are arguing over a minor collision.</context>
      <utterance>So much traffic, this time of day. Does that strike you as peculiar?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at them. You believe they're fighting? I don't believe it.  Why don't you</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You blaming</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman suddenly veers the Oldsmobile onto the sidewalk.</context>
      <utterance>That's true. We could be stuck here for hours. Could be like this all the way to Atlantic City.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman rejoins the New Jersey Turnpike, heading back towards Queens, the roadway now relatively free of traffic.</context>
      <utterance>You're right. Let's go back. I'm sorry. I don't know what got into me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman floors the Oldsmobile. The car flies past the exit for Route 276. He continues along the Jersey Turnpike.</context>
      <utterance>Would you please slow down, Truman?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truman, that was the turnoff!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've changed my mind again. What's Maine like this time of year?! I've never been to Maine.  Or let's just see where the road takes us.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think I'd like a little company.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Keep them together.</context>
      <utterance>What the hell is wrong with the "carousel"?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're rusty. We can't keep up.  We don't know where he's going any more.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oncoming is very thin.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's so close! It's tantilizing!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You want to pull him over?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We don't want him to panic.</context>
      <utterance>No police. Not yet. We shadow him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's trying to outrun the traffic.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's trying to outrun the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's hard to go places, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's been an accident, Truman. We have to go back.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. There's no accident. It'S just more stalling. Truman slows beside a POLICE OFFICER.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there any way around?</utterance>
   <speaker>OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman falls in line behind the cars making a U-turn when, all of a sudden, he guns his car and swerves past the barricade.</context>
      <utterance>The whole area's being evacuated. A precaution.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he see it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The reason for Christof's concern becomes all too apparent as the helicopter passes over the power plant, where the struggling TRUMAN is being escorted away. We see an aerial shot from the helicopter as it emerges directly above the Sydney skyline.</context>
      <utterance>I don't think so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me get you some help, Truman. You're not well.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You can't stand me.</context>
      <utterance>Why do you want to have a child with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not true.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman's raised voice backs Meryl to her feet. Truman follows, getting in her face.</context>
      <utterance>Don't lie to me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, you're scaring</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get somebody in there!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof, never taking his eyes from the monitor, leans into the microphone.</context>
      <utterance>She's in trouble! We've got to help her!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's bluffing. Call his bluff.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman raises the kitchen knife but instead of stabbing Meryl begins to slash viciously at the waterbed, opening a large gash.</context>
      <utterance>How could you buy this damn thing when you know he drowned in front of me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman drops the knife and forces Meryl's head into the gaping hole in the bed, submerging her head in the tepid water. She thrashes her arms wildly trying to free herself. Truman reluctantly jerks her head back out of the water.</context>
      <utterance>You have any idea what it's like to drown?</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truman, stop it!  Don't let him do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At knifepoint, Truman marches Meryl down the hallway to the front door. The doorbell chimes a second and third time, more insistently.</context>
      <utterance>Damn!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay where you are or I'll kill her!</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Truman flinches. He was so convinced it would be the police. He takes a step back against the hallway wall. Before he can decide what to do, Marlon has opened the unlocked front door to be confronted with the sight of Truman holding the knife to Meryl's throat, blood streaming from his own wound. Marlon locks eyes on Truman. Sizing up the situation, he slowly but decisively removes the knife from Truman's hand. Meryl wrenches herself free from Truman's now limp grasp, and collapses into Marlon's arms, sobbing.</context>
      <utterance>Truman? It's me, Marlon.</utterance>
   <speaker>MERYL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were going to let him kill me!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>People know who I am, my every move, complete strangers know my name. Even when there's no one around, I feel the eyes on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman closes his eyes as he takes in the explanation.</context>
      <utterance>I was in the bank today. The Federal on Lewis. A clerk was talking about somebody named Truman messing with her baby. Is that the stranger you're talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No. I've never seen her before.  I know you already think I'm going out of my mind but I genuinely believe the world revolves around me somehow. Everybody seems to be in on it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>you'd made something more of yourself? Christ, Truman, who hasn't sat on the John and had an imaginary interview with Barbara Walters? Who hasn't wanted to be somebody?</context>
      <utterance>It's a lot of world for one man. You sure that's not wishful thinking, you wishing</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's just it. I think I</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlon looks around as if drawing inspiration from somewhere in the night.</context>
      <utterance>Sometimes I think it's in my head, sometimes I think it's for real.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tru, we've known each other since before we could get a hard-on. Truman half-smiles at the ribald remark.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The only way we ever made it through high school was cheating off each other's test papers. Jesus, they were identical. I always liked that, because whatever the answer was, we was</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before we start taking calls, the huge surge in ratings over the last few days, how do you hope to sustain that audience now that Truman appears to have reconciled himself, returned to "normal"?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>imagine we'll lose those voycurs only interested in witnessing Truman's latest torment. However I'm certain our core audience will remain loyal.</context>
      <utterance>Ratings have never been our primary goal. I</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But recent events have been</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've become increasingly frustrated watching actors give us phony emotions, bored with pyrotechnics and special effects. While the world he inhabits is counterfeit, there's nothing fake about Truman himself. No scripts. no cue cards. It's not always Shakespeare but it's genuine. That's how he can support an entire channel.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A window onto the human condition?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I prefer to think of it as a</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We find many viewers leave him on all night for comfort. Haven't you ever watched your child or your lover sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Interviewer presses a blinking illuminated button on his desk's high-tech phone terminal.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go to some of those viewers' calls.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charlotte, North Carolina, for Christof.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE CALLER 1</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're on, caller. Go ahead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE CALLER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Christof, it's a great honor to speak with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MALE CALLER 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truman has never been closer. The way he looked directly at us,</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Working on "Truman" has always been a huge commitment for an actor, not just in terms of separation from friends and family, but since Truman essentially drives the plot, it's a never-ending improvisation. Recent events have raised the pressure but also the prestige.</utterance>
   <speaker>INTERVIEWER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course Truman has always been very much</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FEMALE CALLER 1</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>The Interviewer goes to cut off the call but Christof holds him back.</context>
      <utterance>--He's not a performer. He's a prisoner.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--He can leave at any time. If his was more than just a vague ambition, if he were absolutely determined to discover the truth, there's no way we could prevent him. I think what really distresses you, caller, is that ultimately he</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Chloe tries to conceal her startlement at CHRISTOF's unexpected entrance.</context>
      <utterance>What are you looking for?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was premature, wasn't he?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only by two weeks.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Curious even then? Like he couldn't wait to get started?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His eagerness to leave his mother's womb also meant he was the one selected.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was it like, the first show?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ultimate live television. In competition with five other unwanted pregnancies - the casting of a show determined by an air date - he was the one who arrived on cue.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof stares at his assistant, weighing her loyalty.</context>
      <utterance>Is it true what you said...on the show tonight? About letting him go if he wanted it badly enough. Would you really do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It won't come to that.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope we've got fresh extras.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rotation was made this morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The COUPLE with the stroller are promptly moved further along the street.</context>
      <utterance>I don't like the couple with the baby. They'd never be together.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's doing wardrobe? I keep seeing the same wardrobe...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>At the command, the PEDESTRIANS and VEHICLES begin inoving normally, TRUMAN exits the subway, suspecting nothing. He begins his trek to work, accompanied by the cued rush hour traffic.</context>
      <utterance>...and, action background...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...nice...nice...I like the woman with the dog... let's keep it moving...I want that traffic kept together...everybody look like you've got places to go...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As predicted, Truman walks by, barely glancing at a newspaper's banner headline, "NUCLEAR POWER PLANT REOPENED". Christof scans the shot options available to him on the video wall.</context>
      <utterance>I bet he doesn't stop at the newstand.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The large On-Air Monitor cuts to Truman, via the point-of-view of an approaching PEDESTRIAN. For an instant, the unaware Truman looks directly into the lens of the disguised camera.</context>
      <utterance>...Bodycam Two...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The monitor cuts to an overhead shot from a streetlamp. The camera continues to follow Truman's progress.</context>
      <utterance>...streetlight eight...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TRUMAN enters his office building as a taxi cruises by.</context>
      <utterance>...ready, Car-Cam One. Go to One...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman is immediately picked up by a hidden camera inside the building where he exchanges a half-hearted greeting with an ancient SECURITY GUARD.</context>
      <utterance>...and cut to interior...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The camera widens the angle.</context>
      <utterance>...looser...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks just like Truman's mother at that age. VIVIEN, an insurance adjuster approaches the elevator button at the same time as Truman. However she reaches for it after Truman has already turned his back.</context>
      <utterance>...and action, Vivien...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, she missed her mark!  Why do we bother with walk-throughs if nobody pays attention? Give me a two-shot of Truman and Vivien...go to the master ...hold the elevators...  Vivien, press the elevator button again ...and make sure you catch his eye this time...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The monitor cuts to the inside of the elevator, rapidly filling with co-workers.</context>
      <utterance>Good! Perfect! Cut to the interior...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Just as the doors are about to close, LAWRENCE oozes in. He gives Truman a smug smile.</context>
      <utterance>...and Lawrence...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The elevator doors open and Vivien exits with two co-workers.</context>
      <utterance>...nice look, Lawrence...and, Vivien...</utterance>
   <speaker>LAWRENCE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman doesn't seem to share Lawrence's enthusiasm for the comely young woman. He is miles away.</context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't kick her out of bed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes turn to Meryl. She looks at the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Regrettably, I have to inform you that Hannah has chosen not to renew her contract.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Meryl receives a sympathetic squeeze of the hand from her co- star Marlon, now out of wardrobe, wearing an Armani suit.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure we can all respect her reasons.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The rest of the cast nod politely in Vivien's direction.</context>
      <utterance>Her separation from Truman will be orchestrated over the summer.  However, I'm pleased to announce that television's first on-air conception will still take place. You witnessed the initial contact this morning.  You all know Claudia from her work in theatre. Thankfully, Truman doesn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cast idly flip through the documents, prominently stamped on the cover, "NOT TO BE TAKEN ON SET".</context>
      <utterance>This is a copy of Claudia's back story. Her character's name will be Vivien. She's the new adjuster at the office.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We intend to entice Truman into the affair as soon as possible. Claudia will make her advance at the seminar Truman's attending next week. Details are in your schedules. I'm sure you'll all make Claudia welcome.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Question is, will</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happens when Truman and the baby are both on camera together?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There will simply be duplicate coverage.</utterance>
   <speaker>VIVIEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's just hope we don't have twins.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cast turn in her direction. Christof has a second occasion to question his Assistant's loyalty.</context>
      <utterance>When Truman dies do we go back to the single channel?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he doing in</utterance>
   <speaker>WAITRESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's with the coat?</utterance>
   <speaker>PATRON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman tries to right the display and hurriedly exits the store, the cameras following his journey as always.</context>
      <utterance>Nervous.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh God, he never bought nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give him a break. It's taken him thirty- four years to get the nerve to go in there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Operator, eating a doughnut, presses one of the illuminated buttons on the panel and the camera angle changes to a close shot of Truman's covered head. The camera stays on the blanketed head for a long moment.</context>
      <utterance>...Ready two. Go to two.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another button is pressed and the angle changes. A trace of frustration is evident in the control room. Recording a sleeping subject is unrewarding enough without also having to contend with Truman's recently aquired camera-shyness.</context>
      <utterance>And back to the medium.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...and wide...</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That loser pays our salary.</utterance>
   <speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's given up on himself again.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At the far end of the great room, one of the large double doors opens and CHRISTOF enters, as always accompanied by CHLOE, carrying a leather-bound folder. Simeon and the Operators subtely straighten in their chairs. Christof pretends not to notice. He is staring intently at the On-Air monitor.</context>
      <utterance>Who cares? Makes life easier for us. He is what he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When did he start sleeping like that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About the time Meryl left.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that the best shot we can get?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof watches Truman, a trace of concern in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>What's to see?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened to the room?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Apparently satisfied, Christof turns to an operator.</context>
      <utterance>He started to reorganize. I was going to call you. But half-way through, he gave up and fell asleep.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Reading off the notes in Chloe's folder, the operator punches up a batch of camera angles on smaller preview monitors. They show a generic-looking Marriott Hotel, devoid of actors. A banner in reception reads, "WELCOME AMERICAN LIFE &amp; ACCIDENT". The Operator looks to Christof for approval and realizes his producer's attention has wandered. Christof is staring at the sleeping figure of Truman on the On-Air monitor.</context>
      <utterance>I want to check the set-ups for tomorrow's insurance convention.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me a shot from his wedding band.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He took it off.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof picks up a spare headset from the panel and puts it to his ear.</context>
      <utterance>Why is he so still? He's too still.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An operator pushes up an audio fader on the panel. Christof and his colleagues listen to Truman's steady breathing in their headphones. Simeon and the Operators nod, reassured that nothing is amiss. Christof is not so easily convinced.</context>
      <utterance>Isolate the audio in the cans and amplify.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A camera hidden in the room's bedside lamp zooms in to Truman's prone outline...while the breathing remains steady, the body does not rise and fall.</context>
      <utterance>Give me a preview. An ECU on his torso.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chloe picks up a phone connected to the desk and dials.</context>
      <utterance>Phone him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRI STOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone on the bedside table, inches from Truman's head, begins to ring. Truman doesn't flinch.</context>
      <utterance>Wrong number.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chloe promptly cuts the connection and Truman's phone ceases to ring.</context>
      <utterance>Hang up!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get Marlon over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Under what pretext?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof turns his back on the monitors, his mind racing.</context>
      <utterance>Any fucking pretext!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Frustrated, Marlon runs to the bedroom and thumps on the window. He can see the shape of Truman lying on the bed but his shouts fail to rouse him. Marlon picks up one of Meryl's carefully nurtured flower pots from beneath the bedroom window.</context>
      <utterance>Tru!..Tru!..</utterance>
   <speaker>MARLON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Marlon hurls the flower pot through the window sending a shower of glass over Truman's bed. Still he doesn't move. Marlon reaches his hand through the shards of glass clinging to the window frame and unlatches the window.</context>
      <utterance>I'm comin' in, Tru!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simeon hesitates, unsure if has heard correctly. He looks to Christof for confirmation, his finger poised over an "EMERGENCY" button.</context>
      <utterance>Cut transmission.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof lunges forward and presses the button himself.</context>
      <utterance>I said, "Cut"!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simeon types the appropriate command.</context>
      <utterance>There. Freeze...Zoom into the chair...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the blown-up screen, between a cardboard box and a chair leg, it is barely possible to make out Truman's hand as he crawls commando-style from his bedroom, his inflatable replacement already positioned in the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Enhance.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He wasn't making a mess. He was engineering a blind spot.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How does he know where the cameras are?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRI STOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simeon feels the hostility.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.  All I know is we've been filming a blow-up doll for the last three hours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone else is at first positions.</context>
      <utterance>We've declared a curfew. Only the extras required for the search are on the set.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All prop cars accounted for?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All heads turn to CHLOE as she enters the grand control room with a status report.</context>
      <utterance>He has to be on foot. He has the world's most recognizable face. He can't disappear.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>hour. The media is in a feeding frenzy. The phone lines are jammed. Every network has a pirated shot of Harlon and the dummy.</context>
      <utterance>The sponsors are threatening to pull the plug if we don't make a statement within the next</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any sign of him?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Police Officer takes a second look at Truman. After what seems like an eternity, he motions his PARTNER to drive on.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take it easy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rumors are circulating he's dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? We're getting higher ratings for that graphic than any time in the series.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chloe looks askance at Christof.</context>
      <utterance>We tell him the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're making a movie.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll get him on this next sweep.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What have we missed?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just a matter of time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof turns his back on the screens. Over his shoulder, we see a monitor displaying a view of the harbor.</context>
      <utterance>No. We've missed something.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SYLVIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Christof jabs the "PAUSE" button, freezing the picture. He recites the words to himself.</context>
      <utterance>...Trust that boy...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust that boy...  We're not watching the sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why would we?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sweep the harbor.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's him!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Simeon punches a button and the image of the sailing ship is instantly transferred to the large On-Air monitor.</context>
      <utterance>Resume transmission.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHOPPER PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman screams defiantly back to the chopper.</context>
      <utterance>Alter course immediately. You are entering a restricted area.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>YOUNG MAN 1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew he wasn't dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get the hell away! It's my life!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus! God! Is he out of his mind?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pull back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long will another chopper take?</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the time we pick up the pilots,</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no rescue boat in the area. He won't know what to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For God's sake, Chris. The whole world is watching. We can't kill him in front of a live audience.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not working. He can sail that thing!</utterance>
   <speaker>ROMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>hasn't set foot on a boat since he was seven!</context>
      <utterance>How can he sail?! He's in insurance! He</utterance>
   <speaker>MOSES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On the behalf of the studio, I demand you cease transmission.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep running!  I take full responsibility.  How close?</utterance>
   <speaker>OPERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very close.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Capsize him! Tip him over!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He'll drown!</context>
      <utterance>You can't! He's tied himself to the wheel.</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He doesn't care...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHLOE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chloe lunges for the control panel but Christof throws her to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>You lied, you hypocrite! The only way he can leave, is dead!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>All eyes turn in Christof's direction, as he confirms Chloe's accusation.</context>
      <utterance>Do it!</utterance>
   <speaker>SIMEON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too late...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The terrified Guide pulls jerkily away in the tram, resuming the tour.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody move!  Drive!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guide hesitantly resumes his commentary into his microphone.</context>
      <utterance>Keep talking. Say whatever you say!</utterance>
   <speaker>GUIDE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman's attention drifts to the logo on the side of the tram - "TRUMAN STUDIO TOUR". He is suddenly aware of the tourists gawking at him.</context>
      <utterance>Er,...the ocean tank contains over six hundred and fifty million gallons of man-made salt water, temperature-controlled...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Truman ducks out of sight as a fleet of STUDIO SECURITY CARS speeds towards the tram. But they streak past, on their way to the site of Truman's escape. As he tentatively gets back to his feet, Truman finds a CHILD standing in front of him with an autograph book.</context>
      <utterance>Act normal! Keep filming!</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On the child's T-shirt, a large photograph of Truman's face.</context>
      <utterance>Please, Mister Truman.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Truman turns his attention back to Christof, he suddenly lunges at him, catching him off-guard, the envelope slipping from Christof's hand. With a strength he never knew he possessed, Truman forces Christof to the edge of the soundstage roof, threatening to throw them both off his counterfeit world. Christof clings desperately to Truman to save himself. The studio guards dare not move.</context>
      <utterance>Even the stars I wished on...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHRISTOF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You won't do it, Truman. I've watched you your whole life.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly the doubts flood into Christof's eyes, fearing he has misjudged Truman, fearing for his life.</context>
      <utterance>You never had a camera in my head.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRUMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
