<movie id="333" title="Kingdom The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little girl, MICK raises her hand.</context>
      <utterance>This is my Fredricksburg house and my grandma Ruth playing with my skateboard ramp. It's a Tony Hawk jump ramp.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Silence from Mick</context>
      <utterance>Mick?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kevin points to another picture.</context>
      <utterance>I forgot what I was going to say.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury looks down sweet at his son.</context>
      <utterance>This is me at my second birthday party with my mom and my dad. That's my cake.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Kevin points to another photo.</context>
      <utterance>This is me with my mom at the zoo and this is my dad and me and my grandpa Willie.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this is me and my dad and my grandpa Willie at my dad's office.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>LITTLE BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pretty much all the kids get in on this now. Everyone wants to see Fleury's gun. Fleury makes eyes at Miss Ross. She's giving him a `no fucking way' hard eye.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, where is your gun?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm assuming that there are no bad guys in this room. Isn't that right? I mean, are you guys good guys or bad guys?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This silences the class. Miss Ross keeps things moving, pointing to a photo.</context>
      <utterance>Right. So why would I have brought my gun to a room full of good guys?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that picture?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mick's hand goes back up.</context>
      <utterance>This is me and my dad playing Battleship at my dad's apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mick?</utterance>
   <speaker>MICK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is a battleship?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat. Lyla and Ron look down at Kevin, stalled...</context>
      <utterance>My parents are divorced.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>This hits a bit hard on Lyla and Ron. Miss Ross jumps in.</context>
      <utterance>But that's OK `cause the most important thing is to know that everybody loves each other.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, who's that in that picture up on top?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my fish, his name is Jaws and he's a really mean fish.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is the day that my daddy says is the happiest day of his life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury smiles, looks out at the class.</context>
      <utterance>Really. His happiest day! Can you tell us about that day, Mr. Fleury?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sure can. That was December 4th and that was the day that we spent the whole day in the hospital waiting for this guy right here to come out of Kevin's mom's tummy. And we waited and waited but he wouldn't come and we kept waiting and finally the doctor said `OK...he's not gonna come out on his own so we got to go get him.' And well, Fleury stops, checks in with Miss Ross.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I tell this story?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The kids are mesmerized...</context>
      <utterance>Go for it. RONALD Fleury So they take her and put her on a special bed and they give her some medicine so she doesn't feel any pain then they take out this tiny little knife and make a tiny little cut right here in her tummy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A little girl, LU LU: WIDE EYED</context>
      <utterance>Then what happened? RONALD Fleury Then the doctor put her hands way up into Kevin's mom's tummy. WAY IN! And then you know what they did?</utterance>
   <speaker>LU LU</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did they do?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They started to pull and pull and pull... they had something in there and it started coming and they were pulling and the doctor all of the sudden said "STOP!" The class is frozen. Fleury has them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How are you today, Sergeant?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>How bad can I be doing?</context>
      <utterance>Sun is shining. Wind is blowing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DRIVER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other Officers are checking the inside of the Rover now. They nod to Haytham, Haytham hands the ID back to her. Windows rolls up. Lift-gate goes up. Range Rover pulls away, navigating the zig-zag jersey barriers.</context>
      <utterance>I like that, "Sun is shining..." A tight smile from Haytham.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>FRAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You getting this yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I'm at Kevin's school. What's goin' on?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Brother.  Riyadh. Many Dead. Fleury's demeanor shifts to HARD immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where exactly?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Hit a company picnic.</context>
      <utterance>The Al-Rahmah Western Housing Compound. Oil Company employees.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big. Broad daylight. Blew up a softball game.  Kids, Brother. Fleury looks at the kids eating and laughing.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury smiles best he can at his Son. Into the phone:</context>
      <utterance>Dad?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>FRAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just went off -- twenty minutes ago. Two bombers. A Shooter crew as diversion...it's just awful.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fran, I'm rollin' right now. Let me call you back: I gotta ring bells</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>FRAN MANNER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Fleury hangs up, walks to Kevin, kneels down - oblivious to everyone watching.</context>
      <utterance>Go. I'll be here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Son, I gotta go to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're gonna do ceramics...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gotta go to work...</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big Fran -- you remember him?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uncle Fran? Put peanuts in his Coke so he could drink and eat all at the same time?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where he's from in South Carolina that's called fine-dining, Bud.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>`Lotta bad people out there...'</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kisses his boy's forehead hard.</context>
      <utterance>I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You gonna go see him?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looks at Lyla who's been through this drill too many times, knows this face. Ronald can only give a little shrug, which Lyla gives right back.</context>
      <utterance>I'm gonna try...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>She nods yes. Miss Ross nearby, surprised by this:</context>
      <utterance>Can you get a ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>MISS ROSS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's your husband going?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYLA FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Then a wave of fear ripples across her face. She hesitates, then calls after him:</context>
      <utterance>Ex-husband, and God knows.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Fran turns to find REX BURR: 5'7" fireplug. A long silence. Fran points to the hat:</context>
      <utterance>Fran. You gotta stand Big Man...</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS MANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We watch tears well in Rex's eyes...</context>
      <utterance>Rex, how old were you when your hat was that small?</utterance>
   <speaker>REX BURR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fran does. Wipes his hands on his pants. Slack-jaw hopeless. The first moments in what will be weeks of reverse- engineering the murders of unknown dozens. He and Rex step to a group of WALKING-WOUNDED. A NEIGHBOR doles out mugs of coffee. Most everyone from the compound is out, pondering the proximity. SAUDI emergency teams sprint past. Fran spits, settles in:</context>
      <utterance>You gotta stand, Big Man.</utterance>
   <speaker>FRANCIS MANNER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SOMETHING HUGE EXPLODES over their shoulders, 50 yards away. The Attack's coup de grace: wait for people to lift up their heads, hit them again. Five times the size of the suicide bombs. Shreds emergency vehicles, nearby homes and apartment buildings. Kills Saudi rescuers by the bushel. Fran is crushed by a flying portable light standard. Rex is blown into the man handing out coffee. The walking wounded get decimated.</context>
      <utterance>We need to get everyone back, then get all their-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A PAUSE: Fleury freezes up on a shock of raw emotion, struggling to contain himself.</context>
      <utterance>Glenda, I want you to look at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Please... I'm going to take care of this. Whoever did this... I give you my word. Whoever did this will pay. I can't change this, but I can promise you that I will make someone pay for this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CNN REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...1 hour ago: blasts in Saudi Arabia, in or around the `Al- Rahmah' western housing complex near Riyadh. More than 100 feared dead, including children. The Saudi Foreign Minister has released a statement calling this a `heinous act possibly committed by foreigners...'</utterance>
   <speaker>BBC REPORTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury walks under the televisions. A folder in-hand, heading down a long hallway, subordinating his fury to tasks-at-hand.</context>
      <utterance>...homes to thousands of Westerners and other non-Saudis who work in the Kingdom, there have been several attacks on these compounds in the last five years. As such, they have become very tight in terms of security, with both the Saudi National Guard and police taking command.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fleury lets the news absorb as he steps back to the podium. No one says a thing. Fleury lifts his eyes again, real trouble maintaining control...</context>
      <utterance>So was Rex Burr from State.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>GRANT SYKES. 50 years-old. Virginia State Trooper before joining the FBI. Law-and-order formidable: sharp-smart Charlottesville accent. Studies the images for a beat...</context>
      <utterance>Fran was the best among us...we'll feel this loss the rest of our days...  Grant, take stabs at bomb sizes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From the craters, looks like they used a High Explosive... possibly military grade: can't fit that much TNT into a vest. 20, 30 pounds of PETN: they got it. Semtex or C-4: they could get it. The third there, God knows...that crater looks like a plane dropped a 500-pounder...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Obviously a secondary blast after the initial devices used to lure first responders to the scene. Don't know anything about where or what it was yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>ADAM LEAVITT. 34 years-old, sought-after Investigator. There's a constant, intense grind to this guy, a mind and mouth incapable of quiet. He paces around the room, then eagle-eyes the bomb images... starts surge-scrawling crude diagrams of the blast site on a piece of loose leaf. Feels more like nervous doodling than work. Not looking up from his drawing:</context>
      <utterance>This is how they do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ADAM   LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already know the answer, but any chance in Hell we get to go over there, use our hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury circles Leavitt's name on the roster. Leavitt never stops drawing.</context>
      <utterance>If you already know the answer Adam, why ask the question?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're not seeing this kind of planning and execution anywhere else...these ain't hot-wired artillery shells waiting for Humvees to roll by.  These hits are coordinated: planning, timing, and big, broad- daylight balls-</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another great question. Fleury looks over to AGENT 1 on his immediate right, an egg-head type with a big binder in front of him. Everyone's eyes follow. Agent 1 flips quickly through the binder, back-and-forth, searching. Fleury crosses his name off of his roster. Then:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, So... did they all happen during daylight?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone smells it: that's big -- more proof these attacks are being carried out by one, very skilled Terror Cell.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. At least the first parts of the attacks.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We had two others...North of Riyadh and the oil thing. What was that?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Refinery... Ras Tenura Refinery.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, south of Jeddah. Same thing: daylight, suicide bombers. Right?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same thing. Followed by machine gun crews. Collect and kill.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not new in concept. It is new in scope. It's bigger. Very sophisticated. Command and control was flawless. They found the largest kill zone they could and they did it... they did it by being patient.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any rumors or confirmations of uniforms being used in the other two attacks? Fleury circles Mayes' name on the ERT roster.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I know this is the first for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's `worst case scenario' if you're still asking for my stab, Sir. A crew who can build bombs this big, with this level of eyes- on control and detonation coordination... has access to Saudi uniforms now...I mean...Baby Jesus.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury checks from his notes.</context>
      <utterance>Anyone take credit?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Abu Hamza. Saudi Al-Qaeda. Bin- Laden-wanna-be. We know he was in Afghanistan, then moved to Iraq. Now he seems to have come home. He's clearly becoming increasingly active...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it is Hamza, he's definitely turning up the volume over there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Sykes studies Leavitt with what is best described as substantial skepticism. Fleury circles Sykes' name on his roster.</context>
      <utterance>Not to beat a dead horse, Sir, but if there was ever a time to get boots on Saudi sand...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury's P.O.V.: His open folder on the podium. A memo printed on Department of State letterhead. Pulls the memo, reads it aloud, calm laced with rage.</context>
      <utterance>They can't afford to appear as if they are losing any kind of control. They lose control over their country, their people...then they risk losing control over the oil. They won't let us in. No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leavitt stares at Fleury as he moves fast out of the room.</context>
      <utterance>From the State Department, one hour ago: `We are in agreement with the Saudi security assessment that any additional American presence on Kingdom soil represents reckless risk. Therefore it is the Secretary of State's position that only after the situation has been evaluated and contained, should the Federal Bureau of Investigation activate Rapid Deployment.'  The National Security Advisor and the Attorney General agreed.  I'm going to get us access. Keep your go bags hot. It's gonna come fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sykes just hard-eyes Leavitt.</context>
      <utterance>Well... I guess he's gonna go get us some access.  How's he gonna do that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GENERAL ABDUL-MALIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What was your involvement?</context>
      <utterance>No falsehoods, Sergeant Haytham.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Killing those I saw responsible.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL ABDUL-MALIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So none could be questioned?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A nod from General Malik: another vicious crack.</context>
      <utterance>I don't understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL ABDUL-MALIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You were born and raised in Suweidi-</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-that is not a crime-</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL ABDUL-MALIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-it should be.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>GENERAL ABDUL MALIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know Abu Hamza?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL ABDUL-MALIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your brother was killed fighting the Americans. True or false?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not my brother.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL ABDUL-MALIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your brother--</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am NOT my brother!</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL ABDUL-MALIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>TRUE or- Al-Ghazi interrupts.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Malik shoots Al-Ghazi a unequivocal SHUT THE FUCK UP hard eye. Then back on Haytham.</context>
      <utterance>He has answered the question.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL ABDUL-MALIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another nod, another crack. Al-Ghazi, flinching, becomes more alert.</context>
      <utterance>We found six more uniforms than you were assigned in your possession -- that is a crime: especially when you consider the Attackers wore our Uniform...</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>General Malik in Haytham's face:</context>
      <utterance>Uniforms?</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL ABDUL-MALIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Truth!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sweat. I'll say it again because it is true. I need more uniforms because I must change during shifts...look at my shirts.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GENERAL ABDUL-MALIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am not interested in your sweat.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Colonel Al-Ghazi grimacing now, leaves the room.</context>
      <utterance>-then look at my jackets. Please. Permanent stains...no matter how many times they're cleaned...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The only sound for a long, unsettled moment: Sergeant Haytham's labored breathing. Malik looks at the shirts, then Al-Ghazi, hesitates, steps away.</context>
      <utterance>He's telling the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>GENERAL ADBUL-MALIK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi moves in, begins uncuffing Haytham's bloody-raw wrists, hard-eyeing Malik the whole time. These men clearly don't like each other.</context>
      <utterance>You were injured when you used your vehicle to protect your country. Do you understand?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You saved lives today. I believe that. You served your country. I believe that.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I love my country.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Haytham Holds Al-Ghazi's eyes a good long beat...</context>
      <utterance>I believe that, Haytham...</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi slow nods.</context>
      <utterance>I love my country...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Haytham never blinks. Eyes hard. Stoic. Clear.</context>
      <utterance>You will have your revenge for what needed to be done to assure them you weren't involved.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nothing from Fleury.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone's terrified, so nothing moves. Paralysis. You and your team aren't going anywhere.  And this meeting is just a circle- jerk, Ronnie: Attorney General Young's going to go through the motions because protocol says we get an appeal. We'll be on record, but expect nothing more.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you handle this? Keep your mouth shut when people way above you say things you'll hate?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, sure. No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Agent Mayes?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ask her.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I apologize if we're late-</utterance>
   <speaker>GIDEON YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were early.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know Special Agent Fleury?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIDEON YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet stares at Young, looking mildly in over her head.</context>
      <utterance>This is agent Janet Mayes, she's one of our Arabic experts.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIDEON YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grace sits, nods to Fleury: you're up...</context>
      <utterance>OK. The latest.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young just stares at Fleury kind of odd like a kid staring at a mushroom flavored Popsicle.</context>
      <utterance>Two suicide bombers. Rumors they were dressed as Saudi Police. We believe this is the work of Saudi terrorist named Abu Hamza.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIDEON YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury continues:</context>
      <utterance>Go on.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Shooter crew served as distraction. After the initial attack there was a lull to allow Saudi Emergency Teams...and our own attaches...to collect. Then a secondary blast was triggered, aimed at those first responders. So they targeted families and rescuers with one attack.  I think that's a clear signal that their definition of `Enemy' is expanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARICELLA CANAVESIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My God.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIDEON YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let us never forget how cheap life is over there. Now...I have seven minutes before my next meeting, so who's talking first?  You two digested the memo?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ELLIS LEACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gideon Young remembers, nods along solemnly.</context>
      <utterance>I'll go first if that's okay Maricella?  First, I'm sorry about Fran Manner.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As we are about Rex Burr.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELLIS LEACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Motions to Maricella: the floor is yours.</context>
      <utterance>I met with Prince Thamer at the Saudi embassy fifteen minutes after I heard this morning's news. After speaking with Thamer, I advised we withhold additional US personnel because a big part of the religious justification for these bombs is the presence of current US personnel. More boots on Saudi soil make an already combustible situation more so. I know that's not the answer you want, but...</utterance>
   <speaker>MARICELLA CANAVESIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My two cents: The Saudis haven't asked for FBI help. Sounds like they've done just the opposite. If we force the issue, that could further anger an utterly important ally that shares a 1000-mile long border with Iraq.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIDEON YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all rock-solid logic.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We would just like to be on record as saying we think we should go</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>GIDEON YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Meeting seems over. Not quite. Fleury can't keep his mouth shut.</context>
      <utterance>-so as we present this to the public, let's - as best we can - try to view this through an FBI Agent's eyes.  And please let me know if there's anything else we can do for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, how would you imagine it looks viewed through an FBI agents eyes?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIDEON YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon me?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young, eyes on a Republican-gold Rolex, instantly perturbed the meeting isn't ending.</context>
      <utterance>I'm interested in how you think this situation is viewed through our eyes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIDEON YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's some variation on vengeance... When one of your own is killed, Agents lose their analytical powers - kind of a greatest strength, greatest weakness thing...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I wanted vengeance, I'd have whispered `Rex Burr' into Ellis's ear right when we walked in.  Eyes migrate to Fleury --</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't Terrorism, ma'am. It's just Serial Murder.</utterance>
   <speaker>MARICELLA CANAVESIO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the distinction?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury looks to Mayes. She clears her throat. Delivers the following with utter precision.</context>
      <utterance>To call this massacre an act of terrorism... that implies a specific political agenda. To me, these killings are so futile and unbalanced that they feel utterly sociopathic- more like Charles Manson than Osama Bin Laden...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury studies Janet with solid respect. He gives Janet a subtle nod: "Nice work."</context>
      <utterance>Al Qaeda lost the first phase of this war, so a new, zero-sum phase has begun: if you won't join us, we'll let loose the truly talented Murderers... Abu Hamza. He will kill so many of you that the resulting humiliation of the Saudi Royal Family will cause an exodus, a rebellion, both. Because the Royal Family simply cannot protect you or yours any longer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When she says talented, she's not talking about the walking-bombs who can sneak past any and all security, nor the hi-jackers tough enough to take an airliner. We're talking about the Man who teaches them how...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--the operational commander who organizes, trains, plans, encourages. That is who we're fighting.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we don't get inside Saudi Arabia within 36 hours, there is no chance we catch the killer responsible for Al-Rahmah. None.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELLIS LEACH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. I believe it all. So doesn't your team in that country represent the kind of target one of these `Masters' would die for? Trade ten of their own for one of you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To not engage these criminals out of fear for our personal safety is just another way of saying `uncle.' Fleury takes another deep breath.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>I'll say it another way: Evidence starts to go cold after twenty four hours. If we can't get in now, we will not find the man or men responsible for this crime. We couldn't do it at Khobar; we couldn't do it in Yemen; we have barely scratched the surface in Iraq. And we are on verge of not doing it here. They are getting stronger, we are getting weaker. I just lost a very good friend and I would very much like to go and do my job.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIDEON YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young stands. Fleury contemplates career-ending violence.</context>
      <utterance>That was spirited... let's all thank God Special Agent Fleury doesn't make policy decisions. He'd turn the FBI into Patton's Third Army.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not vengeance.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vengeance is always dirty, Ronnie.</context>
      <utterance>It ain't justice. It's stronger. We've all been there. I have.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just can't sit this out. I can't watch this not get dealt with. Not again.  Know what my high school football coach used to say to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"HIT SOMETHING." All night long, Coach Bailey would scream "HIT SOMETHING." Every play.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's good coaching.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm fixing to go hit something, boss. You with me?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How you gonna do it?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Saudis covet good PR as much as their Oil: 15 of 19 hijackers on 9- 11 means most Americans will never stop asking if that Saudi Oil is worth it. It's all about press.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury digesting Grace's words: moments pass. Then he looks to Janet.</context>
      <utterance>Few more moves and it's Total War, Ronnie. The only time Treason is palatable is when it's done righteously and completely...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I'm in...Not a question. I'm definitely going.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your take?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like every overthrow in history: once the guys with the guns are no longer trustworthy, the government's days are numbered.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>White House call you with a spin?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You kidding? We don't talk since I broke the Vice President's guy cooking dirty intel on Iran. They hate me. What's up, Fleury?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How hard you gonna hit the Royal Family in your column tomorrow?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With a sledgehammer.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With the bombings? Or other things...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's "other" than the bombings?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know you're tracking Al Haramain.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that what you want to talk about? Saudi officials making donations that end up... What? Blowing up trains in Paris? Buses in London?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes. Seems that just might happen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Flowers eyes go WIDE. Smiling...</context>
      <utterance>We got some other stuff: Missing girls out of a Houston Four Seasons Hotel that was heavily populated by some "Saudi officials." Little things...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Murder...Hookers...Houston? Can I take some notes?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not saying that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you saying anything?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need a favor.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't do favors, Ronnie.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Exclusive.</context>
      <utterance>When it's real and it will be real... I'll come to you with what we have first. It's yours.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You call Thamer at the Embassy. Tell him that the FBI is getting real close to laying out some major Saudi VIP indictments relating to newly uncovered charity financing out of a Boston investment firm. We're gonna freeze a lot of Saudi cash and roll out some major embarrassment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I mention Houston?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a free world, baby. Ask him to comment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He won't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell him that I'm not the nicest kid on the block.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be accurate.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I want fifteen minutes with him tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wow. OK. And I get what?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I come to you first. No one else.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury just stares at her.</context>
      <utterance>What's really going on here, Ronnie? You going strong over Fran Manner?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just trying to do my job, Elaine. That's it. Call Thamer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE FLOWERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll see what I can do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too many people we both know were at the bar. It's a pleasure to meet you, Your Highness.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had an interesting conversation with a reporter from the Post.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She can be a bit of an exaggerator... I'm sure things were somewhat over-stated. I see myself as friend of Saudi Arabia. I just need a little cooperation, that's all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of cooperation??</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Full cooperation: my Team cleared to land at Prince Sultan Air Base. Tomorrow. We want to help in a very muscular way, quickly.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury takes a beat.</context>
      <utterance>Next month would be as soon as...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This goes one of two ways. First: The FBI with the White House go on the kind of aggressive PR "Saudi Royal Family Decaying Monarchy" bender that just can't help but hurt. Really hurt. And I don't care how many Chinese are lined up to buy the oil. You know it's gonna hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My family is not decaying-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And then we bring the hammer down hard as hell: Bust Al Haramain - we got direct links from Riyadh - two wives donating ten million to three Arab-American cultural centers in Boston. Then what gets kind of not- funny is how some of that cash found its way to Jakarta and some Mosques that have these training camps built right next to them. It's kinda funny... you got little kids playing over here, and some not so little kids playing with guns over here. That's kinda odd.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have no proof of this.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Thamer is clearly rattled. Fleury is starting to crack this man.</context>
      <utterance>We're getting there, Sir. And I haven't even brought up the two girls still missing out of Houston. This is big. It is real. And I know you only care so much about public American opinion, Sir. But the story will be covered... Big...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And this ain't the Metro section. It's above the fold, just below the date. Words like these get syndicated to papers like the Omaha World-Herald, The Terrell Tribune -- You ever been to Terrell, Texas?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury looks back to him.</context>
      <utterance>What is your point?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That's a rock solid answer.</context>
      <utterance>Last I heard, 112 people lost their lives in your country. One of them was a good friend of mine. I want in and I want in immediately.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Define "immediately."</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury looks back at the Ambassador. A stare down.</context>
      <utterance>Right now immediately.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Prince Thamer slowly reaches for his phone as Fleury opens his door.</context>
      <utterance>If your phone doesn't work international, you can borrow mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll just be right out here.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We cannot allow 100 agents-</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-4. With a 25-man security detail-</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-even 25 more armed Americans could spark rebellion-</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's too bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saudi Security. That's non negotiable. You cannot bring guns into the Kingdom.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Men in Saudi Police uniforms are why we're talking now.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They would be hand picked.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whose hands?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury blinks.</context>
      <utterance>Mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trust me...that's the only hope of this happening.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If anything happens to me or my team... It's on you. Understood?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury just stares.</context>
      <utterance>Cool it with the John Wayne, Mr. Fleury.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can have a week-</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-seven-day or work-week?</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE THAMER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hands shake.</context>
      <utterance>Work week. Five days. No guns.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>OLD VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Haytham's P.O.V.: His FATHER, glass-frail, lying in a bed, a small TV nearby, on but soundless. Haytham goes into a routine: rolls out two prayer mats, steps to his Father, reaches down to pick him up. His Father readies himself -- stops everything when he sees the bandages up close, the black bruises with outer rings of purple covering 1/2 of his Son's cheek. Looks into his boy's eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Just in time.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYTHAM'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Haytham not returning the gaze, hoists his Father into his arms -- pain shoots up his arms from his damaged wrists.</context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't heard about the attack?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYTHAM'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What happened to your face?</context>
      <utterance>I choose not to listen anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An attack today.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYTHAM'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Haytham looks into his father's eyes now. No words. Haytham's eyes well with tears. After a long silence:</context>
      <utterance>Look at me.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYTHAM'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Haytham stares at his father.</context>
      <utterance>Is this how they now treat the men who protect them? Can you look at me? You cannot, can you? Can you look at yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYTHAM'S FATHER</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are protecting the true enemies of God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was Fran Manner to her?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He taught her how to shoot, she taught him most everything else.  Celebrated graduation at the IHOP in-town until some Townie called Janet something...Something not very nice. Townie didn't see Fran coming outta the Head. But he definitely felt Fran's uppercut shatter his jaw.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Points to Fleury's dirty Jeep arriving.</context>
      <utterance>Fran didn't get bounced for that?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SAC Fleury took care of him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leavitt looks up at Mayes as she gets within ear-shot, plops down next to them.</context>
      <utterance>If I knew how I'd be SAC Sykes. I do know the post in Riyadh was part of the deal Fleury cut to save Fran's career.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did SAC Fleury whisper in your ear this morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The three turn as Fleury approaches. Walking fast, clear sense of purpose.</context>
      <utterance>`Grant's age is a liability.'</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for volunteering.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Actually, I didn't volunteer.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks anyway.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're going to Riyadh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yup.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>State department said yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>White House said yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anybody said yes?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not really.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are we bringing security?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury walks onto the plane. Leaving the three on the tarmac.</context>
      <utterance>Nope.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the three follow Fleury onto the massive plane.</context>
      <utterance>This is going to suck so bad.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What can four people do in five days? Really?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aren't you the one who demanded to go this morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Small smile from Leavitt. The Scrabble continues...</context>
      <utterance>I meant the FBI. I didn't mean "me."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's it like on the ground?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mars.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be looked at with what I can only describe as disdain, pretty much the entire time we're on the ground... kind of like South Virginia.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go easy on my kin.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Intercut with the Scrabble.</context>
      <utterance>It's a very confused culture. Extremely religious. Had nothing; wanted nothing. Sixty years ago, they hit oil. Simple religious men become trillionaires... a schizophrenic nation is born. The royal family, who we back, and everyone else.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PRINCE BIN KHALED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi: more than mild shock.</context>
      <utterance>Four FBI Agents will be allowed to land at Prince Sultan Air Base this evening.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE BIN KHALED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Clearly not sitting well with Al-Ghazi.</context>
      <utterance>General Abdul-Malik, Chief of Investigative Services for the National Guard has been put in- charge of solving this crime.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know the General. I attended his interrogation of one of my men.  The General does not have investigative experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE BIN KHALED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi silent. The Prince pulls an anti-acid tablet, puts it in his mouth: that's why his tongue is chalk-white.</context>
      <utterance>Attackers wore YOUR uniform. Police Uniforms. Some of your men may have been involved with this Cell, may still be involved. You're lucky to have a role at all.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE BIN KHALED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And your role will be critically important: make sure the Americans leave our country as alive as when they arrive. Five days they will be our guests. Understood?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sykes puts his hand on Fleury's chest.</context>
      <utterance>I'm good.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Feels like you got a beast in there, Fleury.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm good</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Good" is 6:00 am Sunday morning when your kid climbs into your bed, buries himself into you... sun's creeping through the windows - soft. Birds and wind-chimes... that's "good." A BEAT as Fleury looks at Sykes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm OK...You don't think I'm OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you're not entirely clear right now. That's OK, but you got to know that. You want to go - we go. I got you, but you got to check yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm checked.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury stands up.</context>
      <utterance>OK. I'm just checking that you checked.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How we doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About a half hour out.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They gonna let us land?</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We've been talking to them about an hour or so... they know we're coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't mind my asking, but what the hell you all gonna be doing down there?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hunting...</utterance>
   <speaker>PILOT #1</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hunting...? I think of hunting, I think quail in Tennessee, deer in Pennsylvania. What kind of hunting you all gonna do in Saudi?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big Game hunting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel Al-Ghazi.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Special Agent Ronald Fleury.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Three men multi-task hustle to forklifts, start them up. Into the cargo hold, pulling out paletts. Things moving orderly- fast now. The Americans just kind of step back, dazed.</context>
      <utterance>Your two fallen comrades, Mr. Manner and Mr. Burr.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Sergeant Haytham, driving one of the suburbans, steps forward with kevlar vests for our crew.</context>
      <utterance>Passports and credentials. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you to keep these on whenever you are outside of Al-Rahmah.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The crew hits their bags, pulls out their vests. Another OFFICER checks each team member's FBI badge and passport. Stops at Leavitt's: an Israeli stamp on his passport. Leavitt's quick:</context>
      <utterance>We brought our own.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Israeli stamp in my passport?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi takes the passports and badges, hands them back.</context>
      <utterance>That is not our concern.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>This is like handing over your first-born. Fleury goes first. Haytham puts each weapon in a padded case.</context>
      <utterance>I'm also to collect your sidearms.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I usually just toss it on the kitchen table...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If each of you would please get into the middle vehicle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't need the power a' prayer if there were 2 hands on the wheel.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVIIT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>110 miles per hour... How do you keep so calm? I mean, really? Is it breathing--</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>--Shhhh....</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi on the edge of his seat, no belt, scanning for threats: sidewalks, traffic, rooftops.</context>
      <utterance>If somebody was tailing us it'd be obvious. This is just standard operating speed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Small laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I have been there only once. I spent four days at Quantico... I saw your Michael Jordan play for the Washington Wizards.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury nods to Sykes, giving him the go to start in with the Bad Cop. Throughout the following exchange, we stay TIGHT ON FLEURY: in control, using Sykes to ask the questions he "diplomatically" does not want to ask.</context>
      <utterance>You don't know what you missed... you should have seen him play for our Chicago Bulls.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have portable lights on-scene?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet looks to Leavitt, then Fleury: `what did he say?' Fleury looks to Sykes, `Keep going...'</context>
      <utterance>Yes. But your team cannot work nights.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We only have seven days: we work around the clock.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five days. And you are not safe at night.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury is about to step in when-</context>
      <utterance>We're safe during the day?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury cycling through different angles. Continues:</context>
      <utterance>I don't like camels.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Colonel, do you believe Abu Hamza was responsible for this attack?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were Saudi Police involved in the attack?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't know that either.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi getting tired of the questions: exhausted himself.</context>
      <utterance>Any word on what that third big blast was?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You interviewed witnesses?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're trying. No one who was close enough to see the things we would like to know, lived.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No answer.</context>
      <utterance>Were any of the uniformed bombers brother-officers?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>No answer. Team feeling the tension. Fleury steps in and takes charge.</context>
      <utterance>Do you know yet?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi stanches an explosion. Haytham looks over at his Colonel: rarely ever seen him like this. Looks in the rear- view mirror to see Sykes, the man giving the Colonel fits. Sykes catches him looking back, gives him a quick wink into the mirror. TIGHT ON Haytham's face: the guilty little smile you give when someone takes your boss to task.</context>
      <utterance>You don't know the source of the blast, don't know if your own Officers were involved, but you won't let us work nights?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury stays quiet, studying, calculating, thinking: we got a Handler that's going to be tough to handle.</context>
      <utterance>47 of my `brother-officers' were blown into hundreds of pieces that will take months to collect. 80,000 Officers total, across the country, at four uniforms apiece. Thousands of people who can sew forgeries. Apologies that I don't have definitive answers.  You're still not working nights.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young says nothing, just pulls a memo from his bag, clears his throat -- still no eye-contact -- reads aloud like a poor man's Orson Welles:</context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIDEON YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>`Sunlight is indeed the most powerful disinfectant.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senators? Then I'd change `outmoded' to `outdated,' `echelons' to `ranks' and what in God's name is `contretemps?' These guys aren't the best and brightest- Young's face flashes red, seething:</utterance>
   <speaker>GIDEON YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-never take the Lord's name in vain in this office-</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young apoplectic now: ready to end the Director right there, when Grace leans in, lets the vague threat of physical contact manifest.</context>
      <utterance>-but you can say `Fucking?'</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going to the Senate Select Committee, but not to the President who appointed you. Why's that?  I bet the President wasn't the audience you thought he'd be: I'll bet he realized you can't have Voters asking why the second- longest serving FBI Director gets fired for doing his job, for sending Agents into Saudi Arabia, seven months from mid-term elections-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GIDEON YOUNG</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grace snaps his ID badge off his lapel, puts it on the table.</context>
      <utterance>-you really want to bet?</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Young's pallor tells us his bluff has been called. Goes silent. Grace smells it, finishes him now:</context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Grace waits: nothing else from Young. Stands, snaps his ID badge back on his lapel, walks out.</context>
      <utterance>Westmoreland made all us Officers write our own obituaries during Tet, when it looked like the Cong were going to end it all right there. Once we clued-in that life was finite, the loss of it no longer scared us: the end comes no matter what, it's just a question of how you want to go out: on your feet or on your knees. After that, we went out and pulled triggers until barrels melted. And Vietnam lasted another seven years.  The lesson extends to this career: I ACT, knowing the end of this job will come, no matter what. You should do the same.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll forward Fleury's reports.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's one of the great horrors of television: Crime scene manipulation. They say a TV camera adds pounds to actresses. Isn't that what they say?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's "they?"</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TIGHT ON FLEURY: Quiet and focused, taking everything in.</context>
      <utterance>That is what they say. Doesn't add to crime scenes. Television cameras shrink them. Misrepresent. No smells. Poor sound. Limited view. TV always makes them look smaller. You can't feel the hatred on television.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>...heads on a swivel, people.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The bathrooms are through that door. I will be here tomorrow morning so we can begin.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time tomorrow morning?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sunrise.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What time is sunrise?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi and Haytham leave. The doors close behind them, then the sound of a key turning in a lock. The Americans look on, half-disbelief, half-comedy: locking us in.</context>
      <utterance>When I knock.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's against fire code.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence as the crew digests this odd little verbal outage.</context>
      <utterance>They don't have fire codes. They don't have codes other than codes of war. They'll lock us in and dial up some kind of earth movers if they want to. You know that, Sykes. Dig a big hole and push us in. Fill it up and no one comes calling. You're in the jungle now, baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You alright, girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watch it, boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just asking...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unpack.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>KINGDOM 8/18/06   57.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone hits their own bags first.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury pulls out his laptop, wakes it up from sleep mode. Eyes a photo of Kevin on his desktop, picks up the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Saudi slow roll...</utterance>
   <speaker>LYLA FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey... How are you? How's my boy?</utterance>
   <speaker>LYLA FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Where are you?</context>
      <utterance>We're just fine. How are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A BEAT as Lyla passes the phone to Kevin.</context>
      <utterance>I'm here...  Lemme talk to my boy.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm talking to you. What are you doing right now, Daddy? Right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm missing you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm in Saudi Arabia.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A Beat...</context>
      <utterance>Did you see Big Fran?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... I saw him...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>PAUSE</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I saw him.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he still tall?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silence... as Fleury takes a beat to collect himself.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah... Yeah...he's still tall.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Daddy? Are you still there?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, buddy. I love you. Keep your eye on your mama. Be the man.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You, too Daddy.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll call you tomorrow. I love you.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Fleury begins unpacking.</context>
      <utterance>Bye, Daddy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are in so much trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that right?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury stares at this freak show. Schmidt sticks out a paw.</context>
      <utterance>For sure. I mean, I don't know how you did it. Nice work, but if you live through this, which I put at about fifty percent - if you do, your balls are gonna get stretched and beaten on. Dig that?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>PRINCE BIN KHALED and his INNER-CIRCLE exit a Suburban and approach: All in traditional dress. The Prince locks eyes with Fleury. IN THE BG, forklifts rumble-hiss to life, placing Jersey barriers around the community center.</context>
      <utterance>Damon Schmidt. State Department. I'm in charge of getting you out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>One of the inner-circle, without a word, takes off the FBI- emblazoned windbreaker worn by Leavitt and places it on a short-sleeved Janet. Careful not to touch skin. Only then does Prince Bin Khaled approach. A lone PHOTOGRAPHER follows: snapping pictures. Different definitions of personal space: four inches separation as Bin Khaled greets each Team member in accented English. Janet last: the pictures suddenly stop. The Prince gives a little curtsy, no words, steps back to Fleury: the pictures re- start. Bin Khaled holds Fleury's hand sixth-grade boyfriend- style.</context>
      <utterance>Don't let go of his hand first. Major disrespect.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PRINCE BIN KHALED</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The Prince turns back to the convoy. Entire entourage follows. One of the Security Contractors catches the jacket Janet hurls back at him, tosses it to Leavitt. Convoy gone. The team turns: 100 glares again. Fleury blinks out the camera flashes, takes in all the eyeballs. Fleury looks up at a retreating Damon Schmidt.</context>
      <utterance>We've invited American legal officials into our Kingdom despite current difficulties between the US and Islam. They will observe our advanced investigative techniques, offering helpful hints.  You will please honor me with your presence tonight at my home.  Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dead eyes from Fleury. He's clearly not amused.</context>
      <utterance>Nice pictures. You guys ready to go home now?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He points a finger gun at Fleury.</context>
      <utterance>OK. If you change your minds, I got a plane fueled up and ready to go - got your name all over it...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>SCHMIDT takes off. Sykes by Fleury.</context>
      <utterance>Strap your kevlar on tight, people.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Slow roll... gonna be like when you go deep sea fishing in Florida and you pay seven hundred bucks for the boat and you sit in the ocean for hours and the crew jumps around and screams and points and you think your constantly about to bag a Marlin but you never do and they keep pointing and jumping and-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Haytham walks off by himself, shaking off the shady Royal photo vibe, looking back at the Americans. From behind him:</context>
      <utterance>Enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>POLICE OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Haytham turns. An older POLICE OFFICER stands with a GROUP of SANG twenty feet behind him, eyeing Haytham. Back to Fleury: he looks to Al-Ghazi.</context>
      <utterance>You're willing to die to protect your enemy?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did the Prince say?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That there are more rules than just not working at night.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What rules?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury tries to remain cool.</context>
      <utterance>You are here as observers. Not investigators.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not accurate-- Al-Ghazi ignores Fleury.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leavitt looks around at the Security as Al-Ghazi hustles off:</context>
      <utterance>--I need to make sure the sites are secure. Then you can begin observing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, this is going well...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sykes and Fleury lean against the locked door, staring at the pathetic sight before them: Janet's truly awful jumper... that somehow swishes every time. Before she lands, cocky and smooth:</context>
      <utterance>Saudi Slow Roll.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet gently bounce-passes it back:</context>
      <utterance>How do you do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Check.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet takes the check from Leavitt: before he can react, she drains a 30-footer. Same cockiness, different word:</context>
      <utterance>Don't say `good' again.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury with Sykes still standing in the same spot. Looks up: Al-Ghazi coming into the building. Fleury ready to vent until something surprises him: breathless, Al-Ghazi has broken a wide-sweat hustling back to the Americans. Fleury's face relaxes. He pulls a bottle of water out of a cooler, hands it to Al-Ghazi.</context>
      <utterance>Bueno.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury can't help a small smile.</context>
      <utterance>I am sorry for the time.  You won't need you gear.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course we won't.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would have thought your primary concern was investigating a crime.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sykes looks over to Fleury. Crooked smile.</context>
      <utterance>And you would be mistaken.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi ignores Sykes.</context>
      <utterance>I think it's one of those "something happens to us... his head comes off" kind of deals.  Is it one of those kind of deals, Colonel?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi motions to 50 MEN in uniforms different than his: SANG troops digging, bagging evidence, marking the scene with red-flags.</context>
      <utterance>So, if you're not running the investigation...who is?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Team: so we're on Tour. Fleury still silent.</context>
      <utterance>The National Guard's Military Police Brigade is conducting the investigation. My orders begin and end with your health.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought the SANG were soldiers--</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury finally speaks, asking the most important question:</context>
      <utterance>--the bombers didn't wear a soldier's uniform. They wore mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi points to a Man we've seen before, General Abdul- Malik. Haytham's Interrogator. He pours over a table 20 feet away: maps, blueprints, utility schematics spread before him.</context>
      <utterance>Who is in charge of the investigation then?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General Abdul-Malik. He's given us permission to walk through each crime-scene.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To walk through? Are you kidding me?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Starting to get heated.</context>
      <utterance>I am not.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get him over here now and let's clarify this situation.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is no lack of clarification.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There sure as hell is! I don't know what kind of game you're playing but you got the wrong guy, Colonel Al-Ghazi! That was not the deal-</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat. As Al-Ghazi stabilizes...</context>
      <utterance>This is not a game show, Mr. Fleury! There are no deals made here. There is me telling you what you may or may not do and there is you doing it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A stand off. Fleury eyes Al-Ghazi. Trying to figure this guy out. Sees something that looks like a flash of embarrassment in Al- Ghazi's eyes: unable to perform his profession, relegated to Tour Guide. Leavitt begins taking notes. Haytham sees his notebook, snaps his fingers at Al-Ghazi who looks, nods: let him.</context>
      <utterance>You will be permitted to walk through the crime scenes. When we have determined that it is safe.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How have you guys been doing with the witnesses?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi just stares at Fleury.</context>
      <utterance>What witnesses?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi silent, staring.</context>
      <utterance>I'm guessing there are a bunch of Americans, Brits... Australians? Someone must have seen something. I'm sure they're just dying to talk to you guys, seeing as how the killers were wearing your uniforms. That must be a real confidence booster for them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi looks unsure. He was not expecting this.</context>
      <utterance>Let me talk to them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A moment as Earl and Janine get a bit defensive:</context>
      <utterance>Why Saudi Arabia?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neither of us did anymore schooling than Electra High, Electra Texas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Earl's mother Maddy looks at Fleury, pets the cat.</context>
      <utterance>And the jobs here pay twice what you'd make in Midland or the Gulf a' Mexico. Plus the house is free.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANINE RIPON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I call it combat pay. This place has gone Guns - Guns - Guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So has Everyone else now.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My girlfriends in Texas spend their combat pay on diamonds... I spent mine on a safe room.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two nights back. Can you start one second before you knew anything was wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't really see anything. Just hit the ground and hustled to the safe room. Closed our eyes and prayed. It was so fast. So loud.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you really didn't see anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hit the deck. Horrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not `til after. Just the screams--</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- the kids... they were screaming. That got me out of the house. Those kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which kids were those?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury lets moments pass. Earl rubs his wife's leg, trying to comfort her. Al-Ghazi hides emotion.</context>
      <utterance>The Jackson kids. Tracy Jackson next door was murdered looking out her window...front of her children. No safe room over there...  Not even the Men that did this should die in front a' their babies.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She live with her husband?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aaron.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If I'm facing your house, is the Jackson home to the right or left?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury looks out the window towards the Jackson house.</context>
      <utterance>Left.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Aaron Jackson?</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get him away from me-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-easy, Sir. He's a friend to us-</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-I don't know either one a' you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Special Agent Ronald Fleury of the FBI. This is Colonel Al-Ghazi with the Saudi State Police-</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi quietly backs away, walks away. Fleury looks after him, turns back to Mr. Jackson who stares after Al-Ghazi: hate. Fleury unsure what to do next.</context>
      <utterance>-the Police: they attacked.</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just put my boys down for the first time in two days. I can't wake `em and sure as hell can't be gone if they stir on their own.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can I come back?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson remembers the warning he just spoke...</context>
      <utterance>Your boys...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fresh tears re-animate his face:</context>
      <utterance>To ask about two nights ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When my wife's jaw was shot off in front of our sons? My sons who sat with her while she bled to death? Couldn't speak because she didn't have the bottom of her face and I wasn't home and my baby boys are destroyed for life and my five year- old had a box of band-aids in his hand when I finally got home?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Aaron Jackson settles, wipes away tears, appreciates the honesty. Then bites back into his rage:</context>
      <utterance>...I won't pretend to know...</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kill everyone that had something to do with this. Everyone related to them. Everyone who knew them.  And all you'd be doing is their recruiting for them... It's an entire generation: not small and isolated like they say. But a generation that thinks what they did to my wife, to my children, is a "calling"...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up the street, there was a wreck, did you see any-</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-notice how it wouldn't take a lot to disguise your friend  as a Mexican? Think he couldn't handle crossing our deserts? Look around!</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Aaron-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slow nod from Al-Ghazi.</context>
      <utterance>Can we tour the compound? Can we please do that?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury steps, looks inside: blood and safety glass coat the seat. Janet points to keys in the ignition: still at the `on' position. Then the stick-shift, pulled to the back right: reverse. The shift-knob bloody...</context>
      <utterance>He or she almost made it.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Makes me think of the Trade Centers -- the people on the floors above the impacts -- no matter how fast or strong or smart you are, if you're in the wrong spot, `it' will not let you get away.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sykes notices something on the ground... he picks up a military detonator, discretely hands it over to Fleury. Fleury quietly pockets it.</context>
      <utterance>That's what makes this a War.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hit a water main?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi points to a mass of black metal: looks like a fire truck the way a Jackson Pollock looks like the Mona Lisa. Leavitt and Grant stand back. Quiet:</context>
      <utterance>No -- from the tanks of this fire engine: that's the water that didn't evaporate in the blast.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hole is the case. See, there's "evidence" down in that hole. You understand evidence? Little things that are "clues." Clues can be very helpful to a fella when he's trying to solve a crime.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad to hear it. So can we get in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sykes holds Al-Ghazi's gaze. Smiles.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little high...</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watt-tee...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watt-tee fuck  is his gun doing up so high?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This vehicle was stolen. Two drivers murdered. A team outside the blast-radius...shooting at anything. Everyone.  Sergeant Haytham ended this part.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are the Shooters in-custody-</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>So Sergeant Haytham speaks English...</context>
      <utterance>-dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were any of these shooters your men?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury's thinking, looking into the car. Searching the horizon, he spots a distant apartment building providing a view of the crime scene.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury gets in the car, checking out ballistic shreds in the back of the passenger seat headrest.</context>
      <utterance>They got into the compound. Somehow...took control of this vehicle. I'm guessing they didn't politely ask whoever was in this car if they could take it for a little ride?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, they didn't. There were two officers in the car. Both were executed.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand that. Those men were your men--</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- they were. They were Police.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi offers the slightest of nods to Fleury.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi leads our team to the main gate. Sykes and Fleury follow close.</context>
      <utterance>Where was this car when they hit it? a77A EXT. AL-RAHMAH - MAIN GATE a77A</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leavitt and Mayes lag behind a bit. Leavitt makes eye contact with a YOUNG SAUDI behind the .50 caliber.</context>
      <utterance>Security is a combination of the police and military.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good news is that if he shoots you, he's gonna shoot you sitting on an American tank... with an American- made bullet. So, it's kind of "all in the family."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The car was parked here?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Backed in?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury studies the scene.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were attacked from the front. Must have assumed the killers were fellow officers... Have any of these men been identified?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet. We will check certain neighborhoods. It is likely that the four men prayed at the same Mosque.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The same Mosque is enough to identify them, link them to a cell?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. If the Mosque is in Suweidi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Suweidi?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On Fleury: he looks back at the homes, then up and around: He locks on the OBSERVATION BUILDING in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>Suweidi is a known militant stonghold. Al-Qaeda could recruit from storefronts.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we go to check out some of these surrounding buildings?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is that true? Is that accurate?</context>
      <utterance>Seems reasonable that the Planner had to observe and based on Hamza's past history, it's consistent that he would want to video the attack.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is true.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury points to one particular building.</context>
      <utterance>Well, in order to video, in order to observe, you need a view.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi looks up to the building. Back to Fleury.</context>
      <utterance>That building sees all three crime scenes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's outside the walls-</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-c'mon now. This is insane: we got enough security to invade Suweidi, let alone that building-</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-no you don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Could you ask?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're already seeing the crime- scenes individually -- why not all at once?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any answer will take-</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury speaks slowly and clearly now: like he's cementing his words in his own head as he speaks them.</context>
      <utterance>-time. I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi hesitates, can't help but be charmed. Fleury clearly knows when to step-on or lay-off the gas. He's smooth... and HIGHLY EFFECTIVE: Al-Ghazi nods `yes' to the strange half- question.</context>
      <utterance>You have to ask the General, then the General would ask the Prince. Does it go higher or is that... is the Prince the end of the chain?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll be at the Community Center.  Janet, wanna play hoops?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leavitt calls to Fleury.</context>
      <utterance>This is the kind of radical circumstance that could have seriously upped Shaq's free throw percentages. Take a man. Ship him off to Riyadh. No phones, constant threat of death, no girls, no hip hop. Nothing... just free throws. Shaq, he'd be shooting at least seventy percent. Lakers would still be together. Kobe and Shaq lovers forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Boss... check this out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>IMAGES ON THE COMPUTER: ARABIC EXTREMIST WEBSITE. Video footage shot from the rooftop of all three bombings and some of the machine gun killings.</context>
      <utterance>Just posted half hour ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fleury studies the footage. Backs it up plays it again and again.</context>
      <utterance>So self congratulatory. Makes me sick.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's cleared with General Abdul- Malik. We have five minutes here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL FORCES OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were told they must remain in the vehicles...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is not true...</utterance>
   <speaker>SPECIAL FORCES OFFICER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They must stay in the Toyotas-</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>-Officer reaches down from nowhere and hammers Al-Ghazi open- handed as Al-Ghazi tries to step past. Collective shock. In that breath, Haytham punishes the Officer with a left- cross: knees buckle before he comprehends what hit him. Haytham's kick follows, catches the Officer in the sternum as he hits ground. Al-Ghazi shakes it out, trades blows with the SANG second in- command. Leavitt moves, catches a rifle butt to the shoulder after two steps. Fleury aims, drills the Soldier that butted Leavitt: instant night-night. Another SANG steps up. Fleury throats him, knee caps him, and grabs his weapon before the dude hits the ground. Fleury can obviously fight... all the above happens in four seconds. Then, a `knock-it-off' gunshot aimed at the sky pops one-foot from Janet's head. We hear what she hears: one half-second of the shot, then the big ring. On her knees immediately, hand over her ear. In response: heavy-caliber gunfire flies: group flinch-n-crouch. The warning shots from a .50-caliber mounted on a Humvee racing this way from Al-Rahmah: dust plumes from the speed. Members of the security detail and the Special Forces go Mexican stand-off.</context>
      <utterance>-report me then when you get in- touch with the General-</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me it didn't burst-tell me it didn't burst-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You've seen the images of the attack posted on the internet?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi takes the camera from Fleury. He lines up the same shots we saw posted on Leavitt's computer: clearly a match. This is where they shot the video</context>
      <utterance>Look for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another long moment. Al-Ghazi looks at the table, discarded trash: the Capri Sun containers, the candy wrappers.</context>
      <utterance>He was here...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi quiet for a long while. Then he reciprocates:</context>
      <utterance>Formed the plan up here: saw everything he could hit.  Way too pretty a' plan to have been fully hatched on just one visit. He came here a couple times.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury looks over to the two dozen LOCALS peering out with suspicion at them on the rooftop.</context>
      <utterance>The man who did this is a Saudi - this place, this neighborhood... if foreigners were up here, someone would say something.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury smiles small at whatever just passed between them. Al- Ghazi stays stoic, then looks straight at Fleury:</context>
      <utterance>Nobody's talking. Here, many people love Hamza - they think of him like Bin Laden. Like your Robin Hood.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Shaytan...</context>
      <utterance>A man who thinks of something like this ...while maybe his family played around him... scares me more than I have words to express.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi pauses.</context>
      <utterance>Two big answers in two small minutes. Imagine if we had a couple days together.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi stands still, silent. Fleury reaches into his pocket. Reveals the detonator to Al-Ghazi. Al-Ghazi reaches to take it. Fleury holds it for a BEAT...</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure the General is good guy...and I'm just as sure he's no Investigator.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He hands the detonator to Al-Ghazi. Al-Ghazi now pockets it.</context>
      <utterance>Let me help you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We break now: too hot to work outdoors. Then we will leave for the Palace.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I imagine that will run until sundown?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury just nods back.</context>
      <utterance>I had televisions delivered to your quarters to pass the downtime.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fleury looks over to Janet. Hurt, yet extremely defiant, she looks ready to attack anything that comes near her.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Mayes will not attend this evening. Men only.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The helicopters peel off at steep angles, the sound of the rotors reverberating in your chest. Leavitt watching them go:</context>
      <utterance>We're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big wall.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a big palace.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many Princes are there?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Over 5000.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They all get palaces this big?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some get bigger.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who pays for all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>General Motors, Ford, Chevrolet...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, man - I drive a Hybrid.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Prince will ask you about your flight, the accommodations...lite subjects. If he offers you the chance to hold his Raptors, don't flinch: it's a compliment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Damon Schmidt appears.</context>
      <utterance>What's a Raptor?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PRINCE BIN KHALED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His talons slice bone.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Super.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>PRINCE BIN KHALED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's my most prolific Hunter. I'm trying to teach his friends there by example, but I fear it's something you're born with or not. Do you agree, Mr. Ronald? Innate or not at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE BIN KHALED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When I bull-rush our hosts you'll know it: In his quiet, calm- amidst-the-bullets tone:</context>
      <utterance>What have you seen so far of our Kingdom? -- and know I can arrange tours anywhere within our borders.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pin-drop silence in response to Fleury murdering the Prince's "lite subjects," his attempt to extend the gilded circle-jerk by offering tours. Bin Khaled's face sinks to gray again after the excited pink of talking about his Falcons. His hand slowly moves back over his stomach: Napoleon's ulcers. As Fleury speaks, people unconsciously put their tea-cups down, look up at him with wide-eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I've seen that the man who planned the worst crime in your Kingdom's history is without a doubt Saudi...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>..and that if you walk 300 kilometers from the compound, you will find a rooftop where the attacks were planned. I've seen that the person in this room "born with it" is right there...  Everything I just said came from Colonel Al-Ghazi: his observations of the scene while he was protecting us. And I think you're absolutely right Sir: that kind of instinct can't be taught: not to Falcons. Definitely not to SANG Generals. Innate or not at all.  You want the murder to stop as much as I do. Let us help.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>PRINCE BIN KHALED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the Prince walks out with Al-Ghazi, he signals another corps of servants to serve another round of cups: coffee. Dinner over. A servant takes the Falcon from Leavitt just as he was starting to smile at it. Fleury sips his coffee. Schmidt and Sykes approach.</context>
      <utterance>Colonel Al-Ghazi, a word.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was impressive.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Think it will work?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Maybe. I mean, you can only play the "I'm going to the press card" like three more times. So, maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're paranoid and overly self- protective.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury opens his mouth to interrupt.</context>
      <utterance>They aren't protecting anyone. There's no conspiracy. They're just terrified. Finally. The Saudis have finally seen the Monsters they helped create, because those Monsters have come home. And if Saudis don't catch Saudi Monsters, that's the end.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that end could come double- quick if they let the US "Shaytan" catch those Monsters for them.  Because that's what the Saudi on the street suspects: the only thing keeping the Royal Family upright is American evil.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's dead on accurate. Very impressive. That's why they're making it hard on us, and that's why he wants to help `em turn the screws.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They can have every shred of credit-</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-you see the slums on the way in?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See that even though their homes are falling down, they had satellite dishes bolted on?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Everyone already knows you're here. Credit? If the Saudis cracked this Cell while these servants were pouring coffee, Al-Jazeera still leads the story with your Team.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have you been to the crime-scene?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No-</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-if you had, you'd see the evil work of real Talent. The kind that doesn't stop until it's forced.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the path to Hell is paved with good intentions.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You having fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>(smile vanishing)</context>
      <utterance>Beats hell outta visa-stamping.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're on an island. I hope you know how to get off.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Raising his coffee, toasting Fleury's cup:</context>
      <utterance>By catching Abu Hamza.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then here's to you. Let's bet: when this Colonel Al-Ghazi comes out, he's in-charge of the investigation -if so, you set me up on a date with Janet Mayes.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... every investigator on-scene by midnight, 50 more portable lights, three more pumps-</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi points into darkness...</context>
      <utterance>Do me a favor and tell Janet that she and Damon Schmidt got a date when he gets back to the States.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The rules still stand.  But tomorrow will be a new day.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi smiles...</context>
      <utterance>From now on, any evidence you find you hand over.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm "all ears," Special Agent Fleury.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should start with the dead shooters.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They had no identification on them. Fingerprints and dental have come up empty.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can we photograph all three of them? Couple hundred copies each...</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sykes and Leavitt can't help small smiles. Finally getting to work.</context>
      <utterance>Good. If it's OK with you, I'd like to suggest we split up as follows...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>KINGDOM 8/18/06   89A.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>a89 EXT. BLAST SITE - MORNING a89 Sykes climbs down into the mud hole.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>No reaction from Saudi police</context>
      <utterance>Fellas, what we want to do is get this water out of here... see what's really going on. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>C-VIN hunting--Data Plates-- Something drivable blew up. That's pretty obvious. Feels like ANFO to me, boys--Ammonium Nitrate Fuel Oil. Let's dry this hole and see if we can't figure what she was. Gotta pump?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got to get a little dirty, people. Crawl up in it. Make deep contact. You get that? Dead, confused stares from the Saudis into the mud hole... Sykes happy as a pig in shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>He smiles, watches another Officer write Saudi translations on the stainless-steel paint cans into which you load evidence: shrapnel, soil, DNA, shells, etc.</context>
      <utterance>Get nasty, dirty, filthy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury pulls out the photographs.</context>
      <utterance>No, Sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury puts the three photographs down on the dining room table: not pretty pictures. Earl and Janine study the photos.</context>
      <utterance>Could you tell me if you recognize any of these men?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A few moments, then:</context>
      <utterance>...Horrible.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury thinks a minute. Looks outside.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know any of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just wondering. That chair out side. Looks like it gets a lot of wear. Looks comfortable.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That my mom's chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, that's exactly what I was thinking. I'm guessing she spends a lot of time sitting outside?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All day.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Right?</context>
      <utterance>She must pretty much see it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She does.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is she?</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause: Fleury slow nods, then...</context>
      <utterance>She's sleeping.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've seen him.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maddy thinking...</context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like, a week ago. Twice I've seen him. Watering...With the garden crews. I remember he was wearing a Liza Minnelli T-shirt. I thought that was funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about the others?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Just him. I remember the T- shirt. I remember thinking it was odd...?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What, the Liza Minelli shirt?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I do think Liza Minelli's gone odd, but that wasn't it.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was odd?</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a Saudi. The gardener.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>MADDY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Saudis, like Americans, don't do manual labor. Blowing leaves is beneath them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury and Al-Ghazi start to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EARL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury looks back to Earl.</context>
      <utterance>Who is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's one of the many things we're trying to find out...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Jackson's eyes shrink-wrapped in tears. After a long silence with no answer, Fleury hands him a sheet of paper:</context>
      <utterance>How are your Sons?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the name of a clinical psychologist. Works with Embassy kids...apparently very good at explaining violence-</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-what do you know about what my kids need? What they saw? What the rest of their lives might be like?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought maybe your Boys...without their Mom anymore...might ask you why sometime...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will find the man responsible for the death of your wife. We're close.</utterance>
   <speaker>AARON JACKSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury quiet.</context>
      <utterance>Tomorrow it'll be somebody else's wife.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury turns his head: Al-Ghazi approaches on the next lawn down with three JUNIOR OFFICERS. Fleury nods goodbye to Jackson. Fleury approaches Al-Ghazi, holds up the Shooter's photo.</context>
      <utterance>Then tomorrow I'll come back.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury - a slight nod of satisfaction.</context>
      <utterance>The gardener. We know who he is. He's on several watch lists.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We know where he lives?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We will very soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't seem very excited.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are always the easy ones to catch. Rarely does it lead to the planners.  I want to take you somewhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To someone who may be able to help us catch Hamza.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sykes looks down at the mud colored DIGGERS.</context>
      <utterance>It's a gurney.</utterance>
   <speaker>SYKES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Just stares from the Saudis.</context>
      <utterance>Who's missing an ambulance?</utterance>
   <speaker>SYKES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Confused stares from the Saudis.</context>
      <utterance>Could somebody please go get Sergeant Haytham?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SYKES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Inside the crater: water-level down to the ankles. Three Saudis dig around what looks to be one of the dualie-style back tires. Re-positioning to get a better grip, Sykes notices the top of what looks to be a sizeable, ragged hole, still mostly submerged. Pointing:</context>
      <utterance>Sergeant Haytham!</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sykes slogs over. He drops to his knees, reaches his hand in, all the way to his shoulder, the side of his face to the water: void. Out of the crater, Sykes points to a Bobcat earth-mover, in Arabic:</context>
      <utterance>Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who has the keys?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet takes a breath as the Police hard-eye her.</context>
      <utterance>You cannot touch any Muslims.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem. Can I still touch Americans?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet moves back to the American dead, as the Saudi Tech continues with the Muslims. She pulls another shard of COLORED GLASS from a wound.</context>
      <utterance>Of course.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi smiles.</context>
      <utterance>What's gas running a gallon out here, Al-Ghazi? Penny gallon?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury stares out as the oil spills out overflowing from the station tank.</context>
      <utterance>It was an American. An engineer named Karl Twitchell. Hired by Saudi Arabia to find water. He didn't find so much as a dried oasis, but he found this. Enough oil to turn the earth.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They say my country sits on over 1 trillion more barrels of recoverable oil.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A trillion reasons for our Leaders to hold hands another one hundred years.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A trillion reasons to keep fighting. For both sides of this War.  I think our oil has begun destroying more than it creates.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agreed.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm 46 years-old.  I have three daughters. And I find myself in a place where I no longer care about `why' we are attacked. I only care that 100 people woke up a few mornings ago had no idea it was their last. When we catch the Man who murdered these people, I don't care to ask even one question...I just want to kill him...stop him.  Do you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long moment. Just road noise. We see two men, as different from each other as they could be, yet made from the same things.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is your first name `Colonel?'</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Faris.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At one time, Talal was Arafat's senior bomb-maker and planner in the occupied territories. He joined Bin-Laden when Al Qaeda brought the fight to the Royal Family.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Small smile from Al-Ghazi.</context>
      <utterance>OK. Shouldn't we arrest him or shoot him or something?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He turned himself in last year during an amnesty. He's now part of a new government effort to balance the experience of Saudi Youth.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This place is community service?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If America figures out a way of keeping their kids off the computers please let us know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Before Al-Ghazi can answer, Talal begins talking to him in Arabic. Al-Ghazi translates:</context>
      <utterance>Why did he turn himself in?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>`You only come after I see there were bombs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Subdued laughter. Then Talal becomes quiet, grave. Al-Ghazi continues the translation:</context>
      <utterance>Did you know Bin Laden put 5 million-dollars on my head? Why shouldn't it be 10?'</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Talal looks at Fleury now, speaking directly to him through Al-Ghazi:</context>
      <utterance>The Man who made War on Al-Rahmah is someone my age -- this kind of skill is learned over decades.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A Man who can plan the mass-murder of women and children, then go home at night to his own and sleep soundly...? That kind of Man is supremely difficult to catch.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because he hasn't stopped. You stop when their faces don't let you close your eyes...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that why you quit?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi shows Talal the detonator. The old man studies it. Al-Ghazi and Talal speak in Arabic about the detonator. Al-Ghazi looks to Fleury, translates.</context>
      <utterance>He says he makes my job easier. Here, at least they only fight and kill on computers.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He says that there are several ways to get American military equipment like this detonator but not many men in Saudi Arabia that know how to get them.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do they get them?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Usually smuggled from Iraq by corrupt soldiers working with the Americans.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi asks Talal.</context>
      <utterance>Could Hamza get this equipment?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Without question. Yes, he could.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He thinks for a moment, then speaks. The boys chuckle as Al- Ghazi continues translating:</context>
      <utterance>How do we find him?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury looks at Al-Ghazi, doesn't quite get it...</context>
      <utterance>Prayer. Luck. Handshakes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I think I get the `prayer' and `luck' parts... Talal slowly stands, Al-Ghazi helping him up, moves to Fleury. Reaches his hand out to him, quietly:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Fleury shakes Talal's hand, turns it over: index finger gone.</context>
      <utterance>His hands will feel like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C. - CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every Amir at some point gets bitten by his work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Haytham yells to the Machine Operator in Arabic:</context>
      <utterance>Whatever this is, it blasted-off like NASA.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another gouge of earth: 4 feet. Nothing. Grant sits back.</context>
      <utterance>Driven in at an angle... go deeper...</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leavitt rubs his eyes: adrenaline long gone. Looks at his watch: time passing fast. Sykes drops to his stomach, reaches in with the TRENCHING TOOL to see how much farther the hole goes: a metallic `clink. An oxygen tank. The kind used in ambulances. Nozzle assembly gone, burst in the explosion with a force that drove it several feet into solid ground. Haytham takes a razor blade, scratches off samples of the soil and carbon for explosive residue into a fresh cannister. Then takes a wet rag, begins cleaning the tank to reveal Arabic script...</context>
      <utterance>`High-order explosion' doesn't do it justice: what's left a' this looks like it was put through a wood-chipper.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ambulance identification.</context>
      <utterance>Hospital Identification...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="117" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know this hospital?</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Call it in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="118" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's more: I told you it wouldn't be hard to find the soldiers.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you got?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The stolen ambulance had a twenty man crew that rotated shifts on it. We checked all twenty men. One of them, Muaath Hazmi is now of interest to us.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi reaches for the photo of the dead shooter/attacker.</context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because this gentleman is Fathi Hazmi, Muaath's brother.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="119" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's Muaath?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to show you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="120" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We never get to do anything fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sykes, I'm guessing you don't even remember how to load your gun.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's not trying to be funny.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a very good shot.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Haytham hands Al-Ghazi a walkie-talkie, in Arabic:</context>
      <utterance>I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neighbors clear?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Activity or communication?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Snipers have seen nothing. No telephone line into the house.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="121" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gone... This shrapnel look like the stuff you pulled at the morgue?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah... I pulled so much it's hard to remember it all.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bolts?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wing nuts?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Razor blades?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="122" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Everybody looks at the Colonel, pointing at the pictures:</context>
      <utterance>-the front gates of every other western housing compound in Riyadh.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And Embassies: Italy, Japan, Korea, Norway, England...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leavitt steps, scans the pictures, picks up two in particular: buildings with scaffolding and heavy equipment.</context>
      <utterance>The Coalition...</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are all countries with Troops in Iraq -- Japanese and Italian embassies are under construction?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet pops her head in:</context>
      <utterance>The entire Diplomatic Quarter is being retro-fitted to sustain bigger bomb blasts.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi's face: fear.</context>
      <utterance>-the Prince's Convoy just showed.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is bullshit. You know it. Meaningless. There's no leader here. These are kids. That's it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="123" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>KINGDOM 8/18/06   110.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Al-Ghazi says nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, that's it. Smile for the cameras, body-bag some children. Wrap it up, but us -- out. I get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRINCE BIN KHALED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Damon Schmidt trailing behind the Prince's detail. The Prince locks Al-Ghazi with a mad-dog stare in-between lesson points. One of the Prince's inner-circle heads straight for Al-Ghazi, in Arabic:</context>
      <utterance>Only in death will our enemies realize Allah never permits defiance of his almighty will.</utterance>
   <speaker>INNER-CIRCLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take the Americans inside now and keep them out of sight. You will be spoken to about their presence here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="124" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really ought not look at this.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That fella got shot right through his God damn nipple...</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet's voice causes Schmidt to immediately force composure.</context>
      <utterance>Don't stare too long. It'll start living in your dreams.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No -- I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?  How did you know we were here?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Prince has Men at Al-Rahmah.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What Men?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pissed, reproachful head-shakes.</context>
      <utterance>Ask him.  3 vehicles will stay behind when the Prince and Press leave. You'll convoy straight to BA flights into Dulles -- last minute fares come out of your budget, by-the-by. Tried to swing upgrades, but check at the counter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn those frowns upside down, people. This will be pitched as a stunning Saudi-only counter-punch that killed those responsible for Al-Rahmah. Al-Jazeera will play up an FBI presence, we'll play up their ties to Terror as checkmate. And everyone that was so righteously pissed back home is gonna eat crow.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="125" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Already a rumor that the guy who wrote our State Department memo-</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-Ellis Leach?</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know him? He's gonna be put out to pasture: made an example of by the President to ensure all levels of government get tough on Terror.  You won the hand on the River card.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We didn't win shit, Schmidt. These are teenagers... children with pictures that someone far senior has provided them.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone rings that instant. Leavitt hands it up to Fleury. Schmidt holds his hand up to Janet: high-five -- she gives it up slowly, warily, semi-charmed:</context>
      <utterance>-kidding me? You mean those are Terrorist targets? Holy Wow. Momma, don't let your children grow up to be cowboys.  Just get ready to go home and revel in the fact that for the next few weeks your shit won't stink.</utterance>
   <speaker>DAMON SCHMIDT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Double or nothing that's a congratulatory call.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?  Yes, Sir. We're all here and healthy. I'm sitting next to their corpses but this may not be over. These don't feel like anything resembling senior leadership-  -thank you Sir. I do.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="126" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi looks up at Fleury, slowly shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Amateurs. It's a small win.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A beat.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking about New York - February 26, 1993. The first time they tried to hit the Trade Towers.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm thinking about going straight to Dan's, gonna order six PBRs-</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-Pabst?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Keep it real. You ever drink PBR, Haytham?</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any beer?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="127" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the back, Al-Ghazi can't help a small smile either. Fleury's not into it. All business, pissed, clearly does not want Pabst.</context>
      <utterance>Now...that's just unreasonable. Good Police work and problem drinking are like a chicken and egg thing: which enables the other?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remember how we caught that cell?</utterance>
   <speaker>AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Car bomb. He went back to pick up his deposit on the rental car.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury looks at Al-Ghazi. He knows the win is small. Also knows that's all she wrote, for now.</context>
      <utterance>Four hundred dollars. For four hundred dollars, he was caught. Stupidity. Catching the cell was easy. Just like this. The cell came back.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be back.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The POLICE BAND suddenly squelches loud with excited Arabic. Everyone perks, leans up to listen to the urgency.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, you will.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>A small collective smirk, sigh of relief. Fleury turns in his seat.</context>
      <utterance>Religious demonstration in progress. Back near the City Center.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="128" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury notices the Suburban bringing up the rear has dropped back.</context>
      <utterance>I'm serious. Beer will open up your subconscious. Canned beer especially. Give you instincts they can't teach-</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dropped back...</context>
      <utterance>Is he responding to the call?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>O.C.</mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi and Fleury both looking back to the following Suburban now. Dropped back, sunglasses and blank faces staring back at them. Fleury looks to the overpass above - he sees a YOUNG MAN on a cell phone. As they pass, the kid runs to watch them from the other side. Al-Ghazi gets to the CB radio, in Arabic:</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>-the trailing Suburban doesn't `tighten up.' It falls further back. Fleury instinctively turns, wide-eyed -- out the window: a small brown truck swerves out of the opposing lanes, flying across the desert median, aimed at the Convoy. Without hesitation Fleury reaches over Haytham, rips the steering-wheel right, nosing away from the approach...</context>
      <utterance>Tighten up-</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="129" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You whole?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leavitt unbuckles his seat belt and smashes head first into the ceiling -- running FOOTFALLS approach, quick yell-yips in Arabic: commands? The Driver and three other Police Officers from the trailing Suburban. Smoke fills the interior now: thank God these Police Officers have ripped open a door: saviors. They grip Leavitt by his hair because it's the only thing they can grab. Alarmed, Al-Ghazi begins to scramble for Leavitt.</context>
      <utterance>Think so-</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is not right!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="130" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>GRANT SYKES</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fleury begins sawing Grant's seat-belt with a jagged piece of metal.</context>
      <utterance>Can't release-</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sykes still does, ugly. Fleury and Janet rip him free of the Suburban. Haytham's pulling shotguns, handguns, ammo from the flipped vehicle. Haytham pointing ahead, to the fading roster-tail. In Arabic:</context>
      <utterance>Hands up -- you're gonna fall-</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Desperate, Fleury looks in the direction of the fleeing Suburban: the rooster-tail it leaves getting smaller. Al- Ghazi nods, swings his head to thesnarled/wrecked highway traffic. PEOPLE hesitantly step toward uniforms they trust on instinct. Haytham dumps the pile of weapons at the Team's feet, re-loads his 9MM. Janet ties a half-assed tourniquet around Sykes' reminder of an arm. Al-Ghazi steps toward the approaching crowd: they see his state, his gun, and turn back: panic starts to infect the larger mass, then the topper- -AUTOMATIC GUNFIRE from somewhere. Glass-dirt-metal bursts around us: this attack is still going. Fleury looks up: just the roof of an old Mercedes on the median, dirt kicked up behind them, running behind lines of stopped-wrecked traffic now. The barrel of a rifle held high out the window like a taunt. Accelerating for another opening to finish the job. Scared motorists devolve into terrified motorists. Many have abandoned their vehicles to sprint into the desert, the rest go smash-'em-up derby-folly: 50 panicked drivers aiming for the same spots. Fleury snatches an M4A1 from the stack dropped by Haytham, up to his shoulder, hustling toward the next break in traffic. The Mercedes is approaching at 80 MPH.</context>
      <utterance>They're going to disappear...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="131" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A tunnel networks through all these places... they use attached civilian Apartments, innocent families.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I do not like these people.</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent nods. Bracing for war...</context>
      <utterance>We go in the front door. Haytham - cover the stairs. Janet - hallway. Watch the side doors. Watch your backs.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="132" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slow nods from Leavitt and Janet as Fleury cuts Adam's ties.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody OK?</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Janet's eyes catch on something: a sheet/half-assed backdrop hung from the ceiling has been nearly pulled down - exposing a crude square cut out of the wall - a path into another Apartment. Janet points to the hole in the wall. This isn't over: a seven-year old GIRL peers out at her, shaking, tears in her eyes. Janet tries her best Motherly smile.</context>
      <utterance>There's at least three more of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay Little One.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="133" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Silent stares from the Saudis. The little girl Janet saw earlier, eyes still on Janet, moves to her brother - he holds her tight, his eyes down. Janet kneels, heart-breaking, holds her hand out: I can help you little one. The Little Girl holds a fist out to Janet, tears in her eyes: okay. Janet slowly crouches over to her, the older women's eyes on her, piercing.</context>
      <utterance>Is everyone alright?</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="134" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>The old man looks up at Al-Ghazi: rage and defiance.</context>
      <utterance>...Hamza.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>ABU HAMZA stares, hatred burning into Al-Ghazi.</context>
      <utterance>I got you. Abu Hamza, you are under arrest.</utterance>
   <speaker>NASSAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You are a traitor to your country... a traitor to your God.</utterance>
   <speaker>COLONEL AL-GHAZI</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Al-Ghazi's chest explodes before we hear the booms: the 15 year-old Grandson, firing a cheap, nickel-plated 9MM. Everybody drops. The family huddles that much closer to the floor. Al-Ghazi falls back to the floor, pulling Grandfather with him.</context>
      <utterance>I am no traitor to my God. You are.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="135" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The 15 year-old steps to the doorway, pulls the trigger again: the cheap 9MM jams. Janet lifts up with her AK, aims it at the boy's chest.</context>
      <utterance>...Don't...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>...The teenager wiping his tears: so he can see clear enough to clear his jammed weapon. Half young boy, the other half something much more dangerous...Expert movements from his hands, racking back the slide, thumbing the still smoking shell from the ejector, letting the slide go, racking another round into the chamber. Then... Fleury finally pulls his trigger. Utter Distortion as the old man reaches for the teenager's fallen hand gun. Janet, screaming, raises her gun towards the old man as Al-Ghazi shoots the old man in the chest. Sobbing, the little boy runs to his fallen grandfather. Janet, still screaming, covers the family. The Grandfather whispers something we cannot hear in the Little Boy's ear. TIGHT ON HAYTHAM taking it all in: the bleeding, dying teenager; his hysterical sister; Hamza choking, clutching for his grandson. CHAOS, CONFUSION, CONFLICT swirling in Haytham's eyes. A platoon of SAUDI POLICE slowly enter the room. Janet goes to the shot 15 year old, starts trying to stop the bleeding... Fleury reaching for the dying Al-Ghazi, cradling him. Tears spill as his eyes move from the dying boy to the old man, back down to Al-Ghazi. Fleury grasps Al-Ghazi's hand, as a Saudi man would.</context>
      <utterance>...drop it, Son...please...</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You got him. You got him... You got him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="136" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Haytham says good bye to Leavitt and Sykes. Comes to Fleury. Hands him a beautiful wooden prayer bead necklace.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Lieutenant Haytham.</utterance>
   <speaker>HAYTHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>May peace be with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>143alt OMITTED 143alt</context>
      <utterance>May peace be with all of us, my friend. The two men shake hands.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="137" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SILENCE from the team.</context>
      <utterance>We're going to testify next Tuesday. Fleury's going first. I'm gonna go through it with each of you one on one in advance - make sure we're all on the same page. If they ask if we've talked about this, the answer is unequivocally "No." OK?  You did outstanding work over there. I'm proud of you. You hold your heads high.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR GRACE</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ronnie, you ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Grace turns to leave. Fleury gets up to follow. They head down the hallway.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Confusion from Janet.</context>
      <utterance>Janet... my dreams are...  What did he whisper to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Janet looks up: Leavitt waiting...</context>
      <utterance>In the briefing ... to get you to stop crying about Fran... before any of this... before we even got Airborne? What did he say to you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="138" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADAM LEAVITT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Janet looks at Leavitt, PAUSES...</context>
      <utterance>Do you remember?</utterance>
   <speaker>JANET MAYES</speaker>
      <mode>ALT: RONALD FLEURY</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said... "We'll kill them all."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="139" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>KINGDOM 8/18/06   136.</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Father and son throwing the ball back and forth.</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fleury stops, just staring at his little son. Tosses back the ball.</context>
      <utterance>You stop the people that hurt Uncle Fran?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context>Fleury catches the ball, stares at his son. TIGHT ON FLEURY: He reaches and pulls his son close, holding him for what might just be forever... (alt: He hands Kevin Al- Ghazi's prayer beads.)</context>
      <utterance>Did you get the bad guys, Daddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode>CONT'D</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's a lot of bad people out there... aren't there, Daddy?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, there are...  But you want to know something?</utterance>
   <speaker>KEVIN FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>RONALD FLEURY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kevin smiles up at his dad. For the first time in a long while, Fleury smiles back.</context>
      <utterance>You're not one of them.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
