<movie id="353" title="Limey The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Edward Rama?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eduardo.  Rama.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns, waves away the taxi he's kept waiting. While Eduardo Rama waits for an introduction.</context>
      <utterance>You're home, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Accent speaks for itself. Hard, working-class.</context>
      <utterance>My name's Wilson.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Knows the name. But just now it's unexpected. He's holding a hot TV dinner, hand protected by a dish towel.</context>
      <utterance>Wilson?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You wrote to me about my daughter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="36">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No reason.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, what has it been -- six months?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They've entered a cauldron of family life. TV blaring (SHOWBIZ TONIGHT!). A couple of younger KIDS yelling "Mama". Their MOTHER shouting back at them from the kitchen (in Spanish) that she only has two hands. A sullen TEENAGER walking by.</context>
      <utterance>Round about, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't even know who I was writing to -- just someone with the same last name. She never talked about any family.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed opens a screen door to the backyard.</context>
      <utterance>It was better than a telegram.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed surprised at Wilson's directness. Ed stands nervously.</context>
      <utterance>Snuffed her.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And paces back and forth.</context>
      <utterance>Now, wait up a second, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never said nothin' about nothin' like that. No, no, no. That's not what I wrote to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed stops pacing.</context>
      <utterance>No, but between the lines, eh? Mysterious circumstances, and that.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, I sent you that newspaper clipping, all right? I told you what I know. It was an accident. I didn't say anything about anybody being "snuffed." Beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This bloke she was bunked up with. This Terry what'sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terry Valentine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valentine. What's he got to say for himself?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Makes a kind of scoffing gesture: and you can see what my life is.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno. What's he gonna say? They had a fight that night, she drove away, she was upset? I don't even know the guy. Don't get me wrong, Jenny and me were friends, but we didn't travel in the same social circles. She had her life, I had mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson gazes up at the sky. Clear night. Stars.</context>
      <utterance>Valentine came into the restaurant where I work with Jenny a couple times. He's a money guy. Jenny would say, hey, here's my friend Eddie and he would shake my hand and everything, but he wouldn't even see me, you know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed leans down, palms on the tabletop, facing Wilson.</context>
      <utterance>How long had she been in the States?  Near on ten years, wasn't it? Long enough to know her way about, I reckon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson taps out a cigarette from a pack of "Silk Cut" he's produced from his pocket.</context>
      <utterance>There was an investigation, okay? The car was totalled. Jennifer was ... Her neck was broken. On impact, they said. So she wouldn't have ... felt the effects of the fire.  It happens up there. Happens a lot. What more can I tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What more is there.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson's quiet stillness is getting to him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm just sayin' -- it was a steep hillside. There was no moon that night ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Coulda happened to anyone, man. I never knew her to be reckless. I mean, sure, she would smoke a little grass, or something, have a few drinks. But that's it, nothing more than that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, not my girl. Self-control, she had. Point of pride.  And people don't change, do they.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson notes the tattoos on Ed's forearms.</context>
      <utterance>I dunno ... Maybe they do.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed looks at him. Sits down again. Keeping his forearms under the table.</context>
      <utterance>Going straight, are ya.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boomerang.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Y'what?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew when I was droppin' that letter into the mail slot it was gonna come back and smack me in the face.  I did my time, okay? My sister, her ol' man's up in Chino right now doin' eight years.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This ain't your lot?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And yet -- he lives here. Wilson declines to pursue the matter.</context>
      <utterance>You kiddin', man? I don't need a wife and screamin' kids. I still got my youth.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I go to work, try to keep my life together, put all that shit behind me, man. What d'you want from me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed sighs. Reaches for one of Wilson's cigarettes.</context>
      <utterance>I only asked.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Couple weeks before she died, Jennifer asked me to drive her downtown. Said she was meeting -- her boyfriend -- Valentine. But I think she was looking for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It was someplace else.</context>
      <utterance>That's what I thought, man. But it was not a hotel or nothin' that we went to.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where abouts?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did Jenny know?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valentine wasn't even there. If he was into something, if she was involved -- who can say.  But I'll tell you something. She stood in front of these dudes, man. Eyeballing</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, coppers don't do nothing, do they.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Could be talking about the girl. Wilson doesn't move. But touch him, he'll explode. Out the window lights are passing, but no landmarks. He might as well be on the moon.</context>
      <utterance>Those streets up in the hills, man. Gotta be real careful, keep your eye on the ball. Two o'clock in the morning, it's dark, your mind is all agitated, you're drivin' a little too fast ...  Those curves don't kid around.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You should talk to Elaine. That was her best friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't write to me, did she.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She didn't know what to say.  I thought someone should say something. To someone. With me it was, I don't know -- Jenny liked me for some reason. I felt like I owed her.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who'd Jenny get it off of -- this grass or whatever?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me, man. I'm no drug dealer, what you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you didn't get that lot in the Navy, doing your National Service.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already told you, man. Corcoran. Know what that is? State prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nick's a nick, n' it? No matter what state you're in. State of remorse, most likely -- for gettin' caught.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But that's not me anymore. That's when I was into the gang lifestyle. That's not who I am now. Five years in the joint -- that's it for me, man. Now Wilson drops the clanger.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just got out meself, didn't I. And Ed turns. Looks at Wilson. Fellow ex-con.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Makes his fingers like a gun. And a clicking sound.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be needing a shooter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're kiddin' me, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do I do, then, look in the bleedin' Yellow Pages?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>These are not guys you can just go run a number on, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you a resident of California? You gonna fill out forms, man? Do the background check? Go through a three-day waiting period?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sod that. Gotta get back before my probation officer wonders where I've skived off to.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probation? Man, you crazy. They shouldn't've let you outta your country, much less prison.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Walks round to come face to face with Ed once more.</context>
      <utterance>Travelling on a dodgy passport, n' all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which is why I thought, save some time, get what I need under the table, like.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As if resigned and mulling the problem over:</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Under the table?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PA SYSTEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>... and other anomalous oddball ANNOUNCEMENTS in the background as long as we're here.</context>
      <utterance>Attention: the long-range vermin- shooting panel is due to commence in two minutes in the blue room at the rear of the Convention Center.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEMONSTRATION</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At a booth selling laser attachments.</utterance>
   <speaker>BEAM SALESMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>For purposes of display, a smiling YOUNG WOMAN is the "target."</context>
      <utterance>BeamSight II is easily mountable on any shotgun, rifle, or sidearm and will project a small, bright red dot directly onto the point where your weapon is aimed ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="26">
   <speaker>TABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A .45 passed from a DEALER's hand to Wilson's.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Man knows what he likes.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lookin' good.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's a high-end item. Total reliability.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd you call that -- the Protector?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson's eyes glance up -- but Ed asks the question.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir. Won't find a better CQC on the market.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>CQ what?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Close Quarters Combat. Keep one in my own home.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nods at Ed.</context>
      <utterance>Trouble is, I'm not at home, see. Fancied a bit of target shooting, y'know, while I'm here -- with me mate.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh really? Where you from?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>England.  Only, we saw there was a show on, thought I might pick something up for a price, type of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You came to the right place, sir. My wife's second cousin is English. Well, Scotch-Irish. Can I interest you in a holster?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just luck, this, really. Never been to one of these before.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're in gun country now, my friend.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been to the Boat Show.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Packs a punch, but it's compact, has accessible features -- makes a nice concealed-carry piece.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He don't have a concealed weapons permit.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't have time for a lot of paperwork, y'know. Just popped over on a quick visit.</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can take care of the paperwork.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No problem. If</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not me, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I mean, it's already a steal, n'it -- what you said -- four hundred for this one?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALERS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll have to add another two hundred on top of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, aye?</utterance>
   <speaker>DEALER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... for the paperwork.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You hadda show up on a weekend. This weekend. Wouldn't've even been a gun show ... for another month.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fucking out of order, that. Shouldn't be allowed. As he puts away a box of ammo.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now what. You gonna take your new arsenal, go visit Terry Valentine, just like that? Boom bam boom.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's only insurance. Can't be too careful. This Terry Valentine, he's probably a wonderful fella. They were together how long?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five years, I think. Long time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Doesn't make Ed feel any better. Nor does the way Wilson seems now to be studying Ed's driving techniques. Paying attention to the way traffic lights and left-turn lanes and cars without clutches work over here.</context>
      <utterance>Well, there you are. Jen must've liked him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Him?</context>
      <utterance>Jenny told me she met him at the beach. Got blinded by his smile.  You believe that shit? Son of a bitch never smiled at me. Buried her at a "private" service. Private for who.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hang about. I thought you said he come into the restaurant where you worked with Jenny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He came in with Jenny to the restaurant where I work. That's not where they met.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that's where you met Jenny.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no -- Jenny used to work as a waitress. Before she met him. But that's not where she met me. Not in my restaurant.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd the two of you hook up, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Jenny was in my acting class.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you get in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Walked.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You walked.  What the hell are you doing here.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>MEAT PUPPETS (who we saw before as well) who work here gathering. The Supervisor and the Meat Puppets exchange glances.</context>
      <utterance>Looking for a bloke named Valentine. Know him?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's expecting you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Supervisor moves toward Wilson.</context>
      <utterance>I doubt it.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So why would he want to see you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have a message for him. About Jennifer Wilson.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>More looks are exchanged.</context>
      <utterance>Jennifer Wilson.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know her?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson stares at him.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I know her, all right. She came down here once, stirred up a shitstorm. We lost a full day's work, took me weeks to get back on schedule. If she hadn't a' been Terry's woman I would've broke her jaw. 'Course, she's nobody's problem now.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is Valentine here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson looks at the Meat Puppets, the loading area.</context>
      <utterance>What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson just looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, get the fuck out of here before you get hurt. Who the fuck do you think you are, waltzing in here, asking questions?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Supervisor shoves him. The Meat Puppets move a little in anticipation. Wilson isn't giving any indication that he's going to leave.</context>
      <utterance>Do you hear me, asshole?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes Wilson again, hard.</context>
      <utterance>Jesus, you really want your ass kicked, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pushes Wilson again. Still, Wilson won't leave.</context>
      <utterance>Go on, get outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUPERVISOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This time he tries to slap Wilson. Wilson blocks the Supervisor's hand and then punches him, hard. The Supervisor stumbles back and falls to the floor.</context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' nut. Go on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not before. Not</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I used to hate it. Now I like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns and we see him for the first time.</context>
      <utterance>Could be worse, he could've named you Reticulum.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="45">
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is there anything in the world that you want or need?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then what good is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is it possible that you're too young to be acquainted with the idea of loyalty?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a problem?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not for you, clearly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm loyal to things that make me happy.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Am I a thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you're certainly not a person.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. You're not specific enough to be a person. You're more like a vibe.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm so glad we're having this chat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a knock.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not a compliment.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>When are we eating?</context>
      <utterance>It's an observation. Like: I'm hungry.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As soon as you get dressed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of food?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anything but Japanese.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not into finger foods. Too fussy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Buffets. Salad bars.</context>
      <utterance>I don't like do-it-yourself cuisine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You demand to be served. A fork fetishist.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's just fuel to me. I'm not there for distractions.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For some, eating is a sensual experience.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His cell phone rings.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, god.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He listens, then looks up at his balcony, where a MAN (AVERY) stands holding a phone, obviously talking to Valentine.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be there as soon as I can. He hangs up. VALENTINE  We can leave as soon as you're ready.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's been some trouble downtown.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the papers used to call a "gangland slaying."</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Our black friends?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Terry. They don't work like that. Jenny Wilson's father paid a little visit, left a message.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought he was in prison, in England.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine is a little ruffled. Maybe Avery likes that.</context>
      <utterance>Well, either they have a very liberal work-release program, or he's out, because he's here in L.A., looking for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Beat.</context>
      <utterance>What do we do?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine just looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>We wait, and we watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Italian.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not who, food. Should we get Italian.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sure. Turns to her. VALENTINE  Yes. Are you ready?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles, rises, and offers her his hand.</context>
      <utterance>As long as I don't have to pass Gordon again. I'm never ready for that.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes it.</context>
      <utterance>No. I know another way out.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And the recognition on his part:</context>
      <utterance>You're Jenny's father.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Had a feeling it was you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You look alike.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps it was the smoke.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not her brand.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elaine doesn't soften.</context>
      <utterance>She used to pinch 'em off me.  Funny that. One thing she never tried to get me to stop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why did you come here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wanted to talk to you, didn't I?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>America.</context>
      <utterance>No, why did you come here?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sort a few things out.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Been busy, have you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How d'you mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been a while.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was skint -- didn't have no money to get here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not what I heard.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was that, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard you were -- what's that adorable phrase? -- "at Her Majesty's pleasure."</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Indicating his face, viewed by Elaine through the barred security gate that divides them.</context>
      <utterance>It was the bars, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In any case, I don't suppose the salary you make sewing mailbags is really commensurate with international airline travel.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sewing mailbags? Me? Never did an honest day's work in my life, dear. Wasn't about to start when I was in stir -- not with all that leisure time on my hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And not with all that buried loot you had waiting for you when you got out. From the Wembley Staduim job, wasn't it? Pink Floyd concert receipts. Jenny would've been ... fourteen at the time?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tidy little premium per annum, that.</context>
      <utterance>Hardly buried. Earning interest, love. Earning interest in an offshore account.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to walk away.</context>
      <utterance>Well, that kind of security can't be bought. Must be more comforting than a daughter to greet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, aren't you gonna let me in.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Try calling me again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="30">
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like Beverly Hills.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here, are you always this sarky?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sarcastic, moi? Maybe I'll mellow when my ship comes in. It's expected any day now. I'm all packed and ready to go.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Weren't you on a television series?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If it played in England somebody owes me money. Who told you that -- Eddie?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Said it went on for donkey's years.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Three seasons. They found that's the limit of human tolerance when it comes to following the adventures of a family of Mormons on the Chisum Trail.  I was wife number three -- the ingenue.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, it just ended, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now who's being sarcastic?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you've lost as many years as I have, love, puts things in perspective, know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their food arrives.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry. I guess the rest of us have no excuse for wondering where the time went.  It must've been the bars.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson appears fascinated by the cold glasses of water on the table. Ice cubes CLINKING as he holds his. A BUSBOY bringing them to other people, too, just like that, without anyone even asking.</context>
      <utterance>It's a kind of prison, doing a series. Early to bed, early to rise, no time off for good behavior, you grab the boodle for as long as it lasts.  Only difference is you can't get arrested afterwards.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't believe Jenny told you all that. About me. She was always so embarrassed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not embarrassed.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ashamed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson looks at her. Okay. What then.</context>
      <utterance>Not ashamed.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Disappointed.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She never told Eddie, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She never told anyone else.  About the convict strain -- or is it stain? No, I was privileged. I was someone who helped Jenny efface her past.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you manage that, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I'm not honing my craft in episodic television I do double-duty as a voice coach. Not that her accent would have hobbled her progress. Not with that look.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, she started all that in London.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Modelling.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elaine smiles slightly. None of this information new to her. But warming to this man.</context>
      <utterance>Learnin' 'ow to speak proper.  Central School of Speech and Drama. It's no doddle gettin' in there, y'know. At seventeen. They offered her a place at RADA n' all, only she'd've had to wait till the next session and she was always in hurry to get on, was Jenny. She could talk posh without any training, when she was knee-high to a grasshopper.  Show up the old man, you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You weren't disappointed in her, then.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>'Course I wasn't.</context>
      <utterance>In Jenny? 'Course not. How could I be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was twenty-one when she came to me.  ... Straight from leaving you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Footloose and fancy free.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It's because Wilson thinks the opposite that he's here. Looks at Elaine.</context>
      <utterance>She was happy here. However the two of you might have parted. Don't think she wasn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's the trouble, n' it.  She enjoyed life.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yesterday. Afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't been lurking outside my building all day.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I had -- some other matters to attend to, you know. Getting a car sorted ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might've been away for the weekend.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I reckoned, Saturday night, if you were goin' out, you'd probably have to come home first.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you've seen Eddie Rama.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mates. Friends. Makes a kind of bonding gesture.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, saw Eddie, yeah. Me and him are muckers.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I should really give him a call. He's a character, isn't he. Well, not to you. I meant to us squares in the outside world.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He give me your address.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I gave him yours. Said, here, you want to write, I think this is a relative. I guess I thought I was being true to Jenny. Who told me she didn't have a father -- before proceeding of course to tell me why.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, don't suppose she did, really, most of her life. On her own after her mum died. Aunts and uncles for a time -- and then the bright lights beckoned.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were you still married at the time -- to Jenny's mother, I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, we split up when Jenny was six. Her second husband done a runner after she got sick. They give me compassionate leave from Parkhurst to go visit her in hospital. We were always mates, me and Jenny's mum. I like to think they're together again now. Y'know. Heavenly choir. Beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The address Jenny gave me, that wasn't a prison, was it?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nah, accommodation address.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that, like a P.O. box.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something like that, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson gives a laugh.</context>
      <utterance>Where you get your bank statements.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, you gotta have something permanent, don'tcha. Even if it's a hole in the wall. No matter which jug I might be transferred to, I always got someone on the out checks up on it for me, see. Anything I need to know, comes round on visitor's day -- word in my ear. Elaine pauses.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson leans on the wall overlooking the black ocean. Sound of WAVES gently lapping the beach.</context>
      <utterance>Some word.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I already knew. Knew beforehand. When was it supposed to have happened? -- two o'clock in the morning, Eddie said.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's what was estimated.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand here a while. Listening to the BREAKERS hit the shore.</context>
      <utterance>Eight hours difference between here and London. Would've been, what, ten in the morning, my time. I was just coming out on the yard. Now, I was in the habit of saving my newspaper till then. Bit of fresh air, stretch me legs -- well, stretch the day out, really, that's what you wanna do. And I'll tell ya: I couldn't open the paper. Could not pry the pages apart -- it was like they was glued together. That's how weak my hands went. Thought I was having heart attack, only I knew I wasn't. Bloke come up to me, he says, Dave, he says, you've gone all white. I said, fuck me, I've been in prison half my life, what d'ya expect. But he was dead on, 'cause I could feel the blood drain right out of me head. And I knew ...  Something had happened to Jen.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's nothing I can't afford to lose. She goes to make coffee. Wilson looks around.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you even know who Terry Valentine is?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maybe a smile from Elaine at the quaintness of "pop" music.</context>
      <utterance>Well, I gathered something from the article what Eddie sent me. Some sort of pop music producer, wasn't it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rock n' roll, is what we called it. He's sort of a forgotten figure now, but back when the West Coast was the grooviest place on earth, Terry Valentine was where all the happenings happened. More of a kind of promoter, I guess, whatever that means. Just took that whole Southern California Sixties Zeitgeist and ran with it. Packaged and sold it. Made out like a bandit.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lives high off the hog and waits for the next big thing. Like me -- but on a grander scale of failure.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now, you shouldn't run yourself down. My employer, Mr. Lindgren --</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Your employer?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- Mr. Lindgren.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's Mr. Lindgren?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My employer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What line is he in.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Proprietor of a London firm. Of longstanding.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Based in London, but with international concerns.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Various enterprises, style of thing.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you said you never did an honest day's work in your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, not to say Mr. Lindgren is dishonest, exactly.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyhow, he's always saying to me, Dave, never run yourself down, son -- 'cause there'll always be plenty of people willing to do it for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In what capacity are you employed by this Mr. Lindgren?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This and that. Y'know. Ways and means.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They sort of come together -- in mutual understanding -- and sit down. Coffee steaming.</context>
      <utterance>-- When he wants someone run down, you're willing to do it for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's the deal. You and Terry Valentine at twenty paces. Is that what this is about.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you serious.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elaine looks away:</context>
      <utterance>Have you ever known me not to be.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You fuckin' guys and your dicks.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>[Fuck All].</context>
      <utterance>What'd you want me to do. Stay at home, twiddlin' me thumbs. Doing sweet F.A.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't believe it was a car accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Terry's never going to give you satisfaction. Not the type.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Depends, don' it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On what. What makes you so certain.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll bloody well ask him.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's the phone. You want his number.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That look again.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got his number.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Past caring.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She goes into a bathroom. Shutting the door behind her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not going to help you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sips coffee. Bites into a cookie.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gate's open. I had a butcher's at the house.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who'd you butcher at the house?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Butcher's hook. Look.  I don't much reckon those minders of his.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's brought in the heavy mob.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Extra muscle. Bodyguards.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Has he?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As one of the "bodyguards" runs by, only fleetingly glimpsed by us.</context>
      <utterance>They look a right load of wallies. Patrolling back and forth outside the gate, all ponced up like the fuckin' Household Cavalry.  Watch it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was one of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Off Ed's perplexed look ...</context>
      <utterance>See what I mean? Wearing bloomin' uniforms n' all.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's so fucking funny?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Those aren't guards. They're valets.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RESUME WILSON AND ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ed's still laughing.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valets. What d'ya mean valets. What is he, then, the Earl of fucking Doncaster?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>VALET</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Exchanges the key for a card -- which he turns over in his hand and studies curiously as they head inside.</context>
      <utterance>Cheers.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valets, eh? Aren't we all la-de-da.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you just wanted to check out the house, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, that's what we're doin', n' it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one else is even here yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Looking over to note the multi-car GARAGE off the main house.</context>
      <utterance>First in, first out, that's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now his whole dynamic with Ed is a verbal tease.</context>
      <utterance>Dubonnet with a twist? Baby sham? Tomato juice and Tabasco sauce?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got a Coke?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Valentine turns.</context>
      <utterance>You have the same posters.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmm?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine sits on the edge of the tub. With a nostalgic air as he looks at her: the embodiment of youth.</context>
      <utterance>That you have down at your office.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He strokes her wet skin. They kiss lightly.</context>
      <utterance>Different ones.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I like the colors.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We all did.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It must've been a time. A golden moment. Beat.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>With that exit line (practiced?), he starts to go. Then pauses, turns again.</context>
      <utterance>Have you ever dreamed of a place ... you don't really recall ever having been to ... a place that probably doesn't even exist except in your imagination ... somewhere far away, half-remembered when you wake up ... but when you were there you spoke the language, you knew your way around ...  That was the 60's.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Comes back to her. Faraway look in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>No, it wasn't. Wasn't either.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He goes.</context>
      <utterance>It was '66 ... early '67.  That was all.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And goes away. Leaving Ed more nervous than ever.</context>
      <utterance>Hi.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gets out of the tub and goes for the nearest towel. Quickly wrapping herself, she exits.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up and begins toweling her hair. After a moment she stops. Something isn't right. She looks around the room, and her eyes stop on the TV. Her brow furrows, trying to place the familiar image on the screen: a girl towel- drying her hair by the bed.</context>
      <utterance>Hello? Hey! Great. You got my message? Yeah. No, Crestview Terrace, not Crestview Place. Yeah, there's like three different ways up the hill; the quick way is to bear to the right. Sure. Okay. Okay. 'Bye!</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks over to see the video camera, which has been turned on and pointed toward the bed. She's not sure if it's funny or creepy.</context>
      <utterance>That's me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Makes her way across the room to Valentine.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, I thought you weren't a buffet person.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm a gracious host.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Watching them, when --</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson looks at him. Reluctantly.</context>
      <utterance>Excuse me?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't you work with Ian?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ian?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could swear I met you with Ian at the EMI offices in London.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry. Wasn't me.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unless I'm not who I think I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's too bad. Ian's got a good thing going over there.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turned that place completely around. 180 degrees.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No kidding.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What I like about Ian, he believes in a chain of command, but not a chain of respect, you understand what I'm saying?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right. Chain of respect. That's good, that.</utterance>
   <speaker>GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Good to meet you.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. I really admire the guy. Well.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Guy leaves. Wilson sees that Adhara is now on the other side of the room, separated from Valentine. He heads for her.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Cheers, mate.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you could afford a house like this you would buy a house like this. Wilson edges forward to the rail again.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are we standing on?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stand there looking out. Quite a view once you get used to it. Breeze. ED (cont'd) (nods to the hazy distance) You could see the sea from here if you could see it.</context>
      <utterance>Faith.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But now Ed gives Wilson a nudge -- SEEING that Valentine inside the house is making his way out here.</context>
      <utterance>Could you?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you go nick one of those little cooker what's its warming up the sausages cocktail and meet me in the garage. Look about for a toolbox while you're at it. Ed considers. His is not to reason why.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed moves off. Valentine steps up, smile fully loaded.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He extends his hand. Wilson shakes it.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. Terry Valentine.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pleasure.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Have we met? There's something I can't quite --</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>EMI in London. I work with Ian.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ah.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You must know Ian.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Great bloke. Really turned things around there. 180 degrees.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I suppose that's good, unless things were fine the way they were.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson looks at him. Valentine looks back. Something about those eyes ...</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I think a shake-up was in order. Definitely. Otherwise, people get lazy, don't they? Forgetful. Start thinking they can get away with things. Gotta shake 'em up now and again, make 'em pay attention.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXCITED GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Excited Guy appears, tugging at Valentine.</context>
      <utterance>Terry, Terry ...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Glad I got to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXCITED GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ter ... Ter ... you gotta ...</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks. You, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Excited Guy ushers Valentine away. Wilson watches him go.</context>
      <utterance>Be seein' you.</utterance>
   <speaker>EXCITED GUY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Charles Grodin is here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed points to a table, where a toolbox sits. Wilson crosses to it, begins going through the contents.</context>
      <utterance>Toolbox?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed does. Wilson pulls a brace-and-bit from the toolbox and crosses to the rear of one of the cars. Dropping to the ground, he bores a hole in the gas tank. Ed raises his eyebrows and moves toward the door. Wilson crosses to the other car and puts a hole in that gas tank as well. Then he puts the brace-and-bit back in the toolbox and heads for the exit, Ed right behind him, giving a quick backward glance.</context>
      <utterance>Put the Sterno on the ground, near the center of the garage.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You goin' back inside?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>One thing I need.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>THE GARAGE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is smoke coming from under the door.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You steady on, man. What the fuck else did you do back there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CURVE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Car makes it around on two side wheels.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gulps.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed regains control.</context>
      <utterance>Bloody hell.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In his car, takes a different turn.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That would be too easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Too easy?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gotta know why.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly out of nowhere -- (a side street) -- BAM! -- another car shoots out to cut them off, sideswiping them.</context>
      <utterance>You think a fuckin' guy like that ever will? What more do you want, man?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Calls frantically to Wilson from their car.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SIRENS in the distance.</context>
      <utterance>C'mon, man! C'mon!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, because you're my security consultant?  This cocksucker nearly burnt my house down.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine blows air, runs a hand through his hair.</context>
      <utterance>What did you tell them.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told them a long-time employee flipped out. Had a drug problem, refused counselling. Set the garage on fire, then committed suicide. One of my "guests" tried to stop him --</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Heavier than that now. But are there any drugs in that stomach to back up your story.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As it happens. I didn't make that part up.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And where is this guest? Don't they want to interview him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know everyone here. He was so traumatized he split.  Maybe he was Gordon's</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. I mean. Not even your people should be involved. Right? It's too close now.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could use a few of my prime shitkickers up here.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think I'm staying?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's already gonna be talk about how people close to you keep falling into canyons.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's being glib, but he's being serious. His open-handed gesture inquiring of Avery: are you up to the task?</context>
      <utterance>Well, can we make it one more. Nowhere the fuck near me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to go.</context>
      <utterance>I have other resources.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Makes contact.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stacy turns to see him. Uncle John looks vacantly.</context>
      <utterance>Stacy.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That was in the way of an order. He nods around the corner where it's less crowded. Stacy stops Uncle John from following, and goes after Avery.</context>
      <utterance>Come over here.</utterance>
   <speaker>THOMPSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>At the bar. Keeping his eye on them.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Speaks softly. Alone with Stacy.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How they goin', kid?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not bad.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How'd you like to kill someone for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Avery gives him an envelope.</context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same as last time -- the rest after.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where do we go?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When you find the guy, you'll know.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What shit is this. I just do it. I don't prepare it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll point you in the right direction, but you'll have to take it to the end- zone. He's a hit-and-run gunman -- I figure he's not cruising the Polo Lounge.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is un-fucking professional.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See, a successful man like me has limitations -- I lose touch at a street level. So I have to depend on a smart boy like you who's closer to the nitty and the gritty than I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is a lifestyle I embrace.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck you, Mr. whatever-your-name is.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why I'm letting you take care of this. I'm the one with appearances to maintain. But who gives a shit about you? Not even God.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jenny was supposed to come to my place that night. She called me, asked if she could come over. She and Terry had been -- having some trouble. Lately. I don't know about what. On this occasion, it reached some sort of crisis point.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She told you all about my details but not about his. Lovely.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'd never called me like that before. She sounded more ... pissed off -- angry -- than upset or afraid. But she never turned up. I called the house but only got the answer machine. When they found her ... she'd been going the wrong way. Not the direction she'd have gone if she'd been coming to see me. Or coming</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think Terry gave me access to her things? Probably sold her clothes.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elaine looks at him.</context>
      <utterance>And how did you get it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five thousand.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got half.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Makin' trouble for someone?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Which kind?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The forever kind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This town's been chewing my flesh since ... what we now refer to as "the early 70's."  Christ, my past became nostalgia and no one even asked me.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Early 70's. I was away.  Maidstone. Possibly Brixton.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson looks at her: she's the one who goes to bed with ex- cons.</context>
      <utterance>These more highlights from the Zagat prison guide?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't seem bothered.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know how I've compromised my standards.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell us about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's too involved; a lifetime of non- involvement. Anywhere else I'd be an interesting little number, here I'm just SAG number forty-eight thousand and one.  SAG meaning Screen Actor's Guild.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, I was gonna say ...</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Still, there have been rewards. It's sunny. And some of the producers who call even have credits.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glances up at him to try and see how he means that. Is he looking at her or out the window?</context>
      <utterance>I can see the attraction.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do? To make them take the early 70's away from you.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A jeweller's up the West End. We tunnelled our way under the shop floor from the public lavatory down the road. Filthy work. Trouble was, the bloody thing collapsed --</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We were</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>From pursuing your chosen profession.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell ya something: it made me a model prisoner. Put me right off any escape attempts. Tunnel my way to freedom after that experience? Not bloody likely.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was inside once. I punched a cop at a demo.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you. What was that in aid of?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who remembers.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get seven years, did you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Overnight. What about just now?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just now?  Overnight?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Honest. Didn't know where to look till I was 21.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands again, vaguely disappointing her.</context>
      <utterance>Pushing the legal limit even then.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Me mate introduced me to a woman up the street. Funnily enough, she was married to a milkman. Straight up. I said, "Good is she? Been around?" He said, "</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Adhara looks back over her shoulder. Checking the road behind.</context>
      <utterance>All your life. That happened while I swam the length of my pool.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the matter?</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. I guess it's hard to pass on this road.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The freeway's faster, but lacks a certain majesty.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just feels like the car behind has been following us the longest time.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sure hope so.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever take a look at the women who work in pet stores? Wow.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus, are you gay enough or what.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Very attractive. Good idea. Now I</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Kinda makes you wonder why more people don't put a bullet through their fuckin' skulls, doesn't it.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks like they just airbrushed the dick out of his mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>FAMILY OF LOSERS. Wouldn't that be good?</context>
      <utterance>Why don't they have TV shows about people whose daily lives you'd be interested in watching. Y'know. Like SKINNY LITTLE WEAKLING. Or BIG FAT GUY. SICK OLD MAN.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two blacks and a Mexican in a car. Who's driving?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The L.A.P.D.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh yeah, keep doing that. That's really healthy.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can't you do something about your ass?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Other people's lives scare the shit out of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Homeless" people. Fuck them. Remember when they were just bums? Everyone with an axe to grind. Like to grind in their face. Pretty soon there'll be shit-in- your-pants rights groups. Stupidity activists.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wonder what it's like being a dumb guy in a dumb suit trying to cross the street.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life sure is a minefield.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look at that one. She's really been used.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Uncle John speaks.</context>
      <utterance>I'd love to be famous so I could snub ordinary people. Imagine, you're famous, you're sitting in a restaurant, some fool comes up to you, wants you to sign your name on his napkin, his wife is there, it would be something these poor saps would cherish the rest of their lives, talk about to their cretin friends. Bam! You tell 'em to FUCK OFF! God, I'd love that.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stacy turns.</context>
      <utterance>Is that her? I bet that's her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Avery said she was tight with his daughter.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stacy knows better than to argue with a moron.</context>
      <utterance>That don't mean nothin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's nice lookin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. I just said she's nice lookin'.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And I said so what. You think she's any happier?</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What d'you mean, any happier?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pause.</context>
      <utterance>Any happier than any other asshole in life.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I dunno. I never met her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="18">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever been to London?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Only in the movies.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've 'ardly ever left it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, well, you're here now --  -- where</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stick with me, kid. Looks big when you get here but you can cover it in five minutes. Beat. ELAINE  So, is there anybody in your family who's not a criminal?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not that I recall.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about your grandmother?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crafty old sod.</context>
      <utterance>Nah -- she was married to me grandad -- he was as bent as a boomerang -- used to make knuckle-dusters down the shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He alive to see this?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dropped dead in the stalls in the Odeon, Muswell Hill. Watching Doris Day.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd your father do?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elaine shakes her head.</context>
      <utterance>Black market during the war.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I guess you're just habitual.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sound like my fucking probation officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Won't he be looking for you about now?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good luck to him. He couldn't find his prick if he didn't wear Y-fronts.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Minor officials bother you, don't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do us a favor. Can't even go have a slash without 'em saying, what're you going in there for?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a steady income -- I'm on the dole.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>You don't miss a trick.</context>
      <utterance>A leech on the welfare state in addition.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elaine sort of shares a laugh at that.</context>
      <utterance>I fiddle it. They got me down as an immigrant with five kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Though real ones might have been nice. This an unspoken thought between them. ELAINE (cont'd) Do you remember the last time you saw her?</context>
      <utterance>Yeah ... Jenny spoke fondly of her imaginary siblings.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last time might as well've been the first. I remember all the times, don't I. Watching her grow up --  in increments.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She told me you were a ghost in her life. Daddy the friendly ghost. Coming back to haunt her.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she twigged by the time she was eight or nine that daddy wasn't in the Royal Marines or doing scientific research in the jungles of Borneo or playing Iago in a worldwide tour of</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>Still, you could never ... do what she wanted.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She used to tell me she'd turn me in.  Little kid. Ten year old. "If you're naughty, Dad, I'll tell on ya." She didn't want me sent down again, see. When I was planning some job. "I'll tell 'em, Dad, I promise I will. Here, look, I'm calling the Old Bill right now" -- picking up the telephone. I can see her, the phone in her hand. Became a sort of joke between us. Only it wasn't a joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She never would have turned you in, not in a million years.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>well, it</context>
      <utterance>I know that. But as time went on ...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>FEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's one thing I don't understand.  The thing I don't understand ... is every motherfucking thing you're saying.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look, mush, you're the guv'nor here, I can see that, I'm on your manor now, right. So there's no need to get out of your pram. I'm Johnny-come-lately to all this. Whatever the bollocks between you and this slag Valentine, it's got nothing to do with me. I don't wanna know.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, I'll tell you. I believe this Valentine screwed me out of a fair sum of money.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can well believe it. I'm sure he has done, son. He's about as straight as a dog's hind leg.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I can't be sure. I don't even know who he is. He's too insulated. Too many layers around him.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your guess is as good as mine, mate. I'm here on another matter entirely.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I guess you are.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good job your lot showed up when they did or it would've been</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Shouldn't wonder. Must've done.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So what's your beef, pal?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing financial. Strictly personal.  I can see how all this import-export malarkey might give rise to confusion where I'm concerned. A foreigner, showing up unexpectedly, like.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It was you. Downtown.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eh?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because that wasn't anything to do with me. And suspicion has been cast in my direction.  Didn't make any sense. Choosing those shitheads over me, cutting me out of the deal, then screwing them over too.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I can reassure you on that point. Valentine was just as surprised by that turn of events as you.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He'd already grabbed more than his allotted cut. Didn't think he'd be so bold as to take all of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All of what?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of the deal, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, yeah, right. The deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if you're mad at him too and he's mad at you ... that must make us pals.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As you prefer, squire. As you prefer.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In which case I'll just do what I usually do.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And that is?</utterance>
   <speaker>FEATHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He's standing at the window, staring out. As if Wilson isn't even in the room any more. A ship being loaded out there. Inspectors with clipboards. Trucks like the ones we saw at that warehouse downtown.</context>
      <utterance>What am I doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looking the other way.  Gotcha.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're playing against a couple of other creeps.</context>
      <utterance>Lemme break.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You broke last time.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let him break - he likes to break.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fuck you.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wouldn't talk.</utterance>
   <speaker>CREEP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Huh?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Creep rushes Stacy. But doesn't get past Uncle John. Who drops him with one punch. Flooring him between two pool tables. Stacy then goes over. Supports himself with a hand on each table, swings his boot into the thug's face.</context>
      <utterance>I saw your mother on the Strip last night. She went up to three guys, said she'd like 'em to stick one in each, know what I mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>BARTENDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Stacy looks. Bartender holds up phone. Stacy goes over. BARTENDER (cont'd) I can do without you inhibiting my business. Stacy just scowls, takes the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Stacy.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Breaks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>FIELDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My client has already given a statement regarding yesterday's events.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your client have a deal in Long Beach? How about downtown? There's some folks there -- oh, wait, they're all dead. Any of this ring a bell?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIELDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My client is an entrepreneur. I am his lawyer, not his business manager.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you wouldn't have any idea how your client continues to make so much fucking money.</utterance>
   <speaker>FIELDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He invested wisely.</context>
      <utterance>He's always been very forward-thinking.</utterance>
   <speaker>GRAMMS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he now?</utterance>
   <speaker>FIELDING</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Gramms just laughs. Just laughs and laughs. And we leave him laughing. And Fielding not.</context>
      <utterance>He had urgent business in the north.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Up the coast.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How far?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know -- few hours, I guess.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fancy it?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I could use a vacation. Of course, I keep forgetting, for you this</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's in Big Sur?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's where Valentine's scarpered.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you know?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another beat.</context>
      <utterance>Bloke told me. Beat. WILSON   You shouldn't go back to your place. Not till ... this is resolved.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hear it's a nice drive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not much -- you?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-huh.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Last time I saw you, weren't you up for some equity-waiver thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Probably.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was gonna be in that Michael Mann movie, you know -- with Pacino and DeNiro. Got three callbacks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Really.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Didn't get it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, those are the breaks.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not no more, they ain't. I quit that acting shit, man.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You just cooking then?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Elaine and Wilson exchange glances.</context>
      <utterance>Hell, no. I started writing.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's more than a measly few grand in this.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There is?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Something's on.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I happen to know more about Mr. Whatever- his-name-is than he thinks I know about him and his operation.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You bet.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like what.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Like he'd never hire me for real. Not week-to-week. I don't have the credentials. He thinks I'm just a sociopath, someone he can turn to when he needs "plausible denial."</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, we blew it, didn't we? He ain't wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"He ain't wrong." Listen, I know this asshole who</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Maybe a buyer. But Mr.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know who that English guy is. Some kind of --  -- courier or something. Maybe a seller.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Drugs? Cash? Both if we're lucky.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How we gonna get that lucky?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>While they're all fucking each other over ... couple of parties like us could move right in.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Again?</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have any friends, man?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, I suppose. Call 'em that, yeah. Down the boozer Saturday night. Meet some of the lads.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Friends and</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Little back-seat sarcasm there. Wilson looks kind of bitter.</context>
      <utterance>Poor baby.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Useless gits. I was gonna do the Post Office once.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What post office?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The lot. The whole British bloody Post Office. I had a brilliant plan -- all worked out -- work of genius, it was. Could I get anybody interested? No -- they're too busy pinching orange squash from the milkman. Lazy sods. Jumble sale on in Watford, they'll be up at the crack of dawn.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just on a higher plane, Wilson.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Flicks some cigarette pack paper out the window.</context>
      <utterance>Too bleeding true, 'n' it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing here?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Exercising my visitation rights.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Since when?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I miss my kids.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine goes inside.</context>
      <utterance>They're at college. Or doesn't your accountant even tell you where the money goes anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want you here, Terry.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to look at her. Smiles. Somehow it doesn't work on her. One of the reasons she divorced him. Just one. She sighs. Resigned to his presence. Starts to close the door. VALENTINE (cont'd) Don't shut the door -- I have people with me. Now she gets it.</context>
      <utterance>Sure you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What kind of trouble are you in?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Susan SEES Adhara get out of the sporty car parked in the drive and stand against it in a posture of younger chick defiance.</context>
      <utterance>No trouble.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Surely you can think of somewhere else to take one of your chippies for a quick getaway.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He actually puts his hands on her arms. To hold her firm while he locks onto her eyes. And doesn't smile. VALENTINE (cont'd) I just need ... somewhere remote. Away from L.A. For a couple of days. (now the kicker) I pay for this house too. Susan reads him. He's not claiming ownership rights. He's telling her this house, because of the connection to him, is a target of some kind.</context>
      <utterance>Susan.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Land Cruiser pulls up outside. Avery emerges, comes over, comes in. Susan notes the bodyguards out there as well.</context>
      <utterance>What have you done?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine lets Susan go. Knowing she's now speechless at what's turned into, as far as she's concerned, a home invasion.</context>
      <utterance>We weren't followed.  Susan.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where's ... what's-his-name -- Fred --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>-- You know his name is Frank.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is he here?</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I don't live with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go to him. Go to his studio, or writers workshop or artists colony, Esselin retreat, nudist camp --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you finished?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>In a couple of days this whole thing --</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's looking for you?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Encouraging, if not in fact ushering, her towards a bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>Go now.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's been five minutes and I'm packing to leave again. I can't believe this.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right, your life is Shit, and I'm to blame. It's that simple. That does it. Susan turns on him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SUSAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Elaine. You even know what he's saying half the time?</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, but I know what he means.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ed sighs. Awkward.</context>
      <utterance>Hard to miss.</utterance>
   <speaker>ED</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought maybe you just came for the ride.</utterance>
   <speaker>ELAINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson walks back to them. Looking at Ed as if to say, ready to go? At her as if to say ... maybe farewell.</context>
      <utterance>I'd rather be with him than without him. I don't want to be found dead in L.A.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His brow furrows.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Notices this, looks out toward the backyard.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIS POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same as before, except Larry isn't there.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Turn all the lights out. I'll get Adhara. Tom begins looking for the light switches.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Avery is already heading for the bedroom.</context>
      <utterance>What's happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay away from the windows.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need you to come with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes her by the arm. Firmly, but not roughly.</context>
      <utterance>Why, what --</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sees in his expression that something is up.</context>
      <utterance>Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Valentine and Tom move to join Avery and Adhara.</context>
      <utterance>Everybody in the kitchen.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Everyone moves behind the large counter in the center of the kitchen and crouches down. They have a wall behind them and all the windows in front of them.</context>
      <utterance>Behind the counter.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Avery and Tom have drawn their guns.</context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We think someone is here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We think?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We can't find ...  ... two of our guys.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Larry and Rick.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom snorts. Avery looks at Valentine: Haven't you told this girl anything?</context>
      <utterance>Did somebody call the cops?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because --</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I'm taking care of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You guys are fucking nuts, I'm calling -- She starts to stand. Valentine pulls her down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Avery looks to Tom, who nods toward the back porch.</context>
      <utterance>Mr. Avery.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Locked on him, waiting.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Puts Adhara's hand to her ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We see a little more now than we have before.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>THE FIGURE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hit. Spinning and collapsing to the ground.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lowers his gun. Turns to Tom.</utterance>
   <speaker>AVERY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Avery moves out from behind the counter and heads for the body.</context>
      <utterance>Watch my back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Avery's down.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM'S POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A piece of Uncle John's silhouette appears.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fires at it. Didn't hit anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>TOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tom jumps up and runs for the living room, firing his gun in front of him toward where he last saw Uncle John's silhouette.</context>
      <utterance>Fuck this.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Looks over the edge of the porch.</utterance>
   <speaker>HIS POV</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tom turning toward the steps.</utterance>
   <speaker>UNCLE JOHN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fires at him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ADHARA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIVING ROOM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Valentine runs to the sliding door, smack into:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bounces off the couch and onto the floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Comes toward him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now stands before him.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE TWO OF THEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Both breathing hard.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>This is not what Valentine expected.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me.</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell you ...</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>About Jenny.  Tell me about Jenny.  About the</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She could've had the deal! I would've handed it to her if she wanted. I would have given her everything.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson sits back. Panting. Totally spent. The two of them. Both on the ground now. Whatever energy they had left drained -- Valentine from his confession, Wilson from hearing it. Valentine shaking, sobbing. Still not realizing the pathetic folly of his actions.</context>
      <utterance>She said, "You go ahead with this, I'll turn you in, Terry."</utterance>
   <speaker>VALENTINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She was serious. She would have done it. She had the phone in her hand. She was going to do it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, that's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Leaving home, or coming back.</context>
      <utterance>I can never decide what I like better.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Takes this in.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson nods.</context>
      <utterance>You're a reluctant traveller, then.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Another little matter needs attending to soon as I return.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wilson nods, exhales.</context>
      <utterance>No rest for the wicked.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Longer beat. He actually turns to look at her now. Takes her in, then looks forward again.</context>
      <utterance>Where else?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Nine years.</context>
      <utterance>Out on a oil rig. In the North Sea.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nine years?  Is that legal?</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, time off for good behavior, you know. I shouldn't have even been there -- it was these other blokes who shoulda gone in my place. I got lumbered with the job they were responsible for. I don't mind pulling me own cart, but not someone else's, know what I mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you stuck it out, anyway, all that time.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to, didn't I. Nothing else for it. Then just when I'd finished my nine years -- my contract -- wallop, I had to bugger off to the States.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sounds like you need a rest.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Another beat.</context>
      <utterance>Could do, yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But first I gotta give these lads a talking to, these geezers what sent me up the river, in a manner of speaking.</utterance>
   <speaker>LADY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The ones whose burden you took upon your own shoulders.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And he turns away, to the window. Looks at the blue sky. Sips his drink. Then, hard:</context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>WILSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Them next.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
