<movie id="494" title="Silence of the Lambs">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>excellent. Let's break. Critique in five. A class of about forty young FBI trainees, of both sexes, begins to rise from their seats, mingling and chatting. Clarice nods amiably to the "Suspect", then gives her "Hostage" a hand up. It's ARDELIA MAPP, her roommate. Her broad, clever face breaks into a big smile, as they both remove ear plugs. Clarice's voice has just a soft trace of southern accent.</context>
      <utterance>Starling's reaction time was</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Damn, Clarice, how'd you make me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never cock. Just squeeze.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes out a steel-coiled grip flexer, drops it onto her palm.</context>
      <utterance>What're you laughin' at, Junior G- Man? She got off four rounds to your two.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What'd I do?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stay cool. Just remember to call him "God."</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starling, Clarice M., good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning, Mr. Crawford.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your instructors tell me you're doing well. Top quarter of the class.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I hope so. They haven't posted anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They begin to cross the academy grounds. A group of trainees jogs by, in matching sweats, following a p.e. coach.</context>
      <utterance>A job's come up and I thought about you. Not really a job, more of - an interesting errand. Walk me to my car, Starling.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're trying to interview all of the serial killers now in custody, for a psychobehavioral profile. Could be a big help in unsolved cases. Most of them have been happy to talk to us. They have a compulsion to boast, these people... Do you spook easily, Starling?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, the one we want most refuses to cooperate. I want you to go after him again today, in the asylum.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's the subject?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice stops walking, goes very still. A beat.</context>
      <utterance>The psychiatrist - Dr. Hannibal Lecter.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crawford doesn't respond, except to study her face.</context>
      <utterance>The cannibal...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, well... Okay, right. I'm glad for the chance, sir, but - why me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He walks on again, at a faster clip. She hurried to keep up.</context>
      <utterance>You're qualified and available. And frankly, I can't spare a real agent right now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They're reached his car. His driver stamps on a cigarette, climbs in behind the wheel. BURROUGHS, his assistant, says something into a walkie-talkie, then opens the back door. But Crawford pulls her aside, a hand on her shoulder. His intensity is scary.</context>
      <utterance>I don't expect him to talk to you, but I have to be able to say we tried... Lecter was a brilliant psychiatrist, and he knows all the dodges.  Dossier on him, copy of our questionnaire, special ID for you... If he won't talk, then I want straight reporting. How's he look, how's his cell look, what's he writing? The Director himself will see your report, over your own signature - if I decide it's good enough. I want that by 0800 Wednesday, and keep this to yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now. I want your full attention, Starling. Are you listening to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Be very careful with Hannibal Lecter. Dr. Chilton at the asylum will go over the physical procedures used with him. Do not deviate from them, for any reason. You tell him nothing personal, Starling. Believe me, you don't want Hannibal Lecter inside your head... Just do your job, but never forget what he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what is that, sir?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, he's a monster. A pure psychopath...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>DR. FREDERICK CHILTON looks up from her card. A smarmy little peacock, behind a vast desk; he's conceived an instant, hopeless letch for Clarice. He smiles, stroking her card with his beloved gold pen.</context>
      <utterance>It's so rare to capture one alive. From a research point of view, Dr. Lecter is our most prized asset...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know, we get a lot of detectives here, but I must say, I can't ever remember one so attractive...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice tries, unsuccessfully, to hide her distaste for him.</context>
      <utterance>Will you be in Baltimore overnight...? Because this can be quite a fun town, if you have the right guide.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sure it's a great town, Dr. Chilton, but my instructions are to talk to Lecter and report back this afternoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see.  Let's make this quick, then. I'm busy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lecter carved up nine people - that we're sure of - and cooked his favorite bits. We've tried to study him, of course - but he's much too sophisticated for the standard tests. And my, does he hate us! Thinks I'm his nemesis... Crawford's very clever, isn't he? Using you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How do you mean, Dr. Chilton?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A pretty young woman, to turn him on? I don't believe Lecter's ever seen a woman in eight years. And oh, are you ever his "taste" - so to speak.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I graduated magna from UVA, Doctor. It's not a charm school.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good. Then you should be able to remember the rules.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do not reach through the bars, do not touch the bars. You pass him nothing but soft paper - no pens or pencils. No staples or paperclips in his paper. Use the sliding food carrier, no exceptions. Do not accept anything he attempts to hold out to you. Do you understand me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I understand.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hands Clarice a small, dog-eared photo. Looking at it, she is stopped in her tracks. This pleases Chilton.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to show you why we insist on such precautions... On the afternoon of July 8, 1981, he complained of chest pains and was taken to the dispensary. His mouthpiece and restraints were removed for an EKG. When the nurse bent over him, he did this to her...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns, pushes a button. A steel door BUZZES slowly open, and BARNEY - a big, impassive orderly - awaits them in an anteroom. On its walls: restraints, mouthpieces, Mace, tranquilizer guns.</context>
      <utterance>The doctors managed to re-set her jaw, more or less, and save one of her eyes. His pulse never got over eighty-five, even when he ate her tongue.  I keep him in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Chilton - if Lecter feels you're his enemy - as you've said - then maybe I'll have more luck by myself. What do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might have suggested that in my office, and saved me the time.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She holds out the photo. A beat. He grabs it, jaw twitching.</context>
      <utterance>But then I would've missed the pleasure of your company.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns on his heel, goes. Barney smiles reassuringly.</context>
      <utterance>When she's finished, bring her out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hi, I'm Barney. He told you, don't get near the bars?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clarice Starling. Yes, he did.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Sensing her tension, he indicates a nearby security monitor.</context>
      <utterance>Okay. Past the others, it's the last cell. Stay to the middle. I put out a chair for you.</utterance>
   <speaker>BARNEY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice nods gratefully. She looks down the long corridor, takes a deep breath, walks into it. He watches her go.</context>
      <utterance>I'm watching. You'll do fine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="43">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Hannibal Lecter is lounging on his bunk, in white pajamas, reading an Italian Vogue. He turns, considers her... A face so long out of the sun, it seems almost leached - except for the glittering eyes, and the wet red mouth. He rises smoothly, crossing to stand before her; the gracious host. His voice is cultured, soft.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Lecter... My name is Clarice Starling. May I talk with you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good morning.</utterance>
   <speaker>CUTTING BETWEEN THEM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as Clarice comes a measured distance closer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Doctor, we have a hard problem in psychological profiling. I want to ask for your help with a questionnaire.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"We" being the Behavioral Science Unit, at Quantico. You're one of Jack Crawford's, I expect.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I am, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice is surprised, but fishes her ID card from her bag, holds it up for his inspection. He smiles, soothingly.</context>
      <utterance>May I see your credentials?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She complies each time, trying to hide her fear. Dr. Lecter's nostrils lift, as he gently, like an animal, tests the air. Then he smiles, glancing at her card.</context>
      <utterance>Closer, please... Clo-ser...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That expires in one week. You're not real FBI, are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm - still in training at the Academy.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack Crawford sent a trainee to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're talking about psychology, Doctor, not the Bureau. Can you decide for yourself whether or not I'm qualified?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits in the folding metal desk-chair. He waits politely till she's settled, then sits down himself, faces her happily.</context>
      <utterance>Mmmmm... That's rather slippery of you, Officer Starling. Sit. Please.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now then. What did Miggs say to you?  "Multiple Miggs," in the next cell. He hissed at you. What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He said - "I can smell your cunt."</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see. I myself cannot. You use Evyan skin cream, and sometimes you wear L'Air du Temps, but not today. You brought your best bag, though, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's much better than your shoes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe they'll catch up.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no doubt of it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you do those drawings, Doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. That's the Duomo, seen from the Belvedere. Do you know Florence?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All that detail, just from memory...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A pause, then Clarice takes the questionnaire from her case.</context>
      <utterance>Memory, Officer Starling, is what I have instead of view.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Lecter, if you'd please consider -</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, no, no. You were doing fine, you'd been courteous and receptive to courtesy, you'd established trust with the embarrassing truth about Miggs, and now this ham-handed segue into your questionnaire. It won't do. It's stupid and boring.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm only asking you to look at this, Doctor. Either you will or you won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack Crawford must be very busy indeed if he's recruiting help from the student body. Busy hunting that new one, Buffalo Bill... Such a naughty boy! Did Crawford send you to ask for my advice on him?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, I came because we need -</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How many women has he used, our Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Five... so far.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All flayed...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Partially, yes. But Doctor, that's an active case, I'm not involved. If -</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know why he's called Buffalo Bill? Tell me. The newspapers won't say.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you if you'll look at this form.  It started as a bad joke in Kansas City Homicide. They said... this one likes to skin his humps.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Witless and misleading. Why do you think he takes their skins, Officer Starling? Thrill me with your wisdom.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It excites him. Most serial killers keep some sort of trophies.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A tense beat, then a smile from him, at this small boldness.</context>
      <utterance>No. You ate yours.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rolls him the questionnaire, in his sliding food tray. He rises, glances at it, turning a page or two disdainfully.</context>
      <utterance>Send that through.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, Officer Starling... do you think you can dissect me with this blunt little tool?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly he whips the tray back at her, with a metallic CLANG that makes her start. His voice remains a pleasant purr.</context>
      <utterance>No. I only hoped that your knowledge -</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sooo ambitious, aren't you...? You know what you look like to me, with your good bag and your cheap shoes? You look like a rube. A well- scrubbed, hustling rube with a little, taste... Good nutrition has given you some length of bone, but you're not more than one generation from poor white trash, are you Officer Starling...? That accent you're trying so desperately to shed - pure West Virginia. What was your father, dear? Was he a coal miner? Did he stink of the lamp...? And oh, how quickly the boys found you! All those tedious, sticky fumblings, in the back seats of cars, while you could only dream of getting out. Getting anywhere - yes? Getting all the way - to the</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see a lot, Dr. Lecter. But are you strong enough to point that high- powered perception at yourself? How about it...? Look at yourself and write down the truth.  Or maybe you're afraid to.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're a tough one, aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Reasonably so. Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you'd hate to think you were common. My, wouldn't that sting! Well you're far from common, Officer Starling. All you have is the fear of it.  Now please excuse me. Good day.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And the questionnaire...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He steps backwards, then returns to his cot, becoming as still and remote as a statue. Frustrated, Clarice hesitates, then finally shoulders her bag and goes, leaving the questionnaire in his tray. But after just a few steps, as she passes -</context>
      <utterance>A census taker once tried to test me. I ate his liver with some fava beans and a nice chianti... Fly back to school, little Starling.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I would not have had that happen to you. Discourtesy is - unspeakably ugly to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then please - do this test for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. But I will make you happy... I'll give you a chance for what you love most, Clarice Starling.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that, Dr. Lecter?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Advancement, of course.  Go to Split City. See Miss Mofet, an old patient of mine. M-O-F-E-T... Now go. Go.  I don't think Miggs could manage again so soon, even if he is crazy - do you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phone call, Clarice. It's God.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, Ardelia.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You missed Fourth Amendment law. Unlawful seizure, real juicy stuff. Where were you all afternoon?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ardelia stares at her, figures it's a put-on, laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Pleading with a crazy man, with come all over my face.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice grins, as Ardelia indicates a phone receiver resting on the check-out desk, then moves on. Clarice picks it up.</context>
      <utterance>Damn. Wish I had time for a social life.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Crawford?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all there, sir, practically verbatim.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every word, Starling? Every gesture?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right down to the kleenex I used.  Sir, why? Is something wrong?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He mentioned a name, at the very end. "Mofet..." Any followup on her?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pauses, expecting some soft of approval for her cleverness.</context>
      <utterance>I spent all evening on the mainframe. Lecter altered or destroyed most of his patient histories, prior to capture. No record of anyone named Mofet. But "Split City" sounded like it might have have something to do with divorce. I tracked it down in the library's catalogue of national yellow pages.  It's a mini-storage facility outside Baltimore, where Lecter had his practice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well? Why aren't you there right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, that's a field job. It's outside the scope of my assignment. And I've got a test tomorrow on -</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you recall my instructions to you, Starling? What were they?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>To complete and file my report by 0800 Wednesday. But sir -</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then do that, Starling. Do just exactly that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, what is it? There's something you're not telling me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Miggs has been murdered.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Murdered...? How?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The orderly heard Lecter whispering to him, all afternoon, and Miggs crying. They found him at bed check. He'd swallowed his own tongue... Chilton is scared stiff the family will file a civil rights lawsuit, and he's trying to blame it on you. I told the little prick your conduct was flawless.  Starling...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm here, sir, I just - I don't know how to feel about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to feel any way about it. Lecter did it to amuse himself. Why not, what can they do? Take away his books for awhile, and no jello...  I know it got ugly today. But this is your report, Starling - take it as far as you can. On your own time, outside of class. Now carry on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MR. YOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not to my knowledge. Privacy is a great concern to my customers. But, if you say this is an FBI matter...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Slinging her camera over a shoulder, she tugs at the handle, but the door won't budge. Another tug, harder - no good. Mr. Yow stoops to help, puffing hard, but it's firmly stuck. He sighs.</context>
      <utterance>I won't disturb anything, Mr. Yow, I promise. Be gone before you know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. YOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice crosses to her Pinto, which faces the shed, reaches in to turn on her headlights. Mr. Yow blinks in the sudden brightness. Then she opens her truck, rummaging inside, and returns with a bumper jack, a flashlight, and a rubber floor mat.</context>
      <utterance>We could return tomorrow, with my son. Or perhaps some workmen...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gives him her flashlight and camera, drops the mat on the ground, then sets the bumper jack in place, under the center of the door. She pumps on the jack handle as the door SQUEALS slowly up, but it won't go higher than about 18 inches, despite all her exertions. She spreads out the rubber mat on the cement, takes the flashlight from Mr. Yow, then lies on the mat.</context>
      <utterance>Would you hold these, please?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. YOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice turns onto her back, starts squirming under the door.</context>
      <utterance>It smells like mice... I think I hear them, too - don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. YOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're going in there?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Yow, if this door should fall down -ha ha! - or anything else - would you be kind enough to call this number? It's our Baltimore field office. They know you're here with me... Do you understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. YOW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Might I suggest tucking your pants into your socks? To prevent mouse intrusion.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good idea.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. YOW</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Miss Starling?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She shines her light around. In its narrow beam, we see -</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Mr. Yow...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MR. YOW</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're playing a piano, Miss Starling?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That wasn't me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. YOW</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Clarice crawls a bit further. There's hardly room to stand, but she finally manages to wriggle upright, clawing away cobwebs, next to the car. Holding her light under one arm, she takes several FLASH photos of the shed's interior, ending with the car. Then, slinging her camera over the shoulder, she folds back the tarp, resting it on the roof. The resulting clouds of dust make her cough.</context>
      <utterance>Oh.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Yow? Oh Mr. Yow...? It looks like somebody is sitting in this car.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. YOW</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh my! Oh my... Maybe you better come out now, Miss Starling.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans down with her camera, takes a FLASH through the gap, then tries the door handle. Locked. So is the front door. She looks around, aiming her light, and locates a tangle of coat-hangers, sticking out of a carton of bric-a-brac. She pulls out one of these, straightens it quickly, bends the tip into a hook.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet! - just wait for me.  Maybe in about two seconds.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>PAN TO Clarice, with her wet hair plastered flat, sitting on the corridor floor to one side of this TV, which has been stationed so that Dr. Lecter cannot avoid seeing it.</context>
      <utterance>It's an anagram, isn't it, Doctor?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hester Mofet... "The rest of me." Miss The-Rest-of-Me... Meaning, you rented that place.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="32">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The food carrier suddenly SWISHES out of the cell, making her jump up. In its tray is a clean, folded white towel. She hesitates, then crosses, takes this.</context>
      <utterance>You put those - things in there. Paid for it in advance, ten years ago... Why, Dr. Lecter?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She sits again, rubbing her wet hair. When he finally speaks, he's on the floor, too - a deeper, hunching darkness in the shadows, occasionally striped by the flickering TV light.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your bleeding has stopped.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did -  It's nothing. A scratch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you ask me about Buffalo Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why? Do you know something about him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I might if I saw the case file. You could get that for me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you tell me about "Miss Mofet?" You wanted me to find him. Or do I have to wait for the lab?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His real name is Benjamin Raspail. A former patient of mine, whose romantic attachments ran to, shall we say, the exotic...? I didn't kill him, merely tucked him away. Very much as I found him, in that ridiculous car, in his own garage, after he's missed three appointments. You'd have him under "Missing Person" - which, in poor Raspail's case, could hardly be more true.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you didn't kill him, then who did?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who can say...? Best thing for him, really. His therapy was going nowhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't it have been easier to just leave him for the police to find?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And have them clomping about in my life? Oh dear, no... At that time I still had certain private amusements of my own.  How did you feel when you saw him, Clarice? May I call you Clarice?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Scared, at first. Then - exhilarated.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ahhh... Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because you weren't wasting my time.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have something you use, when you need to get up your courage? Memories, tableaux... scenes from your early life?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Next time I'll have to check.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack Crawford is helping your career, isn't he? Apparently he likes you. And you like him, too.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I never thought about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your first lie to me, Clarice. How sad. Tell me - do you think Crawford wants you, sexually? True, he's much older, but - do you think he visualizes... scenarios, exchanges...? Fucking you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That doesn't interest me, Doctor. And it's the sort of thing Miggs would ask.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not anymore.  Surely the odd confluence of events hasn't escaped you, Clarice. Crawford dangles you before me. Then I give you a bit of help. Do you think it's because I like to look at you, and imagine how good you would taste...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. Is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Lecter slowly turns up the rheostat in his cell. As his lights rise, we see that the cell's been stripped bare. Gone are his books, drawings, mattress - even his toilet seat. She stands, too, startled. They face each other.</context>
      <utterance>Or doesn't this all begin to suggest to you a kind of... negotiation? There's something Crawford can give me, and I want to trade for it. I even wrote to him, offering my help. But he hates me, so he won't deal directly.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Punishment, you see. For Miggs. Just like that gospel program. When you leave, they'll turn the volume way up. Chilton does enjoy his petty torments.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who killed Raspail, Doctor...? You know, don't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been in this room for eight years, Clarice. I know they will never, ever let me out while I'm alive. What I want is a view. I want a window where I can see a tree, or even water. I want to be in a federal institution, away from Chilton - and I want a view. I'll give good value for it. Crawford could do that for me, but he won't. You persuade him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who killed your patient?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, a very naughty boy. Someone you and Jack Crawford are most anxious to meet.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But Dr. Lecter only smiles, enigmatically.</context>
      <utterance>Buffalo Bill...?  Bill killed him, all those years ago...? That's impossible.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Clarice stares at him, unsure how to respond -</context>
      <utterance>Who is he stalking right now, Clarice? I wonder, don't you? How many more young women will have to die, before you trade with me...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This stuff's givin' me the munchies. Where's that bag of popcorn?</utterance>
   <speaker>CODY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He starts to rise, but she pushes him back.</context>
      <utterance>Shit. Left the groceries in the car.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She rises, goes out the front door.</context>
      <utterance>'S okay, I'll go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Help you with that?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His voice is odd, strained, very soft. A fog lamp, set on end on the ground, distorts his features from below. We can't get a good glimpse of his face, but his body is plump, above average height; he's in his mid 30's. She sets down the bag, then together they easily lift the chair into the truck.</context>
      <utterance>Would you? Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's slide it up, you mind?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you about a size 14?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly, in the shadowy dark, he clubs her over the back of her head with his cast. She moans, slumps unconscious, sliding off the armchair to lie on her stomach. He pulls off his cast and sling, tosses them aside, then hops out of the truck, grabs his lamp, climbs back inside, and pulls the door shut. He bends over her face with the lamp. We hear her shallow BREATHING.</context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He peels back the collar of her blouse, reading the size tag.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He carefully slits her blouse up the back, with a pair of bandage scissors, peeling apart the two halves. There's no bra strap. He strokes her bare skin delicately, very happily.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gooood...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Clarice sits at a long table, with other trainees. Ardelia is beside her. Other tables and students in the background. Each trainee has his own microscope. Clarice is tired, but straightens, hearing -</context>
      <utterance>Electron microscopy reveals fiber "signatures" that are nearly as distinct as fingerprints...</utterance>
   <speaker>INSTRUCTOR</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Both of these blouses were worn by victims of Buffalo Bill. They were found in two different states, and four months apart. He always slits them up the back, like a funeral suit...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>BRIGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get your field gear, take stuff for overnight. You're goin' with Crawford.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some fishermen in West Virginia found an unidentified girl's body. It's a Buffalo Bill-type situation. Been in the water about a week, and Jack needs somebody that can print a floater. Think you can handle it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll need the big fingerprint kit... and the one-to-one Polaroid, the CU- 5, with film packs and batteries.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>BRIGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack's pretty tough on you, isn't he? Impatient...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice absorbs this in silence as they stop near an ancient, rather dilapidated Beechcraft. Its door is open, the twin props and beacons already turning. Brigham turns to her, holding out his small canvas bag.</context>
      <utterance>He's got a lot on his mind besides Buffalo Bill... His wife, Bella, is real sick. Comatose... I'm tellin' you about it now, 'cause he may never.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice opens the bag, stares at the big blue gun nestled in its shoulder holster. She looks up at him, touched.</context>
      <utterance>You're goin' in the field, so you gotta have full kit. Take this - it's my own...</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wear it, don't ever leave it in your purse. Dry fire it whenever you get the chance. And do your exercises.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I will... I promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, climbs out. Then she looks back in at him. They're both moved by this rite of passage, but a little embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>Listen, I hope you never need a thing I've taught you. But you've got something... Jack sees it, I do too. If you ever need to, you can shoot.</utterance>
   <speaker>BRIGHAM</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bless you, Starling...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pilot adjusts a valve. Crawford turns to her again.</context>
      <utterance>Why, we don't yet know... There's no evidence of rape or physical abuse prior to death. All the mutilation you see there is post-mortem.  I'm hot, are you hot? Bobby, it's too damned hot back here...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So. Three days. Then he shoots them, skins them - usually just the torsos - and dumps them. Each body in a different river, in a different state, downstream from an interstate highway. The water leaves us no fingerprints, fibers, DNA fluids - no trace evidence at all. That's Fredrica Bimmel, the first one...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Blue square for Belvedere, Ohio, where the Bimmel girl was abducted. Blue triangle where her body was found - down here in Missouri. Same marks for the other four girls, in different colors. This new one, today... washed up here.  Elk River, in West Virginia, about six miles below U.S. 79. Real boonies.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There's no correlation at all between where they're kidnapped and where they're found...?  What if - what if you trace the heaviest-traffic routes backwards from the dump sites? Do they converge at all?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good idea, but he thought of it, too. We've run simulations, using different vectors and the best dates we can assign. You put it all in the computer, and smoke comes out. No, this one is different. This one has seen us coming...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Talk about him, Starling. Tell me what you see.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's a white male... Serial killers tend to hunt within their own ethnic group. And he's not a drifter - he's got his own house, somewhere. Not an apartment.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What he does with them - takes privacy... Time, tools... He's in his 30's or 40's - he's got real physical strength, but combined with an older man's self-control. He's cautious, precise, never impulsive... This won't end in suicide, like they often do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's got a real taste for it now. And he's getting better at his work.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe you've got a knack for this... I guess we're about to find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He studies her a few moments, measuring her anger.</context>
      <utterance>Like I have a "knack" for Dr. Lecter?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Starling. Let's have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You haven't said a word today about that garage. Or what I found there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What should I say? You did fine work. We'll wait on the lab.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You knew. You knew from the start that Lecter held the key to this... But you weren't up front with me. You sent me in to him naked.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you finished?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A shadow of regret passes over his face, but he answers sternly.</context>
      <utterance>He starts this - buzzing in me, in my head. He makes me feel violated... You used me, Mr. Crawford.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>By now the two cars are entering a tidy little town - tree- lined streets, wooden houses, one-story shops, mountains in the background. They slow, turn.</context>
      <utterance>Number One. Maybe there's a connection, maybe not. Lying and breathing are the same thing to Lecter. Number Two. If I'd sent you in there with something to hide from him, he'd have known it, instantly. He'd never have trusted you. She starts to answer, then is silent. He is right.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice nods, silently; it's as close to an apology as she's likely to get. She stares out the windshield.</context>
      <utterance>Number Three, I didn't bring you along today just because you can do first-rate forensics. If Lecter is becoming part of this case, you've got the most current read on him. And Number Four - you don't have to like me, or the way I do things. But you do have to keep a cool head. Especially now... Because from here on out, you'll know everything I do. Are we straight on that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You think about him long enough, you get a feel for him... Then, if you're lucky, out of all the stuff you know, one little part of it tugs at you, tries to get your attention... You let me know when that happens, Starling. Live right behind your eyes, today. Don't try to impose any patterns on this guy. Just stay open and let him show you... One of the troopers, impassive in his sunglasses and hat, peers in through Crawford's window. Crawford nods to him, then turns back to Clarice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>School's out, Starling.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sheriff Perkins? Jack Crawford, FBI... This is Officer Starling. We appreciate your phoning us.</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He casts a sidelong, unhappy glance at Clarice.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't call you. That was somebody from the state attorney's office... 'For you do a thing else, I'm gon' find out if this girl's local. It could just be somethin' that outside elements has dumped on us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well sir, that's where we can help. If -</utterance>
   <speaker>SHERIFF</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't even know you, Mister... Now we'll extend you ever courtesy, just soon as we can, but for right now -</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He indicates Clarice with his eyes. The sheriff hesitates, nods, then lets Crawford guide him into a small office, closing the door behind them. Muffled WORDS from there.</context>
      <utterance>Sheriff, this, ah - this type of sex crime has some aspects I'd rather discuss just between the two of us. Know what I mean?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DR. AKIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leaves, and Clarice leans INTO SHOT, taking another photo.</context>
      <utterance>Wrongful death... She'll have to go to the state pathologist at Claxton when you're done.  I better - get on back for the rest of that service. Lamar'll help you.  Lord almighty...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you see, Starling?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, she's not local. Her ears are pierced three times each, and she's wearing green glitter nail polish. Looks like town to me...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She waxed her legs, I think... A big girl, just like the others - but she was careful about her appearance...</utterance>
   <speaker>UPWARD ANGLE AGAIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as Lamar joins them for a closer look.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes another FLASH, then quickly reloads film.</context>
      <utterance>Two of the fingernails are broken off, and there's - dirt or grit under the others. She tried to claw her way through something... I'll scrape out samples after I've printed her.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Them fishhooks are set too close together. No wonder the Franklin boys was scared to say they found her.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Crawford and Lamar both look at her curiously.</context>
      <utterance>Think they were runnin' a trotline?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a Fish and Game violation. Like poaching. There's a big fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right... Are you from around here?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They do it lots of places.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get photos of her teeth. Then we'll fax her fingerprints to Washington, try to trace her through Missing Persons.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NEW ANGLE - CHEST HIGH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as Clarice examines a developing print.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hands the print to Crawford; he and Lamar look at it, as she searches in her kit.</context>
      <utterance>She's got something in her throat.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice holds up a pair of forceps. She glances at Crawford, who nods. She bends over, partially OUT OF SHOT, and after a few moments reappears, holding up a small, brown cylindrical object. She turns this in the air, as they all stare.</context>
      <utterance>When a body comes out of the water, alots of times there's like, leaves and things in the mouth.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it - some kind of seed pod?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice and Crawford exchange a glance.</context>
      <utterance>Nawsir, that's a bug cocoon. But how come that to get way down in there? 'Less somebody shoved it in...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She'll be easier to print if we turn her over. Lamar, will you give me a hand?</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SOUND of the men's heavy efforts as they turn over the body, off screen. She seals the jar, staring into it at the cocoon.</context>
      <utterance>Yessir, I will. Clarice takes a jar from her kit, carefully drops the cocoon inside.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>She turns to look.</context>
      <utterance>Starling - what do you make of these?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NEW ANGLE - TWO SHOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as Clarice looks at Crawford.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I didn't see those on any of the other girls...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice raises her camera, leans in for another FLASH.</context>
      <utterance>They weren't there. Get close-ups.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, I'm not thirsty.</utterance>
   <speaker>LAMAR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles, touched, and takes the can. When Lamar sees Crawford coming outside, he tactfully departs. Crawford sits beside her; there's a brief silence. She soothes herself with the can.</context>
      <utterance>No, hold it under your chin, there, and on your temples. Cold'll make you feel better. It does me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When I told that sheriff we shouldn't talk in front of a woman, that really burned you, didn't it?  That was just smoke, Starling, I had to get rid of him. You did well in there.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It matters, Mr. Crawford... Other cops know who you are. They look at you to see how to act... It matters.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him a moment, then offers the can. He opens it.</context>
      <utterance>Point taken.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When we get back, I want you to run that bug by the Smithsonian, see if they can identify it. Maybe it's got some limited range, or it only breeds at certain times of year... You found it, Starling, you deserve the credit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm wondering if he's done that before - placed a cocoon, or an insect. It would be easy to miss in an autopsy, especially with a floater... Can we check back on that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The other girls are in the ground. Exhumations are upsetting for the families. I'll do it if I have to, but -</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then have the lab check Raspail's head.  Dr. Lecter's patient - have them probe his soft-palette tissues... They'll find another cocoon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You seem pretty sure of that.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her for a moment, then sips again.</context>
      <utterance>Raspail was killed by the same man who's killing these girls. And Lecter knows him. Maybe even treated him... You think so, too, don't you? Or you'd never have sent me to that asylum.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Before we caught him, Lecter had a big psychiatric practice in Baltimore. But he traveled all over the country - teaching, consulting... Christ, even testifying in murder trials. Who knows how many potential psychos he turned loose, just for the fun of it...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The little dog squirms in his arms, BARKING excitedly.</context>
      <utterance>Rub it in! Or you'll get the hose again.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, it will, Precious, won't it? It will get the hose!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She unzips her jumpsuit, part-way, then squeezes some of the lotion onto a palm. She reaches inside her suit, rubs it on.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God... oh God...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mister, if you let me go, I won't press charges, I promise. You've only had me here a couple days, and -</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Just one day...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A sudden blinding glare of light silences her. She looks up, shielding her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Is that all...? See - see, my mom is a real important woman... Well, I guess you already know that. She'll pay you, no questions asked. Whatever cause you represent - Iran, Palestine - she'll see that -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The photo disappears, replaced by the TV ANCHOR himself.</context>
      <utterance>...was listed at first simply as a missing person, but is now believed to have been kidnapped by the serial killer known only as "Buffalo Bill."</utterance>
   <speaker>TV ANCHOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Memphis Police sources indicate that the missing girl's blouse has been identified, sliced up the back, in what has become a kind of grim calling card. Young Catherine Martin, as we've said, is the only daughter of U.S. Senator Ruth Martin -</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SEN. MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice is moved by what she sees. Other trainees are all around her.</context>
      <utterance>I'm speaking now to the person who is holding my daughter. Her name is Catherine... You have the power to let Catherine go, unharmed. She's very gentle and kind - talk to her and you'll see. Her name is Catherine...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Boy, is that smart...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why does she keep repeating the name?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somebody's coaching her... They're trying to make him see Catherine as a person - not just an object.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RODEN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Time, Pilch! My move.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILCHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No fair! You lured him with produce.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>RODEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tough noogies! It's still my turn.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>They look up, delighted to see Clarice in the doorway. Both men are hopelessly smitten by her.</context>
      <utterance>If the beetle moves one of your men, does that count?</utterance>
   <speaker>RODEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course it counts. How do you play?</utterance>
   <speaker>PILCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Officer Starling. Welcome back.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RODEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where the hell did this one come from? It's practically mush.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You really don't want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your West Virginia specimen gave us quite a bit of trouble, but I finally managed to narrow his species through chaetaxy - studying the skin.</utterance>
   <speaker>RODEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm the one who found his perforating proboscis! Are you wearing a gun, right now?  Ooh, cool! Can I see it? Can I?</utterance>
   <speaker>PILCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just ignore him. He's not a Ph.D.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PILCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you do when you're not detecting, Officer Starling?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I try to be a student, Dr. Pilcher.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ever get out for cheeseburgers and beer? The amusing house wine...?</utterance>
   <speaker>RODEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Positive match!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're sure?</utterance>
   <speaker>RODEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves aside for Clarice to get a closer look at Pilcher's specimen. She leans forward, intently.</context>
      <utterance>West Virginia... Baltimore. Officer Starling, meet Mister Acherontia Styx.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>RODEN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Better known to his friends as the Death's-head Moth...</utterance>
   <speaker>PILCHER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Latin name comes from two rivers in Hell. Your man - he drops these girls into rivers, every time. Didn't I read that?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And there's no way - no natural way - these could've wound up in the bodies?</utterance>
   <speaker>PILCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They live in Malaysia. In this country, they'd have to be specially raised, from imported eggs.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As the two men stare at her, puzzled, we hear a SOUND UPCUT - the wail of police SIRENS - and...</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Lecter...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But for Catherine Martin, it all comes down to you and Lecter. You're the one he talks to.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's already offered to help... What would happen if we just showed our cards - asked him for Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He offered to help, Starling, not to snitch. That wouldn't give him enough chance to show off. Remember, Lecter looks mainly for fun. Never forget fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if he knew we have so little time -</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If we act too anxious, he'll make us wait. He'll let the Senator keep hoping, day after day, until Catherine finally washes up. That'd be the most fun of all.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think he means it, this time. I think he'll deal.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What would it take?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Transfer to a new prison. With a view of trees, he said, or even water... Can we swing that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>State to federal jurisdiction... We can do it - eventually - but we'll never get all the clearances in time. Can you convince him a deal's already in place?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll back me up with some paperwork?  Then I'll try. But wouldn't this have more weight coming from the Senator herself?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice looks at him, surprised.</context>
      <utterance>She doesn't know what we're up to. And we can't afford to let her find out.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She's the mother, Starling. She can't possibly comprehend what Lecter is. She'd make the mistake of pleading with him. Begging him... He'd feast on her pain till the last second of that girl's life...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Chilton falls into step beside Clarice, who has her briefcase. He points his gold pen at her accusingly.</context>
      <utterance>We can't trust Frederick Chilton, either. He's greedy and ambitious. If he knew about Lecter's link to Bill, he's go straight to the newspapers...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you're doing, Miss Starling, is coming into my hospital to conduct an interview, and refusing to share information with me. For the third time!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Chilton, I told you - this is just routine follow-up on the Raspail case.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stares at him, with pity and distaste, till he lets go.</context>
      <utterance>He's my patient! I have rights!  I'm not just some turnkey, Miss Starling. I shouldn't even be here this afternoon. I had a ticket to Holiday on Ice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She walks away, leaving him speechless with frustration and hostility. He clicks his pen, watching her go.</context>
      <utterance>I'm acting on instruction, Dr. Chilton.  This is the U.S. Attorney's number. Now please - either discuss this with him, or let me do my job.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="52">
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice, sitting again at the desk-chair, is taking papers from her briefcase.</context>
      <utterance>Wouldn't you say, Clarice, that for a United States Senator, you're an odd choice of messenger?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I was your choice, Dr. Lecter. You chose to speak to me. Would you prefer someone else now? Or perhaps you don't think you can help us.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That is both impudent and untrue... Tell me, how did you feel when you viewed our Billy's latest effort?  Or should I say, his "next-to-latest"?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>By the book, he's a sadist.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life's too slippery for books, Clarice. Typhoid and swans came from the same God.  Tell me, Miss West Virginia - was she a large girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Big through the hips. Roomy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They all were.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mmm. And what else...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She had an insect deliberately inserted in her throat. That hasn't been made public yet. We don't know what is means.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Was it a butterfly?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A moth... How did you predict that?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice looks down at her papers, taking a moment to collect her thoughts. She looks up at him again, evenly.</context>
      <utterance>I'm waiting for your offer, Clarice. Enchant me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He is silent. She rises, moves closer, carrying papers.</context>
      <utterance>If you help us find Buffalo Bill in time to save Catherine Martin, the Senator promises you a transfer to the V.A. hospital at Oneida Park, New York, with a view of the woods nearby. Maximum security still applies, but you'd have reasonable access to books.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His face remains neutral. She puts the papers in his food tray.</context>
      <utterance>Best of all, though - one week a year you'd get to leave the hospital and go here.  Plum Island. Every afternoon of that week you can walk on the beach or swim in the ocean for up to one hour. Under SWAT team surveillance, of course...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A measured beat, before he rises smoothly, crosses, and looks down at the papers, without touching them.</context>
      <utterance>Copy of the Buffalo Bill case file, copy of Senator Martin's terms. Her offer is final and non-negotiable. If Catherine dies -  You get nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Plum Island Animal Disease Research Center." Sounds charming.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's just part of the island. It has a very nice beach. Terns nest there.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She looks at him. A beat. They are standing uncomfortably close.</context>
      <utterance>Terns... If I help you, Clarice, it will be "turns" with us, too. Quid pro quo. I tell you things, you tell me things. Not about this case, though - about yourself. Yes or no?  Yes or no, Clarice. Catherine is waiting. Tick-tock, tick-tock...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Go, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's your worst memory of childhood?  Quicker than that. I'm not interested in your worst invention.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The death of my father.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice cannot bear the feverish excitement in his eyes. She looks past him, hesitating again.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me. Don't lie, or I'll know.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He was a town marshal... one night he surprised two burglars, coming out the back of a drugstore... They shot him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Killed outright?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He was strong, he lasted almost a month. My mother - died when I was very young, so my father had become - the whole world to me... After he left me, I had nobody. I was ten years old.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're very frank, Clarice. I think - it would be quite something to know you in private life.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quid pro quo, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The significance of the moth is change. Caterpillar into cocoon into beauty... Billy wants to change, too, Clarice. But there's the problem of his size, you see. Even if he were a woman, he'd have to be a big one...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Lecter, there's no correlation in the literature between transsexualism and violence. Transsexuals are very passive.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clever girl. You're so close to the way you're going to catch him - do you realize that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Tell me why.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>After your father's death, you were orphaned. What happened next?  I don't imagine the answer's on those second-rate shoes, Clarice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I went to live with my mother's cousin and her husband in Montana. They had a ranch.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A cattle ranch?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Horses - and sheep...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How long did you live there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Two months.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why so briefly?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I - ran away...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why, Clarice? Did the rancher fuck you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did he try to?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No...! Quid pro quo, Doctor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Billy's not a real transsexual, but he thinks he is. He tries to be. He's tried to be a lot of things, I expect.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You said - I was very close to the way we'd catch him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There are three major centers for transsexual surgery: Johns Hopkins, the University of Minnesota, and Columbus Medical center. I wouldn't be surprised if Billy has applied for sex reassignment at one or all of them, and been rejected.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On what basis would they reject him?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The personality inventories would trip him up. Rorschach, Wechsler, House-Tree-Person... He wouldn't test like a real transsexual.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Dr. Lecter snarls, loudly, stretching. Clarice take a sharp step backwards before he smiles, turning his movement into an elaborate yawn. He gathers the papers from his tray.</context>
      <utterance>How would he test?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's enough, I think. Happy hunting. Oh, and Clarice - next time you will tell me why you ran away. Shall I summarize?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Doctor. Please.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We pass a row of female mannequins, some nude, some wearing colorful leather jackets, designer knockoffs, in various stages of completion... then a huge maroon armoire, in Chinese lacquer; its double doors are slightly ajar... The jaunty background. MUSIC is growing even louder: Fats Waller singing "Bye Bye Baby." And now we hear something else, too - the rapid CLICKING of a sewing machine...</context>
      <utterance>Among those who tried to conceal their past, look for severe childhood disturbances, associated with violence... Possibly you'll find a childhood incarceration... Then go to their personality tests...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We TURN another corner, and there is Mr. Gumb himself. As we APPROACH, his wide back is to us; he's hunched over an old- fashioned sewing machine, humming cheerfully, and working a piece of material that we mercifully cannot see. A female wig rests near him on a head form. He wears a hairnet and a beautiful kimono, and pumps the treadle with his bare feet.</context>
      <utterance>Study their drawings, especially. Billy's house drawings will show no happy future... No baby carriage, out in the yard. No pets, no toys, no flowers, no sun...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Next to Mr. Gumb is an antique phonograph - source of the MUSIC. His little dog, Precious, perches by his plump ankles. As we PASS Mr. Gumb, Precious scurries away from him, panting happily, and we FOLLOW the little dog down another corridor, the music starting to fade behind us...</context>
      <utterance>His females will be more crudely sketched than him males - but he'll compensate by adding exaggerated adornments... jewelry, big breasts... And his tree drawings - oh, his trees will be frightful...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>At the end of this final corridor, the cellar widens into a low-ceilinged chamber, with two additional doorways, and in the center of this is the gaping circle of the oubliette. Precious sniffs her way over to the edge - excited, tail wagging - than BARKS happily as we hear a hoarse, ghostly moan from below.</context>
      <utterance>Billy hates his own identity, he always has - and he thinks that makes him a transsexual. But his pathology is a thousand times more savage... He wants to be reborn, Clarice. He will be reborn...</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pleeeeeeeease.....!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Barney props the hand truck into position, then both orderlies go. Chilton finishes another letter, sighs happily.</context>
      <utterance>Perhaps you should have been less specific about what kind.  Stand him by the toilet. Then leave us.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tossing letters onto the cot, he rises, crosses out into the corridor, and bends to remove a small tape recorder from underneath Clarice's desk. He waggles it triumphantly at Dr. Lecter.</context>
      <utterance>Such a lot of correspondence! I can hardly wait to analyze it in more detail... But first things first.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought she might be looking for a civil rights violation in Migg's death, so I bugged you... Not a word to me in all these years, Hannibal. Then Crawford sends his bit of fluff over here, and you just turn to jelly. It's too pathetic.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON Dr. Lecter's glittering eyes, behind their slits.</context>
      <utterance>You still think you're going to walk on some beach, and see the birdies? I don't think so, Hannibal... I called Senator Ruth Martin, and she never heard of any deal with you. She never heard of Clarice Starling, either. They scammed you, Hannibal...</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When Crawford gets through milking you, he's giving you to Baltimore Homicide for the Raspail murder. And they're preparing some special surprises for you right now, in my electroshock room.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Starling bitch wants you to rot here, in this little box, till your teeth fall out and you're soiling diapers. You've seen the old ones, Hannibal. They weep when their stewed peaches get cold. That'll be you, too. Unless - you trade with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FAVORING CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as he sits chummily on the table.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There never was a deal with Senator Martin - but there is now. I've been on the phone for hours, Hannibal, on your behalf. Here's what you get: if you identify Buffalo Bill, and the girl is found in time, Senator Martin will have you transferred to Brushy Mountain State Prison, in Tennessee...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>A beat. Dr. Lecter is silent. Chilton sticks his face INTO SHOT, almost intimately close to the mask. He is agitated.</context>
      <utterance>In exchange, I get your full cooperation in publishing a professional account of this - my successful interviews with you. You publish nothing. And I get exclusive access to any material from Catherine Martin... So. Do you accept my demands?  Answer me, Hannibal.</utterance>
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You'll answer me now, or by God, you'll answer to Baltimore Homicide. Who is Buffalo Bill?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll tell the Senator herself. But only in Tennessee...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>DR. DANIELSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not having a witch hunt here, Mr. Crawford! Our patients are decent, non-violent people with a real problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Danielson enters a cramped, stainless steel nurse's gallery, with Crawford following, and pours himself a cup of coffee.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Danielson, the man we want was never your patient. It would be someone you refused because he tries to conceal a record of criminal violence. Please, Doctor - time is eating us up. Just show me the ones you've turned away.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. DANIELSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Examination and interview materials are confidential. We've never violated an applicant's trust, and we never will.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a black &amp; white photo from his folder, slaps it down in front of Danielson. From our angle, we can't see it clearly.</context>
      <utterance>You want to see a violation? This is a violation...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her name is Kimberly Jane Emberg, she was just ID'd. I met her on a slab in West Virginia. And sometime tomorrow, or tomorrow night, he's going to do the same thing to Catherine Martin.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. DANIELSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burroughs sticks his head in, looking for Crawford.</context>
      <utterance>That's a childish, bullying stunt, Mr. Crawford. I was a battlefield surgeon, so you can put away your picture.</utterance>
   <speaker>BURROUGHS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Phone, Jack. Director Burke.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Burroughs hurriedly retreats. Crawford strains for patience.</context>
      <utterance>In a minute!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Look... search your own records, if you prefer. You can do it a lot faster than us, anyway. If we find Buffalo Bill through your information, I'll suppress it. Nobody has to know this hospital cooperated.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. DANIELSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I doubt very much that the FBI or any other government agency can keep a secret, Mr. Crawford. Truth will out... And then what? Will you give Johns Hopkins a new identity? Put a big pair of sunglasses on this building, and a funny nose?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, that's clever, Dr. Danielson. Very humorous. You like the truth? Try this.  He kidnaps young women and kills them and rips their skin off. We don't want him to do that anymore. If you don't help me, just as fast as you can, then the Justice Department is going to ask publicly for a court order, We'll ask twice a day, just in time for the morning and evening news. And each one of our press conferences will focus on Dr. Danielson, over at Johns Hopkins, and how we're still hoping for his cooperation. And every time there's any news on the case - when Catherine Martin floats, when the next one floats, and the next one - why, we'll just issue another press release about good ol' Dr. Danielson, over at Johns Hopkins - complete with all his humorous fucking remarks.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. DANIELSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It may be that - I could confer with my colleagues on this. And get back to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Would you, Doctor? That would be so kind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chilton has killed her, hasn't he? That slimy little bastard! We were so close with Lecter - and now her last chance is gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get some coffee and talk.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you in trouble over this, Mr. Crawford? Can Senator Martin do something to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm 53, Starling. If I found Jimmy Hoffa on national TV, I'd still have to retire in two years. It's not a consideration. But you are...  You've done enough. If I keep you out of school any longer, you'll be recycled. Cost you six months, at least. I can guarantee you readmission here, but that's about it.  Now's your chance, Starling. Go back to class. Leave Bill to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks at her steadily, then nods. They walk on.</context>
      <utterance>If you didn't want me chasing him, you shouldn't have taken me to that funeral home.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lecter is still the key, I know he is. Whatever he told me about Bill is just as good now as it was before.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles at this acknowledgment; he never thought she's quit.</context>
      <utterance>Or just as worthless. But I want you in Memphis, close to him. Maybe when he gets tired of toying with Senator Martin, he'll talk to you again. There's a plane waiting for you now at the airstrip.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I lied to Lecter. I'll need some kind of peace offering... Can I get the drawings from his cell?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Good idea. Meantime, try to get a feel for Catherine Martin. Her apartment, her friends... how he might've stalked her. I'm going to the other two clinics, Minnesota and Ohio.  Now's the hardest part, Starling. Use your anger, don't let it keep you from thinking. Just keep your eyes on Catherine. We've got less than 30 hours.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Crawford... can those cops down there handle Dr. Lecter?</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll use their best men. But they better be paying attention...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>BOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to Memphis, Dr. Lecter. I'm Officer Boyle, this is Officer Pembry. We aim to treat you just as nice as you treat us. Act like a gentlemen, you'll get three hots and a cot.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But we ain't pussy-footin' with you, buddy ruff. You get cute, try to bite somebody? - we'll tie your asshole in a knot. You savvy?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The officers turn away, Boyle signing a clipboarded form.</context>
      <utterance>Oh yes, Officer Pembry. I certainly do.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit, he's just an ol' broke-dick. Won't be no trouble as all if he don't flip out.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Chilton...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Chilton instinctively pats his shirt pocket for his gold pen; it's gone. He searches other pockets, with growing unhappiness.</context>
      <utterance>If you'll please sign right here, sir, we'll have us a legal transfer.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Use mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Here they come.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="16">
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare at one another for a long moment: the Senator tense, almost haggard, the madman with his unearthly poise.</context>
      <utterance>Senator Martin, meet Dr. Hannibal Lecter.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEN. MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He assistant unsnaps his briefcase, reaches for the form.</context>
      <utterance>Dr. Lecter, I've brought an affidavit guaranteeing your new rights... You'll want to read it before I sign.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I won't waste your time and Catherine's time bargaining for petty privileges. Clarice Starling and that awful Jack Crawford have wasted far too much already. I only pray they haven't doomed the poor girl... Let me help you now, and I'll trust you when it's all over.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEN. MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Krendler raises a pad, poised to take notes.</context>
      <utterance>You have my word. Paul?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Buffalo Bill's real name is William Rubin. I met him just once. He was referred to me in April or May, 1980, by my patient Benjamin Raspail. They were lovers, but Raspail had become very frightened. Apparently Rubin had murdered a transient, and - done things with the skin. He thought if I could cure Billy, then Billy'd be safe from the police, and he's be safe from Billy... Obviously, he was wrong.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRENDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need his address, a physical descr-</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you nurse Catherine?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEN. MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What...?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He flicks his tongue obscenely.</context>
      <utterance>Did you breast-feed her?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRENDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Senator stills him with a hand. She is trembling.</context>
      <utterance>You son-of-a -</utterance>
   <speaker>SEN. MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes... I did.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Toughened your nipples, didn't it...?  Six foot one, strongly built, about 190 pounds. Hair brown, eyes pale blue. He'd be about 35 now. He said he lived in Philadelphia, but may have lied. That's really all I can remember, Senator - but if I think of any more, I'll let you know.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEN. MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They start towards the car, but he calls out, stopping her.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go with it.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Senator Martin...! You can't trust Jack Crawford or Clarice Starling. It's such a game with these people. They're determined to get the arrest for themselves. The "collar," I think they say.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEN. MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Doctor. I'll keep it in mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, and Senator...? Love you suit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>SEN. MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you, please? I thought the police were through in here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Clarice Starling, Senator. FBI.</utterance>
   <speaker>SEN. MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Krendler enters from the hallway, looks at Clarice.</context>
      <utterance>Clarice Starling...  Paul? Would you come in here, please...?</utterance>
   <speaker>SEN. MARTIN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Overcome, she hurries from the room. Krendler shuts the door behind her, points sternly at Clarice.</context>
      <utterance>Miss Starling, you may know the Deputy Attorney General, Mr. Krendler. Paul, this is the trainee that Jack Crawford sent to Lecter... She lied to him, pretending to have my authority, and thus jeopardized this entire investigation. Now she has the further gall to invade my daughter's privacy, again without permission. If her little games have killed my baby...</utterance>
   <speaker>KRENDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're out of line, Starling, and you're off this case. Back to Quantico.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, Mr. Crawford instructed me -</utterance>
   <speaker>KRENDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your instructions are what I'm giving you now. Jack Crawford answers to the Director, and the Director answers to me. My God, Crawford's losing it...! He shouldn't even be on this, with his wife sick as she is... How the hell did you get in here, anyway? He gave you - what? Some kind of special ID? Let's have it.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need the ID to fly with my gun. The gun belongs in Quantico.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRENDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice, burning, starts for the door, then turns back.</context>
      <utterance>Gun. Jesus. Turn in the ID as soon as you get back. The gun, too. Be on the next plane, Starling, there's one in 90 minutes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Krendler... Dr. Lecter trusts me. Or at least, he used to. If I could just -</utterance>
   <speaker>KRENDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice reacts, surprised. Krendler takes a folded computer sheet from his pocket, shoves it at her. She takes it, reads.</context>
      <utterance>Lecter has already named Buffalo Bill.</utterance>
   <speaker>KRENDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He gave us a perfectly good description, and we're on it now, so we won't be needing your little novelty act any longer - or his, either. He's under close guard at the courthouse, pending a prison transfer. The next plane, Officer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Krendler moves in very close to her, pale with anger.</context>
      <utterance>Sir, doesn't this "William Rubin" strike you as - I don't know - kind of vague?</utterance>
   <speaker>KRENDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you need a police escort, Starling? Or do you think you can find the airport by yourself?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir. I can find it by myself.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SGT. TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you with Mr. Krendler's people?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just left him.</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT. TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He picks up a phone, murmurs into it. As he does so, Clarice glances around this main ground floor lobby.</context>
      <utterance>Access to Lecter is strictly limited. We've been getting death threats.  Log in, and check your weapon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Every cop in Tennessee wants a look at this guy. 'Sit true what they're sayin' - he's some kinda vampire?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't have a name for what he is.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PEMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know the rules, ma'am?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He waves her on her way, but retains the drawings for now.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, Officer Pembry. I've questioned him before.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops at a striped police barricade, before his bars.</context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon, Clarice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I thought you might want your drawings back... Just until you get your view.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How very thoughtful... Or did Crawford send you here for one last wheedle - before you're both booted off the case?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spins in his swivel chair, stops neatly. A coy smile.</context>
      <utterance>Nobody sent me. I came on my own.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spins again in his chair, playfully.</context>
      <utterance>People will say we're in love.  Pity you tried to fool me, isn't it? Pity for poor Catherine. Tick-tock...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Lecter, you find out everything. You couldn't have talked with this "William Rubin", even once, and come out knowing so little about him... You made him up, didn't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clarice... you're hardly in a position to accuse me of lying.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think you were telling me the truth in Baltimore - or starting to. Tell me the rest now.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've studied the case file, have you...? Everything you need to find him is right in these pages. Whatever his name is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then tell me how.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>First principles, Clarice. Simplicity. Read Marcus Aurelius. Of each particular thing, ask: What is it, in itself, what is its nature...? What does he do, this man you seek?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He kills w-</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>CLOSE ANGLE - TWO SHOT as he rises, pained by her ignorance, and crosses to the bars.</context>
      <utterance>No! That's incidental.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is the first and principal thing he does, what need does he serve by killing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anger, social resentment, sexual frus-</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, he covets. That's his nature. And how do we begin to covet, Clarice? Do we seek out things to covet? Make an effort to answer.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. We just -</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Precisely. We begin by coveting what we see every day. Don't you feel eyes moving over your body, Clarice? I hardly see how you couldn't. And don't your eyes move over the things you want?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, then tell me how -</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. It's your turn to tell me, Clarice. You don't have any more vacations to sell, on Anthrax Island. Why did you run away from that ranch?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Lecter, when there's time I'll -</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We don't reckon time the same way, Clarice. This is all the time you'll ever have.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Later, listen, I'll -</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll listen now. After your father's murder, you were orphaned. You were ten years old. You went to live with cousins, on a sheep and horse ranch in Montana. And - ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns from him. He presses closer, gripping the bars.</context>
      <utterance>And - one morning I just - ran away...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not "just," Clarice. What set you off? You started what time?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Early. Still dark.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then something woke you. What? Did you dream...? What was it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I heard a strange sound...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What was it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Screaming! Some kind of - screaming. Like a child's voice...</utterance>
   <speaker>THE LITTLE GIRL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>is terrified; she covers her ears.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you do?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got dressed without turning on the light. I went downstairs... outside...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And what did you see, Clarice?</utterance>
   <speaker>A SQUIRMING LAMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>is held down on a table by two ranch hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>A third cowboy stretches out the lamb's neck, raises a bloody knife. Just as he's about to slice its throat -</context>
      <utterance>Lambs. The lambs were screaming...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They were slaughtering the spring lambs?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...! They were screaming.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So you ran away...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. First I tried to free them... I opened the gate of their pen - but they wouldn't run. They just stood there, confused. They wouldn't run...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But you could. You did.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I took one lamb. And I ran away, as fast as I could...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where were you going?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The tiny figure stops, and after a few moments sinks to the ground, hunched over in dispair.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I had no food or water. It was very cold. I thought - if I can even save just one... but he got so heavy. So heavy...</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't get more than a few miles before the sheriff's car found me. The rancher was so angry he sent me to live at the Lutheran orphanage in Bozeman. I never saw the ranch again...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what became of your lamb?  Clarice...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You still wake up sometimes, don't you? Wake up in the dark, with the lambs screaming?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes...</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you think if you saved Catherine, you could make them stop...? Do you think, if Catherine lives, you won't wake up in the dark, ever again, to the screaming of the lambs? Do you...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes! I don't know...! I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Clarice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me his name, Dr. Lecter.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Chilton... I believe you know each other?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CHILTON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Out. Let's go.</utterance>
   <speaker>PEMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice struggles, pulling free of them for a moment.</context>
      <utterance>Sorry, ma'a m - we've got orders to have you put on a place.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Brave Clarice. Will you let me know if ever the lambs stop screaming?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I'll tell you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Promise...?  Then why not take your case file? I won't be needing it anymore. He holds out the file, arm extended between the bars. She hesitates, then reaches to take it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He seizes one of the dangling jackets, pulling up the plastic wrapper. He examines it, stroking the sleeve.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, dear! Punctual as always. And what have you brought us today?</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, marvelous... You know, I always say you're the Leonardo of leather.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oil.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pardon...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>The foreman quickly releases the jacket.</context>
      <utterance>You're leaving oil on the skin.</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Gumb's hand reaches INTO SHOT, snatching an envelope from him. The foreman is watching him walk away, as a seamstress comes over to take the rack of garments. The foreman is vaguely troubled, but shakes it off. He strokes the jacket again, admiringly.</context>
      <utterance>Of course... You'll be wanting your -</utterance>
   <speaker>FOREMAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I wish we had a dozen like him... SOUND UPCUT - Glenn Gould playing Bach's Goldberg Variations...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Pembry grunts, sets the tray down. Boyle joins him, handing him a riot baton and a Mace cannister, which Pembry fastens to belt clips. Boyle is similarly armed, and carries a ring of keys.</context>
      <utterance>Just another minute, please!</utterance>
   <speaker>PEMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sumbitch demanded lamb chops for dinner, extra rare.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOYLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What you reckon he'll want for breakfast - some fuckin' thing from the zoo?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>PEMBRY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dr. Lecter sits on the floor, legs straight, then wriggles backwards. He stretches his arms behind him, hands and wrists through the bars, with two bars between them, and clasps his hands.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, Doc, grab some floor. Same drill as lunchtime.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pembry comes around the cell to squat behind Dr. Lecter. He tugs his hands farther out, rather roughly, handcuffs his wrists. He shakes the cuffs, making sure of them, then nods to Boyle.</context>
      <utterance>I'm ready when you are, Officer Pembry.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>SGT. TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A GUNSHOT, and then, moments later, TWO MORE quick ones, echo down the nearby stairwell. Sgt. Tate jumps to his feet, grabs a radio mike, as the other cops stir, confused and noisy.</context>
      <utterance>What is this shit...? Did somebody go up to five?  Call Pembry, ask him what -</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT. TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>CP, shots fired on five! Repeat, shots fires on five! Outside posts look sharp, we've got a... Ho-ly shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>THE BRONZE ARROW</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>has begun to descend. Down to 4, then past 4...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SGT. TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SHUT UP...! Guard mount, double up on your outside posts. Bobby, get the vests. Rainey, Howard, cover that fucking elevator if it comes all the way to -</utterance>
   <speaker>A COP</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It stopped!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tate crosses, kneels to see for himself. Murray looks green.</context>
      <utterance>This one's alive!</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT. TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take ahold of him where he can feel your hands, son. Talk to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's his name, Sarge?</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT. TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other cop, checking the cylinder of Pembry's gun, holds up one finger to Tate.</context>
      <utterance>It's Pembry, now talk to him, God dammit.  Boyle's dead, Pembry's read bad. Lecter is missing and armed - he took Boyle's gun...</utterance>
   <speaker>SGT. TATE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Pembry got off one round - there's a chance Lecter was hit. We heard a total of three shots fired, so he's got four left... He's got a knife, too.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MURRAY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>One orderly massages the heart. Another is popping a plasma bag, ready to insert the needle, when the body starts convulsing.</context>
      <utterance>You're just fine, Pembry, lookin' good, buddy, you're gonna make it...</utterance>
   <speaker>ORDERLY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Quickly the gurney is elevated, wheeled out of the room, with cops rushing forward to open the doors, help push, SWAT men are running by in the hall, automatic rifles at the ready...</context>
      <utterance>Downstairs - let's go!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>PETERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I see him... There's a weapon by his hand. He's not moving...</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you get the drop?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got the drop.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Peterson nods to Kubell, who switches ON the flashlight, as Peterson shouts down the shaft.</context>
      <utterance>One warning. Then take him out.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Quinn!! put your hands on your head!!</utterance>
   <speaker>PETERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Put one in his leg.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>PETERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>staring down the shaft, raises his mike again.</utterance>
   <speaker>PETERSON</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No movement.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay, Johnny, hold your fire...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>SWAT COMMANDER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We're coming into the car, we're opening the hatch. Watch his hands. Any fire will come from us. Affirm?</utterance>
   <speaker>PETERSON'S VOICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The SWAT commander hands his radio to another cop, then looks at Tate. A long, tense moment. Then he waves a signal.</context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's comatose, but his vital signs are good. Pressure's 130 over 90... Yeah, 90! Pulse 85... Behind him, in slightly BLURRED FOCUS, the bloody figure sits slowly upright...</utterance>
   <speaker>ATTENDANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly he stops, becoming aware of a strange HISSING. He turns, puzzled...</context>
      <utterance>His convulsions have stopped, but he's got so much loose skin on his face, it's hard to tell if -</utterance>
   <speaker>THE POCKETKNIFE BLADE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>in Lecter's fist, flashes high in the air...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice looks up. Her eyes are red-rimmed with exhaustion, and something close to despair. She reads Ardelia's thought.</context>
      <utterance>In the parking garage at Memphis airport. The crew was dead. He killed a tourist, too. Got his clothes, cash... By now he could be anywhere.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. He won't come after me.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ardelia sits beside her, touches her arm.</context>
      <utterance>It would be rude. And he wouldn't get to ask any more questions...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clarice - you did the best anybody could have for Catherine Martin. You stuck your neck out for her and you got your butt kicked for her and you tried. It's not your fault it ended this way.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The worst part - the thing that's making me crazy - is that Bill is right in front of me. Only I can't see him...  Lecter said, everything I need to catch him is right here, in these pages...</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lecter said a lot of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SOUND UPCUT - the low throb of a washing machine...</context>
      <utterance>He's here, Ardelia. Ardelia stares back at her.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"Desperately random." What does he mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not random at all, maybe. Like there's some pattern here...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But there is no pattern. There's no connection at all among these places, or the computers would've nailed it! They're even found in random order.</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Well, except for the one girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What girl?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They search among the inserts. Clarice finds the graduation photo.</context>
      <utterance>The one that was weighted down. Where is she...? Fred something.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Fredrica Bimmel, from Belvedere, Ohio. The first girl taken, but the third body found... Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>'Cause she didn't drift. He weighted her down.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But why? He didn't weight the others. Clarice moves, on fire, unable to keep still.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stops, turns. She grabs the photo of Fredrica from Ardelia, stares at it. She looks up, trembling.</context>
      <utterance>The first, what the hell did Lecter say about... "First principles," he said. Simplicity... What does this guy do, he "covets." How do we first start to covet? "We covet what we see -"</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>"- every day."</utterance>
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hot damn, Clarice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He knew her...!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Maybe he lives in this, this Belvedere, Ohio, too! Maybe he saw her every day, and killed her sort of spontaneously. Maybe he just meant to... give her a 7-Up and talk about the choir. But then -</utterance>
   <speaker>KRENDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starling -</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But then he had to cover up, make her seem just like all the rest of them. That's what Lecter was hinting!</utterance>
   <speaker>KRENDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The market in Lecter hints is way down, today, okay? I've got two good men dead in Memphis, and three civilians. I've got -</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who the hell's fault is -</utterance>
   <speaker>KRENDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>- a U.S. Senator who's half out of her head because her daughter's going to be murdered today! And all because of your mind games with fucking Lecter!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you hadn't interfered, he'd still be in custody in Baltimore!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack -</utterance>
   <speaker>KRENDLER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You sent in a green recruit, with a phony goddamn offer -</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're just trying to cover your ass for letting him escape!</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A long silence, as they all struggle to regain composure. Crawford, who was at the point of striking Krendler, finally retakes his seat. Burke looks sadly at Crawford and Clarice.</context>
      <utterance>THAT'S ENOUGH! All of you...</utterance>
   <speaker>BURKE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starling, I'm afraid I have no choice. You're suspended from the Academy.  Not another word!  This is pending a reevaluation of your fitness for the service. I promise you'll get a fair hearing.  Jack... you're ordered to take compassionate leave. You'll spend the rest of the day briefing the AG's office, then transfer command of the task force, effective by 1800 hours.  I'm sorry, Jack... Go home. Take care of Bella. Clarice and Crawford stare back at him, drained. A long and very painful silence. Not even Krendler looks happy.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All his victims are women... His obsession is women, he lives to hunt women. But not one women is hunting him - except me. I can walk in a woman's room and know three times as much about her as a man would.  I have to go to Belvedere.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You heard them. I don't have that authority anymore.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her sadly. He looks, for the first time, defeated, old beyond his years.</context>
      <utterance>You do until six p.m.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ohio is cold ground. Picked over, ten months ago. Our people worked it, so did the locals.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But not from this angle. Not thinking he knew her. You've got to send me!</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm Bureau for 28 years, Starling. I won't disobey orders, not even now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But I just became a private citizen. I can go anywhere I want to.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>With ID and a gun...? Impersonating a federal agent is a felony.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at her, a long moment. Catherine's life. Clarice's passion, and future. His loyalty to the Bureau. Call it.</context>
      <utterance>He's going to kill her, Mr. Crawford. This morning, or maybe at noon, but today, and Belvedere's our last chance. I'm flying there, right now, unless you stop me. You want my ID? Here - take it...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She raises her hand to him. She wants to touch him face, or his neck, but can't. Finally she takes his money and card.</context>
      <utterance>There's about $300 here... And a hotline code number. They'll patch you through to me, wherever I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He watches, frightened for both of them, as she backs away, smiles, then turns, racing towards the surveillance van. SOUND UPCUT - the scratchy recording of Fats Waller SINGING, as we...</context>
      <utterance>Thank you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON the moth cage, as Mr. Gumb's fingers search through the humus, and find a plump new cocoon, lifting it out. The door of the cage is left open, and one or two of the adult moths flutter out.</context>
      <utterance>Preeeeecious...!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON a clean towel, beside the sink. The cocoon is gently placed in readiness alongside four shiny skinning knives.</context>
      <utterance>Precious, come on Precious! Busy busy day today...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>CLOSE ON a stainless steel Colt Python, with a six-inch barrel, as the cylinder is spun, and the hammer gets a practice cock. The metallic CLICK is deep and loud. A note of alarm has entered Mr. Gumb's voice.</context>
      <utterance>Momma's gonna be sooo beautiful!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>LOW ANGLE on Mr. Gumb, wearing the kimono, as he walks through his sewing workroom. His back is to us; he is looking anxiously under the furniture. He stops, straightens. Genuinely scared.</context>
      <utterance>You come here this minute, you little scamp!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Precious...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the distant bottom of the pit, we hear Catherine's voice.</context>
      <utterance>Sweetheart...?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Mr. Gumb's fist flies to his mouth, and he sags against the doorframe. A little groan escaped him; the dog answers with a series of YIPS.</context>
      <utterance>She'd down here you sack of shit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You shoot motherfucker you better kill me quick or I'll break her fucking neck, I swear to God!</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Tucking the dog under one arm, she grabs its muzzle, twisting the head. The dog WHINES piteously.</context>
      <utterance>Nooooooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Back off, you son of a bitch! Back off!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>REVERSE ANGLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>On Catherine, as she maintains her grip.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's better... Now get me a live telephone. Get a long extension and lower is down here... And you better do it fast, too, 'cause I think her leg's broken. She's in pain, mister, she needs a vet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. BIMMEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice pauses, at the landing, to look at a framed photo: the familiar graduation portrait. Others pictures show Fredrica as a young girl, toddler, infant - plump and hopeful at each age.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know nothin' new to tell ya. The police been back here so many times already... Fredrica went into Columbus on the bus to see about a job. She left the interview OK. She never come home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BIMMEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Her room's how she left it. Just shut the door when you're done.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>who stares at them, starting to tremble.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Even if he were a woman, he'd have to be a big one...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLOSE ON CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as she jumps to her feet, with a fierce joy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sewing darts. You bastard.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's making himself a "woman suit," Mr. Crawford - out of real women! And he can sew, this guy, he's really skilled. A dressmaker, or a tailor -</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starling -</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why they're all so big - because he needs a lot of skin! He keeps them alive to starve them awhile - to loosen their skin, so that -</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starling, we know who he is! And where he is. We're on our way now.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir, that's great news. But how -</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Johns Hopkins finally came up with a name for us. We fed him into Known Offenders, and he came up cherries.  Subject's name is "Jamie Gumb," AKA "John Grant." Lecter's description was accurate, he just lied about the name.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sewing...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Take a bow. Customs had some paper on his alias. They stopped a carton two years ago at LAX - live caterpillars from Surinam. The addressee was "John Grant." Calumet Power &amp; Light's given us two possible residences under that alias. We're hitting one, Chicago SWAT's taking the other.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Chicago's only about 400 miles from here. I could be there in -</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice tries hard to swallow her disappointment.</context>
      <utterance>No, Starling, there isn't time. And you've still got crucial work to do in Ohio. We want him for murder, not kidnapping. I'm counting on you to link him to the Bimmel girl, before he's indicted.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir... I'll do my best.</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starling - you've earned back your place in the Academy. We never would've found him without you, and nobody's ever going to forget that. Least of all me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes sir. Thank you, sir...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="100" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>somewhat embarrassed, crosses over to him.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Bimmel... did Fredrica ever mention a man named Jamie Gumb, from Calumet City? Or John Grant?  Did she know any men that sew?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. BIMMEL</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She sewed for everybody. Stores, ladies, whatever. I don't know about men.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who was her best friend, Mr. Bimmel? Who'd she hang out with?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="101" n_utterances="12">
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They said she was just rags, like somebody -</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stacy, did Fredrica ever mention a man named Jamie Gumb? Or John Grant?  Do you think she could've had a friend you didn't know about?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. She had a guy, I'da known, believe me. Sewing was her life, she was really great at it. Poor Freddie.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you ever work with her?</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh sure, me'n Pam Malavesi used to help her do alterations for old Mrs. Lippman. Lots of people worked for her, she had the business from all these retail stores? But she was like, totally old, it was more'n she could handle.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where does Mrs. Lippman live? I'd like to talk to her.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Clarice reacts, disappointed at the ending of this trail.</context>
      <utterance>She died. She went to Florida to retire, like two years ago? She dies own there.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that a pretty good job, FBI agent?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You get to travel around and stuff? I mean, better places then this?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sometimes you do.</utterance>
   <speaker>STACY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly she's fighting tears. Clarice reaches to hug her.</context>
      <utterance>Freddie was so happy for me when I got this job. This - toaster giveaways, and Barry Manilow on the speakers all day - she thought this was really hot shit. What did she know, big dummy...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="102" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Gumb frowns out at Clarice. For the first time ever, we get a well-lit view of his bland, pale-eyed moon of a face.</context>
      <utterance>Good afternoon... I wonder if you could help me. I'm looking for Mrs. Lippman's family?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They don't live here anymore.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="103" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Excuse me, but I really do need to talk to you. This was Mrs. Lippman's house. Did you know her?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just briefly. What's the problem, Officer?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="104" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm investigating the death of Fredrica Bimmel. Who are you, please?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jack Gordon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Gordon, did you know Fredrica when she worked for Mrs. Lippman?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. Wait... Was she a great, fat person? I may have seen her, I'm not sure...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="105" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mrs. Lippman had a son, maybe he could help you. I have his card somewhere. Do you mind stepping inside, while I looks for it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="106" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CAMERA RUSHES VERY CLOSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>on his stricken face...</utterance>
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clarice.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="107" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Overstuffed furniture, porcelain figurines. One archway onto the front hall, another onto a dining alcove, and through there, the kitchen. Mr. Gumb is crossing to a rolling desk, raising the top. He bends over, begins poking through cubby holes. His tone is casual, neutral.</context>
      <utterance>That horrible business, I shiver every time I think about it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are they close to catching somebody, do you think?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mr. Gumb stiffens, almost imperceptibly. His back is to her, as he continues opening drawers, rustling papers.</context>
      <utterance>I think we may be, yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Gordon, did you take over this place after Mrs. Lippman died?</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. I bought the house from her, two years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did she leave any records here? Tax or business records? Maybe a list of employees?</utterance>
   <speaker>CLOSE ON MR. GUMB'S BACK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>as he continues his rummaging.</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Out of the folds of his kimono crawls a Death's-head Moth. It creeps slowly to the center of his back, raising its wings.</context>
      <utterance>No, nothing at all. Has the FBI learned something? Because the police here don't seem to have the first clue...</utterance>
   <speaker>MR. GUMB</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you have his description yet, or some fingerprints...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="108" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>tries to force more authority into her voice.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay... Okay, Mr. Gumb, you're under arrest. Down on the floor, hands and legs spread, move it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="109" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>FBI, Catherine, you're safe.</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Safe, SHIT, he's got a gun! Getmeout.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="110" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're all right! Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get me out!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll get you out! Just be quiet so I can hear. Shut that dog up.  Is there a ladder? Is there a rope?</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know! Get me out!!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Catherine. Listen to me. I have to find a rope. I have to leave this room, just for a minute, but -</utterance>
   <speaker>CATHERINE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>NOOOOO! You fucking bitch don't you LEAVE ME down here, DON'T YOU - YOU</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The other officers will be here any minute! you're perfectly safe now! Ignoring Catherine, whose shouts turn to sobs, she backs away, turns, picks one of the other doorways, moves into it quickly.</context>
      <utterance>Shut UP!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="111" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>spins, almost shoots, before seeing -</utterance>
   <speaker>A SMALL REFRIGERATOR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>with its thermostat just switching ON.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="112" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CRAWFORD</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>And then all at once she is sobbing, her knees giving way, but he is there to catch her, he is hugging her fiercely. HOLD ON them for a long beat.</context>
      <utterance>Starling... your father sees you.</utterance>
   <speaker>DIRECTOR BURKE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Congratulations! You are now officers of the Federal Bureau of Investigation...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="113" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>ARDELIA</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Agent Starling! Telephone!</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods to Pilcher, leaves them. Roden, who is quite happily drunk, grabs the startled Ardelia around the waist.</context>
      <utterance>Agent Mapp! Thank you!</utterance>
   <speaker>RODEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Ardelia looks at Pilcher, confused.</context>
      <utterance>Hel-lo, gorgeous! Let's get down.</utterance>
   <speaker>PILCHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just ignore him. He's not a Ph.D.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="114" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Starling.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She freezes, stunned by the familiar voice. Then she turns, waving frantically towards</context>
      <utterance>Well, Clarice, have the lambs stopped screaming...?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="115" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Don't bother with a trace, I won't be on long enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>turns back, gripping the phone more tightly.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where are you, Dr. Lecter?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="116" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your lambs are still for now, Clarice, but not forever... You'll have to earn it again and again, this blessed silence. Because it's the plight that drives you, and the plight will never end.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Dr. Lecter -</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I have no plans to call on you, Clarice, the world being more interesting with you in it. Be sure you extend me the same courtesy.</utterance>
   <speaker>CLARICE</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know I can't make that promise.</utterance>
   <speaker>DR. LECTER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Clarice...  You looked - so very lovely today, in your blue suit.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
