<movie id="382" title="Matrix The">

<dialogue id="1" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>COMPUTER SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A blinking cursor pulses in the electric darkness like a heart coursing with phosphorous light, burning beneath the derma of black-neon glass. A PHONE begins to RING, we hear it as though we were making the call. The cursor continues to throb, relentlessly patient, until --</context>
      <utterance>So close it has no boundaries.</utterance>
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Data now slashes across the screen, information flashing faster than we read.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>2-19-96 13:24:18 REC:Log></context>
      <utterance>Call trans opt: received.</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We listen to the phone conversation as though we were on a third line. The man's name is CYPHER. The woman,</context>
      <utterance>I'm inside. Anything to report?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="2" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The entire screen fills with racing columns of numbers. Shimmering like green-electric rivets, they rush at a 10- digit phone number in the top corner.</context>
      <utterance>Trace program: running.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The area code is identified. The first three numbers suddenly fixed, leaving only seven flowing columns. We begin MOVING TOWARD the screen, CLOSING IN as each digit is matched, one by one, snapping into place like the wheels of a slot machine.</context>
      <utterance>He caught the northbound Howard line. Got off at Sheridan. Stopped at 7-11. Purchased six- pack of beer and a box of Captain Crunch. Returned home.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right, you're relieved. Use the usual exit.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you know when we're going to make contact?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Only two thin digits left.</context>
      <utterance>Soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just between you and me, you don't believe it, do you? You don't believe this guy is the one?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Morpheus believes he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. But what about you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think Morpheus knows things that I don't.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, but if he's wrong -- The final number pops into place --</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you hear that?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hear what?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trace complete. Call origin:</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="3" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you sure this line is clean?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We MOVE STILL CLOSER, the ELECTRIC HUM of the green numbers GROWING INTO an OMINOUS ROAR.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah, course I'm sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I better go.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She hangs up as we PASS THROUGH the numbers, entering the netherworld of the computer screen. Where gradually the sound of a police radio grows around us.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Right. See you on the other side.</utterance>
   <speaker>RADIO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Suddenly, a flashlight cuts open the darkness and we find ourselves in --</context>
      <utterance>Attention all units. Attention all units.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="4" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>BIG COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room is almost devoid of furniture. There is a fold- up table and chair with a phone, a modern, and a powerbook computer. The only light in the room is the glow of the computer. Sitting there, her hands still on the keyboard, is TRINITY; a woman in black leather.</context>
      <utterance>Police! Freeze!</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trinity rises.</context>
      <utterance>Get your hands behind your head!</utterance>
   <speaker>BIG COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She slowly puts her hands behind her head.</context>
      <utterance>Hands behind your head! Now! Do it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="5" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant?</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lieutenant, you were given specific orders --</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm just doing my job. You gimme that Juris-my dick-tion and you can cran it up your ass.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Lieutenant laughs.</context>
      <utterance>The orders were for your protection.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Smith nods to Agent Brown as they start toward the hotel.</context>
      <utterance>I think we can handle one little girl.</utterance>
   <speaker>LIEUTENANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I sent two units. They're bringing her down now.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, Lieutenant, your men are dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="6" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Operator.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morpheus! The link was traced! I don't know how.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Stay calm.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are there any agents?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She takes a deep breath, centering herself.</context>
      <utterance>You have to focus. There is a phone. Wells and Laxe. You can make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right --</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>She drops the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="7" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They stare, slack-jawed, as Agent Brown duplicates the move exactly, landing, rolling over a shoulder, up onto one knee. Just below the building are the runbling tracks of riveted steel. The TRAIN SCREECHES beneath her, a rattling blur of gray metal. Trinity junps, landing easily. She looks back just as Agent Brown hurls through the air barely reaching the last car Agent Brown stands, yanking out a gun. Trinity is running hard as BULLETS WHISTLE past her head. Ahead she sees her only chance, 50 feet beyond the point where the train has begun to turn, there is -- A window; a yellow glow in the midst of a dark brick building. Trinity zeroes in on it, running as hard as she can, her speed compounded by the train. The SCREAM of the STEEL rises as she nears the edge where the train rocks into the turn. Trinity hurtles into the empty night space, her body leveling into a dive. She falls, arms covering her head as -- The whole world seems to spin on its axis -- And she crashes with an EXPLOSION of GLASS and WOOD, then falls onto a back stairwell, tumbling, bouncing down stairs bleeding, broken -- But still alive. Through the smashed window, she glimpses Agent Brown, still on the train, his tie and coat whipping in the wind; stone-faced, he touches his ear piece as the train slides him past the window. Trinity tries to move. Everything hurts.</context>
      <utterance>Motherfucker -- that's impossible!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She stands and limps down the rest of the stairs.</context>
      <utterance>Get up, Trinity. You're fine. Get up -- just get up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="8" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you get anything from the room?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The handset of the pay phone lays on the ground, separated in the crash like a severed limb.</context>
      <utterance>Their next target. The name is Neo.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We'll need a search running.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We are SUCKED TOWARDS the mouthpiece of the phone, CLOSER and CLOSER, UNTIL the smooth gray plastic spreads out like a horizon and the small HOLES WIDEN until we fall through one -- Swallowed by the darkness that becomes -- A computer screen. We are on-line, inside a chat room called "The Matrix." It is an exklusive web-site where hackers hang out.</context>
      <utterance>It's already begun.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>SUPERASTIC: I mean Sega.</context>
      <utterance>JACKON: I heard Morpheus has been on this board. SUPERASTIC: Morpheus doesn't even exist and the Matrix is nothing but an advertising gimmick 4 a new game. TIMAXE: All I want to know is Trinity really a girl? LODIII: 87% of all women on line are really men. QUARK: The Matrix is a euphemism for the government. SUPERASTIC: No, The Matrix is the system controlling our lives. TIMAXE: You mean MTV.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="9" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He finishes his cereal and is about to disconnect when an anonynous message slices onto the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Fuckin' idiots don't know shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo is frozen when he reads his name.</context>
      <utterance>Do you want to know what the Matrix is, Neo?</utterance>
   <speaker>SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>SUPERASTIC: Who said that? JACKON: Who's Neo? GIBSON: This is a private board. If you want to know, follow the white rabbit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell...</utterance>
   <speaker>SCREEN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A chill runs down his spine and when someone KNOCKS on his door he almost jumps out of his chair. He looks at the door, then back at the computer but the message is gone. He shakes his head, not completely sure what happened. Again, someone knocks. Cautiously, Neo approaches the door.</context>
      <utterance>TIMAXE: Someone is hacking the hackers! FOS4: It's Morpheus!!!!! JACKON: Identify yourself. Knock, knock, Neo.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Recognizing the voice, he relaxes and opens it. ANTHONY, who lives down the hall, is standing outside with a group of friends.</context>
      <utterance>Hey, Tommy-boy! You in there?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you want, Anthony?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTHONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up the red notice that accompanies the Denver boot.</context>
      <utterance>I need your help, man. Desperate. They got me, man. The shackles of fascism.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He holds up two hundred dollars and Neo opens the door. Anthony's girlfriend, DUJOUR, stops in front of Neo.</context>
      <utterance>You got the money this time?</utterance>
   <speaker>DUJOUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can really get that thing off, right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTHONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, honey, he may look like just another geek but this here is all we got left standing between Big Brother and the New World Order.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="10" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>ANTHONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He slaps the money in Neo's hand.</context>
      <utterance>Look at 'em. Automatons. Don't think about what they're- doing or why. Computer tells 'em what to do and they do it. FRIEND l Thc banality of evil.</utterance>
   <speaker>ANTHONY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks, neighbor.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUJOUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why don't you come to the party with us?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't know. I have to work tomorrow.</utterance>
   <speaker>DUJOUR</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at her and suddenly notices on her black leather motorcycle jacket dozens of pins: bands, symbols, slogans, military medals and -- A small white rabbit. The ROOM TILTS.</context>
      <utterance>Come on. It'll be fun.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah, yeah. Sure, I'll go.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="11" n_utterances="28">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Neo.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know that --</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know a lot about you. I've been wanting to meet you for some time.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>My name is Trinity.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Kansas City D-Base?</context>
      <utterance>Trinity? The Trinity? The Trinity that cracked the I.R.S.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That was a long time ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gee-zus.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I just thought... you were a guy.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo is a little embarrassed.</context>
      <utterance>Most guys do.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you want to go sorewhere and talk?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The MUSIC is so loud they must stand very close, talking directly into each other's ear.</context>
      <utterance>No. It's safe here and I don't have much time.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>That was your note, wasn't it?</context>
      <utterance>That was you on the board tonight.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had to gamble that you would see and they wouldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who wouldn't?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't explain everything to you. I'm sure that it's all going to seem very strange, but I brought you here to warn you, Neo. You are in a lot of danger.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What? Why?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're watching you. Something happened and they found out about you. Normally, if our target is exposed we let it go. But this time, we can't do that.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't understand --</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You came here because you wanted to know the answer to a hacker's question.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Matrix. What is the Matrix?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Her body is against his; her lips very close to his ear.</context>
      <utterance>Twelve years ago I met a man, a great man, who said that no one could be told the answer to that question. That they had to see it, to believe it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a hypnotic quality to her voice and Neo feels the words like a drug, seeping into him.</context>
      <utterance>He told me that no one should look for the answer unless they have to because once you see it, everything changes. Your life and the world you live in will never be the same. It's as if you wake up one morning and the sky is falling.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She takes hold of him with her eyes.</context>
      <utterance>The truth is out there, Neo. It's looking for you and it will find you, if you want it to.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's all I can tell you right now. Good-bye, Neo. And good luck.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She leans close, her lips alrost touching his ear as she whispers.</context>
      <utterance>Wait. Who was it? Who was the man?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns and he watches her melt into the shifting wall of bodies. A SOUND RISES steadily, growing out of the music, pressing in on Neo until it is all he can hear as we --</context>
      <utterance>You know who.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="12" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>RHINEHEART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stops, glancing over his glasses at Neo, who turns in time.</context>
      <utterance>You have a problem, Mr. Anderson. You think that you're special. You believe that somehow the rules do not apply to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHINEHEART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His long, bony fingers resume clicking the keyboard.</context>
      <utterance>Obviously, you are mistaken.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHINEHEART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns again.</context>
      <utterance>This company is one of the top software companies in the world because every single employee understands that they are a part of a whole. Thus, if an employee has a problem, the company has a problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>RHINEHEART</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The time has come to make a choice, Mr. Anderson. Either you choose to be at your desk on time from this day forth, or you choose to find yourself another job. Do I make myself clear?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes, Mr. Rhineheart. Perfectly clear.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="13" n_utterances="41">
   <speaker>TALL EMPLOYEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did he say?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smirks.</context>
      <utterance>If I was late again, I'm going to be fired.</utterance>
   <speaker>TALL EMPLOYEE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo glares at him, as he sinks down.</context>
      <utterance>Well, it was nice working with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Neo turns and finds a FEDERAL EXPRESS MAN at his cubicle door.</context>
      <utterance>Thomas Anderson?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo signs the electronic pad and the Fedex guy hands him the softpak.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. That's me.</utterance>
   <speaker>FEDEX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the bag. Inside is a CELLULAR PHONE. It seems the instant it is in his hand, it RINGS. Unnerved, he flips it open.</context>
      <utterance>Have a nice day.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Neo. This is Morpheus. Neo's knees give and he falls into his chair.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I had hoped for this conversation to take place under less adverse conditions, but you can never count on hope, can you, Neo?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I've been watching you, Neo, and I want to meet you. I don't know if you're ready to see what I want to show you, but unfortunately, we have run out of time. They're coming for you, Neo. And I'm not sure what they're going to do.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who's coming for me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stand up and see for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Neo starts to stand.</context>
      <utterance>Yes. Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>His head slowly peeks up over the partition. At the elevator, he sees Agent Brown and Agent Jones leading a group of cops. A female employee turns and points out Neo's cubicle. Neo ducks.</context>
      <utterance>Do it slowly. Slowly. The elevator.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy fuckin' shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>One cop stays at the elevator, the others follow the agents.</context>
      <utterance>Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the fuck do they want with me?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm not sure. But, if you don't want to find out, you better get out of there.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The agents are moving quickly towards the cubicle.</context>
      <utterance>I can guide you out, but you have to do exactly what I say.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The cubicle across from you is empty.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But what if...?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Neo lunges across the hall, diving into the other cubicle just as the agents turn into his row. Neo crams himself into a dark corner, clutching the phone tightly to him.</context>
      <utterance>Go! Now!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>The agents enter Neo's empty cubicle. A cop is sent to search the bathroom. Morpheus' voice is a whisper in Neo's ear.</context>
      <utterance>Stay here for a moment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Brown is talking to the tall employee.</context>
      <utterance>A little longer...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Sweat trickles down his forehead.</context>
      <utterance>When I tell you, go to the end of the row to the first office on the left, stay.as low as you can.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Neo rolls out of the cubicle, his eyes popping as he freezes right behind a cop who has just turned around. Staying crouched, he sneaks away, down the row, SHOOTING across the opening to the first office on the left. The room is empty.</context>
      <utterance>Now.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Open it.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Now there is a window.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus laughs quietly.</context>
      <utterance>How do you know all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>He opens the window. The window howls into the room.</context>
      <utterance>The answer is coming, Neo.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Leaning out the window, he sees that the scaffold is several offices away.</context>
      <utterance>Outside, there's a scaffold. You can use it to get to the roof.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! It's too far away.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Neo looks down; the building's glass wall vertigos into a concrete chasm.</context>
      <utterance>There's a small ledge. It's a short climb. You can make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way, no way, this is crazy.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CLICK. He hangs up. Neo looks at the door, then back at the scaffold.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be controlled by your fear, Neo. There are only two ways out of this building. One is that scaffold. The other is in their custody. You take a chance either way. I leave it to you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He climbs up onto the window ledge. Hanging onto the frame, he steps onto the small ledge. The scaffold seems even farther away.</context>
      <utterance>This is insane! Why is this happening to me? What did I do? I'm nobody. I didn't do anything. Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The WIND suddenly BLASTS up the face of the building, knocking Neo off balance. Recoiling, he clings harder to the frame, and the phone falls out of his hand. He watches as it is swallowed by the distance beneath him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to die.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He climbs back into the office just as a cop opens the door.</context>
      <utterance>This is insane. I can't do this! Forget it!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I didn't do anything!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="14" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He opens the file. Paper rattle marks the silence as he flips several pages. Neo cannot tell if he is looking at the file or at him.</context>
      <utterance>As you can see, we've had our eye on you for some time now, Mr. Anderson.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pages continue to turn.</context>
      <utterance>It seems that you have been living two lives. In one life, you are Thomas A. Anderson, program writer for a respectable software company. You have a social security number, you pay your taxes and you help your land lady carry out her garbage.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The other life is lived in computers where you go by the hacker alias Neo, and are guilty of virtually every computer crime we have a law for, including the unauthorized use of the D.M.V. system for the removal of automobile boots. Neo feels himself sinking into a pit of shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He closes the file.</context>
      <utterance>One of these,lives has a future. One of them does not.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes his sunglasses; his eyes are an unnatural ice- blue.</context>
      <utterance>I'm going to be as forthcoming as I can be, Mr. Anderson. You are here because we need your help.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans closer.</context>
      <utterance>We know that you have been contacted by a certain individual. A man who calls himself Morpheus. Whatever you think you know about this man is irrelevant to the fact that he is wanted for acts of terrorism in more countries than any other man in the world. He is considered by many authorities to be the most dangerous man alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo tries to match his stare.</context>
      <utterance>My colleagues believe that I am wasting my time with you, but I believe you want to do the right thing. It is obvious that you are an intelligent man, Mr. Anderson, and that you are interested in the future. That is why I believe you are ready to put your past mistakes behind you and get on with your life.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo nods to himself.</context>
      <utterance>We are willing to wipe the slate clean, to give you a fresh start and all we are asking in return is your cooperation in bringing a known terrorist to justice.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Wow. That sounds like a real good deal. But I think I have a better one. How about I give you the finger -- He does.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Smith puts his glasses back on.</context>
      <utterance>And you can cram that file up your Secret Service sphincter.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You disappoint me, Mr. Anderson.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ain't seen nothing yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The irony of your situation is that you have no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Smith smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You can't scare me with this gestapo crap. I know my rights. I want my phone call.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The question unnerves Neo and strangely, he begins to feel the muscles in his jaw tighten. The standing agents snicker, watching Neo's confusion grow into panic. Neo feels his lips grow soft and sticky as they slowly seal shut, melding into each other until all trace of his mouth is gone. Wild with fear, he lunges for the door but the agents restrain him holding him in the chair.</context>
      <utterance>And tell me, Mr. Anderson, what good is a phone call iy you are unable to speak?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith nods and the other two rip open his shirt. From a case taken out of his suit coat, Smith removes a long, fiber-optic wire tap. Neo struggles helplessly as Smith dangles the wire over his exposed abdomen. Horrified, he watches as the electronic device animates, become an organic creature that resembles a hybrid of an insect and a fluke worm. Thin, whisker-like tendrils reach out and probe into Neo's navel. He bucks wildly as Smith drops the creature which looks for a moment like an uncut umbilical cord -- Before it begins to burrow its, tail thrashing as it worms its way inside.</context>
      <utterance>You are going to help us, Mr. Anderson, whether you want to or not.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS .</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This line is tapped, so I must be brief.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The agents --</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Neo feels sick.</context>
      <utterance>They got to you first, but they've underestimated how important you are. If they knew what I know, you would probably be dead.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Neo's throat cracks, dry as the Sahara.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know what you are thinking right now but I want you to understand that I will not give up on you until you give up on me.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you still want to meet?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... Yes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>CLICK. He closes his eyes, unsure of what he has done.</context>
      <utterance>Take the Howard line south.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="15" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>We got him. Call the chop-shop.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She tears off a long strip of black duct-tape and reaches for his face.</context>
      <utterance>Listen to me, Neo. You have to, trust us.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She seals his eyes shut with the tape.</context>
      <utterance>This has to be done for your protection and ours.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't understand right now, but if you're not one of us, you're one of them.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="16" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Va va va voom. Still the hottest software around.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo hears the voices around him.</context>
      <utterance>Hello, Gizmo.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This is really the guy? The guy that Morpheus thinks --</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But he's so old.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Are you going to help us or aren't you?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hacksaw is a huge man in a leather welder's apron. He shoulders Neo and hauls him into the van. A moment later the green lights of Lower Wacker curve over the tinted windshield as the van rushes through the underworld.</context>
      <utterance>Hacksaw. Load up the copper-top and let's get the hell outta here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="17" n_utterances="25">
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pulls up the goggles hanging at his neck and they blink to life with tiny halogen lights and lenses irising to varying levels of magnification.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, first we take a little look under the hood.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He inserts acupuncture-like needles into Neo's lower abdomen. The needles are wired to video monitors. Hacksaw pilots the fiber-optic lens.</context>
      <utterance>You're going to feel a little prick.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We think you're bugged. We can't take you to Morpheus until you're clean.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On a monitor, we see the bug nestled in among Neols large intestines.</context>
      <utterance>There it is.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hacksaw loads a hypodermic needle and pumps an anesthetic around Neols navel. Using a device that looks like a miniature speculum, Gizmo inserts a knuckled dental pick. Typing into a calculator keypad wired to the pick, he automates the tip. On the monitor, we watch it telescope out and the end separate into a tiny hooked, metal claw.</context>
      <utterance>Hit him with 10 ccs of local.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The claw snags hold of the bug.</context>
      <utterance>Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>But the bug reacts violently. Neo screams as it wraps itself around the soft tissue web of intestine.</context>
      <utterance>Gotcha!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's happening?</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo writhes in pain.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. They've never done that before.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hold him down.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jesus! God!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do something!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got it! Maybe we can stun it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We watch Neo, who can't see what they are talking about.</context>
      <utterance>Are you crazy? That will kill him.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It'll work. Come on, do it or Hacksaw will.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The instant he hears the word, he knows.</context>
      <utterance>Do what?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Clear.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The cry is frozen in his mouth as the paddles hit his chest. Gizmo wrestles with the bug.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit --</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, the electricity convulses through him as Gizmo yanks the speculum out.</context>
      <utterance>Hit him again!</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trinity touches Neo, who is just beginning to breathe. She eases the tape off his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>Got it!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods.</context>
      <utterance>Neo, are you okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Hanging from the claw pick is the inanimate metal wire- tap.</context>
      <utterance>It's over. We got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nasty little bugger, ain't it?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="18" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks for your help, Gizmo.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods then climbs out of the van. Gizmo ogles the tight leather pants.</context>
      <utterance>I just hope the man knows what he's doing.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trinity turns around.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn, what I wouldn't give for a copy of that software.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He howls with adolescent laughter as the van pulls away. Trinity turns to Neo.</context>
      <utterance>Gizmo, you don't have the hardware to handle this software.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's go. He's waiting.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="19" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo can hear his own heart pounding.</context>
      <utterance>This is it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me give one piece of advice. Be honest. He knows more than you can possibly imagine.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="20" n_utterances="72">
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wears a long black coat and his eyes are invisible behind circular mirrored glasses. He strides to Neo and they shake hands.</context>
      <utterance>At last.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome, Neo. As you no doubt have guessed, I am Morpheus.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's an honor.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nods to Trinity.</context>
      <utterance>Please. Come. Sit.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She bows her head sharply and exits through a door to an adjacent room. They sit across from one another in cracked, burgundy- leather chairs.</context>
      <utterance>Thank you, Trinity.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I imagine, right now, you must be feeling a bit like Alice, tumbling down the rabbit hole?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You could say that.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A smile, razor-thin, curls the corner of his lips.</context>
      <utterance>I can see it in your eyes. You have the look of a man who accepts what he sees because he is expecting to wake up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ironically, this is not far from the truth. But I'm getting ahead of myself. Can you tell me, Neo, why are you here?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're Morpheus, you're a legend. Most hackers would die to meet you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yes. Thank you. But I think we both know there's more to it than that. Do you believe in fate, Neo?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why not?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Because I don't like the idea that I'm not in control of my life.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Again, that smile that could cut glass.</context>
      <utterance>I know exactly what you mean.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let me tell you why you are here. You are here because you have the gift.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What gift?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo shrugs.</context>
      <utterance>I've watched you, Neo. You do not use a computer like a tool. You use it like it was part of yourself. What you can do inside a computer is not normal. I know. I've seen it. What you do is magic.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's not magic.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans forward.</context>
      <utterance>But it is, Neo. It is. How else would you describe what has been happening to you?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo shakes his head.</context>
      <utterance>We are trained in this world to accept only what is rational and logical. Have you ever wondered why?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>As children, we do not separate the possible from the impossible which is why the younger a mind is the easier it is to free while a mind like yours can be very difficult.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Free from what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo locks at his eyes but only sees a reflection of himself.</context>
      <utterance>From the Matrix.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo swallows and nods his head.</context>
      <utterance>Do you want to know what it is, Neo?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The LEATHER CREAKS as he leans back.</context>
      <utterance>It's that feeling you have had all your life. That feeling that something was wrong with the world. You don't know what it is but it's there, like a splinter in your mind, driving you mad, driving you to me. But what is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Matrix is everywhere, it's all around us, here even in this room. You can see it out your window, or on your television. You feel it when you go to work, or go to church or pay your taxes. It is the world that has been pulled over your eyes to blind you from the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What truth?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Outside, the WIND BATTERS a loose PANE of glass.</context>
      <utterance>That you are a slave, Neo. That you, like everyone else, was born into bondage... ... kept inside a prison that you cannot smell, taste, or touch. A prison for your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Unfortunately, no one can be told what the Matrix is. You have to see it for yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In Neo's right hand, Morpheus drops a red pill.</context>
      <utterance>Hold out your hands.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In his left, a blue pill.</context>
      <utterance>This is your last chance. After this, there is no going back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The pills in his open hands are reflected in the glasses.</context>
      <utterance>You take the blue pill and the story ends. You wake in your bed and you believe whatever you want to believe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo feels the smooth skin of the capsules, with the moisture growing in his palms.</context>
      <utterance>You take the red pill and you stay in Wonderland and I show you how deep the rabbit-hole goes.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo opens his mouth and swallows the red pill. The Cheshire smile returns.</context>
      <utterance>Remember that all I am offering is the truth. Nothing more.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leads Neo into the other room, which is cramped with high-tech equipment, glowing ash-bliie and electric green from the racks of monitors. Trinity, Apoc and Cypher look up as they enter.</context>
      <utterance>Follow me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cypher saddles up to Morpheus, talking in a hushed tone away from, Neo.</context>
      <utterance>I knew he would.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morpheus, I know what you believe but I think this is a mistake. We're rushing him. He's old. I'm afraid he might pop.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo recognizes the large man from the El train.</context>
      <utterance>Haven't I always told you, Cypher, not to let fear control your life. Apoc, are we on-line?</utterance>
   <speaker>APOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He and Trinity are working quickly, hardwiring a complex system of monitors, modules and drives.</context>
      <utterance>Almost.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apoc? You wrote the Four Horsemen Virus.</utterance>
   <speaker>APOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the center of the room sits a chair. Near the chair is an old oval dressing mirror that is cracked.</context>
      <utterance>Neo, time is always against us. Will you take a seat there?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo sits and Trinity begins gently fixing white electrode disks to his head, arns, and the back of his neck.</context>
      <utterance>I imagine you know sonething about virtual reality.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A little.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tell me about it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Essentially, it's a hardware system that uses an apparatus; headgear, gloves and whatever to make you feel that you are in a computer program.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If the virtual reality apparatus, as you called it, was wired to all of your senses and controlled them completely, would you be able to tell the difference between the virtual world and the real world?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You might not, no.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo whispers to Trinity.</context>
      <utterance>No, you wouldn't.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She nods, placing a set of headphones over his ears. They are wired to an old hotel phone.</context>
      <utterance>You did all this?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Distantly, through the ear phones, he hears Apoc POUNDING on a KEYBOARD. Sweat beads his face. His eyes blink and twitch when he notices the mirror. Wide-eyed he stares as it begins to heal itself, a webwork of cracks that slowly run together as though the mirror were becoming liquid.</context>
      <utterance>The pill you took is part of a trace program. It's going to make things feel a bit strange.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cypher works with Apoc checking reams of phosphorescent data. Trinity monitors Neo's electric vital signs. Neo reaches out to touch the mirror and his fingers disappear beneath the rippling surface. Quickly, he tries to pull his fingers out but the mirror stretches in long rubbery strands like mirrored-taffy stuck to his fingertips.</context>
      <utterance>Shit...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is this? Mescaline?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The strands thin like rubber cement as he pulls away, until the fragile wisps of mirror thread break. With the TINKLING of GLASS, shimmering snowflakes of electric-blinking mercury fall, hit the ground, and fade. He looks at his hand; fingers distended into mirrored icicles that begin to melt rapidly, dripping, running like wax down his fingers, spreading across his palms where he sees his face reflected.</context>
      <utterance>Just relax, Neo.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Uh-oh...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's going into replication.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Apoc?</utterance>
   <speaker>APOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus takes out a cellular phone and dials a number.</context>
      <utterance>Still nothing.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mirror gel seems to come to life, racing, crawling up his arns like hundreds of insects.</context>
      <utterance>Tank, we're going to need the signal soon. Stay calm, Neo.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The mirror creeps up his neck as Neo begins to panic, tipping his head as though he were sinking into the mirror, trying to keep his mouth up.</context>
      <utterance>It's cold.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus is right next to him, with the phone.</context>
      <utterance>It's all over me --</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got a fibrillation!</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew it, I knew it...</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Streams of mercury run from Neo's nose.</context>
      <utterance>Shit! Apoc?</utterance>
   <speaker>APOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>An ALARM, on Trinity's monitor ERUPTS.</context>
      <utterance>Targeting... almost there.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going into arrest!</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gonna pop!</utterance>
   <speaker>APOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lock! I got him!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His eyes tear with mirror, rolling up and closing as a high-pitched ELECTRIC SCREAM ERUPTS in the headphones -- It is a piercing SHRIEK like a computer calling to another computer -- Neo's body arches in agony and we are pulled like we were pulled into the holes of the phone Sucked into his SCREAM and swallowed by darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Now, Tank now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="21" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>Do you think he could be the One?</context>
      <utterance>Do you think Morpheus is right?</utterance>
   <speaker>WOMAN</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter now. But if he's wrong...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="22" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>... am I dead?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Far from it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="23" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>DOZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He needs a lot of work.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dozer and Morpheus are operating on Neo.</context>
      <utterance>I know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Fluorescent light sticks burn unnaturally bright.</context>
      <utterance>Your muscles have atrophied. We're rebuilding them.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why do my eyes hurt?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus takes his sunglasses off and puts them on Neo. Neo lays back.</context>
      <utterance>You've never used them before.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Rest, Neo. The answers are coming.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="24" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What is this place?</context>
      <utterance>Morpheus, what's happened to me?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>More important than what is when?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The wind is knocked from Neo's chest.</context>
      <utterance>You believe the year is 1997 when in fact it is much closer to 2197. I can't say for certain what year it is because we honestly do not know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's not possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I promised you the truth, Neo, and the truth is that the world you were living in was a lie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll show you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="25" n_utterances="34">
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They climb a ladder up to the main deck.</context>
      <utterance>This is my ship, the Nebuchadnezzar. It's a hovercraft. Small like a submarine. It's dark. It's cramped and cold. But it's home.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trinity smiles and nods.</context>
      <utterance>This is the main deck. You know most of my crew.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The names and faces wash meaninglessly over Neo.</context>
      <utterance>The ones you don't know. That's Mouse and Switch. The two big guys are Tank and Dozer.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>It is a swamp of bizarre electronic equipment. Vines of coaxial hang and snake to and from huge monolithic battery slabs, a black portable satellite dish and banks of little systems and computer monitors. At the center of the web, there are six ectoskeleton chairs made of a poly-alloy frame and suspension harness. Near the circle of chairs is the control console and operator's station where the network is monitored.</context>
      <utterance>And this, this is the Core. This is where we broadcast our pirate signal and hack into the Matrix.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo allows himself to be helped into one of the chairs.</context>
      <utterance>Help him, Trinity.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo nods.</context>
      <utterance>Do you remember when I asked you about an apparatus that could turn a virtual reality into reality?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He touches Neo's head.</context>
      <utterance>It's right here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo feels Morpheus guiding a coaxial line into the jack at the back of his neck. The cable has the same kind of cerebellum chip we saw inside the plant.</context>
      <utterance>And it's accessed here.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There are several disturbing NOISES as he works the needle in. We MOVE IN as Neo's shoulders bunch and his face tightens into a grimace until a loud CLICK fires and his ears pop like when you equalize them underwater. He relaxes, opening his eyes as we pull back to a feeling of weightlessness inside another place --</context>
      <utterance>This will feel a little weird.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Startled, Neo whips around and finds Morpheus now in the room with him.</context>
      <utterance>This is the Construct.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus walks past Neo and when Neo turns he sees the two leather chairs from the hotel set up in front of a large-screen television.</context>
      <utterance>It is our loading program. We can load anything from clothes, to weapons, to training simulations. Anything we need.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo stands at the back of the chair as Morpheus sits.</context>
      <utterance>Sit down.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Right now, we're inside a computer program?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo's hands run over the cracked leather.</context>
      <utterance>Wild, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>This isn't real?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>TELEVISION. We drift through the Windy City circa 1996.</context>
      <utterance>What is real? How do you define real? If you're talking about your senses, what you feel, taste, smell, or see, then all you're talking about are electrical signals interpreted by your brain. He picks up a remote control and clicks ON the</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We GLIDE AT the television as he changes the channel.</context>
      <utterance>This is the Chicago you know. Chicago as it was at the end of the twentieth century. This Chicago exists only as part of a neural-interactive simulation that we call the Matrix.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sky is an endless sea of black and green bile. The earth, scorched and split like burnt flesh, spreads out beneath us as we ENTER the television.</context>
      <utterance>You have been living inside Baulliaurd's vision, inside the map, not the territory. This is Chicago as it exists today.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the distance, we see the ruins of a future Chicago protruding from the wasteland like the blackened ribs of a long-dead corpse.</context>
      <utterance>'The desert of the real.'</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Still MOVING, we TURN and find Neo and Morpheus; the chairs now sitting in the middle of the black desert. Dizzy, Neo holds onto the chair.</context>
      <utterance>We are, right now, miles below the earth's surface. The only place humans can survive outside the Matrix is underground.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In his sunglasses, we see storm clouds gather.</context>
      <utterance>It started early in the twenty- first century, with the birth of artificial intelligence, a singular consciousness that spawned an entire race of machines.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>In the circular window of the glasses, EXPLOSIONS light up a bloody battle field.</context>
      <utterance>At first all they wanted was to be treated as equals, entitled to the same human inalienable rights. Whatever they were given, it was not enough.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We MOVE INTO his glasses and the war surrounds us.</context>
      <utterance>We don't know who struck first. Us or them. But sometime at the end of the twenty-first century the battle was joined.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>At last we see the Sentinels; killing machines that are at once terrifying and beautiful. They have an organic architecture like a microbiotic organism, that is perpetually in motion. The Sentinel cracks the body armor of a soldier, splitting open the soft, stearing meat inside.</context>
      <utterance>The war raged for generations and turned the face of our planet from green and blue to black and red.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Sentinel locks up, as heat lightning of black ink bursts against the sky, spreading into a permanent cloud of stain.</context>
      <utterance>It scorched and burned the sky. Without the sun, the machines sought out a new energy source to survive.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We return to the power plant that Neo escaped from where we see human beings looking almost blissful in their gelatin cocoons.</context>
      <utterance>They discovered a new form of fusion. All that was required to initiate the reaction was a small electric charge. Throughout human history we have been dependent on machines to survive. Fate, it seems, is not without a sense of irony.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Outside, spreading all around the power plant, beneath a breathing greenhouse, are the growing fields.</context>
      <utterance>The human body generates more bio- electricity than a 120-volt battery and over 25,000 B.T.U.'s of body heat.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Huge farm-like reapers are harvesting the crop.</context>
      <utterance>We are, as an energy source, easily renewable and completely recyclable, the dead liquified and fed intravenously to the living.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We see inside a clear tubular husk. Floating in viscous fluid, there is a human fetus; its soft skull already growing around the brain-jack.</context>
      <utterance>All they needed to control this new battery was something to occupy our mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We PULL BACK to find the image is now on the television and we are again inside the white space of the Construct.</context>
      <utterance>And so they built a prison out of our past, wired it to our brains and turned us into slaves.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No! I don't believe it! It's not possible!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The room without walls begins to spin.</context>
      <utterance>I didn't say that it would be easy, Neo. I just said that it would be the truth.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Stop! Let me out! I want out!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="26" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get this thing out of me!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Dozer holds him while Trinity unlocks it. Once it's out, he tears away from them, falling as he trips free of the harness.</context>
      <utterance>Easy, Neo. Easy.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>On his hands and knees, he reels as the world spins. Sweat pours off him as a pressure builds inside his skull as if his brian had been put into a centrifuge.</context>
      <utterance>Don't touch me! Get away from me!</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Vomiting violently, Neo pitches forward and blacks out.</context>
      <utterance>He's going to pop!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="27" n_utterances="11">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus sitting like a shadow on a chair in the far corner.</context>
      <utterance>I can't go back, can I?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo isn't sure of that answer.</context>
      <utterance>No. But if you could, would you really want to?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares into the darkness, confessing as much to himself as Neo.</context>
      <utterance>I feel that I owe you an apology. There is a rule that we do not free a mind once it reaches a certain age. It is dangerous. They have trouble letting go.. Their mind turns against them. I've seen it happen. I broke the rule because I had to.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pauses.</context>
      <utterance>When the Matrix was first built there was a man born inside that had the ability to change what he wanted, to remake the Matrix as he saw fit. It was this man that freed the first of us and taught us the secret of the war; control the Matrix and you control the future.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo can feel his eyes on him.</context>
      <utterance>When he died, the Oracle at the temple of Zion prophesied his return and envisioned an end to the war and freedom for our people. That is why there are those of us that have spent our entire lives searching the Matrix, looking for him.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I did what I did, because I believe we have been brought here for a reason, Neo. You are here to serve a purpose, just as I am here to serve mine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus smiles, leaning towards hin.</context>
      <utterance>I told you I don't believe in fate.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands up.</context>
      <utterance>But I do, Neo. I do.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Get some rest. You're going to need it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>For what?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Your training.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="28" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morning. Did you sleep?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He offers his hand and Neo shakes it. He notices that Tank doesn't have any jacks.</context>
      <utterance>You will tonight. I guarantee it. I'm Tank. I'll be your operator.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have...</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Any holes? Nope. Me and my brother Dozer, we are 100 percent pure, old fashioned, home-grown human. Born free. Right here in the real world. Genuine child of Zion.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Zion?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tank smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Zion is the place, man. You'll see it one day. Last human city. All we got left.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn, I got to tell you I'm fairly excited to see what you are capable of. I mean if Morpheus is right and all. We're not supposed to talk.about any of that, but if you are, well then this is an exciting time. We got a lot to do so let's get to it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="29" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tank smiles as he plops into his operator's chair. He begins flipping through a tall carousel loaded with micro discs.</context>
      <utterance>We're supposed to load all these operations programs first, but this is some major boring shit. Why don't we start something a little fun?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo reads the label on the disk.</context>
      <utterance>How about sore combat training?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tank slides the disk into Neo's supplement drive.</context>
      <utterance>Jiujitsu? I'm going to learn jujitsu?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiling, Tank punches the "load" code. His body jumps against the harness as his eyes clamp shut. The monitors kick wildly as his heart pounds, adrenaline surges, and his brain sizzles. An instant later his eyes snap open.</context>
      <utterance>No way.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Holy shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hey, Mikey, he likes it! Ready for more?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hell yes!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="30" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tank looks at his watch, rubs his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>How is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo's body spasms and relaxes as his eyes open, breath hissing from his lips. He looks like he just orgasmed. He locks at Morpheus.</context>
      <utterance>Ten hours straight. He's a machine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus sits in the drive chair next to hin. He nods to Tank.</context>
      <utterance>This is incredible. I know Kung Fu.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Show me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="31" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He assumes a fighting stance.</context>
      <utterance>This is a sparring program, similar to the programmed reality of the Matrix. Consider this your first lesson.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo assumes a similar stance, cautiously circling until he gives a short cry and launches a furious attack. It is like a Jackie Chan movie at high speed, fists and feet striking from every angle as Neo presses his attack</context>
      <utterance>Attack me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="32" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus attacks him and it is like nothing we have seen. His feet and fists are everywhere taking Neo apart. For every blow Neo blocks, five more hit their marks until -- Neo falls. Panting, on his hands and knees, blood spits fror, his mouth speckling the white floor of the Dojo.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Adaption. Improvisation. But your weakness isn't your technique.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did I beat you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You -- You're too fast.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo is frustrated, still unable to catch his breath.</context>
      <utterance>Do you think my being faster, stronger has anything to do with my muscles in this place?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo squints at him.</context>
      <utterance>Do you believe that's air you are breathing now?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo stands, nodding.</context>
      <utterance>If you can free your mind, the body will follow.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Their fists fly with pneumatic speed.</context>
      <utterance>Again.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="33" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeezus Keerist! That boy is fast!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You ever seen anyone that fast that soon, Tank?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never.</utterance>
   <speaker>APOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morpheus is right. He's got to be the one.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="34" n_utterances="19">
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't believe it!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo pants.</context>
      <utterance>You are angry with me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I, uh... maybe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's all right. It's natural.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I feel better.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Good, good. Anger is a gift, Neo, but it's a heavy one.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo straightens as the dojo DISSOLVES away like a curtain lifting, leaving the two men now standing on a building rooftop in a city skyline.</context>
      <utterance>Tank, load the jump program.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A WIND HOWLS, whipping Morpheus' long coat to the side.</context>
      <utterance>You have to learn to let go of that anger. You must let go of everything.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus spins, running hard at the edge of the rooftop. And jumps. He sails through the air, his coat billowing out behind him like a cape -- Somersaults once and lands on the rooftop across the street.</context>
      <utterance>You must empty yourself to free your mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo looks down at the street twenty floors below, then at Morpheus an impossible fifty feet away.</context>
      <utterance>Shit.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He takes a deep breath.</context>
      <utterance>Okie dokie.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He concentrates. Runs.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Free my mind. Right. No problem.</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's gonna make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>APOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No way. Not possible.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one's ever made their first jump.</utterance>
   <speaker>SWITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What if he does?</utterance>
   <speaker>APOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He won't.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trinity stares at the screen, her fists clenching as she whispers.</context>
      <utterance>It's never been done.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="35" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo nods quietly.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone falls the first time.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you never know failure, how can you know success?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What does it mean?</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't mean anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo's eyes open as Tank eases the plug out. He tries to move and groans, cradling his ribs. While Tank helps Morpheus, Neo spits blood into his hand.</context>
      <utterance>Everyone falls, right, Trinity? But Trinity has left.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo stares at the blood.</context>
      <utterance>I thought it wasn't real.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If you are killed in the Matrix, you die here?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The body cannot live without the mind.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="36" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Whoa! Shit, Neo, you scared the bejeezus out of ne.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No, it's all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo's eyes light up as he steps closer to the screens that seem alive with a constant flow of data.</context>
      <utterance>Midnight watch.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that... ?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The monitors are packed with bizarre codes and equations.</context>
      <utterance>The Matrix? Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He pours Neo a drink from a large plastic jug.</context>
      <utterance>You want a drink?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo takes a sip and it almost kills him. Cypher pounds on his back.</context>
      <utterance>I'll tell you, I feel for you, man. I really do. Most of us were still young, just punks, when Morpheus jacked us. But you, you had a real life.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Red-faced, Neo finally stops coughing.</context>
      <utterance>Good shit, huh? Dozer makes it. It's good for two things: degreasing engines and killing brain cells.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo nods.</context>
      <utterance>Did he tell you why he did it?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER,</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo shakes his head as Cypher fills his cup and laughs.</context>
      <utterance>I'll be the didn't tell you that this wasn't the first time he thought he found the One.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cypher raises his drink. Neo swallows another throat- scorching mouthful.</context>
      <utterance>Let me give you a piece of advice. Between you and me, if Morpheus says you can fly, I wouldn't go jumping out any windows to find out if he's right. Understand?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the real world!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="37" n_utterances="15">
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The meat is so perfect, charred on the outside, oozing red juice from the inside, that it could be a dream.</context>
      <utterance>That's what he said to me nine years ago.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We recognize the grating voice, the insidious laugh.</context>
      <utterance>The real world. Ha, what a joke.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A fork stabs the cube of meat and we FOLLOW it UP TO the face of Cypher.</context>
      <utterance>You know what real is? I'll tell you what real is.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs, shoving the steak into his mouth. The restaurant is located on the top floor of a Chicago skyscraper where the view is breathtaking and the menu has no prices. Sitting across from Cypher is Agent Smith.</context>
      <utterance>Real is just another four-letter word.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cypher chews the steak loudly, smacking it between his teeth.</context>
      <utterance>Do we have a deal, Mr. Reagan?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smith watches him shovel another hunk of meat into his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>Mmm, so, so fucking good.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pausing, he examines the meat skewered on his fork. He pops it in, eyes rolling up, savoring the tender beef melting in his mouth.</context>
      <utterance>You know, I know that this steak doesn't exist. I know when I put it in my mouth, the Matrix is telling my brain that it is juicy and delicious. After nine years, do you know what I've realized?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Ignorance is bliss.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then we have a deal?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I don't want to remember nothing. Nothing! You understand? And I want to be rich. Someone important. Like an actor. You can do that, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cypher takes a deep drink of wine.</context>
      <utterance>Whatever you want, Mr. Reagan.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>All right. You get my body back in a power plant, reinsert me into the Matrix and I'll get you what you want.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Access codes to Zion.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, I don't know them. But I can give you the man who does.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morpheus.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="38" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Jeez, I was wondering about that.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why I was bald here but not in the Matrix.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="39" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Residual self image.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He points to one of Neo's monitors.</context>
      <utterance>Good. Now what's this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Life systems monitor, glucose levels.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's that?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He follows Tank to the operator's station where he points to a red key-switch.</context>
      <utterance>Main power supply to the core.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How about this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mainframe self-destruct. Uses all remaining power to generate an...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="40" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo nods as Morpheus comes up behind them.</context>
      <utterance>Electromagnetic pulse. Our best weapon against the machines. The problem is if someone is still in the Matrix when that thing goes off, they're not coming back.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's he doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We just finished the operation programs and he's showing great retention.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus walks away.</context>
      <utterance>Good. I want everyone alerted to 12-hour stand-by. We're going in. Neo, it's time for you to know why you're here.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's he talking about?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's taking you into the Matrix to see her.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See who?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo looks down at the monitor teeming with Matrix data that seems to coalesce, equations giving way to images as a METAL SCREAM RISES BECOMING --</context>
      <utterance>The Oracle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="41" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>We're in.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Let's go.</context>
      <utterance>Mouse and Cable hold the exit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="42" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you have to do this?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did she tell you?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lots of things.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trinity looks at him, then looks away.</context>
      <utterance>Any of them true?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Some of them.</utterance>
   <speaker>GIZMO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Were they good or bad?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They cross the old lobby. Switch and Apoc stop at the doors.</context>
      <utterance>There's no point in worrylng. Whatever is going to happen is going to happen.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should be back in an hour.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="43" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you now understand what it means when we say, if you're not one of us, you're one of them?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The agents. They're sentient programs. They can commandeer any software hardwired to the mainframe.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Anyone that is still in a power plant. That is why we try to be invisible in the Matrix.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cypher and Trinity move away from them, securing the perimeter. As Cypher passes a garbage can, he surreptitiously drops something inside. It is a cellular phone and we watch the blue display as the LINE CONNECTS. An early 1970s, black Lincoln Continental emerges from a corrugated roll-up garage. Morpheus and Neo get in.</context>
      <utterance>The best hacking is always traceless.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="44" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOJO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morpheus, been a long time coming.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Mojo coughs a brown, cankerous laugh, juice speckling his chin and shirt. He stares at Neo.</context>
      <utterance>You're looking well, Mojo.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOJO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He spits and laughs again.</context>
      <utterance>You bringing us geriatrics now. Morpheus?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOJO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guess you are locking for a miracle.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="45" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MOJO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They weave their way to the back of the bar, the STICKY FLOOR SNAPPING under their FEET. A monolith of a man rises from his stool as they walk up.</context>
      <utterance>All right, it's cool. Go on back.</utterance>
   <speaker>REX</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He moves to the side, opening the heavy iron door behind him. They descend the basement staircase toward the single bare bulb at the bottom, hanging above the only door.</context>
      <utterance>You're late.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="46" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What -- what happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Two PRIESTESSES are waiting in the antechamber.</context>
      <utterance>This is the temple. It is a part of Zion's mainframe. It's hidden inside the Matrix so that we can access it.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIESTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Morpheus. We've been expecting you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>They take Neo by the arm, leading him down a hall into another room.</context>
      <utterance>Okay, you're on your own. Go with them.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIESTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Wait here. Among the other Potentials.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="47" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>SPOON BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo watches as it curls into a knot.</context>
      <utterance>Your spoon does not bend because it is just that, a spoon. Mine bends because there is no spoon, just my mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>SPOON BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo nods, again holding up his spoon.</context>
      <utterance>Link yourself to the spoon. Become the spoon and bend yourself.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He concentrates. The spoon begins to bend just as the Priestess touches his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>There is no spoon. Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>PRIESTESS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Spoon Boy smiles.</context>
      <utterance>The Oracle will see you now.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="48" n_utterances="31">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A DISTANT FEMALE VOICE calls to him and he follows it up the stairs. At the top of the dais, he smells something cooking. Following the scent, he moves behind the pillars where he finds an open door.</context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>VOICE</speaker>
      <mode>O.S.</mode>
      <context>He walks through a vestibule where he sees a fabulous moonstone headdress and velvet robes. A second door leads into --</context>
      <utterance>Just come on in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode>WOMAN</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. You're Neo. Be right with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're the Oracle?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Bingo. I got to say I love seeing you non-believers. It's really a relief. All that pomp and circumstances just plain tucker me out. Almost done. Smell good, don't they?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'd ask you to sit down, but you're not going to anyway. And don't worry about the vase.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns to look around and his elbow knocks a VASE from the table. It BREAKS against the linoleum floor.</context>
      <utterance>What vase?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The vase.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls out a tray of chocolate chip cookies and turns. She is an older woman, wearing big oven mitts, comfortable slacks and a print blouse. She looks like someone's grandma.</context>
      <utterance>Shit, I'm sorry.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I said don't worry about it. I'll get one of my kids to fix it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How did you know...? She sets the cookie tray on a wooden hot-pad.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Smiling, she lights a cigarette.</context>
      <utterance>What's really going to bake your noodle later on is, would you still have broken it if I hadn't said anything.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're cuter than I thought. I see why she likes you.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Who?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She winks.</context>
      <utterance>Not too bright, though.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know why Morpheus brought you to see me?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I think so.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So? What do you think? You think you're the one?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She gestures to a wooden plaque, the kind every grandma has, except that the words are in Latin.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You know what that means? It's Latin. Means, 'Know thyself.' She puts her cigarette down.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She widens his eyes, checks his ears, then feels the glands in his neck.</context>
      <utterance>Well, let's have a look at you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Open your mouth. Say, 'ahhh.' She nods then looks at his palms.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hmmm. You sure got the gift, but it's tricky. I'd say the bad news is, you're not the one. Still got a lot to learn. Maybe next life.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's the good news?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Same as the bad news, you're not the one.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Is that it, then?</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She picks up the tray of cooling cookies.</context>
      <utterance>No. Here.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He eyes her, then takes a cookie.</context>
      <utterance>You better take a cookie. Got a big day ahead of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>ORACLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Make a believer out of you yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="49" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't have to tell me anything, Neo, because I already know what she said.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You do?</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo finishes his cookie.</context>
      <utterance>I brought you so that you could hear it for yourself. I knew it would help.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one will ever ask you because it is a gift from her. It is for you and you alone.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="50" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Welcome to Movie-Phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're on their way.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The phone flips shut as he jumps up.</context>
      <utterance>Right.</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Let's get to work.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="51" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Oh, shit! Oh, shit!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What did you just say?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nothing. Just had a little deja vu.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened? What did you see?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>A black cat went past us and then I saw another that looked just like it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much like it? Was it the same cat?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trinity looks at Morpheus, who listens quietly to the rasping breath of the old building.</context>
      <utterance>It might have been. I'm not sure.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She also listens as the staccato BEAT of HELICOPTER BLADES GROW ominously LOUDER.</context>
      <utterance>A deja vu is usually a glitch in the Matrix. It happens when they change something.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It's a trap!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="52" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you just feel something weird?</utterance>
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The CELLULAR RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="53" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>MOUSE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What's going on?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Cable yanks open the curtain.</context>
      <utterance>They cut the hard-line! It's a trap! Get out!</utterance>
   <speaker>CABLE</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The windows are bricked up.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, no.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="54" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The sound of heavy BOOT-STEPS close around them with the mechanical sureness of a vice.</context>
      <utterance>That's what they changed. We're trapped. There's no way out.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Give me your phone.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They'll be able to track it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have no choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>His fingers pound the keyboard.</context>
      <utterance>Tank, find a structural drawing of this building and find it fast.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="55" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need the main wet-wall.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="56" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now left and that's it in front of you.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He cuts off the phone.</context>
      <utterance>Good.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighth floor. They're on the eighth floor.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT BROWTJ</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Eighth floor! Move!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="57" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cypher seems to trip as the cloud envelops him.</context>
      <utterance>Come on!</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Nerve gas.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="58" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You have to get Neo out. Understand? That's all that matters now.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morpheus, don't --</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>A font of water erupts as Morpheus leaps for the manhole ladder, his coat flying open like the wings of a manta ray.</context>
      <utterance>He must get out. Do you understand me? She nods.</utterance>
   <speaker>COPS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Pools of light wash over him as he hauls himself to the surface.</context>
      <utterance>There he is! That's him!</utterance>
   <speaker>COP</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trinity urges the others to follow her. Grabbing Neo, they wade quietly away from the chaos.</context>
      <utterance>He's heading for the street!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="59" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So, we meet at last.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>And you are?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Smith. I am Agent Smith.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You all look the same to me.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Faster than a snake spits, Morpheus cracks Smith with a jaw-breaking right.</context>
      <utterance>I've been waiting for this noment.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Smith smiles.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, so have I.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="60" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus smiles.</context>
      <utterance>You can't win.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands up and drops his fists; a steely resolve in his eyes.</context>
      <utterance>I already have.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cops swarm over Morpheus.</context>
      <utterance>Take him.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="61" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>AGENT JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The others were lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Jones nods.</context>
      <utterance>You've taken care of Reagan?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Then the others do not matter.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="62" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PHONE RINGS.</context>
      <utterance>We gotta find the others. They're still alive.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Operator.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I need an exit! Fast!</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cypher? I thought they had you?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="63" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There was an accident. A fucking car accident. All of a sudden. Boom. They're all dead. I still got the shakes but, Jesus, someone's going to make a believer out of me.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>There he is.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I got you.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Just get me outta here.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An actor. Definitely.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Operator.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tank, it's me.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="64" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We need an exit!</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Gotcha. You're not far from Cypher.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cypher, I thought --</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>So did we. That boy's got nine lives. I sent him to Franklin and Erie.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She hangs up.</context>
      <utterance>Got it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="65" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cypher's body twitches in its harness, jerking itself awake. His eyes blink open. Dozer unplugs him.</context>
      <utterance>Got him.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cypher stands, a raspy cough spewing from his lungs.</context>
      <utterance>System check looks fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>DOZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You okay?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He crosses to an overhead bin.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamn gas. My lungs are killing me.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We got any pain killers?</utterance>
   <speaker>DOZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>As Dozer stoops for a cabinet, Cypher pulls back a heavy blanket exposing a plasma rifle.</context>
      <utterance>The first aid kit's over here.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="66" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>DOZER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tank spins as red hot wads of PLASMA EXPLODE through his chair and into his back. Diving, a second BURST tears up his side -- As Dozer shoots a look at the monitor where Tank was working. He stabs the enter command activating the exit sequence and ducks under a BARRAGE of PLASMA FIRE-</context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>SWITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>God, I love that sound.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="67" n_utterances="3">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo answers the phone when there is a CLICK. There is no signal. Nothing but silence.</context>
      <utterance>You first,.Neo.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trinity listens to the dead line and takes out the cellular.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. It just went dead.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="68" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hello, Trinity.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Cypher? Where's Tank?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He had an accident.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Is Dozer there?</context>
      <utterance>An accident? What about Dozer?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="69" n_utterances="23">
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He nuzzles his face against hers, feeling the softness of it.</context>
      <utterance>You know, for a long time, I thought I was in love with you, Trinity. I used to dream about you...</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>We INTERCUT BETWEEN the appliance store and the main deck.</context>
      <utterance>You are a beautiful woman. Too bad things had to work out like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You killed them.</utterance>
   <speaker>APOC</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?!</utterance>
   <speaker>SWITCH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Wearing Tank's operator headgear, Cypher moves among the silent bodies.</context>
      <utterance>Oh God.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands over the body of Morpheus, as his anger boils up out of him.</context>
      <utterance>In a way you're very lucky. Most people never know why they die. One minute they're alive, the next they're dead. No warning. Nothing. That's why I thought maybe I should tell you. It seemed the least I could do.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, the truth, the real,truth is that the war is over. It's been over for a long time. And guess what? We lost! Did you hear that? We lost the war!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What about Zion?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She suddenly sees the entire dark plan.</context>
      <utterance>Zion? Zion is a part of this delusion. More of this madness. That's why this has to be done. It has to end. Now and forever.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cypher walks away from Morpheus and bends down next to Apoc's body.</context>
      <utterance>Oh rny God. This is abzut Zion. You gave them Morpheus for the access codes to Zion.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You see, Trinity, we humans have a place in the future. But it's not here. It's in the Matrix.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The Matrix isn't real!</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He grabs hold of the cable in Apoc's neck, twists it and yanks it out.</context>
      <utterance>Oh, I disagree, Trinity. I disagree. I think the Matrix is more real than this world. I mean, all I do is pull a plug here. But there, you watch a man die.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Apoc seems to go blind for an instant, a scream caught in his throat, his hands reaching for nothing, and then falls dead. Switch screams.</context>
      <utterance>You tell me which is more real.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He laughs.</context>
      <utterance>Welcome to the real world, right?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Somehow, some way, you're going to pay for this.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His hand slides around the neck of Switch as he takes hold of her plug. She suddenly feels her body severed from her mind as she is murdered.</context>
      <utterance>Pay for it? I'm not even going to remember it. It'll be like it never happened. The tree falling in the forest. It doesn't make a sound.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamn you, Cypher!</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stands over Neo.</context>
      <utterance>Don't hate me, Trinity. I'm just the messenger. And right now I'm going to prove that the message is true.</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She turns to Neo, eyes wide with fear, and he knows he is next.</context>
      <utterance>If Morpheus was right, then there's no way I can pull this plug, is there?</utterance>
   <speaker>CYPHER</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cypher is on the ground, his left leg blown off at the knee. He rolls over and finds Tank on the ground, and the sights of the plasma rifle.</context>
      <utterance>If he is the One, then in the next few seconds there has to be some kind of miracle to stop me. Because if he dies like the others that means Morpheus was wrong. How can he be the One if he's dead? He takes hold of the cord when -- She hears an EXPLOSION and a scream.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How's it feel, Cypher? Knowing you're about to die?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Cypher lunges for Neo's plug just as Tank BLOWS his head off.</context>
      <utterance>It's Tank! He's alive.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="70" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We should, we should hurry.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Yeah. Right.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="71" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tank, you're hurt.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'll be all right.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tank's face tightens.</context>
      <utterance>Dozer?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry, Tank.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="72" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AGENT JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Smith stares out the window.</context>
      <utterance>There is a problem. Reagan has failed to secure the hardware.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Never send a human to do a machine's job.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But if Reagan has failed, why haven't they pulled the plug?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns.</context>
      <utterance>Haven't you learned by now, that it is impossible to understand why they do the things they do?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus is handcuffed to a chair, stripped to the waist. He is bleeding from numerous wounds and is pumped full of serum, alternately shivering and sweating. He is hooked up to various monitors with white disk electrodes. Agent Brown begins running a trace program.</context>
      <utterance>Continue as planned. Trace his signal to locate their position and deploy an extermination unit.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="73" n_utterances="22">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are they doing to him?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're cracking his mind.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They inject virus-like serums to break down the system. It's like cracking a computer. All it takes is time.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How much time?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Tank punches several commands on Morpheus' personal unit. The monitor waves change from a chaotic pattern to an orderly symmetrical one.</context>
      <utterance>Depends on the mind. But eventually, it will crack and his alpha pattern will change from this to this.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>When it does, Morpheus will tell them anything they want to know.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The access codes to Zion.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He looks up at Trinity who is pacing relentlessly.</context>
      <utterance>If an agent got inside Zion's mainframe he could do anything. Disable the defense system. It would be the end of us.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trinity sees Cypher's dead body. Rage overtakes her and she starts kicking hin.</context>
      <utterance>We can't let that happen. We have to do it, Trinity. Zion has to be protected.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit! Goddamnit!</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have to pull the plug.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No!</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Those words are like using gasoline to put out a fire and we watch the pain in her eyes burn into a blaze. She walks past him and gets into her chair.</context>
      <utterance>We don't have any other choice.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Trinity, what are you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going in after him.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morpheus could conform at any minute --</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>If he does I'm sure you'll do what has to be done.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She glares at him.</context>
      <utterance>You saw that place. It's suicide.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know what Morpheus means to you --</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She yanks her harness tight.</context>
      <utterance>No. No, I don't think you do. If you did, then you would know that I'm not letting him go. Not without a fight, Tank.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not without a fight.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="74" n_utterances="20">
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Brown sucks a serum from a glass vial, filling a hypodermic needle.</context>
      <utterance>Have you ever stood and stared at it, Morpheus? Marveled at its beauty. Its genius. Billions of people just living out their lives... oblivious.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Brown jams the needle into Morpheus' shoulder, and plunges down.</context>
      <utterance>Did you know that the first Matrix was designed to be a perfect human world? Where none suffered, where everyone would be happy. It was a disaster. No one would accept the program. Entire crops were lost.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Brown studies the screens as the life signs react violently to the injection.</context>
      <utterance>Some believed we lacked the programming language to describe your perfect world. But I believe that, as a species, human beings define their reality through suffering and misery.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He turns from the window.</context>
      <utterance>The perfect world was a dream that your primitive cerebrum kept trying to wake up from. Which is why the Matrix was re-designed to this: the peak of your civilization.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He sits down directly in front of Morpheus.</context>
      <utterance>I say 'your civilization' because as soon as we start thinking for you, it really becomes our civilization, which is, of course, what this is all about.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts Morpheus' head.</context>
      <utterance>Evolution, Morpheus. Evolution.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus stares hard at him, trying hard not to show the pain racking his mind.</context>
      <utterance>Like the dinosaur. Look out that window. You had your time.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The future is our time.</context>
      <utterance>The future is our world, Morpheus.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What do you think you're doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You need help. I'm coming with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No. No way. Morpheus sacrificed himself so you could escape. There's no way you're going back in.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morpheus did what he did because he believed that I'm something that I'm not.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trinity is stunned.</context>
      <utterance>I'm not the One, Trinity. The Oracle told me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>She said I had a gift but I still had a lot to learn. She told me maybe next life.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Did you tell Morpheus?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He straps in.</context>
      <utterance>Why? It wouldn't mean anything. He'd still believe what he wanted to believe. But Morpheus is the one that matters. He's more important than me and we both know it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I may not be what Morpheus thinks I am, but if I don't try to help him, then I'm not even what I think I am.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What are you?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>His friend.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="75" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The life signs continue their chaotic patterns.</context>
      <utterance>I'd like to share a revelation that I've had during my time here. It came to me when I tried to classify your species. I've realized that you are not actually mammals.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He leans forward.</context>
      <utterance>Every mammal on this planet instinctively develops a natural equilibrium with the surrounding environment. But you humans do not. You move to an area and you multiply and multiply until every natural resource is consumed and the only way you can survive is to spread to another area.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He smiles.</context>
      <utterance>There is another organism on this planet that follows the same pattern. Do you know what it is? A virus.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Human beings are a disease, a cancer of this planet. You are a plague. And we are... the cure.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="76" n_utterances="14">
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Okay. Store's open. What do you need?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Guns. Lots of guns.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He loads the weapons disk.</context>
      <utterance>Coming right up.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>No one has ever done anything like this.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He snap cocks an Uzi.</context>
      <utterance>Yeah?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That's why it's going to work.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Why isn't the serum working?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Perhaps we are asking the wrong questions.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Or he doesn't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Of course he knows. He's resisting.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>How?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Smith hides his knotting fist. He is becoming angry. It is something that isn't supposed to happen to agents.</context>
      <utterance>I don't know. If I knew...</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Brown and Jones look at each other.</context>
      <utterance>Leave me with him.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="77" n_utterances="9">
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He removes his earphone, letting it dangle over his shoulder.</context>
      <utterance>Can you hear me, Morpheus? I'm going to be honest with you.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He wipes sweat from Morpheus' forehead, coating the tips of his fingers, holding them to Morpheus' nose.</context>
      <utterance>I hate this place. This zoo. This prison. This reality, whatever you want to call it, I can't stand it any longer. It's the smell, if there is such a thing. I feel saturated by it. I can taste your stink and every time I do, I fear that I've somehow been infected by it.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He lifts Morpheus' head, holding it tightly with both hands.</context>
      <utterance>Repulsive, isn't it?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus sneers through his pain.</context>
      <utterance>I must get out of here, I must get free. In this mind is tlie key. My key.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He begins squeezing, his fingers gouging into his flesh.</context>
      <utterance>Once Zion is gone, there's no need for me to be here. Do you understand? I need the codes. I have to get inside Zion. You have to tell me how.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The skull is about to shatter when Agents Jones and Brown burst into the room. Agent Smith releases Morpheus.</context>
      <utterance>Tell me! Tell me!</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Smith recovers, replacing his ear piece.</context>
      <utterance>What were you doing?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You don't know.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Smith listens to his earphone, not believing what he is hearing.</context>
      <utterance>Know what?</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="78" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AGENT JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Lower level --</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They are actually attacking.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="79" n_utterances="13">
   <speaker>PILOT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly his face, his whole body dissolves, consumed by spreading locust-like swarm, of STATIC as -- Agent Jones emerges. Just as she drops the last Marine, Trinity sees what's coming. Neo sees her, the fear in her face, and he knows what is behind him. Screaming, he whirls, GUNS filling his hands with thought-speed. Fingers PUMPING, SHELLS ejecting, dancing up and away, we look through the sights and gun smoke at -- The Agent blurred with motion -- Until the HAMMERS CLICK against empty metal.</context>
      <utterance>I repeat, we are under attack!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Jones charges.</context>
      <utterance>Trinity!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>His GUN BOOMS as we enter the liquid space of -- Bullet-time. The AIR SIZZLES with wads of lead-like angry flies as Neo twists, bends, ducks just between them. Agent Jones still running, narrows the gap, the BULLETS coming faster until -- Neo bent impossibly back, one hand on the ground as a spiraling gray ball shears open his shoulder. He starts to scream as another digs a red groove across his thigh. He has only time to look up, to see the barrel when Agent Jones, standing over him, pulls the TRIGGER the final time. CLICK. Empty. Neo rolls, reaching for another gun when around-house kick snaps his jaw. Agent Jones grabs the gun and levels it at Neo.</context>
      <utterance>... help.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Suddenly Agent Jones stops. Something is wrong. He scans the roof. Trinity is gone. Immediately, he whirls around and turns straight into the muzzle of her .45 -- Jammed right into his head.</context>
      <utterance>Only human...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>BOOM! BOOM! BOOM! The body flies back with a flash of mercurial light and when it hits the ground -- It is the pilot. Trinity helps Neo up.</context>
      <utterance>Dodge this, motherfucker!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Thanks.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You're hit --</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo is already looking at the helicopter.</context>
      <utterance>I'm fine.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Can you fly that thing?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls out a cellular phone.</context>
      <utterance>Not yet.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Operator.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Tank is immediately searching the disk drawers.</context>
      <utterance>Tank, I need a pilot program for a military M-109 helicopter.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>His fingers flash over the gleaming laser disks, finding one that he feeds into Trinityls supplement drive, punching the "load" cormands on her keyboard.</context>
      <utterance>Hurry!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="80" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sir! Sir! There was gunfire -- we've lost communication with the roof!</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Remain at your posts.</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>But, sir -- the fire -- we should evacuate!</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You will do as you are ordered!</utterance>
   <speaker>SERGEANT</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Jones marches into the Presidential Suite.</context>
      <utterance>Yes, sir.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="81" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The GUN jumps and BULLETS EXPLODE through the WINDOW in a cacophony of CRASHING GLASS -- As the Agents go for their weapons. But Neo is too close, the .50 CALIBER too fast and BULLETS are everywhere, perforating the room. Agent Smith is hit first, his body jack-knifing back, blood arcing out with a sudden flash of light -- Then Agent Brown, his GUN still FIRING as his body falls. And finally Agent Jones. Neo stares at Morpheus, trying to will him into action.</context>
      <utterance>No.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus sits unmoving, his head still down. Neo grabs the climbing rope just as marines burst into the adjoining room. He attaches only one end to his harness when they OPEN</context>
      <utterance>Get up, Morpheus! Get up!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="82" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He FIRES, sweeping across the sheetrocked wall in a perfect line. For an instant, we see the BULLETS SHRED, PUNCTURING the WALL, searing through the wet air with jet trails of chalk. And as Morpheus starts to dive for the window, a bullet buries itself in his leg -- Knocking him off balance.</context>
      <utterance>Nooo!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus lunges, out of control -- As Neo spins, every move a whip crack -- Snapping the other rope-end onto a bolted bar. Morpheus begins to fall when Neo hurls himself into the wide blue empty space -- Flying for a moment. The rope snaking out behind him; an umbilical cord attached to a machine. As their two bodies, set in motion, rushing at each other on a seemingly magnetic course until -- They collide. Almost bouncing free of each other, arms, legs, scrambling, hands searching in furious desperation, finding hold and clinging. Until the line ends, snapping taut, cracking their fragile embrace. Morpheus tumbles, legs flipping over, falling down -- The ground deliriously distant -- As Neo snatches hold of his mentor's still handcuffed wrist.</context>
      <utterance>He won't make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trinity is already pulling the copter up and away. As Agent Smith grabs the M-16 from the nearest marine. He'll bring them all down. Targeting the helicopter, he aims at something only he can see: the oil line. PONK. PONK. PONK. The rear HULL is PUNCHED full of holes and smoke and oil pours out like black blood.</context>
      <utterance>Gotcha!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo is pulling Morpheus up to him when he hears the</context>
      <utterance>Shit-shit-no!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="83" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Trinity throws the helicopter towards the roof of the nearest building. Morpheus and Neo cling to one another as they and the machine above them begin to fall. The ENGINE GRINDS, the CHOPPING BLADES start to slow while -- The Agents stand in the open shattered window, watching the helicopter disappear behind taller buildings. Carried by its nomentum, Trinity guides the parabolic fall over the nearest roof where -- Neo and Morpheus drop safely, rolling free as the rope goes slack. Neo gets to his feet, trying to detach himself but -- The helicopter is falling too fast, arcing over the roof like a setting sun -- The coils of slack snap taught -- Yanking Neo off his feet, dragging him with ferocious speed towards the edge even as -- Trinity lunges for the back door, her gun in one hand, grabbing for the rope with the other -- Neo flies like a skipping stone, hurtling straight AT us, when his feet hit the rain gutter -- A fulcrum that levers him up just as -- Trinity FIRES, severing the cord from the HELICOPTER, falling free of it as it SMASHES, blades first into a glass skyscraper. Holding onto the rope she swings, connected to Neo, who stands on the building's edge watching her arc beneath him as the HELICOPTER EXPLODES -- She bounces against a shatterproof window that spider- cracks out while FLAMES ERUPT behind her.</context>
      <utterance>Oh fuck.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's the One. He's got to be...</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="84" n_utterances="10">
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I knew it! I goddamn knew it!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She runs at him, throwing her arms around him.</context>
      <utterance>Morpheus!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do you believe me now? He's the One! Who else could have done this?</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Morpheus, I know you won't believe me but the Oracle told ne I'm not the One.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>It doesn't matter if I don't believe you -- His eyes light up.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What matters is that you don't believe her.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Tank, get us out of here.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Got one ready. An underground El station. State and Balbo.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>LINE GOES DEAD. Tank looks at the bodies and smiles.</context>
      <utterance>See ya soon.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>See ya soon.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="85" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>AGENT BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The trace was completed.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>We have their position.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>The extermination unit is in place.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT JONES</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Smith can't stand listening to them. He moves to the edge of the building, looking out at the surrounding city.</context>
      <utterance>Order the strike.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>They're not out yet.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="86" n_utterances="6">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Man stops, Neo rushes at hin, gliding smoothly over the turnstiles.</context>
      <utterance>Don't!</utterance>
   <speaker>OLD MAN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Man is shaking, terrified. Neo looks at his gun. He glances over his shoulder, then eases back the hammer.</context>
      <utterance>I'm sorry -- I didn't mean!</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The Old Man nods, turns and hurries deeper into the urban cave, disappearing into the shadows as Trinity and Morpheus arrive.</context>
      <utterance>Get outta here. Okay? Run! Go!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What happened? Was that --</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo turns to the RINGING BOOTH.</context>
      <utterance>It was nobody.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Morpheus gets in and answers the phone. Lost in the shadow, the Old Man turns back and watches as Morpheus disappears, the phone dropping, dangling by its cord. His eyes grow wide, glowing white in the dark.</context>
      <utterance>Let's go! You first, Morpheus.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="87" n_utterances="5">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>What matters is what you believe.</context>
      <utterance>Morpheus is right, you know. It doesn't matter what he believes or even what the Oracle believes.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He stares at the fullness of her lips.</context>
      <utterance>I believe...</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She smiles.</context>
      <utterance>I want to kiss you.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The PHONE begins to RING.</context>
      <utterance>I want to kiss you too...</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pulls herself away and gets into the booth when something catches Neo's eye and he looks to where the Old Man had been. She hears him SCREAM and sees Agent Smith emerge as if formed by congealing darkness, charging with a fistful of metal. The GUN FIRES, the BULLET flying at her, BURSTING through the plastic WINDOW just as -- Trinity disappears. The handset hanging in the air as the BULLET HITS, SHATTERING the EAR-PIECE.</context>
      <utterance>But I want it to be real.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="88" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Neo!</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What the hell just happened?</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>An Agent! You have to send me back!</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I can't!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="89" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo pulls the TRIGGER. CLICK.</context>
      <utterance>You're empty.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The smile falls. Agent Smith yanks his TRIGGER.</context>
      <utterance>So are you.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="90" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't win.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>He attacks with a vicious series of blows but the Agent seems to absorb them, waiting for his opening. And this time Agent Smith's attack is too much, an unrelenting fury, fists pounding like jackhammers.</context>
      <utterance>I already have.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="91" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Send me back, Tank! Anywhere!</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>From the cockpit, an ALARM sounds. Morpheus hurries to the front console, typing, bringing up the radar. Trinity follows him.</context>
      <utterance>I'm looking, Trinity! I'm looking!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What is it... oh no. In every pipe surrounding them, they see the Extermination Unit.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Sentinels.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="92" n_utterances="7">
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Smith grabs Neo in a choke-hold, forcing him to look down the tracks, the train's headlight burning a hole in the darkness.</context>
      <utterance>Do you hear that, Mr. Anderson?</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Neo sees it coming and he starts to fight.</context>
      <utterance>That is the sound of inevitability.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is another METAL SCREECH, MUCH LOUDER, closer, as Agent Smith tightens his hold. Neo is unable to breathe.</context>
      <utterance>It is the sound of your death.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>The TRAIN ROARS at them, swallowing Agent Smith's words. The veins bulge in Neo's head, as he grits through the pain. He is not ready to die.</context>
      <utterance>Goodbye, Mr. Anderson.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Impossibly, he hurls himself straight up, smashing Smith against the concrete ceiling of the tunnel. They fall as the sound and fury of the TRAIN EXPLODES INTO the station. Neo back-flips up off the tracks just as -- The train barrels over Agent Smith. Neo stands, knees shaking, when the train slams on its emergency brake. With an ear-splitting SHRIEK of TORTURED RAILS, the train slows, part of it still in the station. Neo turns, limping, starting to run, racing for the escalator -- As the train comes to a stop and the doors of the last car open; Agent Smith bursts out in furious pursuit, his glasses again intact.</context>
      <utterance>My name is Neo.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>You can't use that until Neo is out!</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I know. Don't worry, he'll make it.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="93" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Operator.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mr. Wizard, Get me the fuck out of here!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="94" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm trying, Trinity. I'm trying.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Neo glances to his right and sees Agent Brown, now driving the car beside his. Agent Brown swerves, slamming into him.</context>
      <utterance>I got one!</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Neo fights the steering wheel as Agent Brown pushes the car up over the median.</context>
      <utterance>Wabash and Lake. A hotel.</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>Neo drops the phone as his car bucks into the opposing lane -- Directly into the charging path of an enormous truck driven by Agent Smith. Neo dives from the Mercedes as the truck plows into it, rending metal and GLASS, crushing through, totaling other cars, as it EXPLODES. Neo is up and running even as orange and black clouds billow up behind hin.</context>
      <utterance>Room 303.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="95" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I'm going to make the call.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Do it!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="96" n_utterances="4">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Where is he?</utterance>
   <speaker>TANK</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Almost there.</utterance>
   <speaker>MORPHEUS</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>He's going to make it.</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Hurry, Neo.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="97" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>AGENT BROWN</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>Agent Smith smiles, standing over him.</context>
      <utterance>He's gone.</utterance>
   <speaker>AGENT SMITH</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>I told you, you couldn't win.</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="98" n_utterances="2">
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>She pounds on his chest.</context>
      <utterance>Goddamnit, Neo! Don't give it up! Not now!</utterance>
   <speaker>TRINITY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Not now!</utterance>
</dialogue>

<dialogue id="99" n_utterances="8">
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We CLOSE IN ON the racing columns of numbers shimmering across the screen.</context>
      <utterance>Hi. It's me. I know you're out there. I know you're working as fast as you can to catch me.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We DIVE THROUGH the numbers, surging UP THROUGH the darkness, sucked TOWARDS a tight constellation of stars.</context>
      <utterance>I thought I should call and let you know how things stand.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We realize that the constellation is actually the holes in the mouthpiece of a phone. Seen from inside.</context>
      <utterance>I know you're real proud of this world you've built, the way it works, all the nice little rules and such, but I've got some bad news.</utterance>
   <speaker>NEO</speaker>
      <mode>V.O.</mode>
      <context>We SHOOT THROUGH the holes as Neo hangs up the phone. He steps out of the phone booth and starts walking, wearing a long black coat and dark glasses. He passes a mother dragging her little BOY, who cranes his neck as -- Neo takes off, flying up into the air.</context>
      <utterance>I've decided to make a few changes.</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>Mommy! Mommy!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>What?</utterance>
   <speaker>BOY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context></context>
      <utterance>That man! That man flies!</utterance>
   <speaker>MOMMY</speaker>
      <mode></mode>
      <context>There is a RUSH of AIR as the Boy stares up as Neo shoots overhead. His coat billowing like a black leather cape as he soars up, up, and away.</context>
      <utterance>Don't be silly, honey. Men don't fly.</utterance>
</dialogue>


</movie>
